{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Budgeting overview\ndescription: Almost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals. This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition or load them from a third-party program.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 60113\nms.assetid: 28a9793e-d376-47af-a345-69046bad17df\nms.search.region: global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sigitac\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Budgeting overview\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nAlmost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals. This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations or load them from a third-party program.\n\nOverview\n--------\n\nThe approved budget for a legal entity is maintained in a document that is known as a *budget register entry*. The lines in a budget register entry document are known as *budget account* entries, and contain financial dimension information, dates, and the amounts of the approved budget. The budget register entry document is integrated with basic financial reports and inquiry pages where ledger actual amounts are compared to budget amounts. \n\nThere are multiple methods for creating budget register entries in Finance and Operations:\n\n-   Manually enter the document information on the **Budget register entries** page.\n-   Use the Microsoft Excel template that you can open by clicking the **Open in Excel** button on the **Budget register entries** page.\n-   Use the **Budget Account Entries** data entity in Data management to import budget register entries. You should consider using this method and turning on the **Set based** **processing **parameter when you must import many budget account entries into the system.\n-   If the company uses Budget planning functionality to prepare budget data, you can use the **Generate budget register entry** periodic process.\n\nThe budget register entry is considered completed when the budget balances have been updated. On the **Budget register entries** page, click **Update budget balances** for a selected budget register entry or multiple entries. After you update the budget balances, the status of the budget register entry changes to **Completed**. Completed budget register entry can't be re-opened for edits. Therefore, if the budget data must be adjusted, you must create a new budget register entry instead of correcting data in the completed budget register entry.\n\n## Configuration\nWhen you configure budgeting, start on the **Budgeting parameters** page. On this page, you must define the budget journal, the number sequence for budget register entries, and the default behavior in the workspaces.\n\nNext, if there are policies that govern the approval of budget register entries, based on budget type (for example, transfers or revisions), you must create budget register entry workflows on the **Budgeting workflows** page. If there are scenarios where transfers might be allowed without workflow approval, you can define budget transfer rules to support those scenarios. \n\nOn the **Budgeting dimensions** page, you must select the financial dimensions that are used for budgeting, based on the dimensions that are used in the chart of accounts. You can select all financial dimensions or a subset of them for budgeting.\n\nDefine a *budget model *that corresponds to all or some of the budgets. You can use a single budget model for all budget register entries. Alternatively, you can create separate models that are based on the budget type, the geographical location, or some other way that a budget can be classified. \n\n> [!NOTE] \n> If budget control is used, you can associate only one budget model with a specific budget cycle time span. \n\nCreate *budget codes* that identify the type of budget transactions to record and any related workflow. Budget codes can support the following budget types:\n\n-   Original budget\n-   Transfer\n-   Revision\n-   Encumbrance\n-   Pre-encumbrance\n-   Carry-forward budget\n\nBudget codes let you have an audit trail of approved budget modifications throughout the course of the budget cycle. If a workflow is associated with a budget code, the workflow will be enabled for all budget register entries that use that budget code, and workflow steps must be completed before the budget register entry can reach the **Completed** stage.  \n\nYou can also optionally set up *budget transfer rules*. To use budget transfer rules, select **Use rules for budget transfers** on the **Budget parameters** page. When budget transfer rules are used, if a user creates a document by using a budget code of the **Transfer** type, budget balances won't be updated if the budget transfer rules are violated. For example, you can allow budget transfer documents where the expense budget is transferred between the main accounts for the Sales and Marketing department, but can prohibit budget from being transferred from or to that department unless workflow approval has been granted for that type of budget account entry.\n\n## Using workspaces and inquiry pages to track budget vs. actuals\nThe budget manager can review the current state of a budget in the **Ledger budgets and forecasts** workspace. The **Expense over budget** and **Revenue under budget** tabs provide a quick view of the financial dimension combinations where budget targets aren't being met or are approaching the threshold. You can personalize the budget threshold percentage and financial dimension sets that are used on those tabs by clicking **Configure my workspace**. You can click **Unit managers** to see the workers who are responsible for specific financial dimension combinations that are selected on those tabs. For example, if you see that the expense budget of the Operations department is going over the budget threshold, you can easily find and contact the Operations department manager to discuss the issue. \n\n> [!NOTE] \n> The **Department manager** field on the **Organization Units** page determines which managers support specific financial dimension combinations. Click **See more** at the bottom of the tab to open the **Budget vs actuals** inquiry page for more details about budget amounts versus actual amounts. \n\nThe **Actual vs budget** inquiry page lets you drill into the details of the budget versus actual amounts. Select a line on the inquiry page, and then click **Period balances** to see budget and actual amounts spread across fiscal periods. The **Budget account entries** page provides drill-through to the details of the budget amount in budget register entries. The **General journal entries** page opens the ledger transactions that are included in the calculated **Actuals** amount. \n\nA company that is using Budget planning functionality can create and use *budget forecasts* in the **Ledger budgets and forecasts** workspace.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,961],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Budgeting overview\ndescription: Almost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals. This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition or load them from a third-party program.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 60113\nms.assetid: 28a9793e-d376-47af-a345-69046bad17df\nms.search.region: global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sigitac\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Budgeting overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,18],"content":"Budgeting overview","nodes":[{"content":"Budgeting overview","pos":[0,18]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"Almost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals. This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition or load them from a third-party program.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,369],"content":"Almost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals. This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition or load them from a third-party program.","nodes":[{"content":"Almost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals. This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition or load them from a third-party program.","pos":[0,369],"nodes":[{"content":"Almost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals.","pos":[0,190]},{"content":"This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition or load them from a third-party program.","pos":[191,369]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[969,987],"content":"Budgeting overview","linkify":"Budgeting overview","nodes":[{"content":"Budgeting overview","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"Almost every company that uses Financials functionality in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition will have to be able to create reports of budget vs. actuals.","pos":[1033,1223]},{"content":"This article explains the minimum configuration that is required in order to create budgets in Finance and Operations or load them from a third-party program.","pos":[1224,1382]},{"pos":[1384,1392],"content":"Overview","linkify":"Overview","nodes":[{"content":"Overview","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"The approved budget for a legal entity is maintained in a document that is known as a <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>budget register entry<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[1403,1513],"source":"The approved budget for a legal entity is maintained in a document that is known as a *budget register entry*."},{"content":"The lines in a budget register entry document are known as <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>budget account<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> entries, and contain financial dimension information, dates, and the amounts of the approved budget.","pos":[1514,1690],"source":" The lines in a budget register entry document are known as *budget account* entries, and contain financial dimension information, dates, and the amounts of the approved budget."},{"content":"The budget register entry document is integrated with basic financial reports and inquiry pages where ledger actual amounts are compared to budget amounts.","pos":[1691,1846]},{"content":"There are multiple methods for creating budget register entries in Finance and Operations:","pos":[1849,1939]},{"pos":[1945,2025],"content":"Manually enter the document information on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budget register entries<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"Manually enter the document information on the **Budget register entries** page."},{"pos":[2030,2162],"content":"Use the Microsoft Excel template that you can open by clicking the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open in Excel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Budget register entries<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","source":"Use the Microsoft Excel template that you can open by clicking the **Open in Excel** button on the **Budget register entries** page."},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budget Account Entries<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> data entity in Data management to import budget register entries.","pos":[2167,2267],"source":"Use the **Budget Account Entries** data entity in Data management to import budget register entries."},{"content":"You should consider using this method and turning on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Set based<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> **processing **parameter when you must import many budget account entries into the system.","pos":[2268,2429],"source":" You should consider using this method and turning on the **Set based** **processing **parameter when you must import many budget account entries into the system."},{"pos":[2434,2576],"content":"If the company uses Budget planning functionality to prepare budget data, you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Generate budget register entry<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> periodic process.","source":"If the company uses Budget planning functionality to prepare budget data, you can use the **Generate budget register entry** periodic process."},{"content":"The budget register entry is considered completed when the budget balances have been updated.","pos":[2578,2671]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budget register entries<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Update budget balances<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> for a selected budget register entry or multiple entries.","pos":[2672,2803],"source":" On the **Budget register entries** page, click **Update budget balances** for a selected budget register entry or multiple entries."},{"content":"After you update the budget balances, the status of the budget register entry changes to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Completed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2804,2907],"source":" After you update the budget balances, the status of the budget register entry changes to **Completed**."},{"content":"Completed budget register entry can't be re-opened for edits.","pos":[2908,2969]},{"content":"Therefore, if the budget data must be adjusted, you must create a new budget register entry instead of correcting data in the completed budget register entry.","pos":[2970,3128]},{"pos":[3133,3146],"content":"Configuration","linkify":"Configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Configuration","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"When you configure budgeting, start on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budgeting parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3147,3220],"source":"When you configure budgeting, start on the **Budgeting parameters** page."},{"content":"On this page, you must define the budget journal, the number sequence for budget register entries, and the default behavior in the workspaces.","pos":[3221,3363]},{"content":"Next, if there are policies that govern the approval of budget register entries, based on budget type (for example, transfers or revisions), you must create budget register entry workflows on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budgeting workflows<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3365,3590],"source":"Next, if there are policies that govern the approval of budget register entries, based on budget type (for example, transfers or revisions), you must create budget register entry workflows on the **Budgeting workflows** page."},{"content":"If there are scenarios where transfers might be allowed without workflow approval, you can define budget transfer rules to support those scenarios.","pos":[3591,3738]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budgeting dimensions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you must select the financial dimensions that are used for budgeting, based on the dimensions that are used in the chart of accounts.","pos":[3741,3912],"source":"On the **Budgeting dimensions** page, you must select the financial dimensions that are used for budgeting, based on the dimensions that are used in the chart of accounts."},{"content":"You can select all financial dimensions or a subset of them for budgeting.","pos":[3913,3987]},{"content":"Define a *budget model *that corresponds to all or some of the budgets.","pos":[3989,4060]},{"content":"You can use a single budget model for all budget register entries.","pos":[4061,4127]},{"content":"Alternatively, you can create separate models that are based on the budget type, the geographical location, or some other way that a budget can be classified.","pos":[4128,4286]},{"pos":[4291,4408],"content":"[!NOTE] \nIf budget control is used, you can associate only one budget model with a specific budget cycle time span.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"If budget control is used, you can associate only one budget model with a specific budget cycle time span.","pos":[9,115]}]},{"content":"Create <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>budget codes<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> that identify the type of budget transactions to record and any related workflow.","pos":[4411,4514],"source":"Create *budget codes* that identify the type of budget transactions to record and any related workflow."},{"content":"Budget codes can support the following budget types:","pos":[4515,4567]},{"content":"Original budget","pos":[4573,4588]},{"content":"Transfer","pos":[4593,4601]},{"content":"Revision","pos":[4606,4614]},{"content":"Encumbrance","pos":[4619,4630]},{"content":"Pre-encumbrance","pos":[4635,4650]},{"content":"Carry-forward budget","pos":[4655,4675]},{"content":"Budget codes let you have an audit trail of approved budget modifications throughout the course of the budget cycle.","pos":[4677,4793]},{"content":"If a workflow is associated with a budget code, the workflow will be enabled for all budget register entries that use that budget code, and workflow steps must be completed before the budget register entry can reach the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Completed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> stage.","pos":[4794,5034],"source":" If a workflow is associated with a budget code, the workflow will be enabled for all budget register entries that use that budget code, and workflow steps must be completed before the budget register entry can reach the **Completed** stage."},{"content":"You can also optionally set up <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>budget transfer rules<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[5038,5093],"source":"You can also optionally set up *budget transfer rules*."},{"content":"To use budget transfer rules, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use rules for budget transfers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Budget parameters<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[5094,5200],"source":" To use budget transfer rules, select **Use rules for budget transfers** on the **Budget parameters** page."},{"content":"When budget transfer rules are used, if a user creates a document by using a budget code of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Transfer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> type, budget balances won't be updated if the budget transfer rules are violated.","pos":[5201,5391],"source":" When budget transfer rules are used, if a user creates a document by using a budget code of the **Transfer** type, budget balances won't be updated if the budget transfer rules are violated."},{"content":"For example, you can allow budget transfer documents where the expense budget is transferred between the main accounts for the Sales and Marketing department, but can prohibit budget from being transferred from or to that department unless workflow approval has been granted for that type of budget account entry.","pos":[5392,5705]},{"pos":[5710,5772],"content":"Using workspaces and inquiry pages to track budget vs. actuals","linkify":"Using workspaces and inquiry pages to track budget vs. actuals","nodes":[{"content":"Using workspaces and inquiry pages to track budget vs. actuals","pos":[0,62]}]},{"content":"The budget manager can review the current state of a budget in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ledger budgets and forecasts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> workspace.","pos":[5773,5883],"source":"The budget manager can review the current state of a budget in the **Ledger budgets and forecasts** workspace."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Expense over budget<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Revenue under budget<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tabs provide a quick view of the financial dimension combinations where budget targets aren't being met or are approaching the threshold.","pos":[5884,6078],"source":" The **Expense over budget** and **Revenue under budget** tabs provide a quick view of the financial dimension combinations where budget targets aren't being met or are approaching the threshold."},{"content":"You can personalize the budget threshold percentage and financial dimension sets that are used on those tabs by clicking <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure my workspace<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6079,6227],"source":" You can personalize the budget threshold percentage and financial dimension sets that are used on those tabs by clicking **Configure my workspace**."},{"content":"You can click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Unit managers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to see the workers who are responsible for specific financial dimension combinations that are selected on those tabs.","pos":[6228,6377],"source":" You can click **Unit managers** to see the workers who are responsible for specific financial dimension combinations that are selected on those tabs."},{"content":"For example, if you see that the expense budget of the Operations department is going over the budget threshold, you can easily find and contact the Operations department manager to discuss the issue.","pos":[6378,6578]},{"pos":[6583,6890],"content":"[!NOTE] \nThe **Department manager** field on the **Organization Units** page determines which managers support specific financial dimension combinations. Click **See more** at the bottom of the tab to open the **Budget vs actuals** inquiry page for more details about budget amounts versus actual amounts.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The **Department manager** field on the **Organization Units** page determines which managers support specific financial dimension combinations. Click **See more** at the bottom of the tab to open the **Budget vs actuals** inquiry page for more details about budget amounts versus actual amounts.","pos":[9,305],"nodes":[{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Department manager<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Organization Units<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page determines which managers support specific financial dimension combinations.","pos":[0,144],"source":"The **Department manager** field on the **Organization Units** page determines which managers support specific financial dimension combinations."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>See more<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the bottom of the tab to open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Budget vs actuals<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> inquiry page for more details about budget amounts versus actual amounts.","pos":[145,296],"source":" Click **See more** at the bottom of the tab to open the **Budget vs actuals** inquiry page for more details about budget amounts versus actual amounts."}]}]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Actual vs budget<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> inquiry page lets you drill into the details of the budget versus actual amounts.","pos":[6893,6999],"source":"The **Actual vs budget** inquiry page lets you drill into the details of the budget versus actual amounts."},{"content":"Select a line on the inquiry page, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Period balances<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to see budget and actual amounts spread across fiscal periods.","pos":[7000,7132],"source":" Select a line on the inquiry page, and then click **Period balances** to see budget and actual amounts spread across fiscal periods."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Budget account entries<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page provides drill-through to the details of the budget amount in budget register entries.","pos":[7133,7255],"source":" The **Budget account entries** page provides drill-through to the details of the budget amount in budget register entries."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General journal entries<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page opens the ledger transactions that are included in the calculated <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Actuals<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> amount.","pos":[7256,7378],"source":" The **General journal entries** page opens the ledger transactions that are included in the calculated **Actuals** amount."},{"pos":[7381,7523],"content":"A company that is using Budget planning functionality can create and use <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>budget forecasts<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Ledger budgets and forecasts<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> workspace.","source":"A company that is using Budget planning functionality can create and use *budget forecasts* in the **Ledger budgets and forecasts** workspace."}]}