{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Postdated checks\ndescription: This article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date. Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 21741\nms.assetid: 4eb7c7da-1e6b-4d35-9f41-373b66103229\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: leguo\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Postdated checks\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date. Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.\n\nMicrosoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations supports the full management cycle for postdated checks in both Accounts receivable and Accounts payable, as shown in the following table.\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Scenario</th>\n<th>Details</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Set up postdated checks</td>\n<td>You must set up a new payment method, and specify the payment routine for clearing accounts for issued checks, received checks, and withholding tax.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Register and post a postdated check for a vendor</td>\n<td>Register the details of a postdated check that you issue to a vendor. When the payment is posted, the vendor liability is recognized, but the bank account isn’t yet credit. Instead, a clearing account is used for this purpose.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Register and post a postdated check for a customer</td>\n<td>Register the details of a postdated check that you receive from a customer. When the payment is posted, the customer receivable is credit, but the bank account isn’t yet debit. Instead, a clearing account is used for this purpose.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Register and post a replacement postdated check for a customer or a vendor</td>\n<td>\nIf your original check to a vendor or from a customer is lost or damaged, you can issue a replacement postdated check. When you register the check details, provide a reference to the original check, and indicate that the new check is a replacement for the original. You can also post the replacement check.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Transfer a customer postdated check to a vendor</td>\n<td>When you receive a postdated check from a customer, you can transfer that check to a vendor as a payment.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Settle a postdated check for a customer or a vendor</td>\n<td>Settle a postdated check that is posted to a bridging account for a customer or a vendor when the check finally matures. When the check is settled, the bank is finally debit or credit against the clearing account that was used earlier.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Cancel a postdated check for a vendor</td>\n<td>You can cancel a posted postdated check in these situations:\n - The check is returned by the bank.\n - The check is applied to an incorrect invoice.\n - A cash payment is made against the check.\n</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Stop payment for a postdated check</td>\n<td>You can stop payment on a postdated check that was issued to a vendor, for reasons such as not sufficient funds, changes in the terms of the agreement with the vendor, supply of defective goods by the vendor, or return of goods to the vendor. You can stop payment only on checks that haven’t cleared.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,884],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Postdated checks\ndescription: This article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date. Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 21741\nms.assetid: 4eb7c7da-1e6b-4d35-9f41-373b66103229\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: leguo\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Postdated checks","nodes":[{"pos":[0,16],"content":"Postdated checks","nodes":[{"content":"Postdated checks","pos":[0,16]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date. Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,296],"content":"This article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date. Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date. Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.","pos":[0,296],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[0,142]},{"content":"Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date.","pos":[143,233]},{"content":"Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.","pos":[234,296]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[892,908],"content":"Postdated checks","linkify":"Postdated checks","nodes":[{"content":"Postdated checks","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"This article provides information about support for postdated checks in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[954,1096]},{"content":"Postdated checks are checks that are issued to make and receive payments on a future date.","pos":[1097,1187]},{"content":"Therefore, the check can't be cashed until the specified date.","pos":[1188,1250]},{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations supports the full management cycle for postdated checks in both Accounts receivable and Accounts payable, as shown in the following table.","pos":[1252,1440]},{"content":"Scenario","pos":[1544,1552]},{"content":"Details","pos":[1562,1569]},{"content":"Set up postdated checks","pos":[1619,1642]},{"content":"You must set up a new payment method, and specify the payment routine for clearing accounts for issued checks, received checks, and withholding tax.","pos":[1652,1800]},{"content":"Register and post a postdated check for a vendor","pos":[1834,1882]},{"content":"Register the details of a postdated check that you issue to a vendor.","pos":[1892,1961]},{"content":"When the payment is posted, the vendor liability is recognized, but the bank account isn’t yet credit.","pos":[1962,2064]},{"content":"Instead, a clearing account is used for this purpose.","pos":[2065,2118]},{"content":"Register and post a postdated check for a customer","pos":[2151,2201]},{"content":"Register the details of a postdated check that you receive from a customer.","pos":[2211,2286]},{"content":"When the payment is posted, the customer receivable is credit, but the bank account isn’t yet debit.","pos":[2287,2387]},{"content":"Instead, a clearing account is used for this purpose.","pos":[2388,2441]},{"content":"Register and post a replacement postdated check for a customer or a vendor","pos":[2475,2549]},{"content":"If your original check to a vendor or from a customer is lost or damaged, you can issue a replacement postdated check.","pos":[2560,2678],"source":"\nIf your original check to a vendor or from a customer is lost or damaged, you can issue a replacement postdated check."},{"content":"When you register the check details, provide a reference to the original check, and indicate that the new check is a replacement for the original.","pos":[2679,2825]},{"content":"You can also post the replacement check.","pos":[2826,2866]},{"content":"Transfer a customer postdated check to a vendor","pos":[2899,2946]},{"content":"When you receive a postdated check from a customer, you can transfer that check to a vendor as a payment.","pos":[2956,3061]},{"content":"Settle a postdated check for a customer or a vendor","pos":[3095,3146]},{"content":"Settle a postdated check that is posted to a bridging account for a customer or a vendor when the check finally matures.","pos":[3156,3276]},{"content":"When the check is settled, the bank is finally debit or credit against the clearing account that was used earlier.","pos":[3277,3391]},{"content":"Cancel a postdated check for a vendor","pos":[3424,3461]},{"content":"You can cancel a posted postdated check in these situations: - The check is returned by the bank.","pos":[3471,3569],"source":"You can cancel a posted postdated check in these situations:\n - The check is returned by the bank."},{"content":"- The check is applied to an incorrect invoice.","pos":[3570,3618],"source":"\n - The check is applied to an incorrect invoice."},{"content":"- A cash payment is made against the check.","pos":[3619,3663],"source":"\n - A cash payment is made against the check."},{"content":"Stop payment for a postdated check","pos":[3698,3732]},{"content":"You can stop payment on a postdated check that was issued to a vendor, for reasons such as not sufficient funds, changes in the terms of the agreement with the vendor, supply of defective goods by the vendor, or return of goods to the vendor.","pos":[3742,3984]},{"content":"You can stop payment only on checks that haven’t cleared.","pos":[3985,4042]}]}