{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement\ndescription: This topic explains how you can use external catalogs to create and submit requisitions.\nauthor: mkirknel\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: PurchTable, PurchVendorPortalRequests\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 30211\nms.assetid: 3c7e0e1c-703c-4bbf-b90c-84d29a131360\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mkirknel\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement\nBy using external catalogs for PunchOut e-procurement, you don't have to maintain information about your vendors' products in your own master data. \nInstead, the shopping cart on a vendor's website is converted to requisition lines that have the correct product information. \n\nYou should avoid maintaining the descriptions and prices of your vendors’ products in your own product master data. Instead, use external catalogs for PunchOut e-procurement. Then, when employees create requisitions, they can “punch out” to a vendor’s external catalog site (in other words, they leave your system and go to the vendor’s site). The products that are added to the shopping cart on the vendor’s website can then be converted to requisition lines. Therefore, you get the correct product information: product ID, name, price, and so on.\n\nTo use external catalogs, an employee must create a requisition on the **My purchase requisitions** page.\n\nThe employee who creates a requisition is referred to as the preparer of the requisition. As a preparer, you can complete the following tasks.\n\nUse the **External catalogs** line action to open a page that includes all external catalogs that are available for the specified requester, buying legal entity, and receiving operating unit.\n\nDepending on your permissions, change the requester, buying legal entity, and receiving operating unit. A change in those values might change the list of external catalogs that are available to a requester. The external catalogs that are available depend on the current active purchasing policies for the buying legal entity or the receiving operating unit. These policies can allow or prevent access to specific procurement categories. Therefore, the list of external catalogs that are mapped to these procurement categories can be affected.\n\nFor more information about policies, see [Purchasing policies](../procurement/purchase-policies.md).\n\n- To find external catalogs for specific procurement categories, enter text in the catalog search field.\n- To add products from a vendor’s external catalog on the vendor’s website, click the external catalog. Then add products to the shopping cart, and check out. The shopping cart lines will be transferred to Microsoft Dynamics 365.\n\nIf there are multiple options for procurement categories, select the correct procurement category before you add the lines to the requisition.\nAfter lines have been added to a requisition, you can add more lines without using external catalogs. Alternatively, you can continue to use external catalogs to add lines.\n\nWhen the requisition is ready, use the **Workflow** > **Submit** action to submit it for approval.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,742],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement\ndescription: This topic explains how you can use external catalogs to create and submit requisitions.\nauthor: mkirknel\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: PurchTable, PurchVendorPortalRequests\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 30211\nms.assetid: 3c7e0e1c-703c-4bbf-b90c-84d29a131360\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mkirknel\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement","nodes":[{"pos":[0,47],"content":"Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement","nodes":[{"content":"Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement","pos":[0,47]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic explains how you can use external catalogs to create and submit requisitions.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,88],"content":"This topic explains how you can use external catalogs to create and submit requisitions.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how you can use external catalogs to create and submit requisitions.","pos":[0,88]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[750,797],"content":"Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement","linkify":"Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement","nodes":[{"content":"Use external catalogs for PunchOut eProcurement","pos":[0,47]}]},{"content":"By using external catalogs for PunchOut e-procurement, you don't have to maintain information about your vendors' products in your own master data.","pos":[798,945]},{"content":"Instead, the shopping cart on a vendor's website is converted to requisition lines that have the correct product information.","pos":[946,1072],"source":" \nInstead, the shopping cart on a vendor's website is converted to requisition lines that have the correct product information."},{"content":"You should avoid maintaining the descriptions and prices of your vendors’ products in your own product master data.","pos":[1075,1190]},{"content":"Instead, use external catalogs for PunchOut e-procurement.","pos":[1191,1249]},{"content":"Then, when employees create requisitions, they can “punch out” to a vendor’s external catalog site (in other words, they leave your system and go to the vendor’s site).","pos":[1250,1418]},{"content":"The products that are added to the shopping cart on the vendor’s website can then be converted to requisition lines.","pos":[1419,1535]},{"content":"Therefore, you get the correct product information: product ID, name, price, and so on.","pos":[1536,1623]},{"pos":[1625,1730],"content":"To use external catalogs, an employee must create a requisition on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>My purchase requisitions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"To use external catalogs, an employee must create a requisition on the **My purchase requisitions** page."},{"content":"The employee who creates a requisition is referred to as the preparer of the requisition.","pos":[1732,1821]},{"content":"As a preparer, you can complete the following tasks.","pos":[1822,1874]},{"pos":[1876,2067],"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>External catalogs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> line action to open a page that includes all external catalogs that are available for the specified requester, buying legal entity, and receiving operating unit.","source":"Use the **External catalogs** line action to open a page that includes all external catalogs that are available for the specified requester, buying legal entity, and receiving operating unit."},{"content":"Depending on your permissions, change the requester, buying legal entity, and receiving operating unit.","pos":[2069,2172]},{"content":"A change in those values might change the list of external catalogs that are available to a requester.","pos":[2173,2275]},{"content":"The external catalogs that are available depend on the current active purchasing policies for the buying legal entity or the receiving operating unit.","pos":[2276,2426]},{"content":"These policies can allow or prevent access to specific procurement categories.","pos":[2427,2505]},{"content":"Therefore, the list of external catalogs that are mapped to these procurement categories can be affected.","pos":[2506,2611]},{"pos":[2613,2713],"content":"For more information about policies, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Purchasing policies<ept id=\"p1\">](../procurement/purchase-policies.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information about policies, see [Purchasing policies](../procurement/purchase-policies.md)."},{"content":"To find external catalogs for specific procurement categories, enter text in the catalog search field.","pos":[2717,2819]},{"content":"To add products from a vendor’s external catalog on the vendor’s website, click the external catalog.","pos":[2822,2923]},{"content":"Then add products to the shopping cart, and check out.","pos":[2924,2978]},{"content":"The shopping cart lines will be transferred to Microsoft Dynamics 365.","pos":[2979,3049]},{"content":"If there are multiple options for procurement categories, select the correct procurement category before you add the lines to the requisition.","pos":[3051,3193]},{"content":"After lines have been added to a requisition, you can add more lines without using external catalogs.","pos":[3194,3295],"source":"\nAfter lines have been added to a requisition, you can add more lines without using external catalogs."},{"content":"Alternatively, you can continue to use external catalogs to add lines.","pos":[3296,3366]},{"pos":[3368,3466],"content":"When the requisition is ready, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Workflow<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> &gt; </ph><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Submit<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> action to submit it for approval.","source":"When the requisition is ready, use the **Workflow** > **Submit** action to submit it for approval."}]}