{"content":"--- \n# required metadata \n \ntitle: Configure wave processing\ndescription: This guide describes how to set up the criteria that determine what work is generated for a warehouse when a wave is processed, and whether waves are processed manually or automatically. \nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 06/07/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Distribution\nms.author: mirzaab\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 \n---\n# Configure wave processing\n\n[!include[task guide banner](../../includes/task-guide-banner.md)]\n\nThis guide describes how to set up the criteria that determine what work is generated for a warehouse when a wave is processed, and whether waves are processed manually or automatically. You specify the criteria by setting up wave templates and queries that match a wave with released lines in sales orders, production orders, or kanban orders. Wave processing is used in warehouses that use the functionality in the Warehouse management module, and not those that use the functionality in the Inventory management module. You can run this procedure in demo data company USMF.\n\n1. Go to Warehouse management > Setup > Waves > Wave templates.\n2. Click New.\n3. In the Wave template name field, type a value.\n    * When you set up a wave template, you specify the sequence in which the templates will be matched to released lines on sales orders, production orders, or kanbans. When a line is released to the warehouse or to production, it uses the first wave template that it meets the criteria for. We recommend that you put templates with the most specific criteria at the top of the list. The broader the criteria, the more likely it is for a line to meet the criteria, and this could lead to lines being assigned to the wrong wave.  \n4. In the Wave template description field, type a value.\n5. In the Site field, enter or select a value.\n    * If you’re using USMF, you can select site 2.  \n6. In the Warehouse field, enter or select a value.\n    * If you’re using USMF, you can select warehouse 24.  \n7. Set the Automate wave creation field to Yes.\n    * Select this option to automatically create a wave when a sales order, production order, or kanban is released to the warehouse.  \n8. Set the Process wave at release to warehouse option to Yes. \n    * Select this option to automatically process the wave and create work when a line is released to the warehouse.  \n9. Set the Automate wave release option to Yes. \n    * Select this option to automatically release the wave. The picking work is created and made available on mobile devices.  \n10. Set the Assign to open waves option to Yes. \n    * Lines are assigned to waves based on the query filter for the wave template.  \n11. Set the Process wave automatically at threshold option to Yes. \n    * Select this option to automatically process the wave when its values reach the thresholds for weight, shipment, and lines specified in the Wave thresholds field group. This option is available only if Shipping is selected in the Wave template type field.  \n12. Set the Automate replenishment work release option to Yes. \n    * Select this option to create demand-based replenishment work and release it automatically. You must add the replenishment wave method to the wave template, and create a replenishment template of the type Wave demand.  \n13. Expand the Methods section.\n    * Wave template methods allow you to control the sequence of activities that each wave is going through when it’s processed. For example, you might have a method for wave replenishment. When you add a method, it’s automatically listed in the appropriate location in the sequence of steps. If you’ve set the Automate replenishment work release option to Yes, you need to add the replenish method here.  \n    * Wave attributes act as filters, to restrict the kind of items that can use the wave. For example, you could specify an item group.  \n14. Click Save.\n15. Close the page.\n16. Go to Warehouse management > Setup > Warehouse management parameters.\n17. Expand the Wave processing section.\n18. In the Wave processing batch group field, enter or select a value.\n19. Set the Process waves in batch option to Yes.\n20. In the Wait for lock (ms) field, enter a number.\n    * Enter the time, in milliseconds, that an allocation step will wait for a system resource that is locked by another allocation step. When this time is exceeded, the wave is not processed and an error message is displayed.  \n21. Click Save.\n22. Close the page.\n23. Go to Production control > Setup > Production control parameters.\n24. In the Release to warehouse field, select an option.\n    * For sales orders and kanban orders, inventory must be reserved before the order is released to the warehouse. Otherwise, the items or allocation lines cannot be processed in a wave. For production orders, you also have the option of choosing Allow partial reservation. For example, this is useful if you have the materials that you need to start production, and can then wait until the additional materials become available to finish the process. If you select this option, you must manually repeat the release to warehouse process when the additional materials become available.  \n25. Close the page.\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[5,732],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata \n \ntitle: Configure wave processing\ndescription: This guide describes how to set up the criteria that determine what work is generated for a warehouse when a wave is processed, and whether waves are processed manually or automatically. \nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 06/07/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Distribution\nms.author: mirzaab\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 ","nodes":[{"content":"Configure wave processing","nodes":[{"pos":[0,25],"content":"Configure wave processing","nodes":[{"content":"Configure wave processing","pos":[0,25]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This guide describes how to set up the criteria that determine what work is generated for a warehouse when a wave is processed, and whether waves are processed manually or automatically.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,186],"content":"This guide describes how to set up the criteria that determine what work is generated for a warehouse when a wave is processed, and whether waves are processed manually or automatically.","nodes":[{"content":"This guide describes how to set up the criteria that determine what work is generated for a warehouse when a wave is processed, and whether waves are processed manually or automatically.","pos":[0,186]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata \n","yml":true},{"pos":[739,764],"content":"Configure wave processing","linkify":"Configure wave processing","nodes":[{"content":"Configure wave processing","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"This guide describes how to set up the criteria that determine what work is generated for a warehouse when a wave is processed, and whether waves are processed manually or automatically.","pos":[834,1020]},{"content":"You specify the criteria by setting up wave templates and queries that match a wave with released lines in sales orders, production orders, or kanban orders.","pos":[1021,1178]},{"content":"Wave processing is used in warehouses that use the functionality in the Warehouse management module, and not those that use the functionality in the Inventory management module.","pos":[1179,1356]},{"content":"You can run this procedure in demo data company USMF.","pos":[1357,1410]},{"content":"Go to Warehouse management &gt; Setup &gt; Waves &gt; Wave templates.","pos":[1415,1475],"source":"Go to Warehouse management > Setup > Waves > Wave templates."},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[1479,1489]},{"content":"In the Wave template name field, type a value.","pos":[1493,1539]},{"content":"When you set up a wave template, you specify the sequence in which the templates will be matched to released lines on sales orders, production orders, or kanbans.","pos":[1546,1708]},{"content":"When a line is released to the warehouse or to production, it uses the first wave template that it meets the criteria for.","pos":[1709,1831]},{"content":"We recommend that you put templates with the most specific criteria at the top of the list.","pos":[1832,1923]},{"content":"The broader the criteria, the more likely it is for a line to meet the criteria, and this could lead to lines being assigned to the wrong wave.","pos":[1924,2067]},{"content":"In the Wave template description field, type a value.","pos":[2073,2126]},{"content":"In the Site field, enter or select a value.","pos":[2130,2173]},{"content":"If you’re using USMF, you can select site 2.","pos":[2180,2224]},{"content":"In the Warehouse field, enter or select a value.","pos":[2230,2278]},{"content":"If you’re using USMF, you can select warehouse 24.","pos":[2285,2335]},{"content":"Set the Automate wave creation field to Yes.","pos":[2341,2385]},{"content":"Select this option to automatically create a wave when a sales order, production order, or kanban is released to the warehouse.","pos":[2392,2519]},{"content":"Set the Process wave at release to warehouse option to Yes.","pos":[2525,2584]},{"content":"Select this option to automatically process the wave and create work when a line is released to the warehouse.","pos":[2592,2702]},{"content":"Set the Automate wave release option to Yes.","pos":[2708,2752]},{"content":"Select this option to automatically release the wave.","pos":[2760,2813]},{"content":"The picking work is created and made available on mobile devices.","pos":[2814,2879]},{"content":"Set the Assign to open waves option to Yes.","pos":[2886,2929]},{"content":"Lines are assigned to waves based on the query filter for the wave template.","pos":[2937,3013]},{"content":"Set the Process wave automatically at threshold option to Yes.","pos":[3020,3082]},{"content":"Select this option to automatically process the wave when its values reach the thresholds for weight, shipment, and lines specified in the Wave thresholds field group.","pos":[3090,3257]},{"content":"This option is available only if Shipping is selected in the Wave template type field.","pos":[3258,3344]},{"content":"Set the Automate replenishment work release option to Yes.","pos":[3351,3409]},{"content":"Select this option to create demand-based replenishment work and release it automatically.","pos":[3417,3507]},{"content":"You must add the replenishment wave method to the wave template, and create a replenishment template of the type Wave demand.","pos":[3508,3633]},{"content":"Expand the Methods section.","pos":[3640,3667]},{"content":"Wave template methods allow you to control the sequence of activities that each wave is going through when it’s processed.","pos":[3674,3796]},{"content":"For example, you might have a method for wave replenishment.","pos":[3797,3857]},{"content":"When you add a method, it’s automatically listed in the appropriate location in the sequence of steps.","pos":[3858,3960]},{"content":"If you’ve set the Automate replenishment work release option to Yes, you need to add the replenish method here.","pos":[3961,4072]},{"content":"Wave attributes act as filters, to restrict the kind of items that can use the wave.","pos":[4081,4165]},{"content":"For example, you could specify an item group.","pos":[4166,4211]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[4218,4229]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4234,4249]},{"content":"Go to Warehouse management &gt; Setup &gt; Warehouse management parameters.","pos":[4254,4323],"source":"Go to Warehouse management > Setup > Warehouse management parameters."},{"content":"Expand the Wave processing section.","pos":[4328,4363]},{"content":"In the Wave processing batch group field, enter or select a value.","pos":[4368,4434]},{"content":"Set the Process waves in batch option to Yes.","pos":[4439,4484]},{"content":"In the Wait for lock (ms) field, enter a number.","pos":[4489,4537]},{"content":"Enter the time, in milliseconds, that an allocation step will wait for a system resource that is locked by another allocation step.","pos":[4544,4675]},{"content":"When this time is exceeded, the wave is not processed and an error message is displayed.","pos":[4676,4764]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[4771,4782]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4787,4802]},{"content":"Go to Production control &gt; Setup &gt; Production control parameters.","pos":[4807,4872],"source":"Go to Production control > Setup > Production control parameters."},{"content":"In the Release to warehouse field, select an option.","pos":[4877,4929]},{"content":"For sales orders and kanban orders, inventory must be reserved before the order is released to the warehouse.","pos":[4936,5045]},{"content":"Otherwise, the items or allocation lines cannot be processed in a wave.","pos":[5046,5117]},{"content":"For production orders, you also have the option of choosing Allow partial reservation.","pos":[5118,5204]},{"content":"For example, this is useful if you have the materials that you need to start production, and can then wait until the additional materials become available to finish the process.","pos":[5205,5382]},{"content":"If you select this option, you must manually repeat the release to warehouse process when the additional materials become available.","pos":[5383,5515]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[5522,5537]}]}