{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Set up bar codes\ndescription: This article describes how to use bar codes in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.\nauthor: josaw1\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-365-retail\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: josaw\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations, Retail\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 15971\nms.assetid: 6b4b2ac2-0344-41aa-8818-62c30017d5ac\nms.search.region: global\nms.search.industry: Retail\nms.author: jeffbl\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0, Retail July 2017 update\n\n\n---\n\n# Set up bar codes\n\n[!include[banner](includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article describes how to use bar codes in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.\n\nYou can use bar codes to purchase and sell products, track product variants, and set up customers and employees. You can also use bar codes to issue and endorse coupons, gift cards, and credit memos. You can set up retail products so that they have standard bar codes or custom, in-house bar codes. Products can have more than one bar code. For example, a product might have multiple bar codes if it comes from various manufacturers, or if it has variants that are based on size, style, or color. Bar codes can include the weight or price of the product. Bar code masks are templates that are used to create bar codes. **Note:** If you assign a unique bar code to each variant combination, you can scan the bar code at the register and let the program determine which variant of the product is being sold. You can also collect and view statistics about sales by variant. Each size, color, and style group can be assigned a unique number that identifies that group in the bar code. Dynamics 365 for Retail uses the bar code mask to automatically generate bar codes for each variant combination. This functionality can be useful if there are many sizes, colors, and styles, because the number of combinations increases significantly as each variant code is added. If this functionality isn't used, bar codes must be manually assigned to each combination that represents a product variant. You can create bar codes manually or automatically. To create bar codes, complete the following tasks in the order in which they are listed.\n\n1.  [Set up bar code mask characters](set-up-bar-code-masks.md).\n2.  [Set up bar code masks](set-up-bar-code-masks.md).\n3.  Configure bar code setups.\n4.  Create bar codes for products.\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Set up bar code masks](set-up-bar-code-masks.md)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,698],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Set up bar codes\ndescription: This article describes how to use bar codes in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.\nauthor: josaw1\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-365-retail\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: josaw\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations, Retail\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 15971\nms.assetid: 6b4b2ac2-0344-41aa-8818-62c30017d5ac\nms.search.region: global\nms.search.industry: Retail\nms.author: jeffbl\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0, Retail July 2017 update\n\n","nodes":[{"content":"Set up bar codes","nodes":[{"pos":[0,16],"content":"Set up bar codes","nodes":[{"content":"Set up bar codes","pos":[0,16]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article describes how to use bar codes in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,81],"content":"This article describes how to use bar codes in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.","nodes":[{"content":"This article describes how to use bar codes in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.","pos":[0,81]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[706,722],"content":"Set up bar codes","linkify":"Set up bar codes","nodes":[{"content":"Set up bar codes","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"This article describes how to use bar codes in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.","pos":[765,846]},{"content":"You can use bar codes to purchase and sell products, track product variants, and set up customers and employees.","pos":[848,960]},{"content":"You can also use bar codes to issue and endorse coupons, gift cards, and credit memos.","pos":[961,1047]},{"content":"You can set up retail products so that they have standard bar codes or custom, in-house bar codes.","pos":[1048,1146]},{"content":"Products can have more than one bar code.","pos":[1147,1188]},{"content":"For example, a product might have multiple bar codes if it comes from various manufacturers, or if it has variants that are based on size, style, or color.","pos":[1189,1344]},{"content":"Bar codes can include the weight or price of the product.","pos":[1345,1402]},{"content":"Bar code masks are templates that are used to create bar codes.","pos":[1403,1466]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you assign a unique bar code to each variant combination, you can scan the bar code at the register and let the program determine which variant of the product is being sold.","pos":[1467,1653],"source":"**Note:** If you assign a unique bar code to each variant combination, you can scan the bar code at the register and let the program determine which variant of the product is being sold."},{"content":"You can also collect and view statistics about sales by variant.","pos":[1654,1718]},{"content":"Each size, color, and style group can be assigned a unique number that identifies that group in the bar code.","pos":[1719,1828]},{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Retail uses the bar code mask to automatically generate bar codes for each variant combination.","pos":[1829,1941]},{"content":"This functionality can be useful if there are many sizes, colors, and styles, because the number of combinations increases significantly as each variant code is added.","pos":[1942,2109]},{"content":"If this functionality isn't used, bar codes must be manually assigned to each combination that represents a product variant.","pos":[2110,2234]},{"content":"You can create bar codes manually or automatically.","pos":[2235,2286]},{"content":"To create bar codes, complete the following tasks in the order in which they are listed.","pos":[2287,2375]},{"pos":[2381,2441],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up bar code mask characters<ept id=\"p1\">](set-up-bar-code-masks.md)</ept>.","source":"[Set up bar code mask characters](set-up-bar-code-masks.md)."},{"pos":[2446,2496],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up bar code masks<ept id=\"p1\">](set-up-bar-code-masks.md)</ept>.","source":"[Set up bar code masks](set-up-bar-code-masks.md)."},{"content":"Configure bar code setups.","pos":[2501,2527]},{"content":"Create bar codes for products.","pos":[2532,2562]},{"pos":[2565,2573],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[2584,2633],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up bar code masks<ept id=\"p1\">](set-up-bar-code-masks.md)</ept>","source":"[Set up bar code masks](set-up-bar-code-masks.md)"}]}