{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Consignment\ndescription: This topic explains how to use the inbound consignment inventory processes.\nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: ConsignmentDraftReplenishmentOrderJournal, ConsignmentProductReceiptLines, ConsignmentReplenishmentOrder, ConsignmentVendorPortalOnHand, InventJournalOwnershipChange, InventOnHandItemListPage, PurchTable, PurchVendorPortalConfirmedOrders\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 220834\nms.assetid: 3c9d6de4-45d4-459a-aef7-0d9ad2c22b3a\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: perlynne\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Consignment\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic explains how to use the inbound consignment inventory processes.\n\nConsignment inventory is inventory that’s owned by a vendor, but stored at your site. When you’re ready to consume or use the inventory, you take over the ownership of the inventory. This topic includes information about how to physically receive vendor-owned inventory on-hand without creating general ledger transactions, how to start a production process where the vendor-owned inventory can be physically reserved. and how to change the ownership of the raw material in order to be able to process the consumption as part of the production order processing. There’s also some information about how vendors can monitor consumption of their inventory using the vendor collaboration interface. For information about how to enable and configure inbound consignment processes, see [Setting up consignment](set-up-consignment.md).\n\n## Overview of the consignment process\nIn this example scenario, company USMF has a consignment agreement with vendor US-104 for the raw material M9211CI.\n\n1.  A consignment replenishment order is manually created by someone in USMF, based on the expected demand. The order is created for vendor US-104 and a line is added for item MS9211CI.\n2.  The vendor gets informed about the expected delivery. This can happen in one of three ways:\n    -   Someone working at USMF sends the order information to the vendor.\n    -   The vendor can monitor the expected inventory on-hand using the vendor collaboration interface.\n    -   Someone working at USMF filters the data on the **On-hand inventory** page to show only the records for vendor US-104, where the receipt status is **Ordered**, and then sends this information to the vendor.\n\n3.  The inventory is delivered from US-104 to USMF.\n4.  When the material arrives at USMF, the consignment replenishment order is updated with a product receipt. Only the physical quantities of the vendor-owned inventory are recorded. There are no general ledger transactions created, because the inventory is still owned by the vendor.\n5.  The vendor monitors updates to the physical on-hand inventory using the **On-hand consignment inventory** page.\n6.  Now that the physical inventory is on-hand, the production process reserves the vendor-owned inventory and starts the production order for the finished goods that are going to consume the raw material M9211CI.\n7.  The owner of the reserved raw materials that are going to be consumed in today’s production is changed from US-104 to USMF. This is done using an Inventory ownership change journal. This process creates purchase orders where the **Origin** field is set to **Consignment**.\n8.  The vendor monitors the consumption (change of ownership) on the **Products received from consignment inventory** page and issues an invoice based on the agreements between the two companies.\n9.  The production process consumes the raw material via a production picking list. The physical reservation is automatically updated to reflect that the on-hand inventory is owned by USMF.\n10. The invoice from US-104 is processed against the purchase orders which were auto-generated when the inventory ownership change journal was processed. Payment is made to vendor US-104 for the inventory that was consumed.\n\nUSMF carries out additional periodic processes:\n\n-   The physical movement of the vendor-owned inventory between different warehouses is processed using a transfer journal.\n-   The physical inventory on-hand is updated using an **Item counting** journal. Counting can also be used by the vendor to update the on-hand inventory, if they have permission to do this.\n\nThe vendor, US-104, can monitor the updates using the **On-hand consignment inventory** page.\n\n## Consignment replenishment orders\nA consignment replenishment order is a document that is used to request and keep track of inventory quantities of products that a vendor intends to deliver within a certain date interval by creating ordered inventory transactions. Typically, this will be based on the forecast and actual demand of the specific products. The inventory that’s going to be received against the consignment replenishment order remains in the ownership of the vendor. Only the possession of the products related to the physical receipt update is recorded and therefore no general ledger transaction updates occur. The **Owner** dimension is used to separate information about which inventory is owned by the vendor and which is owned by the receiving legal entity. Consignment replenishment order lines have an **Open order** status as long as the full quantity of the lines has not been received or cancelled. When the full quantity has been received or canceled, the status is changed to **Completed**. The physical on-hand inventory that’s related to a consignment replenishment order can be recorded using a Registration process as well as a Product receipt update process. Registration can be done as part of the item arrival process or by manually updating the order lines. When the Product receipt update process is used, a record is made in the product receipt journal, which can be used to acknowledge the receipt of goods to the vendors. \n\n[![consignment-replenishment-order](./media/consignment-replenishment-order.png)](./media/consignment-replenishment-order.png)\n\n## Inventory ownership change journal\nThe process of changing the owner of the inventory from the vendor to the receiving legal entity is done using an Inventory ownership change journal. No expected inventory transactions are created for the journal. The only inventory transactions created are those that relate to a posted journal. When the journal is posted:\n\n-   The vendor-owned inventory is issued using an **Ownership change** reference with a **Sold** status.\n-   On-hand inventory is received by the legal entity that’s consuming it using a product receipt updated inventory transaction on the purchase order. This sets the status of the order to **Received**. Purchase orders used for consignment have the **Origin** field set to **Consignment**.\n\nIt’s not possible to update the quantity on consignment purchase order lines after the order has been created. \n\n[![inventory-ownership-change-journal](./media/inventory-ownership-change-journal.png)](./media/inventory-ownership-change-journal.png)\n\n## Vendor collaboration in consignment processes\nThe vendor collaboration interface has three pages related to the inbound consignment process:\n\n-   **Purchase orders** **consuming consignment inventory** - Shows detailed purchase order information related to the ownership change from the consignment process.\n-   **Products received from consignment inventory** - Shows information about the items and quantities that have product receipts updated during the ownership change process.\n-   **On-hand consignment inventory** - Shows information about the consignment items that they are expected to deliver, and the items that are already physically available at the customer site.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,892],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Consignment\ndescription: This topic explains how to use the inbound consignment inventory processes.\nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: ConsignmentDraftReplenishmentOrderJournal, ConsignmentProductReceiptLines, ConsignmentReplenishmentOrder, ConsignmentVendorPortalOnHand, InventJournalOwnershipChange, InventOnHandItemListPage, PurchTable, PurchVendorPortalConfirmedOrders\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 220834\nms.assetid: 3c9d6de4-45d4-459a-aef7-0d9ad2c22b3a\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: perlynne\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n","nodes":[{"content":"Consignment","nodes":[{"pos":[0,11],"content":"Consignment","nodes":[{"content":"Consignment","pos":[0,11]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic explains how to use the inbound consignment inventory processes.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,75],"content":"This topic explains how to use the inbound consignment inventory processes.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how to use the inbound consignment inventory processes.","pos":[0,75]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[900,911],"content":"Consignment","linkify":"Consignment","nodes":[{"content":"Consignment","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"This topic explains how to use the inbound consignment inventory processes.","pos":[957,1032]},{"content":"Consignment inventory is inventory that’s owned by a vendor, but stored at your site.","pos":[1034,1119]},{"content":"When you’re ready to consume or use the inventory, you take over the ownership of the inventory.","pos":[1120,1216]},{"content":"This topic includes information about how to physically receive vendor-owned inventory on-hand without creating general ledger transactions, how to start a production process where the vendor-owned inventory can be physically reserved.","pos":[1217,1452]},{"content":"and how to change the ownership of the raw material in order to be able to process the consumption as part of the production order processing.","pos":[1453,1595]},{"content":"There’s also some information about how vendors can monitor consumption of their inventory using the vendor collaboration interface.","pos":[1596,1728]},{"content":"For information about how to enable and configure inbound consignment processes, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Setting up consignment<ept id=\"p1\">](set-up-consignment.md)</ept>.","pos":[1729,1862],"source":" For information about how to enable and configure inbound consignment processes, see [Setting up consignment](set-up-consignment.md)."},{"pos":[1867,1902],"content":"Overview of the consignment process","linkify":"Overview of the consignment process","nodes":[{"content":"Overview of the consignment process","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"In this example scenario, company USMF has a consignment agreement with vendor US-104 for the raw material M9211CI.","pos":[1903,2018]},{"content":"A consignment replenishment order is manually created by someone in USMF, based on the expected demand.","pos":[2024,2127]},{"content":"The order is created for vendor US-104 and a line is added for item MS9211CI.","pos":[2128,2205]},{"content":"The vendor gets informed about the expected delivery.","pos":[2210,2263]},{"content":"This can happen in one of three ways:","pos":[2264,2301]},{"content":"Someone working at USMF sends the order information to the vendor.","pos":[2310,2376]},{"content":"The vendor can monitor the expected inventory on-hand using the vendor collaboration interface.","pos":[2385,2480]},{"pos":[2489,2695],"content":"Someone working at USMF filters the data on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>On-hand inventory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to show only the records for vendor US-104, where the receipt status is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Ordered<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then sends this information to the vendor.","source":"Someone working at USMF filters the data on the **On-hand inventory** page to show only the records for vendor US-104, where the receipt status is **Ordered**, and then sends this information to the vendor."},{"content":"The inventory is delivered from US-104 to USMF.","pos":[2701,2748]},{"content":"When the material arrives at USMF, the consignment replenishment order is updated with a product receipt.","pos":[2753,2858]},{"content":"Only the physical quantities of the vendor-owned inventory are recorded.","pos":[2859,2931]},{"content":"There are no general ledger transactions created, because the inventory is still owned by the vendor.","pos":[2932,3033]},{"pos":[3038,3149],"content":"The vendor monitors updates to the physical on-hand inventory using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>On-hand consignment inventory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"The vendor monitors updates to the physical on-hand inventory using the **On-hand consignment inventory** page."},{"content":"Now that the physical inventory is on-hand, the production process reserves the vendor-owned inventory and starts the production order for the finished goods that are going to consume the raw material M9211CI.","pos":[3154,3363]},{"content":"The owner of the reserved raw materials that are going to be consumed in today’s production is changed from US-104 to USMF.","pos":[3368,3491]},{"content":"This is done using an Inventory ownership change journal.","pos":[3492,3549]},{"content":"This process creates purchase orders where the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Origin<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Consignment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3550,3640],"source":" This process creates purchase orders where the **Origin** field is set to **Consignment**."},{"pos":[3645,3836],"content":"The vendor monitors the consumption (change of ownership) on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Products received from consignment inventory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page and issues an invoice based on the agreements between the two companies.","source":"The vendor monitors the consumption (change of ownership) on the **Products received from consignment inventory** page and issues an invoice based on the agreements between the two companies."},{"content":"The production process consumes the raw material via a production picking list.","pos":[3841,3920]},{"content":"The physical reservation is automatically updated to reflect that the on-hand inventory is owned by USMF.","pos":[3921,4026]},{"content":"The invoice from US-104 is processed against the purchase orders which were auto-generated when the inventory ownership change journal was processed.","pos":[4031,4180]},{"content":"Payment is made to vendor US-104 for the inventory that was consumed.","pos":[4181,4250]},{"content":"USMF carries out additional periodic processes:","pos":[4252,4299]},{"content":"The physical movement of the vendor-owned inventory between different warehouses is processed using a transfer journal.","pos":[4305,4424]},{"content":"The physical inventory on-hand is updated using an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Item counting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> journal.","pos":[4429,4506],"source":"The physical inventory on-hand is updated using an **Item counting** journal."},{"content":"Counting can also be used by the vendor to update the on-hand inventory, if they have permission to do this.","pos":[4507,4615]},{"pos":[4617,4710],"content":"The vendor, US-104, can monitor the updates using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>On-hand consignment inventory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"The vendor, US-104, can monitor the updates using the **On-hand consignment inventory** page."},{"pos":[4715,4747],"content":"Consignment replenishment orders","linkify":"Consignment replenishment orders","nodes":[{"content":"Consignment replenishment orders","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"A consignment replenishment order is a document that is used to request and keep track of inventory quantities of products that a vendor intends to deliver within a certain date interval by creating ordered inventory transactions.","pos":[4748,4978]},{"content":"Typically, this will be based on the forecast and actual demand of the specific products.","pos":[4979,5068]},{"content":"The inventory that’s going to be received against the consignment replenishment order remains in the ownership of the vendor.","pos":[5069,5194]},{"content":"Only the possession of the products related to the physical receipt update is recorded and therefore no general ledger transaction updates occur.","pos":[5195,5340]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Owner<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dimension is used to separate information about which inventory is owned by the vendor and which is owned by the receiving legal entity.","pos":[5341,5491],"source":" The **Owner** dimension is used to separate information about which inventory is owned by the vendor and which is owned by the receiving legal entity."},{"content":"Consignment replenishment order lines have an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open order<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status as long as the full quantity of the lines has not been received or cancelled.","pos":[5492,5637],"source":" Consignment replenishment order lines have an **Open order** status as long as the full quantity of the lines has not been received or cancelled."},{"content":"When the full quantity has been received or canceled, the status is changed to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Completed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[5638,5731],"source":" When the full quantity has been received or canceled, the status is changed to **Completed**."},{"content":"The physical on-hand inventory that’s related to a consignment replenishment order can be recorded using a Registration process as well as a Product receipt update process.","pos":[5732,5904]},{"content":"Registration can be done as part of the item arrival process or by manually updating the order lines.","pos":[5905,6006]},{"content":"When the Product receipt update process is used, a record is made in the product receipt journal, which can be used to acknowledge the receipt of goods to the vendors.","pos":[6007,6174]},{"pos":[6177,6303],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>consignment-replenishment-order<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/consignment-replenishment-order.png)](./media/consignment-replenishment-order.png)</ept>","source":"[![consignment-replenishment-order](./media/consignment-replenishment-order.png)](./media/consignment-replenishment-order.png)"},{"pos":[6308,6342],"content":"Inventory ownership change journal","linkify":"Inventory ownership change journal","nodes":[{"content":"Inventory ownership change journal","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"The process of changing the owner of the inventory from the vendor to the receiving legal entity is done using an Inventory ownership change journal.","pos":[6343,6492]},{"content":"No expected inventory transactions are created for the journal.","pos":[6493,6556]},{"content":"The only inventory transactions created are those that relate to a posted journal.","pos":[6557,6639]},{"content":"When the journal is posted:","pos":[6640,6667]},{"pos":[6673,6773],"content":"The vendor-owned inventory is issued using an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ownership change<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> reference with a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Sold<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> status.","source":"The vendor-owned inventory is issued using an **Ownership change** reference with a **Sold** status."},{"content":"On-hand inventory is received by the legal entity that’s consuming it using a product receipt updated inventory transaction on the purchase order.","pos":[6778,6924]},{"content":"This sets the status of the order to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Received<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6925,6975],"source":" This sets the status of the order to **Received**."},{"content":"Purchase orders used for consignment have the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Origin<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Consignment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[6976,7062],"source":" Purchase orders used for consignment have the **Origin** field set to **Consignment**."},{"content":"It’s not possible to update the quantity on consignment purchase order lines after the order has been created.","pos":[7064,7174]},{"pos":[7177,7312],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>inventory-ownership-change-journal<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/inventory-ownership-change-journal.png)](./media/inventory-ownership-change-journal.png)</ept>","source":"[![inventory-ownership-change-journal](./media/inventory-ownership-change-journal.png)](./media/inventory-ownership-change-journal.png)"},{"pos":[7317,7362],"content":"Vendor collaboration in consignment processes","linkify":"Vendor collaboration in consignment processes","nodes":[{"content":"Vendor collaboration in consignment processes","pos":[0,45]}]},{"content":"The vendor collaboration interface has three pages related to the inbound consignment process:","pos":[7363,7457]},{"pos":[7463,7624],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Purchase orders<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>consuming consignment inventory<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> - Shows detailed purchase order information related to the ownership change from the consignment process.","source":"**Purchase orders** **consuming consignment inventory** - Shows detailed purchase order information related to the ownership change from the consignment process."},{"pos":[7629,7800],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Products received from consignment inventory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Shows information about the items and quantities that have product receipts updated during the ownership change process.","source":"**Products received from consignment inventory** - Shows information about the items and quantities that have product receipts updated during the ownership change process."},{"pos":[7805,7995],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>On-hand consignment inventory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Shows information about the consignment items that they are expected to deliver, and the items that are already physically available at the customer site.","source":"**On-hand consignment inventory** - Shows information about the consignment items that they are expected to deliver, and the items that are already physically available at the customer site."}]}