{"content":"--- \n# required metadata \n \ntitle: Set up number sequences on an individual basis\ndescription: Number sequences are used to generate readable, unique identifiers for master data records and transaction records that require them. \nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 06/07/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sericks\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 \n---\n# Set up number sequences on an individual basis\n\n[!include[task guide banner](../../includes/task-guide-banner.md)]\n\nNumber sequences are used to generate readable, unique identifiers for master data records and transaction records that require them. A master data or transaction record that requires an identifier is referred to as a reference. Before you can create new records for a reference, you must set up a number sequence and associate it with the reference. You can set up all required number sequences at the same time by using the Set up number sequences wizard, or you can create or modify individual number sequences by using the Number sequences page.\n\n1. Go to Organization administration > Number sequences > Number sequences.\n2. Click Number sequence.\n3. In the Number sequence code field, type a value.\n4. In the Name field, type a value.\n5. Expand the Scope parameters section.\n    * On the Scope parameters FastTab, select a scope for the number sequence and select scope values.     The scope defines which organizations use the number sequence. In addition, number sequences that have a scope other than Shared can have segments that correspond to their scope. For example, a number sequence with a scope of Legal entity can have a legal entity segment. For more information about scopes, see the \"Number sequence overview\" help topic.  \n6. Expand the Segments section.\n    * On the Segments FastTab, define the format for the number sequence by adding, removing, and rearranging segments.  \n    * Number sequences of all scopes can contain Constant segments and Alphanumeric segments. Constant segments contain a set of alphanumeric characters that do not change. Use this segment type to add a hyphen or other separators between number sequence segments. Alphanumeric segments contain a combination of number signs (#) and ampersands (&). These characters represent letters and numbers that increment every time that a number from the sequence is used. Use a number sign (#) to indicate incrementing numbers and an ampersand (&) to indicate incrementing letters. For example, the format #####_2014 creates the sequence 00001_2014, 00002_2014, and so on.     At least one alphanumeric segment must be present. Scope segments, such as company or legal entity, are not required. However, if you do not include scope segments in the format, numbers for the selected reference are still generated per scope.  \n7. Expand the References section.\n    * On the References FastTab, select the document type or record to assign this number sequence to.     This step is optional for sequences that are defined for special application usage patterns. In these scenarios, a new number is generated by using the value of a number sequence code or ID, without using a reference. An example of a special application usage pattern is a voucher series that is used for specific journal names. However, we do not recommend that you use such patterns.  \n8. Expand the General section.\n    * On the General FastTab, specify whether the number sequence is manual, and continuous or non-continuous. In addition, enter the lowest and highest numbers that can be used in the number sequence.     We do not recommend changing a non-continuous number sequence to a continuous number sequence. The number sequence will not be truly continuous. This change may also cause duplicate key violations in the database. In addition, continuous number sequences have a larger effect on performance.   \n9. Click Save.\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[5,690],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata \n \ntitle: Set up number sequences on an individual basis\ndescription: Number sequences are used to generate readable, unique identifiers for master data records and transaction records that require them. \nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 06/07/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sericks\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 ","nodes":[{"content":"Set up number sequences on an individual basis","nodes":[{"pos":[0,46],"content":"Set up number sequences on an individual basis","nodes":[{"content":"Set up number sequences on an individual basis","pos":[0,46]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"Number sequences are used to generate readable, unique identifiers for master data records and transaction records that require them.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,133],"content":"Number sequences are used to generate readable, unique identifiers for master data records and transaction records that require them.","nodes":[{"content":"Number sequences are used to generate readable, unique identifiers for master data records and transaction records that require them.","pos":[0,133]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata \n","yml":true},{"pos":[697,743],"content":"Set up number sequences on an individual basis","linkify":"Set up number sequences on an individual basis","nodes":[{"content":"Set up number sequences on an individual basis","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"Number sequences are used to generate readable, unique identifiers for master data records and transaction records that require them.","pos":[813,946]},{"content":"A master data or transaction record that requires an identifier is referred to as a reference.","pos":[947,1041]},{"content":"Before you can create new records for a reference, you must set up a number sequence and associate it with the reference.","pos":[1042,1163]},{"content":"You can set up all required number sequences at the same time by using the Set up number sequences wizard, or you can create or modify individual number sequences by using the Number sequences page.","pos":[1164,1362]},{"content":"Go to Organization administration &gt; Number sequences &gt; Number sequences.","pos":[1367,1439],"source":"Go to Organization administration > Number sequences > Number sequences."},{"content":"Click Number sequence.","pos":[1443,1465]},{"content":"In the Number sequence code field, type a value.","pos":[1469,1517]},{"content":"In the Name field, type a value.","pos":[1521,1553]},{"content":"Expand the Scope parameters section.","pos":[1557,1593]},{"content":"On the Scope parameters FastTab, select a scope for the number sequence and select scope values.","pos":[1600,1696]},{"content":"The scope defines which organizations use the number sequence.","pos":[1701,1763]},{"content":"In addition, number sequences that have a scope other than Shared can have segments that correspond to their scope.","pos":[1764,1879]},{"content":"For example, a number sequence with a scope of Legal entity can have a legal entity segment.","pos":[1880,1972]},{"content":"For more information about scopes, see the \"Number sequence overview\" help topic.","pos":[1973,2054]},{"content":"Expand the Segments section.","pos":[2060,2088]},{"content":"On the Segments FastTab, define the format for the number sequence by adding, removing, and rearranging segments.","pos":[2095,2208]},{"content":"Number sequences of all scopes can contain Constant segments and Alphanumeric segments.","pos":[2217,2304]},{"content":"Constant segments contain a set of alphanumeric characters that do not change.","pos":[2305,2383]},{"content":"Use this segment type to add a hyphen or other separators between number sequence segments.","pos":[2384,2475]},{"content":"Alphanumeric segments contain a combination of number signs (#) and ampersands (&amp;).","pos":[2476,2559],"source":" Alphanumeric segments contain a combination of number signs (#) and ampersands (&)."},{"content":"These characters represent letters and numbers that increment every time that a number from the sequence is used.","pos":[2560,2673]},{"content":"Use a number sign (#) to indicate incrementing numbers and an ampersand (&amp;) to indicate incrementing letters.","pos":[2674,2783],"source":" Use a number sign (#) to indicate incrementing numbers and an ampersand (&) to indicate incrementing letters."},{"content":"For example, the format #####_2014 creates the sequence 00001_2014, 00002_2014, and so on.","pos":[2784,2874]},{"content":"At least one alphanumeric segment must be present.","pos":[2879,2929]},{"content":"Scope segments, such as company or legal entity, are not required.","pos":[2930,2996]},{"content":"However, if you do not include scope segments in the format, numbers for the selected reference are still generated per scope.","pos":[2997,3123]},{"content":"Expand the References section.","pos":[3129,3159]},{"content":"On the References FastTab, select the document type or record to assign this number sequence to.","pos":[3166,3262]},{"content":"This step is optional for sequences that are defined for special application usage patterns.","pos":[3267,3359]},{"content":"In these scenarios, a new number is generated by using the value of a number sequence code or ID, without using a reference.","pos":[3360,3484]},{"content":"An example of a special application usage pattern is a voucher series that is used for specific journal names.","pos":[3485,3595]},{"content":"However, we do not recommend that you use such patterns.","pos":[3596,3652]},{"content":"Expand the General section.","pos":[3658,3685]},{"content":"On the General FastTab, specify whether the number sequence is manual, and continuous or non-continuous.","pos":[3692,3796]},{"content":"In addition, enter the lowest and highest numbers that can be used in the number sequence.","pos":[3797,3887]},{"content":"We do not recommend changing a non-continuous number sequence to a continuous number sequence.","pos":[3892,3986]},{"content":"The number sequence will not be truly continuous.","pos":[3987,4036]},{"content":"This change may also cause duplicate key violations in the database.","pos":[4037,4105]},{"content":"In addition, continuous number sequences have a larger effect on performance.","pos":[4106,4183]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[4190,4201]}]}