{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Nonconformance management\ndescription: This article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances. Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders. \nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: InventParameters, InventProblemType, InventProblemTypeSetup, InventQuarantineZone, InventTestDiagnosticType, InventTestReportSetup, SysUserManagement\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 28951\nms.assetid: a62d4ba8-eebc-4b14-b587-630be7298522\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: perlynne\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Nonconformance management\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances. Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders. \n\nTo enable nonconformance management, follow these steps:\n\n1.  Define the Inventory and warehouse management parameters that are related to nonconformances:\n    -   Set the **Use quality management** option to **Yes**.\n    -   In the **Hourly rate** field, enter an hourly labor rate in the local currency. The hourly rate is used to calculate costs for operations that are related to a nonconformance. The hourly rate and calculated costs provide reference information for a nonconformance. They don't interact with other functionality.\n    -   Use the **Quality management** tab on the **Report setup** page to define the type of document to print. You can print a nonconformance report, a nonconformance tag, or a correction report. You can define more than one record to print different document types on a report, or to print internal and external notes. You might find it helpful to use the **Document type** page to define a unique document type for nonconformances and a unique document type for corrections. For example, want to enter notes about a nonconformance by using the unique document type for nonconformances. In this case, identify the unique document type in the report options.\n    -   Enable number sequences for nonconformance and correction references.\n\n2.  Enable user approval of nonconformances. Use the **Name** field on the **Users** page to assign an employee to each user who must approve a nonconformance. The system uses the employees who change the status of a noncomformance to track the nonconformance history. Users can't approve a nonconformance unless they have been assigned an employee identifier.\n3.  Define the problem types that will be assigned to nonconformances. Use the **Problem types** page to define a classification of quality problems that are encountered for the various nonconformance types. You can set up the following nonconformance types: **Internal**, **Customer**, **Vendor**, **Service request**, **Production**, and **Co-product production**. Use the **Non conformance types** page to authorize a problem type to be used in one or more nonconformance types. For example, a problem type that is related to a defect code might apply to all nonconformance types, whereas a problem type that is related to customer complaints might apply only to the **Customer** and **Service request** nonconformance types.\n4.  Define quarantine zones to provide guidance about defective material should be handled. Use the **Quarantine zones** page to define zones that can be assigned to a nonconformance. The printed nonconformance tag will show the assigned quarantine zone and information about usage, to provide guidance about how to handle defective material. The zones might correspond to inventory locations or operations resources.\n5.  Define the diagnostic types that will be assigned to corrections. Use the **Diagnostic types** page to define a classification of diagnostic actions. A correction specifies what type of diagnostic action should be taken for an approved nonconformance, and who should take that action. It also specifies the requested completion date and the planned completion date.\n6.  Define the related operations that will be assigned to nonconformances. Use the **Operations** page to define a classification of the work that can be performed for an approved nonconformance. When you assign a related operation to a nonconformance, you can provide detailed information, such as information about the associated material, labor hours, and miscellaneous charges that are required in order to perform the operation. This information is used to calculate an estimated cost for the operation. The detailed information and estimated costs are for reference. The related operations for quality differ from the operations that can be defined for a production route.\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Create and process a non conformance (Task guide)](/dynamics365/unified-operations/supply-chain/inventory/tasks/create-process-non-conformance)\n\n[Quality management processes](quality-management-processes.md)\n\n[Set up prerequisites for non-conformance management (Task guide)](/dynamics365/unified-operations/supply-chain/inventory/tasks/set-up-prerequisites-nonconformance-management)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,901],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Nonconformance management\ndescription: This article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances. Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders. \nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: InventParameters, InventProblemType, InventProblemTypeSetup, InventQuarantineZone, InventTestDiagnosticType, InventTestReportSetup, SysUserManagement\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 28951\nms.assetid: a62d4ba8-eebc-4b14-b587-630be7298522\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: perlynne\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Nonconformance management","nodes":[{"pos":[0,25],"content":"Nonconformance management","nodes":[{"content":"Nonconformance management","pos":[0,25]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances. Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,152],"content":"This article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances. Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders.","nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances. Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders.","pos":[0,152],"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances.","pos":[0,88]},{"content":"Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders.","pos":[89,152]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[909,934],"content":"Nonconformance management","linkify":"Nonconformance management","nodes":[{"content":"Nonconformance management","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"This article describes the basic setup that is required in order to use nonconformances.","pos":[980,1068]},{"content":"Additional setup is required if you want to use quality orders.","pos":[1069,1132]},{"content":"To enable nonconformance management, follow these steps:","pos":[1135,1191]},{"content":"Define the Inventory and warehouse management parameters that are related to nonconformances:","pos":[1197,1290]},{"pos":[1299,1352],"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Use quality management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"Set the **Use quality management** option to **Yes**."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Hourly rate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter an hourly labor rate in the local currency.","pos":[1361,1440],"source":"In the **Hourly rate** field, enter an hourly labor rate in the local currency."},{"content":"The hourly rate is used to calculate costs for operations that are related to a nonconformance.","pos":[1441,1536]},{"content":"The hourly rate and calculated costs provide reference information for a nonconformance.","pos":[1537,1625]},{"content":"They don't interact with other functionality.","pos":[1626,1671]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quality management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Report setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page to define the type of document to print.","pos":[1680,1784],"source":"Use the **Quality management** tab on the **Report setup** page to define the type of document to print."},{"content":"You can print a nonconformance report, a nonconformance tag, or a correction report.","pos":[1785,1869]},{"content":"You can define more than one record to print different document types on a report, or to print internal and external notes.","pos":[1870,1993]},{"content":"You might find it helpful to use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Document type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to define a unique document type for nonconformances and a unique document type for corrections.","pos":[1994,2150],"source":" You might find it helpful to use the **Document type** page to define a unique document type for nonconformances and a unique document type for corrections."},{"content":"For example, want to enter notes about a nonconformance by using the unique document type for nonconformances.","pos":[2151,2261]},{"content":"In this case, identify the unique document type in the report options.","pos":[2262,2332]},{"content":"Enable number sequences for nonconformance and correction references.","pos":[2341,2410]},{"content":"Enable user approval of nonconformances.","pos":[2416,2456]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Users<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page to assign an employee to each user who must approve a nonconformance.","pos":[2457,2571],"source":" Use the **Name** field on the **Users** page to assign an employee to each user who must approve a nonconformance."},{"content":"The system uses the employees who change the status of a noncomformance to track the nonconformance history.","pos":[2572,2680]},{"content":"Users can't approve a nonconformance unless they have been assigned an employee identifier.","pos":[2681,2772]},{"content":"Define the problem types that will be assigned to nonconformances.","pos":[2777,2843]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Problem types<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to define a classification of quality problems that are encountered for the various nonconformance types.","pos":[2844,2980],"source":" Use the **Problem types** page to define a classification of quality problems that are encountered for the various nonconformance types."},{"content":"You can set up the following nonconformance types: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Internal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Customer<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Vendor<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Service request<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Production<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Co-product production<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept>.","pos":[2981,3139],"source":" You can set up the following nonconformance types: **Internal**, **Customer**, **Vendor**, **Service request**, **Production**, and **Co-product production**."},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Non conformance types<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to authorize a problem type to be used in one or more nonconformance types.","pos":[3140,3254],"source":" Use the **Non conformance types** page to authorize a problem type to be used in one or more nonconformance types."},{"content":"For example, a problem type that is related to a defect code might apply to all nonconformance types, whereas a problem type that is related to customer complaints might apply only to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Service request<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> nonconformance types.","pos":[3255,3501],"source":" For example, a problem type that is related to a defect code might apply to all nonconformance types, whereas a problem type that is related to customer complaints might apply only to the **Customer** and **Service request** nonconformance types."},{"content":"Define quarantine zones to provide guidance about defective material should be handled.","pos":[3506,3593]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quarantine zones<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to define zones that can be assigned to a nonconformance.","pos":[3594,3685],"source":" Use the **Quarantine zones** page to define zones that can be assigned to a nonconformance."},{"content":"The printed nonconformance tag will show the assigned quarantine zone and information about usage, to provide guidance about how to handle defective material.","pos":[3686,3844]},{"content":"The zones might correspond to inventory locations or operations resources.","pos":[3845,3919]},{"content":"Define the diagnostic types that will be assigned to corrections.","pos":[3924,3989]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Diagnostic types<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to define a classification of diagnostic actions.","pos":[3990,4073],"source":" Use the **Diagnostic types** page to define a classification of diagnostic actions."},{"content":"A correction specifies what type of diagnostic action should be taken for an approved nonconformance, and who should take that action.","pos":[4074,4208]},{"content":"It also specifies the requested completion date and the planned completion date.","pos":[4209,4289]},{"content":"Define the related operations that will be assigned to nonconformances.","pos":[4294,4365]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operations<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to define a classification of the work that can be performed for an approved nonconformance.","pos":[4366,4486],"source":" Use the **Operations** page to define a classification of the work that can be performed for an approved nonconformance."},{"content":"When you assign a related operation to a nonconformance, you can provide detailed information, such as information about the associated material, labor hours, and miscellaneous charges that are required in order to perform the operation.","pos":[4487,4724]},{"content":"This information is used to calculate an estimated cost for the operation.","pos":[4725,4799]},{"content":"The detailed information and estimated costs are for reference.","pos":[4800,4863]},{"content":"The related operations for quality differ from the operations that can be defined for a production route.","pos":[4864,4969]},{"pos":[4972,4980],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[4991,5135],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create and process a non conformance (Task guide)<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/supply-chain/inventory/tasks/create-process-non-conformance)</ept>","source":"[Create and process a non conformance (Task guide)](/dynamics365/unified-operations/supply-chain/inventory/tasks/create-process-non-conformance)"},{"pos":[5137,5200],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Quality management processes<ept id=\"p1\">](quality-management-processes.md)</ept>","source":"[Quality management processes](quality-management-processes.md)"},{"pos":[5202,5377],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up prerequisites for non-conformance management (Task guide)<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/supply-chain/inventory/tasks/set-up-prerequisites-nonconformance-management)</ept>","source":"[Set up prerequisites for non-conformance management (Task guide)](/dynamics365/unified-operations/supply-chain/inventory/tasks/set-up-prerequisites-nonconformance-management)"}]}