{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Purchasing policies\ndescription: This article provides information about purchasing policies. A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process. Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.\nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: PurchReqSourcingPolicyRule, SysPolicy, SysPolicyListPage\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 11614\nms.assetid: 729a304d-0f3f-4ccb-bd5b-46ee0976c57f\nms.search.region: Global\n\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mkirknel\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Purchasing policies\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article provides information about purchasing policies. A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process. Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.\n\nA purchasing policy consists of a set of policy rules. When you define a policy rule, you first select a rule type. You then create a rule for the rule type by defining the settings, the start date, and the end date for the rule.  \n\nFor example, an administrator creates a policy, selects the **Catalog policy** rule type, and then adds a catalog policy rule to the policy. This catalog policy rule specifies that the Adventure catalog must be used for internal procurement. After the purchasing policy is associated with a particular organization, employees of that organization see the Adventure catalog when they create requisitions.\n\n## Assigning policies to organizations\nBefore a policy can take effect, it must be associated with an organization. Purchasing policies are associated with the **Procurement internal control** hierarchy purpose. Therefore, purchasing policies apply only to organizations in hierarchies that have a hierarchy purpose of **Procurement internal control**. You can also select organizations from the flat list of legal entities in the CompanyInfo table. These legal entities are designated in the policy framework as “Companies.”\n\n## Determining which rule to apply\nDepending on how you configure your purchasing policies, multiple rules can affect the users in an organization. The following examples illustrate different ways that you can configure purchasing policies and specify how policies are applied when a transaction occurs.\n\n### Example 1: Simple purchasing policy configuration\n\nOrganizations that are small and less complex can set up purchasing policies by legal entity, and can use only the Companies organization hierarchy.  \n\nFor Fabrikam, a small business, purchasing requirements vary little across the organization. Purchasing rules vary only among the organization's legal entities. For example, employees of Fabrikam Canada and employees of Fabrikam U.S. purchase goods and services from different catalogs and different vendors. Therefore, Fabrikam sets up its purchasing policies at the legal-entity level.  \n\nFabrikam creates two purchasing policies. Policy A applies to its U.S. legal entity, 1111. Policy B applies to its Canadian legal entity, 2222. When an employee in legal entity 1111 creates a purchase requisition, the policy rules are derived from policy A. For example, the product catalog that the employee sees is specified in the catalog policy rule for policy A.  \n\nWhen an employee in legal entity 2222 creates a purchase requisition, the policy rules are derived from policy B.  \n\n**Note:** If an employee of legal entity 1111 purchases an item on behalf of an employee of legal entity 2222, the policy rules that are specified for legal entity 2222 (that is, the policy rules from policy B) are applied.\n\n### Example 2: Complex purchasing policy configuration\n\nIn the previous example, all purchasing rules were defined in a single organization hierarchy, the Companies organization hierarchy. However, a complex organization might define policies for multiple organization hierarchies.  \n\n\nContoso is a large company that requires complex purchasing rules to control the requisition process. Contoso has defined rules for two different organization hierarchies: Department and Global purchasing control.  \n\nPolicy 123 is defined for the Department organization hierarchy for the Sales UK – Sales department. In policy 123, the purchase requisition control rule specifies that restrictions must be enforced for minimum order quantities. In this rule, the **Enforce minimum order quantity restrictions** option is selected.  \n\nPolicy 456 is defined for the Global purchasing control organization hierarchy for the Sales and Marketing department. In policy 456, the purchase requisition control rule doesn't specify that restrictions must be enforced for minimum order quantities. In this rule, the **Enforce minimum order quantity restrictions** option is de-selected.  \n\nSam works in the Sales UK – Sales department in Contoso’s United Kingdom office. The policies for both the Department and Global purchasing control organization hierarchies apply to his department. When Sam creates a purchase requisition, the system must determine which policy to apply. The system administrator set up the purchasing policy parameters to specify that purchasing policies must be applied in the following order of precedence:\n\n1.  Global purchasing control\n2.  Department\n3.  Companies\n\nTherefore, policy 456 is applied to the purchase requisition that Sam creates, and no minimum order quantity is required for the purchase requisition.\n\n## Policy rules\n### Catalog policy rule\n\nThe catalog policy rule determines which procurement catalog users see when they create purchase requisitions. If a user has been granted permission to order products on behalf of another user, the requisition uses the catalog policy rule that is defined for the requester’s legal entity and operating unit to determine which catalog to display. Before you can define a catalog policy rule, you must create and publish a procurement catalog.\n\n### Category access policy rule\n\nThe category access policy rule determines which categories users have access to when they create purchase requisitions. If no rule is specified, all the procurement categories can be added to the purchase requisition.\n\n1.  Select the **Include parent rule** option to apply the category access policy rule of the parent organization to the category.\n2.  In the **Available categories** pane, select the categories that the rule applies to. When you select a category, all categories that are higher in the hierarchy are also added to the **Selected categories** list.\n3.  Select the **Include subcategories** option to apply the rule to all subcategories of the selected category.\n\n### Category policy rule\n\nThe category policy rule defines how users can select vendors for each category. It also defines requirements for the receiving and invoicing processes.\n\n### Re-approval rule for purchase orders\n\nThe re-approval rule is an optional rule that defines the criteria for requiring re-approval when a purchase order is changed. The selected fields are evaluated in the purchase order workflow when the \"Requires purchase order re-approval\" condition is set up in the workflow.\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> Accounting distribution will always be reset when an approved purchase order with change management enabled is changed. So you should be aware that if you want to avoid a re-approval of a purchase order when certain fields are changed, the field Accounting distribution.changed should NOT be included as a selected field for re-approval. \n\n### Purchase requisition RFQ rule\n\nThe purchase requisition RFQ rule defines criteria for requiring a request for quotation (RFQ) for a purchase requisition line. If a line meets the conditions, the \"informal RFQ\" or \"formal RFQ\" stamp appears on the requisition line.\n\n### Purchase requisition control rule\n\nThe purchase requisition control rule is an optional rule. When you create rules of this type, you can set options on various tabs:\n\n-   On the **Workflow submission** tab, you can configure the fields that must be entered on the requisition line for the requisition to be submitted for approval when the requisition purpose is **Consumption**.\n-   On the **Order quantities** tab, you can configure the fields that are required on the purchase requisition under certain conditions. You can also enforce order quantities.\n-   On the **Dates** tab, you can configure whether the accounting date is the same as the requested date\n-   On the **Address** tab, you can define whether the user is allowed to create new addresses in the system to apply to the purchase requisition.\n\n### Requisition purpose rule\n\nThe requisition purpose rule is an optional rule that determines the type of requisition purpose that is allowed for a specific legal entity. Unless another purpose is indicated in this rule, requisitions automatically have a purpose of **Consumption** when they are created.\n\n### Replenishment category access policy rule\n\nThe replenishment category access policy rile is an optional rule that determines the products that are available to fulfill requisition demand for a specific legal entity when the requisition purpose is **Replenishment**.\n\n### Replenishment control rule\n\nThe replenishment control rule is an optional rule that defines the fields that must be entered on the requisition line for the requisition to be submitted for approval when the requisition purpose is **Replenishment**.\n\n### Purchase order creation and demand consolidation rule\n\nThe purchase order creation and demand consolidation rule defines the policy rules to use when a purchase order is generated from an approved purchase requisition. When you create rules of this type, you can set options on various tabs:\n\n-   On the **Purchase order split** tab, you can define criteria for splitting purchase requisition lines onto separate purchase orders.\n-   On the **Price/discount transfer** tab, you can define when to recalculate the price agreement when a purchase order is created:\n    -   **Only if no trade agreement** – Prices and discounts are transferred from the purchase requisition only if there is no applicable trade agreement or base price. If a trade agreement or base price exists for the item or vendor, the prices and discounts are recalculated based on the trade agreement or the base price, and are applied to the purchase order. Unless otherwise specified, this is the default behavior.\n    -   **Always** – Prices and discounts are always transferred from the purchase requisition.\n\n    You can also allow the requester to change the method of price and discount transfer for individual purchase requisition lines, regardless of the price/discount transfer rule that is defined. Select the **Allow manual override per purchase requisition line** option to enable this capability.\n-   On the **Item description transfer** tab, you can transfer the item description from the requisition when it originates from an RFQ.\n-   On the **Price Tolerance** tab, you can define rules to route approved purchase requisitions back through the review process when the price of a procurement catalog item increases. Set the maximum amount that the net amount on a line item on a purchase requisition can increase between the time when the purchase requisition is approved and the time when the purchase order is created. The net amount is calculated by using the following formula: (\\[Quantity × (Unit price – Discount) ÷ Price unit\\] + Purchase miscellaneous charges) × (100 – Discount percent) ÷ 100 Purchase requisition lines that exceed the price tolerance that you set are held for manual processing. The rules that you configure on the **Error processing** tab determine how the purchase requisition lines are processed.\n-   On the **Error processing** tab, you can configure the processing rule that is applied to a purchase requisition if it fails validation during purchase order creation because of a vendor error or a price tolerance error. Select one of the following options:\n    -   **No action** – The purchase requisition lines remain on the **Release approved purchase requisitions** page. The status of the purchase requisition lines remains **Approved**. However, the errors must be resolved before a purchase order can be generated for the purchase requisition lines.\n    -   **Cancel the purchase requisition line** – The purchase requisition lines are canceled. The requester can create a new purchase requisition for the canceled lines if he or she still wants to request the line items.\n    -   **Create a new purchase requisition line** – The purchase requisition lines are canceled. New purchase requisitions are then generated that contain only the purchase requisition lines that failed validation. The new purchase requisitions that are generated have a status of **Draft**. These purchase requisitions can be resubmitted for review after the validation errors have been resolved. The preparer of the purchase requisition lines is notified that the lines were canceled, and that new purchase requisitions were generated for the purchase requisition lines that failed.\n-   On the **Manual purchase order creation** tab, you can define the parameters that determine whether a purchase requisition must be manually processed, or whether it can be automatically converted to a purchase order. The parameters can apply to internal catalog items, external catalog items, or non-catalog items. Select one of the following options:\n    -   **Manually create purchase orders** – Manually create purchase orders for all purchase requisitions.\n    -   **Automatically create purchase orders** – Automatically create purchase orders for all approved purchase requisitions. No purchase requisitions are held for manual purchase order creation.\n    -   **Automatically create purchase orders except under these conditions** – Manually create purchase orders for purchase requisitions that match the criteria that you define. All other purchase requisitions that are approved are automatically converted to purchase orders. If you select **Automatically create purchase orders except under these conditions**, you can add procurement categories and vendors to specify which approved purchase requisition lines are held for manual processing. This option can apply to internal catalog items, external catalog items, and non-catalog items. When you select a procurement category, any subcategories for that procurement category are also selected. Select the **All** option for a specific type of purchase requisition line to hold all lines of that line type for manual processing.\n\n    If you want purchase orders to be generated automatically from approved purchase requisitions when the batch job for purchase order generation runs, select the **Run automatic purchase order creation as a batch job** option. This option applies only to purchase requisitions that don't require manual processing. By running automatic purchase order generation as a batch job, you can schedule this activity at a time when resources are less constrained. If the **Prepayment required** option is selected on the purchase requisition lines, select the **When the requisition is set up for prepayment** option to hold approved purchase requisitions for manual processing. Purchase requisitions that are held for manual processing can be filtered so that you can view only those purchase requisition lines that require prepayment.\n-   On the **Demand consolidation** tab, you can define the parameters that determine whether purchase requisitions that are manually processed can be considered for purchase requisition consolidation. The parameters can apply to internal catalog items, external catalog items, or non-catalog items. Select one of the following options:\n    -   **Do not allow demand consolidation** – No approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation. This option is selected by default and applies only to purchase requisition lines that require manual processing for purchase order creation.\n    -   **Always allow demand consolidation** – All approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation. **Note:** If you select the **Always allow demand consolidation** option on the **Demand consolidation** tab, but you select the **Automatically create purchase orders** option on the **Manual purchase order creation** tab, all purchase requisitions are held for manual processing.\n    -   **Allow demand consolidation under these conditions** – Define the criteria that determine whether approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation. For each type of purchase requisition line, you can set the criteria by procurement category and vendor. If you select **Allow demand consolidation under these conditions**, you can set the criteria by procurement category and vendor for each type of purchase requisition line. When you select a procurement category, any subcategories for that procurement category are also selected. If you select the **All** option for a specific line type, all purchase requisition lines of that line type are eligible for demand consolidation.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,988],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Purchasing policies\ndescription: This article provides information about purchasing policies. A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process. Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.\nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: PurchReqSourcingPolicyRule, SysPolicy, SysPolicyListPage\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: yuyus\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 11614\nms.assetid: 729a304d-0f3f-4ccb-bd5b-46ee0976c57f\nms.search.region: Global\n\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mkirknel\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Purchasing policies","nodes":[{"pos":[0,19],"content":"Purchasing policies","nodes":[{"content":"Purchasing policies","pos":[0,19]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides information about purchasing policies. A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process. Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,338],"content":"This article provides information about purchasing policies. A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process. Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about purchasing policies. A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process. Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.","pos":[0,338],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about purchasing policies.","pos":[0,60]},{"content":"A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process.","pos":[61,143]},{"content":"Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.","pos":[144,338]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[996,1015],"content":"Purchasing policies","linkify":"Purchasing policies","nodes":[{"content":"Purchasing policies","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"This article provides information about purchasing policies.","pos":[1061,1121]},{"content":"A purchasing policy is a collection of rules that control the requisition process.","pos":[1122,1204]},{"content":"Purchasing policies help procurement administrators implement their procurement strategy by creating a policy structure that is aligned with the organization’s strategic purchasing requirements.","pos":[1205,1399]},{"content":"A purchasing policy consists of a set of policy rules.","pos":[1401,1455]},{"content":"When you define a policy rule, you first select a rule type.","pos":[1456,1516]},{"content":"You then create a rule for the rule type by defining the settings, the start date, and the end date for the rule.","pos":[1517,1630]},{"content":"For example, an administrator creates a policy, selects the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Catalog policy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> rule type, and then adds a catalog policy rule to the policy.","pos":[1634,1774],"source":"For example, an administrator creates a policy, selects the **Catalog policy** rule type, and then adds a catalog policy rule to the policy."},{"content":"This catalog policy rule specifies that the Adventure catalog must be used for internal procurement.","pos":[1775,1875]},{"content":"After the purchasing policy is associated with a particular organization, employees of that organization see the Adventure catalog when they create requisitions.","pos":[1876,2037]},{"pos":[2042,2077],"content":"Assigning policies to organizations","linkify":"Assigning policies to organizations","nodes":[{"content":"Assigning policies to organizations","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"Before a policy can take effect, it must be associated with an organization.","pos":[2078,2154]},{"content":"Purchasing policies are associated with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Procurement internal control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> hierarchy purpose.","pos":[2155,2250],"source":" Purchasing policies are associated with the **Procurement internal control** hierarchy purpose."},{"content":"Therefore, purchasing policies apply only to organizations in hierarchies that have a hierarchy purpose of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Procurement internal control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2251,2391],"source":" Therefore, purchasing policies apply only to organizations in hierarchies that have a hierarchy purpose of **Procurement internal control**."},{"content":"You can also select organizations from the flat list of legal entities in the CompanyInfo table.","pos":[2392,2488]},{"content":"These legal entities are designated in the policy framework as “Companies.”","pos":[2489,2564]},{"pos":[2569,2600],"content":"Determining which rule to apply","linkify":"Determining which rule to apply","nodes":[{"content":"Determining which rule to apply","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"Depending on how you configure your purchasing policies, multiple rules can affect the users in an organization.","pos":[2601,2713]},{"content":"The following examples illustrate different ways that you can configure purchasing policies and specify how policies are applied when a transaction occurs.","pos":[2714,2869]},{"pos":[2875,2924],"content":"Example 1: Simple purchasing policy configuration","linkify":"Example 1: Simple purchasing policy configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Example 1: Simple purchasing policy configuration","pos":[0,49]}]},{"content":"Organizations that are small and less complex can set up purchasing policies by legal entity, and can use only the Companies organization hierarchy.","pos":[2926,3074]},{"content":"For Fabrikam, a small business, purchasing requirements vary little across the organization.","pos":[3078,3170]},{"content":"Purchasing rules vary only among the organization's legal entities.","pos":[3171,3238]},{"content":"For example, employees of Fabrikam Canada and employees of Fabrikam U.S. purchase goods and services from different catalogs and different vendors.","pos":[3239,3386]},{"content":"Therefore, Fabrikam sets up its purchasing policies at the legal-entity level.","pos":[3387,3465]},{"content":"Fabrikam creates two purchasing policies.","pos":[3469,3510]},{"content":"Policy A applies to its U.S. legal entity, 1111.","pos":[3511,3559]},{"content":"Policy B applies to its Canadian legal entity, 2222.","pos":[3560,3612]},{"content":"When an employee in legal entity 1111 creates a purchase requisition, the policy rules are derived from policy A. For example, the product catalog that the employee sees is specified in the catalog policy rule for policy A.","pos":[3613,3836]},{"content":"When an employee in legal entity 2222 creates a purchase requisition, the policy rules are derived from policy B.","pos":[3840,3953]},{"pos":[3957,4180],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If an employee of legal entity 1111 purchases an item on behalf of an employee of legal entity 2222, the policy rules that are specified for legal entity 2222 (that is, the policy rules from policy B) are applied.","source":"**Note:** If an employee of legal entity 1111 purchases an item on behalf of an employee of legal entity 2222, the policy rules that are specified for legal entity 2222 (that is, the policy rules from policy B) are applied."},{"pos":[4186,4236],"content":"Example 2: Complex purchasing policy configuration","linkify":"Example 2: Complex purchasing policy configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Example 2: Complex purchasing policy configuration","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"In the previous example, all purchasing rules were defined in a single organization hierarchy, the Companies organization hierarchy.","pos":[4238,4370]},{"content":"However, a complex organization might define policies for multiple organization hierarchies.","pos":[4371,4463]},{"content":"Contoso is a large company that requires complex purchasing rules to control the requisition process.","pos":[4468,4569]},{"content":"Contoso has defined rules for two different organization hierarchies: Department and Global purchasing control.","pos":[4570,4681]},{"content":"Policy 123 is defined for the Department organization hierarchy for the Sales UK – Sales department.","pos":[4685,4785]},{"content":"In policy 123, the purchase requisition control rule specifies that restrictions must be enforced for minimum order quantities.","pos":[4786,4913]},{"content":"In this rule, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enforce minimum order quantity restrictions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is selected.","pos":[4914,4999],"source":" In this rule, the **Enforce minimum order quantity restrictions** option is selected."},{"content":"Policy 456 is defined for the Global purchasing control organization hierarchy for the Sales and Marketing department.","pos":[5003,5121]},{"content":"In policy 456, the purchase requisition control rule doesn't specify that restrictions must be enforced for minimum order quantities.","pos":[5122,5255]},{"content":"In this rule, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enforce minimum order quantity restrictions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is de-selected.","pos":[5256,5344],"source":" In this rule, the **Enforce minimum order quantity restrictions** option is de-selected."},{"content":"Sam works in the Sales UK – Sales department in Contoso’s United Kingdom office.","pos":[5348,5428]},{"content":"The policies for both the Department and Global purchasing control organization hierarchies apply to his department.","pos":[5429,5545]},{"content":"When Sam creates a purchase requisition, the system must determine which policy to apply.","pos":[5546,5635]},{"content":"The system administrator set up the purchasing policy parameters to specify that purchasing policies must be applied in the following order of precedence:","pos":[5636,5790]},{"content":"Global purchasing control","pos":[5796,5821]},{"content":"Department","pos":[5826,5836]},{"content":"Companies","pos":[5841,5850]},{"content":"Therefore, policy 456 is applied to the purchase requisition that Sam creates, and no minimum order quantity is required for the purchase requisition.","pos":[5852,6002]},{"pos":[6007,6019],"content":"Policy rules","linkify":"Policy rules","nodes":[{"content":"Policy rules","pos":[0,12]}]},{"pos":[6024,6043],"content":"Catalog policy rule","linkify":"Catalog policy rule","nodes":[{"content":"Catalog policy rule","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"The catalog policy rule determines which procurement catalog users see when they create purchase requisitions.","pos":[6045,6155]},{"content":"If a user has been granted permission to order products on behalf of another user, the requisition uses the catalog policy rule that is defined for the requester’s legal entity and operating unit to determine which catalog to display.","pos":[6156,6390]},{"content":"Before you can define a catalog policy rule, you must create and publish a procurement catalog.","pos":[6391,6486]},{"pos":[6492,6519],"content":"Category access policy rule","linkify":"Category access policy rule","nodes":[{"content":"Category access policy rule","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"The category access policy rule determines which categories users have access to when they create purchase requisitions.","pos":[6521,6641]},{"content":"If no rule is specified, all the procurement categories can be added to the purchase requisition.","pos":[6642,6739]},{"pos":[6745,6871],"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Include parent rule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to apply the category access policy rule of the parent organization to the category.","source":"Select the **Include parent rule** option to apply the category access policy rule of the parent organization to the category."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Available categories<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> pane, select the categories that the rule applies to.","pos":[6876,6961],"source":"In the **Available categories** pane, select the categories that the rule applies to."},{"content":"When you select a category, all categories that are higher in the hierarchy are also added to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Selected categories<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list.","pos":[6962,7089],"source":" When you select a category, all categories that are higher in the hierarchy are also added to the **Selected categories** list."},{"pos":[7094,7202],"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Include subcategories<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to apply the rule to all subcategories of the selected category.","source":"Select the **Include subcategories** option to apply the rule to all subcategories of the selected category."},{"pos":[7208,7228],"content":"Category policy rule","linkify":"Category policy rule","nodes":[{"content":"Category policy rule","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"The category policy rule defines how users can select vendors for each category.","pos":[7230,7310]},{"content":"It also defines requirements for the receiving and invoicing processes.","pos":[7311,7382]},{"pos":[7388,7424],"content":"Re-approval rule for purchase orders","linkify":"Re-approval rule for purchase orders","nodes":[{"content":"Re-approval rule for purchase orders","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"The re-approval rule is an optional rule that defines the criteria for requiring re-approval when a purchase order is changed.","pos":[7426,7552]},{"content":"The selected fields are evaluated in the purchase order workflow when the \"Requires purchase order re-approval\" condition is set up in the workflow.","pos":[7553,7701]},{"pos":[7705,8052],"content":"[!NOTE]\nAccounting distribution will always be reset when an approved purchase order with change management enabled is changed. So you should be aware that if you want to avoid a re-approval of a purchase order when certain fields are changed, the field Accounting distribution.changed should NOT be included as a selected field for re-approval.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Accounting distribution will always be reset when an approved purchase order with change management enabled is changed. So you should be aware that if you want to avoid a re-approval of a purchase order when certain fields are changed, the field Accounting distribution.changed should NOT be included as a selected field for re-approval.","pos":[8,345],"nodes":[{"content":"Accounting distribution will always be reset when an approved purchase order with change management enabled is changed.","pos":[0,119]},{"content":"So you should be aware that if you want to avoid a re-approval of a purchase order when certain fields are changed, the field Accounting distribution.changed should NOT be included as a selected field for re-approval.","pos":[120,337]}]}]},{"pos":[8059,8088],"content":"Purchase requisition RFQ rule","linkify":"Purchase requisition RFQ rule","nodes":[{"content":"Purchase requisition RFQ rule","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"The purchase requisition RFQ rule defines criteria for requiring a request for quotation (RFQ) for a purchase requisition line.","pos":[8090,8217]},{"content":"If a line meets the conditions, the \"informal RFQ\" or \"formal RFQ\" stamp appears on the requisition line.","pos":[8218,8323]},{"pos":[8329,8362],"content":"Purchase requisition control rule","linkify":"Purchase requisition control rule","nodes":[{"content":"Purchase requisition control rule","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"The purchase requisition control rule is an optional rule.","pos":[8364,8422]},{"content":"When you create rules of this type, you can set options on various tabs:","pos":[8423,8495]},{"pos":[8501,8708],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Workflow submission<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can configure the fields that must be entered on the requisition line for the requisition to be submitted for approval when the requisition purpose is <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Consumption<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Workflow submission** tab, you can configure the fields that must be entered on the requisition line for the requisition to be submitted for approval when the requisition purpose is **Consumption**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Order quantities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can configure the fields that are required on the purchase requisition under certain conditions.","pos":[8713,8846],"source":"On the **Order quantities** tab, you can configure the fields that are required on the purchase requisition under certain conditions."},{"content":"You can also enforce order quantities.","pos":[8847,8885]},{"pos":[8890,8991],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can configure whether the accounting date is the same as the requested date","source":"On the **Dates** tab, you can configure whether the accounting date is the same as the requested date"},{"pos":[8996,9138],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Address<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can define whether the user is allowed to create new addresses in the system to apply to the purchase requisition.","source":"On the **Address** tab, you can define whether the user is allowed to create new addresses in the system to apply to the purchase requisition."},{"pos":[9144,9168],"content":"Requisition purpose rule","linkify":"Requisition purpose rule","nodes":[{"content":"Requisition purpose rule","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"The requisition purpose rule is an optional rule that determines the type of requisition purpose that is allowed for a specific legal entity.","pos":[9170,9311]},{"content":"Unless another purpose is indicated in this rule, requisitions automatically have a purpose of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Consumption<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> when they are created.","pos":[9312,9445],"source":" Unless another purpose is indicated in this rule, requisitions automatically have a purpose of **Consumption** when they are created."},{"pos":[9451,9492],"content":"Replenishment category access policy rule","linkify":"Replenishment category access policy rule","nodes":[{"content":"Replenishment category access policy rule","pos":[0,41]}]},{"pos":[9494,9716],"content":"The replenishment category access policy rile is an optional rule that determines the products that are available to fulfill requisition demand for a specific legal entity when the requisition purpose is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Replenishment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"The replenishment category access policy rile is an optional rule that determines the products that are available to fulfill requisition demand for a specific legal entity when the requisition purpose is **Replenishment**."},{"pos":[9722,9748],"content":"Replenishment control rule","linkify":"Replenishment control rule","nodes":[{"content":"Replenishment control rule","pos":[0,26]}]},{"pos":[9750,9969],"content":"The replenishment control rule is an optional rule that defines the fields that must be entered on the requisition line for the requisition to be submitted for approval when the requisition purpose is <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Replenishment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"The replenishment control rule is an optional rule that defines the fields that must be entered on the requisition line for the requisition to be submitted for approval when the requisition purpose is **Replenishment**."},{"pos":[9975,10028],"content":"Purchase order creation and demand consolidation rule","linkify":"Purchase order creation and demand consolidation rule","nodes":[{"content":"Purchase order creation and demand consolidation rule","pos":[0,53]}]},{"content":"The purchase order creation and demand consolidation rule defines the policy rules to use when a purchase order is generated from an approved purchase requisition.","pos":[10030,10193]},{"content":"When you create rules of this type, you can set options on various tabs:","pos":[10194,10266]},{"pos":[10272,10404],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Purchase order split<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can define criteria for splitting purchase requisition lines onto separate purchase orders.","source":"On the **Purchase order split** tab, you can define criteria for splitting purchase requisition lines onto separate purchase orders."},{"pos":[10409,10537],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Price/discount transfer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can define when to recalculate the price agreement when a purchase order is created:","source":"On the **Price/discount transfer** tab, you can define when to recalculate the price agreement when a purchase order is created:"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Only if no trade agreement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Prices and discounts are transferred from the purchase requisition only if there is no applicable trade agreement or base price.","pos":[10546,10707],"source":"**Only if no trade agreement** – Prices and discounts are transferred from the purchase requisition only if there is no applicable trade agreement or base price."},{"content":"If a trade agreement or base price exists for the item or vendor, the prices and discounts are recalculated based on the trade agreement or the base price, and are applied to the purchase order.","pos":[10708,10902]},{"content":"Unless otherwise specified, this is the default behavior.","pos":[10903,10960]},{"pos":[10969,11056],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Always<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Prices and discounts are always transferred from the purchase requisition.","source":"**Always** – Prices and discounts are always transferred from the purchase requisition."},{"content":"You can also allow the requester to change the method of price and discount transfer for individual purchase requisition lines, regardless of the price/discount transfer rule that is defined.","pos":[11062,11253]},{"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Allow manual override per purchase requisition line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to enable this capability.","pos":[11254,11354],"source":" Select the **Allow manual override per purchase requisition line** option to enable this capability."},{"pos":[11359,11491],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Item description transfer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can transfer the item description from the requisition when it originates from an RFQ.","source":"On the **Item description transfer** tab, you can transfer the item description from the requisition when it originates from an RFQ."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Price Tolerance<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can define rules to route approved purchase requisitions back through the review process when the price of a procurement catalog item increases.","pos":[11496,11676],"source":"On the **Price Tolerance** tab, you can define rules to route approved purchase requisitions back through the review process when the price of a procurement catalog item increases."},{"content":"Set the maximum amount that the net amount on a line item on a purchase requisition can increase between the time when the purchase requisition is approved and the time when the purchase order is created.","pos":[11677,11881]},{"content":"The net amount is calculated by using the following formula: (<ph id=\"ph1\">\\[</ph>Quantity × (Unit price – Discount) ÷ Price unit<ph id=\"ph2\">\\]</ph> + Purchase miscellaneous charges) × (100 – Discount percent) ÷ 100 Purchase requisition lines that exceed the price tolerance that you set are held for manual processing.","pos":[11882,12166],"source":" The net amount is calculated by using the following formula: (\\[Quantity × (Unit price – Discount) ÷ Price unit\\] + Purchase miscellaneous charges) × (100 – Discount percent) ÷ 100 Purchase requisition lines that exceed the price tolerance that you set are held for manual processing."},{"content":"The rules that you configure on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Error processing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab determine how the purchase requisition lines are processed.","pos":[12167,12287],"source":" The rules that you configure on the **Error processing** tab determine how the purchase requisition lines are processed."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Error processing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can configure the processing rule that is applied to a purchase requisition if it fails validation during purchase order creation because of a vendor error or a price tolerance error.","pos":[12292,12512],"source":"On the **Error processing** tab, you can configure the processing rule that is applied to a purchase requisition if it fails validation during purchase order creation because of a vendor error or a price tolerance error."},{"content":"Select one of the following options:","pos":[12513,12549]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>No action<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The purchase requisition lines remain on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Release approved purchase requisitions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[12558,12667],"source":"**No action** – The purchase requisition lines remain on the **Release approved purchase requisitions** page."},{"content":"The status of the purchase requisition lines remains <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[12668,12734],"source":" The status of the purchase requisition lines remains **Approved**."},{"content":"However, the errors must be resolved before a purchase order can be generated for the purchase requisition lines.","pos":[12735,12848]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cancel the purchase requisition line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The purchase requisition lines are canceled.","pos":[12857,12944],"source":"**Cancel the purchase requisition line** – The purchase requisition lines are canceled."},{"content":"The requester can create a new purchase requisition for the canceled lines if he or she still wants to request the line items.","pos":[12945,13071]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create a new purchase requisition line<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The purchase requisition lines are canceled.","pos":[13080,13169],"source":"**Create a new purchase requisition line** – The purchase requisition lines are canceled."},{"content":"New purchase requisitions are then generated that contain only the purchase requisition lines that failed validation.","pos":[13170,13287]},{"content":"The new purchase requisitions that are generated have a status of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Draft<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[13288,13364],"source":" The new purchase requisitions that are generated have a status of **Draft**."},{"content":"These purchase requisitions can be resubmitted for review after the validation errors have been resolved.","pos":[13365,13470]},{"content":"The preparer of the purchase requisition lines is notified that the lines were canceled, and that new purchase requisitions were generated for the purchase requisition lines that failed.","pos":[13471,13657]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Manual purchase order creation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can define the parameters that determine whether a purchase requisition must be manually processed, or whether it can be automatically converted to a purchase order.","pos":[13662,13878],"source":"On the **Manual purchase order creation** tab, you can define the parameters that determine whether a purchase requisition must be manually processed, or whether it can be automatically converted to a purchase order."},{"content":"The parameters can apply to internal catalog items, external catalog items, or non-catalog items.","pos":[13879,13976]},{"content":"Select one of the following options:","pos":[13977,14013]},{"pos":[14022,14122],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Manually create purchase orders<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Manually create purchase orders for all purchase requisitions.","source":"**Manually create purchase orders** – Manually create purchase orders for all purchase requisitions."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Automatically create purchase orders<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Automatically create purchase orders for all approved purchase requisitions.","pos":[14131,14250],"source":"**Automatically create purchase orders** – Automatically create purchase orders for all approved purchase requisitions."},{"content":"No purchase requisitions are held for manual purchase order creation.","pos":[14251,14320]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Automatically create purchase orders except under these conditions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Manually create purchase orders for purchase requisitions that match the criteria that you define.","pos":[14329,14500],"source":"**Automatically create purchase orders except under these conditions** – Manually create purchase orders for purchase requisitions that match the criteria that you define."},{"content":"All other purchase requisitions that are approved are automatically converted to purchase orders.","pos":[14501,14598]},{"content":"If you select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Automatically create purchase orders except under these conditions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you can add procurement categories and vendors to specify which approved purchase requisition lines are held for manual processing.","pos":[14599,14816],"source":" If you select **Automatically create purchase orders except under these conditions**, you can add procurement categories and vendors to specify which approved purchase requisition lines are held for manual processing."},{"content":"This option can apply to internal catalog items, external catalog items, and non-catalog items.","pos":[14817,14912]},{"content":"When you select a procurement category, any subcategories for that procurement category are also selected.","pos":[14913,15019]},{"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option for a specific type of purchase requisition line to hold all lines of that line type for manual processing.","pos":[15020,15153],"source":" Select the **All** option for a specific type of purchase requisition line to hold all lines of that line type for manual processing."},{"content":"If you want purchase orders to be generated automatically from approved purchase requisitions when the batch job for purchase order generation runs, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run automatic purchase order creation as a batch job<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option.","pos":[15159,15383],"source":"If you want purchase orders to be generated automatically from approved purchase requisitions when the batch job for purchase order generation runs, select the **Run automatic purchase order creation as a batch job** option."},{"content":"This option applies only to purchase requisitions that don't require manual processing.","pos":[15384,15471]},{"content":"By running automatic purchase order generation as a batch job, you can schedule this activity at a time when resources are less constrained.","pos":[15472,15612]},{"content":"If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Prepayment required<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is selected on the purchase requisition lines, select the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>When the requisition is set up for prepayment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> option to hold approved purchase requisitions for manual processing.","pos":[15613,15827],"source":" If the **Prepayment required** option is selected on the purchase requisition lines, select the **When the requisition is set up for prepayment** option to hold approved purchase requisitions for manual processing."},{"content":"Purchase requisitions that are held for manual processing can be filtered so that you can view only those purchase requisition lines that require prepayment.","pos":[15828,15985]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Demand consolidation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can define the parameters that determine whether purchase requisitions that are manually processed can be considered for purchase requisition consolidation.","pos":[15990,16187],"source":"On the **Demand consolidation** tab, you can define the parameters that determine whether purchase requisitions that are manually processed can be considered for purchase requisition consolidation."},{"content":"The parameters can apply to internal catalog items, external catalog items, or non-catalog items.","pos":[16188,16285]},{"content":"Select one of the following options:","pos":[16286,16322]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Do not allow demand consolidation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – No approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation.","pos":[16331,16448],"source":"**Do not allow demand consolidation** – No approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation."},{"content":"This option is selected by default and applies only to purchase requisition lines that require manual processing for purchase order creation.","pos":[16449,16590]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Always allow demand consolidation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – All approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation.","pos":[16599,16717],"source":"**Always allow demand consolidation** – All approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you select the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Always allow demand consolidation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> option on the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Demand consolidation<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> tab, but you select the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Automatically create purchase orders<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> option on the <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Manual purchase order creation<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> tab, all purchase requisitions are held for manual processing.","pos":[16718,16999],"source":"**Note:** If you select the **Always allow demand consolidation** option on the **Demand consolidation** tab, but you select the **Automatically create purchase orders** option on the **Manual purchase order creation** tab, all purchase requisitions are held for manual processing."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Allow demand consolidation under these conditions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Define the criteria that determine whether approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation.","pos":[17008,17181],"source":"**Allow demand consolidation under these conditions** – Define the criteria that determine whether approved purchase requisition lines are eligible for demand consolidation."},{"content":"For each type of purchase requisition line, you can set the criteria by procurement category and vendor.","pos":[17182,17286]},{"content":"If you select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Allow demand consolidation under these conditions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, you can set the criteria by procurement category and vendor for each type of purchase requisition line.","pos":[17287,17459],"source":" If you select **Allow demand consolidation under these conditions**, you can set the criteria by procurement category and vendor for each type of purchase requisition line."},{"content":"When you select a procurement category, any subcategories for that procurement category are also selected.","pos":[17460,17566]},{"content":"If you select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option for a specific line type, all purchase requisition lines of that line type are eligible for demand consolidation.","pos":[17567,17713],"source":" If you select the **All** option for a specific line type, all purchase requisition lines of that line type are eligible for demand consolidation."}]}