{"content":"--- \n# required metadata \n \ntitle: Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order\ndescription: This procedure shows how to set up a Mobile device menu item. \nauthor: BibiSp\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 08/25/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Distribution\nms.author: bibis\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 \n---\n# Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order\n\n[!include[task guide banner](../../includes/task-guide-banner.md)]\n\nThis procedure shows how to set up a Mobile device menu item. In this example, the menu item is used for performing work of type Purchase order. The work class that’s associated with the menu item determines which work is valid. You can use this guide in demo data company USMF. This procedure is typically carried out by a warehouse manager.\n\n\n## Create a mobile device menu item\n1. Go to Mobile device menu items.\n2. Click New.\n3. In the Menu item name field, type a value.\n    * Enter a unique value. For example, you could type POMove. Remember the value, you'll need it later.  \n4. In the Title field, type a value.\n    * This is the title which will be displayed on the mobile device. For example, you could type PO Move.  \n5. In the Mode field, select 'Work'.\n6. Select Yes in the Use existing work field.\n    * This mobile device menu item is used to perform existing work. Therefore you must set this value to Yes.  \n    * The Display inventory status field determines whether the inventory status of the on-hand inventory will be displayed to the warehouse worker on the mobile device.  \n7. In the Directed by field, select 'System grouping'.\n    * When you select something in the Directed by field, additional fields appear in the General section on this page. The fields that appear depend on what you selected. When you select System grouping, two new fields are added. These are explained below.  \n8. In the System grouping field, select 'WorkPoolId'.\n    * When warehouse workers open this menu item, they’ll be asked to scan a Work pool ID. All work orders with this Work pool ID and open work order lines with one of the work classes added to this menu item will be pushed to the user.  \n9. In the System grouping label field, type a value.\n    * This is the text displayed to the user on the mobile device. For example, you could type Work pool.  \n10. Select Yes in the Override license plate during put field.\n    * This option allows warehouse workers to override the target license plate when items are put down on a license plate controlled location.  \n11. Select Yes in the Group put away field.\n    * If all the Put lines on the work order share the same location, the user will receive one combined Put instruction for all lines.  \n    * Audit template ID: A work audit template allows you to specify that the work process for a menu item should be interrupted so that another operation can be performed. For example, if this menu item is for inbound work, the audit template might require that the worker checks the temperature. The point at which the process is interrupted is specified on the audit template and can be, for example, when work is started or completed, or when its status changes.  \n12. Expand the Work classes section.\n13. Click New.\n14. In the Work class ID field, type 'Purchase'.\n    * The work pool restricts the work that the menu item can be used for. In this case it will be used for open work order lines that have the Purchase work class ID.  \n15. Click Save.\n\n## Set up work confirmation\n1. Click Work confirmation setup.\n2. In the Work type field, select 'Pick'.\n3. Select the Auto confirm check box.\n    * The work instruction with work type Pick will be auto-confirmed. This instruction will not be presented to the user.  \n4. Click New.\n5. In the Work type field, select 'Put'.\n6. Select the Location confirmation check box.\n    * The warehouse worker will be asked to perform a confirmation scan of the location, when the item is put down.  \n7. Click Save.\n8. Close the page.\n9. Close the page.\n\n## Add the menu item to a mobile device menu\n1. Go to Mobile device menu.\n2. Click Edit.\n3. Use the Quick Filter to find records. For example, filter on the Name field with a value of 'inbound'.\n    * You want to find the menu you use for inbound menu items. In USMF this is called Inbound.  \n4. In the tree, select 'a value'.\n5. Click on the arrow that points to the right.\n6. Click Save.\n7. Close the page.\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[5,646],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata \n \ntitle: Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order\ndescription: This procedure shows how to set up a Mobile device menu item. \nauthor: BibiSp\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 08/25/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Distribution\nms.author: bibis\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 ","nodes":[{"content":"Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order","nodes":[{"pos":[0,72],"content":"Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order","nodes":[{"content":"Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order","pos":[0,72]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This procedure shows how to set up a Mobile device menu item.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,61],"content":"This procedure shows how to set up a Mobile device menu item.","nodes":[{"content":"This procedure shows how to set up a Mobile device menu item.","pos":[0,61]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata \n","yml":true},{"pos":[653,725],"content":"Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order","linkify":"Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order","nodes":[{"content":"Set up a mobile device menu item for completing work in a purchase order","pos":[0,72]}]},{"content":"This procedure shows how to set up a Mobile device menu item.","pos":[795,856]},{"content":"In this example, the menu item is used for performing work of type Purchase order.","pos":[857,939]},{"content":"The work class that’s associated with the menu item determines which work is valid.","pos":[940,1023]},{"content":"You can use this guide in demo data company USMF.","pos":[1024,1073]},{"content":"This procedure is typically carried out by a warehouse manager.","pos":[1074,1137]},{"pos":[1143,1175],"content":"Create a mobile device menu item","linkify":"Create a mobile device menu item","nodes":[{"content":"Create a mobile device menu item","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"Go to Mobile device menu items.","pos":[1179,1210]},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[1214,1224]},{"content":"In the Menu item name field, type a value.","pos":[1228,1270]},{"content":"Enter a unique value.","pos":[1277,1298]},{"content":"For example, you could type POMove.","pos":[1299,1334]},{"content":"Remember the value, you'll need it later.","pos":[1335,1376]},{"content":"In the Title field, type a value.","pos":[1382,1415]},{"content":"This is the title which will be displayed on the mobile device.","pos":[1422,1485]},{"content":"For example, you could type PO Move.","pos":[1486,1522]},{"content":"In the Mode field, select 'Work'.","pos":[1528,1561]},{"content":"Select Yes in the Use existing work field.","pos":[1565,1607]},{"content":"This mobile device menu item is used to perform existing work.","pos":[1614,1676]},{"content":"Therefore you must set this value to Yes.","pos":[1677,1718]},{"content":"The Display inventory status field determines whether the inventory status of the on-hand inventory will be displayed to the warehouse worker on the mobile device.","pos":[1727,1890]},{"content":"In the Directed by field, select 'System grouping'.","pos":[1896,1947]},{"content":"When you select something in the Directed by field, additional fields appear in the General section on this page.","pos":[1954,2067]},{"content":"The fields that appear depend on what you selected.","pos":[2068,2119]},{"content":"When you select System grouping, two new fields are added.","pos":[2120,2178]},{"content":"These are explained below.","pos":[2179,2205]},{"content":"In the System grouping field, select 'WorkPoolId'.","pos":[2211,2261]},{"content":"When warehouse workers open this menu item, they’ll be asked to scan a Work pool ID.","pos":[2268,2352]},{"content":"All work orders with this Work pool ID and open work order lines with one of the work classes added to this menu item will be pushed to the user.","pos":[2353,2498]},{"content":"In the System grouping label field, type a value.","pos":[2504,2553]},{"content":"This is the text displayed to the user on the mobile device.","pos":[2560,2620]},{"content":"For example, you could type Work pool.","pos":[2621,2659]},{"content":"Select Yes in the Override license plate during put field.","pos":[2666,2724]},{"content":"This option allows warehouse workers to override the target license plate when items are put down on a license plate controlled location.","pos":[2731,2868]},{"content":"Select Yes in the Group put away field.","pos":[2875,2914]},{"content":"If all the Put lines on the work order share the same location, the user will receive one combined Put instruction for all lines.","pos":[2921,3050]},{"content":"Audit template ID: A work audit template allows you to specify that the work process for a menu item should be interrupted so that another operation can be performed.","pos":[3059,3225]},{"content":"For example, if this menu item is for inbound work, the audit template might require that the worker checks the temperature.","pos":[3226,3350]},{"content":"The point at which the process is interrupted is specified on the audit template and can be, for example, when work is started or completed, or when its status changes.","pos":[3351,3519]},{"content":"Expand the Work classes section.","pos":[3526,3558]},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[3563,3573]},{"content":"In the Work class ID field, type 'Purchase'.","pos":[3578,3622]},{"content":"The work pool restricts the work that the menu item can be used for.","pos":[3629,3697]},{"content":"In this case it will be used for open work order lines that have the Purchase work class ID.","pos":[3698,3790]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[3797,3808]},{"pos":[3813,3837],"content":"Set up work confirmation","linkify":"Set up work confirmation","nodes":[{"content":"Set up work confirmation","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"Click Work confirmation setup.","pos":[3841,3871]},{"content":"In the Work type field, select 'Pick'.","pos":[3875,3913]},{"content":"Select the Auto confirm check box.","pos":[3917,3951]},{"content":"The work instruction with work type Pick will be auto-confirmed.","pos":[3958,4022]},{"content":"This instruction will not be presented to the user.","pos":[4023,4074]},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[4080,4090]},{"content":"In the Work type field, select 'Put'.","pos":[4094,4131]},{"content":"Select the Location confirmation check box.","pos":[4135,4178]},{"content":"The warehouse worker will be asked to perform a confirmation scan of the location, when the item is put down.","pos":[4185,4294]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[4300,4311]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4315,4330]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4334,4349]},{"pos":[4354,4395],"content":"Add the menu item to a mobile device menu","linkify":"Add the menu item to a mobile device menu","nodes":[{"content":"Add the menu item to a mobile device menu","pos":[0,41]}]},{"content":"Go to Mobile device menu.","pos":[4399,4424]},{"content":"Click Edit.","pos":[4428,4439]},{"content":"Use the Quick Filter to find records.","pos":[4443,4480]},{"content":"For example, filter on the Name field with a value of 'inbound'.","pos":[4481,4545]},{"content":"You want to find the menu you use for inbound menu items.","pos":[4552,4609]},{"content":"In USMF this is called Inbound.","pos":[4610,4641]},{"content":"In the tree, select 'a value'.","pos":[4647,4677]},{"content":"Click on the arrow that points to the right.","pos":[4681,4725]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[4729,4740]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4744,4759]}]}