{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Ledger allocation rules\ndescription: This article provides information about ledger allocation rules. It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerAllocation, LedgerAllocationBasisRule, LedgerAllocationRequest, LedgerAllocationRule\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 15402\nms.assetid: 8147e148-7c11-45ef-95c6-f9889a875b54\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: peakerbl\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Ledger allocation rules\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article provides information about ledger allocation rules. It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.\n\nLedger allocation rules are used to automatically calculate and generate allocation journals and account entries for the allocation of ledger balances or fixed amounts. Allocation methods can be variable or fixed. The following allocation methods can be used for ledger allocation rules:\n\n-   **Basis** – This variable method is used when the allocation depends on the actual ledger balance, based on filter criteria. For example, advertising expenses can be allocated based on each department's sales in proportion to the total departmental sales.\n-   **Fixed percentage** and **Fixed weight** – For these methods, the allocation percentage or weight is defined directly for the rule. For example, advertising expenses can be allocated so that Department A receives 70 percent of the advertising expense and Department B receives 30 percent.\n-   **Equally** – This method distributes the amount equally to each defined destination. For example, if destinations are defined for Department A and Department B, advertising expenses can be allocated so that both Department A and Department B receive 50 percent of the advertising expense.\n\nIf Basis is used as the allocation method for an allocation rule, you must also define separate ledger allocation basis rules. The \"Process allocation request\" process lets users process the ledger allocation rule and preview the resulting allocation journal entries before they either post or delete the calculated allocations.\n\n## Components of ledger allocation rules\nEach allocation rule has four components: general, source, destination, and offset. An additional component, ledger allocation bases rules, is required if Basis is used as the allocation method. Each component provides a critical piece of the information that is required in order to process allocations.\n\n-   **General** – This component is where the user specifies options such as the allocation method, intercompany rule settings, and whether the rule is active.\n-   **Source** – This component is where the user specifies the source data for the allocation. Allocation can be based on ledger balances (**Data source** = **Ledger**) or fixed amounts (**Data source** = **Fixed value**). When **Data source** is set to **Ledger**, source filter criteria must be defined for the ledger allocation rule (for example, for the advertising expenses).\n-   **Destination** – This component defines how the result of the allocation calculation should be distributed and accounted for. For example, there can be one destination line for each department.\n-   **Offset** – This component defines how main accounts and dimensions should be determined for the offset entries that balance the destination entries. User-defined options are typically used instead of accounts and dimensions that are based on the source. When **Data source** is set to **Fixed value**, **Source** can't be used as an option.\n-   **Ledger allocation basis rules** – These rules use their own source filter criteria to determine which ledger balances should be used for allocation (for example, the revenue per department). Each allocation basis rule can be used with multiple allocation rules.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,866],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Ledger allocation rules\ndescription: This article provides information about ledger allocation rules. It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerAllocation, LedgerAllocationBasisRule, LedgerAllocationRequest, LedgerAllocationRule\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 15402\nms.assetid: 8147e148-7c11-45ef-95c6-f9889a875b54\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: peakerbl\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Ledger allocation rules","nodes":[{"pos":[0,23],"content":"Ledger allocation rules","nodes":[{"content":"Ledger allocation rules","pos":[0,23]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides information about ledger allocation rules. It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,180],"content":"This article provides information about ledger allocation rules. It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about ledger allocation rules. It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.","pos":[0,180],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about ledger allocation rules.","pos":[0,64]},{"content":"It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.","pos":[65,180]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[874,897],"content":"Ledger allocation rules","linkify":"Ledger allocation rules","nodes":[{"content":"Ledger allocation rules","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"This article provides information about ledger allocation rules.","pos":[943,1007]},{"content":"It describes the various components of these allocation rules and the allocation methods that can be used for them.","pos":[1008,1123]},{"content":"Ledger allocation rules are used to automatically calculate and generate allocation journals and account entries for the allocation of ledger balances or fixed amounts.","pos":[1125,1293]},{"content":"Allocation methods can be variable or fixed.","pos":[1294,1338]},{"content":"The following allocation methods can be used for ledger allocation rules:","pos":[1339,1412]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Basis<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This variable method is used when the allocation depends on the actual ledger balance, based on filter criteria.","pos":[1418,1542],"source":"**Basis** – This variable method is used when the allocation depends on the actual ledger balance, based on filter criteria."},{"content":"For example, advertising expenses can be allocated based on each department's sales in proportion to the total departmental sales.","pos":[1543,1673]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Fixed percentage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Fixed weight<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> – For these methods, the allocation percentage or weight is defined directly for the rule.","pos":[1678,1810],"source":"**Fixed percentage** and **Fixed weight** – For these methods, the allocation percentage or weight is defined directly for the rule."},{"content":"For example, advertising expenses can be allocated so that Department A receives 70 percent of the advertising expense and Department B receives 30 percent.","pos":[1811,1967]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Equally<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This method distributes the amount equally to each defined destination.","pos":[1972,2057],"source":"**Equally** – This method distributes the amount equally to each defined destination."},{"content":"For example, if destinations are defined for Department A and Department B, advertising expenses can be allocated so that both Department A and Department B receive 50 percent of the advertising expense.","pos":[2058,2261]},{"content":"If Basis is used as the allocation method for an allocation rule, you must also define separate ledger allocation basis rules.","pos":[2263,2389]},{"content":"The \"Process allocation request\" process lets users process the ledger allocation rule and preview the resulting allocation journal entries before they either post or delete the calculated allocations.","pos":[2390,2591]},{"pos":[2596,2633],"content":"Components of ledger allocation rules","linkify":"Components of ledger allocation rules","nodes":[{"content":"Components of ledger allocation rules","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"Each allocation rule has four components: general, source, destination, and offset.","pos":[2634,2717]},{"content":"An additional component, ledger allocation bases rules, is required if Basis is used as the allocation method.","pos":[2718,2828]},{"content":"Each component provides a critical piece of the information that is required in order to process allocations.","pos":[2829,2938]},{"pos":[2944,3099],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This component is where the user specifies options such as the allocation method, intercompany rule settings, and whether the rule is active.","source":"**General** – This component is where the user specifies options such as the allocation method, intercompany rule settings, and whether the rule is active."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Source<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This component is where the user specifies the source data for the allocation.","pos":[3104,3195],"source":"**Source** – This component is where the user specifies the source data for the allocation."},{"content":"Allocation can be based on ledger balances (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data source<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\"> = </ph><bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Ledger<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>) or fixed amounts (<bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Data source<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph2\"> = </ph><bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Fixed value<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>).","pos":[3196,3323],"source":" Allocation can be based on ledger balances (**Data source** = **Ledger**) or fixed amounts (**Data source** = **Fixed value**)."},{"content":"When <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data source<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Ledger<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, source filter criteria must be defined for the ledger allocation rule (for example, for the advertising expenses).","pos":[3324,3481],"source":" When **Data source** is set to **Ledger**, source filter criteria must be defined for the ledger allocation rule (for example, for the advertising expenses)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Destination<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This component defines how the result of the allocation calculation should be distributed and accounted for.","pos":[3486,3612],"source":"**Destination** – This component defines how the result of the allocation calculation should be distributed and accounted for."},{"content":"For example, there can be one destination line for each department.","pos":[3613,3680]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Offset<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This component defines how main accounts and dimensions should be determined for the offset entries that balance the destination entries.","pos":[3685,3835],"source":"**Offset** – This component defines how main accounts and dimensions should be determined for the offset entries that balance the destination entries."},{"content":"User-defined options are typically used instead of accounts and dimensions that are based on the source.","pos":[3836,3940]},{"content":"When <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data source<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Fixed value<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Source<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> can't be used as an option.","pos":[3941,4027],"source":" When **Data source** is set to **Fixed value**, **Source** can't be used as an option."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ledger allocation basis rules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – These rules use their own source filter criteria to determine which ledger balances should be used for allocation (for example, the revenue per department).","pos":[4032,4224],"source":"**Ledger allocation basis rules** – These rules use their own source filter criteria to determine which ledger balances should be used for allocation (for example, the revenue per department)."},{"content":"Each allocation basis rule can be used with multiple allocation rules.","pos":[4225,4295]}]}