{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Intercompany invoicing\ndescription: This article provides information and examples about intercompany invoicing for projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 94153\nms.assetid: 33e98da7-01c1-4369-923d-aa1c8326cb80\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Intercompany invoicing\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article provides information and examples about intercompany invoicing for projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.\n\nYour organization might have multiple divisions, subsidiaries, and other legal entities that transfer products and services to each other for projects. The legal entity that provides the service or product is called the *lending legal entity*, and the legal entity that receives the service or product is called the *borrowing legal entity*. \n\nThe following illustration shows a typical scenario where two legal entities, SI FR (the borrowing legal entity) and SI USA (the lending legal entity) share resources to deliver a project for customer A. For this scenario, SI FR is contracted to deliver the work to customer A. \n\n[![Intercompany invoicing example](./media/interco.invoicing-01.jpg)](./media/interco.invoicing-01.jpg) \n\nThe goal is to make cost control, revenue recognition, taxes, and transfer price for intercompany project transactions more flexible and powerful. In addition, the following capabilities are provided:\n\n-   Create customer invoices against a project in a borrowing legal entity by using intercompany timesheets, expenses, and vendor invoices in a lending legal entity.\n-   Support tax calculations and indirect costs.\n-   Defer revenue recognition in a lending legal entity and when a borrowing legal entity should recognize the cost.\n-   Accrue work in process (WIP) revenue in the lending legal entity.\n-   Set transfer prices that can be based on various pricing models. Here are some examples:\n    -   **Quantity** – The amount that you enter in the **Pricing** field is the actual cost per quantity or unit.\n    -   **Charges amount** – The price/cost per transaction plus the charges amount that you enter in the **Pricing** field.\n    -   **Charges percentage** – The transfer price is the price/cost per transaction multiplied by the charges percentage that you enter in the **Pricing** field.\n    -   **Percentage of sales price** – The percentage of the sales price that is transferred to the lending legal entity.\n    -   **Amount below sales price** – The amount that the borrowing legal entity holds back from the sales prices before transfer to the lending legal entity.\n    -   **Contribution ratio** – The number that you enter in the **Pricing** field is the contribution ratio, which is expressed as a percentage of the sales price.\n\n## Example 1: Set up parameters for intercompany invoicing\nIn this example, USSI is a lending legal entity, and its resources are reporting time against the borrowing legal entity, FRSI, which owns the contract with the end customer. Hours and expenses that USSI employees report can be included in the project invoice that FRSI generates. In addition, there is a third source of transactions that can originate from the lending legal entity (USSI in this example) when it provides shared vendors services to subsidiaries (such as FRSI) and then passes on those costs to projects within those subsidiaries. All matching invoice documents and tax calculations are completed by Finance and Operations. \n\nFor this example, FRSI must be a customer in the USSI legal entity, and USSI must be a vendor in the FRSI legal entity. You can then set up an intercompany relationship between the two legal entities. The following procedure shows how to set up the parameters so that both legal entities can participate in intercompany invoicing.\n\n1.  Set up FRSI as a customer in the USSI legal entity, and set up USSI as a vendor in the FRSI legal entity. There are three entry points for the steps that are required for this task.\n    | Step | Entry point                                                                       | Description   |\n    |------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n    | A    | In USSI, click **Accounts receivable** &gt; **Customers** &gt; **All customers**. | Create a new customer record for FRSI, and select the customer group.                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n    | B    | In FRSI, click **Accounts payable** &gt; **Vendors** &gt; **All vendors**.        | Create a new vendor record for USSI, and select the vendor group.                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n    | C    | In FRSI, open the vendor record that you just created.                            | On the Action Pane, on the **General** tab, in the **Set up** group, click **Intercompany**. On the **Intercompany** page, on the **Trading relationship** tab, set the **Active** slider to **Yes**. In the **Customer company** field, select the customer record that you created in step A. |\n\n2.  Click **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Project management accounting parameters**, and then click the **Intercompany** tab. The way that you set up the parameters depends on whether you're the borrowing legal entity or the lending legal entity.\n    -   If you're the borrowing legal entity, select the procurement category that should be used to match the vendor invoices, which are automatically generated.\n    -   If you're the lending legal entity, for each borrowing entity, select a default project category for each transaction type. Project categories are used for tax configuration when the invoiced category in intercompany transactions exists only in the borrowing legal entity. You can choose to accrue revenue for intercompany transactions. This accrual is done when the transactions are posted, and it's then reversed when the intercompany invoice is posted.\n\n3.  Click **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Prices** &gt; **Transfer price**.\n4.  Select a currency, transaction type, and transfer price model. The currency that is used on the invoice is the currency that is configured in the customer record for the borrowing legal entity in the lending legal entity. The currency is used to match entries in the transfer price table.\n5.  Click **General ledger** &gt; **Posting setup** &gt; **Intercompany accounting**, and set up a relationship for USSI and FRSI.\n\n## Example 2: Create and post an intercompany timesheet\nUSSI, the lending legal entity, must create and post the timesheet for a project from FRSI, the borrowing legal entity. There are two entry points for the steps that are required for this task.\n\n| Step | Entry point                                                                       | Description                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n|------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| A    | **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Timesheets** &gt; **All timesheets** | Create a new timesheet. On the timesheet line, in the **Legal entity** field, select **FRSI**. In the **Project ID** field, select the project in FRSI. Enter the hours for each day of the week. |\n| B    | **Timesheet** page                                                                | After the workflow runs, post the timesheet, and make a note of the voucher number.                                                                                                               |\n\n## Example 3: Create and post an intercompany vendor invoice\nUSSI, the lending legal entity, must create and post the intercompany vendor invoice for a project from FRSI, the borrowing legal entity. This vendor invoice represents the outsourced labor and expense that were performed by vendors that are paid by USSI. There are two entry points for the steps that are required for this task.\n\n| Step | Entry point                                                                                      | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n|------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| A    | **Accounts payable** &gt; **Invoices** &gt; **Open vendor invoices** &gt; **New vendor invoice** | Create a new vendor invoice, and enter the services that were procured on behalf of FRSI's project.                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| B    | The **Vendor invoice** page                                                                      | Enter lines that represent the outsourced services on behalf of FRSI. On the **Line details** FastTab, on the **Project** tab for the invoice line, in the **Project company** field, enter **FRSI**. Enter the project and corresponding information. Then post the vendor invoice. |\n\n## Example 4: Create and post the intercompany invoice\nUSSI, the lending legal entity, must create and post the intercompany invoice. There are two entry points for the steps that are required for this task.\n\n| Step | Entry point                                                                                             | Description                                                                                                                                      |\n|------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| A    | **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Intercompany customer invoice**  | Click **New** to open the **Create intercompany invoice** page.                                                                                  |\n| B    | **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Intercompany customer invoices** | On the **Create intercompany invoice** page, enter the legal entity, specify the transaction that should be included, and then click **Search**. |\n| C    | **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Intercompany customer invoices** | Select the transactions to invoice, or click **Select all** to invoice all the transactions in the list, and then click **OK**.                  |\n| D    | The **Intercompany invoice** page                                                                       | The intercompany customer invoice proposal is shown.                                                                                             |\n| E    | The **Intercompany invoice** page                                                                       | Click **Post**.                                                                                                                                  |\n\n## Example 5: Post the vendor invoice and invoice the customer\nWhen the lending legal entity, USSI, posts the intercompany customer invoice, a matching pending vendor invoice is created in the borrowing legal entity, FRSI. After this vendor invoice is posted, FRSI also invoices the project customer for the hours that USSI entered. There are three entry points for the steps that are required for this task.\n\n| Step | Entry point                                                                                        | Description                                                                                                             |\n|------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| A    | **Accounts payable** &gt; **Invoices** &gt; **Pending vendor invoices**                            | Review the invoice to verify that the timesheet values are included, and then post the vendor invoice.                  |\n| B    | **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Project invoice proposals** | Create a new project invoice for the project, and verify that the hour transactions that were posted appear.            |\n| C    | The **Project invoice** page                                                                       | Select the project invoice, and then click **View details** to review the cost and sales amount. Then post the invoice. |\n\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,759],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Intercompany invoicing\ndescription: This article provides information and examples about intercompany invoicing for projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 94153\nms.assetid: 33e98da7-01c1-4369-923d-aa1c8326cb80\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Intercompany invoicing","nodes":[{"pos":[0,22],"content":"Intercompany invoicing","nodes":[{"content":"Intercompany invoicing","pos":[0,22]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides information and examples about intercompany invoicing for projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,162],"content":"This article provides information and examples about intercompany invoicing for projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information and examples about intercompany invoicing for projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[0,162]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[767,789],"content":"Intercompany invoicing","linkify":"Intercompany invoicing","nodes":[{"content":"Intercompany invoicing","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"This article provides information and examples about intercompany invoicing for projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[835,997]},{"content":"Your organization might have multiple divisions, subsidiaries, and other legal entities that transfer products and services to each other for projects.","pos":[999,1150]},{"content":"The legal entity that provides the service or product is called the <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>lending legal entity<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>, and the legal entity that receives the service or product is called the <bpt id=\"p2\">*</bpt>borrowing legal entity<ept id=\"p2\">*</ept>.","pos":[1151,1340],"source":" The legal entity that provides the service or product is called the *lending legal entity*, and the legal entity that receives the service or product is called the *borrowing legal entity*."},{"content":"The following illustration shows a typical scenario where two legal entities, SI FR (the borrowing legal entity) and SI USA (the lending legal entity) share resources to deliver a project for customer A. For this scenario, SI FR is contracted to deliver the work to customer A.","pos":[1343,1620]},{"pos":[1623,1726],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Intercompany invoicing example<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/interco.invoicing-01.jpg)](./media/interco.invoicing-01.jpg)</ept>","source":"[![Intercompany invoicing example](./media/interco.invoicing-01.jpg)](./media/interco.invoicing-01.jpg)"},{"content":"The goal is to make cost control, revenue recognition, taxes, and transfer price for intercompany project transactions more flexible and powerful.","pos":[1729,1875]},{"content":"In addition, the following capabilities are provided:","pos":[1876,1929]},{"content":"Create customer invoices against a project in a borrowing legal entity by using intercompany timesheets, expenses, and vendor invoices in a lending legal entity.","pos":[1935,2096]},{"content":"Support tax calculations and indirect costs.","pos":[2101,2145]},{"content":"Defer revenue recognition in a lending legal entity and when a borrowing legal entity should recognize the cost.","pos":[2150,2262]},{"content":"Accrue work in process (WIP) revenue in the lending legal entity.","pos":[2267,2332]},{"content":"Set transfer prices that can be based on various pricing models.","pos":[2337,2401]},{"content":"Here are some examples:","pos":[2402,2425]},{"pos":[2434,2540],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The amount that you enter in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pricing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field is the actual cost per quantity or unit.","source":"**Quantity** – The amount that you enter in the **Pricing** field is the actual cost per quantity or unit."},{"pos":[2549,2665],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Charges amount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The price/cost per transaction plus the charges amount that you enter in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pricing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field.","source":"**Charges amount** – The price/cost per transaction plus the charges amount that you enter in the **Pricing** field."},{"pos":[2674,2829],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Charges percentage<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The transfer price is the price/cost per transaction multiplied by the charges percentage that you enter in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pricing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field.","source":"**Charges percentage** – The transfer price is the price/cost per transaction multiplied by the charges percentage that you enter in the **Pricing** field."},{"pos":[2838,2952],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Percentage of sales price<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The percentage of the sales price that is transferred to the lending legal entity.","source":"**Percentage of sales price** – The percentage of the sales price that is transferred to the lending legal entity."},{"pos":[2961,3112],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Amount below sales price<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The amount that the borrowing legal entity holds back from the sales prices before transfer to the lending legal entity.","source":"**Amount below sales price** – The amount that the borrowing legal entity holds back from the sales prices before transfer to the lending legal entity."},{"pos":[3121,3278],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Contribution ratio<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The number that you enter in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pricing<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field is the contribution ratio, which is expressed as a percentage of the sales price.","source":"**Contribution ratio** – The number that you enter in the **Pricing** field is the contribution ratio, which is expressed as a percentage of the sales price."},{"pos":[3283,3338],"content":"Example 1: Set up parameters for intercompany invoicing","linkify":"Example 1: Set up parameters for intercompany invoicing","nodes":[{"content":"Example 1: Set up parameters for intercompany invoicing","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"In this example, USSI is a lending legal entity, and its resources are reporting time against the borrowing legal entity, FRSI, which owns the contract with the end customer.","pos":[3339,3513]},{"content":"Hours and expenses that USSI employees report can be included in the project invoice that FRSI generates.","pos":[3514,3619]},{"content":"In addition, there is a third source of transactions that can originate from the lending legal entity (USSI in this example) when it provides shared vendors services to subsidiaries (such as FRSI) and then passes on those costs to projects within those subsidiaries.","pos":[3620,3886]},{"content":"All matching invoice documents and tax calculations are completed by Finance and Operations.","pos":[3887,3979]},{"content":"For this example, FRSI must be a customer in the USSI legal entity, and USSI must be a vendor in the FRSI legal entity.","pos":[3982,4101]},{"content":"You can then set up an intercompany relationship between the two legal entities.","pos":[4102,4182]},{"content":"The following procedure shows how to set up the parameters so that both legal entities can participate in intercompany invoicing.","pos":[4183,4312]},{"content":"Set up FRSI as a customer in the USSI legal entity, and set up USSI as a vendor in the FRSI legal entity.","pos":[4318,4423]},{"content":"There are three entry points for the steps that are required for this task.","pos":[4424,4499]},{"content":"Step","pos":[4506,4510]},{"content":"Entry point","pos":[4513,4524]},{"content":"Description","pos":[4597,4608]},{"content":"A","pos":[5006,5007]},{"pos":[5013,5094],"content":"In USSI, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounts receivable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Customers<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>All customers<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"In USSI, click **Accounts receivable** &gt; **Customers** &gt; **All customers**."},{"content":"Create a new customer record for FRSI, and select the customer group.","pos":[5097,5166]},{"content":"B","pos":[5393,5394]},{"pos":[5400,5474],"content":"In FRSI, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounts payable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Vendors<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>All vendors<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"In FRSI, click **Accounts payable** &gt; **Vendors** &gt; **All vendors**."},{"content":"Create a new vendor record for USSI, and select the vendor group.","pos":[5484,5549]},{"content":"C","pos":[5780,5781]},{"content":"In FRSI, open the vendor record that you just created.","pos":[5787,5841]},{"content":"On the Action Pane, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Set up<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> group, click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Intercompany<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[5871,5963],"source":"On the Action Pane, on the **General** tab, in the **Set up** group, click **Intercompany**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Intercompany<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Trading relationship<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab, set the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Active<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> slider to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[5964,6068],"source":" On the **Intercompany** page, on the **Trading relationship** tab, set the **Active** slider to **Yes**."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customer company<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select the customer record that you created in step A.","pos":[6069,6158],"source":" In the **Customer company** field, select the customer record that you created in step A."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Project management accounting parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and then click the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Intercompany<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[6166,6316],"source":"Click **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Project management accounting parameters**, and then click the **Intercompany** tab."},{"content":"The way that you set up the parameters depends on whether you're the borrowing legal entity or the lending legal entity.","pos":[6317,6437]},{"content":"If you're the borrowing legal entity, select the procurement category that should be used to match the vendor invoices, which are automatically generated.","pos":[6446,6600]},{"content":"If you're the lending legal entity, for each borrowing entity, select a default project category for each transaction type.","pos":[6609,6732]},{"content":"Project categories are used for tax configuration when the invoiced category in intercompany transactions exists only in the borrowing legal entity.","pos":[6733,6881]},{"content":"You can choose to accrue revenue for intercompany transactions.","pos":[6882,6945]},{"content":"This accrual is done when the transactions are posted, and it's then reversed when the intercompany invoice is posted.","pos":[6946,7064]},{"pos":[7070,7169],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Prices<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Transfer price<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Project management and accounting** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Prices** &gt; **Transfer price**."},{"content":"Select a currency, transaction type, and transfer price model.","pos":[7174,7236]},{"content":"The currency that is used on the invoice is the currency that is configured in the customer record for the borrowing legal entity in the lending legal entity.","pos":[7237,7395]},{"content":"The currency is used to match entries in the transfer price table.","pos":[7396,7462]},{"pos":[7467,7593],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General ledger<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Posting setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Intercompany accounting<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and set up a relationship for USSI and FRSI.","source":"Click **General ledger** &gt; **Posting setup** &gt; **Intercompany accounting**, and set up a relationship for USSI and FRSI."},{"pos":[7598,7650],"content":"Example 2: Create and post an intercompany timesheet","linkify":"Example 2: Create and post an intercompany timesheet","nodes":[{"content":"Example 2: Create and post an intercompany timesheet","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"USSI, the lending legal entity, must create and post the timesheet for a project from FRSI, the borrowing legal entity.","pos":[7651,7770]},{"content":"There are two entry points for the steps that are required for this task.","pos":[7771,7844]},{"content":"Step","pos":[7848,7852]},{"content":"Entry point","pos":[7855,7866]},{"content":"Description","pos":[7939,7950]},{"content":"A","pos":[8426,8427]},{"pos":[8433,8514],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Timesheets<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>All timesheets<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>","source":"**Project management and accounting** &gt; **Timesheets** &gt; **All timesheets**"},{"content":"Create a new timesheet.","pos":[8517,8540]},{"content":"On the timesheet line, in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Legal entity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>FRSI<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[8541,8611],"source":" On the timesheet line, in the **Legal entity** field, select **FRSI**."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select the project in FRSI.","pos":[8612,8668],"source":" In the **Project ID** field, select the project in FRSI."},{"content":"Enter the hours for each day of the week.","pos":[8669,8710]},{"content":"B","pos":[8715,8716]},{"pos":[8722,8740],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Timesheet<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page","source":"**Timesheet** page"},{"content":"After the workflow runs, post the timesheet, and make a note of the voucher number.","pos":[8806,8889]},{"pos":[9006,9063],"content":"Example 3: Create and post an intercompany vendor invoice","linkify":"Example 3: Create and post an intercompany vendor invoice","nodes":[{"content":"Example 3: Create and post an intercompany vendor invoice","pos":[0,57]}]},{"content":"USSI, the lending legal entity, must create and post the intercompany vendor invoice for a project from FRSI, the borrowing legal entity.","pos":[9064,9201]},{"content":"This vendor invoice represents the outsourced labor and expense that were performed by vendors that are paid by USSI.","pos":[9202,9319]},{"content":"There are two entry points for the steps that are required for this task.","pos":[9320,9393]},{"content":"Step","pos":[9397,9401]},{"content":"Entry point","pos":[9404,9415]},{"content":"Description","pos":[9503,9514]},{"content":"A","pos":[10171,10172]},{"pos":[10178,10274],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounts payable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Open vendor invoices<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>New vendor invoice<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>","source":"**Accounts payable** &gt; **Invoices** &gt; **Open vendor invoices** &gt; **New vendor invoice**"},{"content":"Create a new vendor invoice, and enter the services that were procured on behalf of FRSI's project.","pos":[10277,10376]},{"content":"B","pos":[10558,10559]},{"pos":[10565,10592],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Vendor invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page","source":"The **Vendor invoice** page"},{"content":"Enter lines that represent the outsourced services on behalf of FRSI.","pos":[10664,10733]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Line details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Project<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab for the invoice line, in the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Project company<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> field, enter <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>FRSI<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[10734,10861],"source":" On the **Line details** FastTab, on the **Project** tab for the invoice line, in the **Project company** field, enter **FRSI**."},{"content":"Enter the project and corresponding information.","pos":[10862,10910]},{"content":"Then post the vendor invoice.","pos":[10911,10940]},{"pos":[10947,10998],"content":"Example 4: Create and post the intercompany invoice","linkify":"Example 4: Create and post the intercompany invoice","nodes":[{"content":"Example 4: Create and post the intercompany invoice","pos":[0,51]}]},{"content":"USSI, the lending legal entity, must create and post the intercompany invoice.","pos":[10999,11077]},{"content":"There are two entry points for the steps that are required for this task.","pos":[11078,11151]},{"content":"Step","pos":[11155,11159]},{"content":"Entry point","pos":[11162,11173]},{"content":"Description","pos":[11268,11279]},{"content":"A","pos":[11679,11680]},{"pos":[11686,11788],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Project invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Intercompany customer invoice<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>","source":"**Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Intercompany customer invoice**"},{"pos":[11792,11855],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Create intercompany invoice<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","source":"Click **New** to open the **Create intercompany invoice** page."},{"content":"B","pos":[11941,11942]},{"pos":[11948,12051],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Project invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Intercompany customer invoices<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>","source":"**Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Intercompany customer invoices**"},{"pos":[12054,12198],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create intercompany invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, enter the legal entity, specify the transaction that should be included, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Search<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Create intercompany invoice** page, enter the legal entity, specify the transaction that should be included, and then click **Search**."},{"content":"C","pos":[12203,12204]},{"pos":[12210,12313],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Project invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Intercompany customer invoices<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>","source":"**Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Intercompany customer invoices**"},{"pos":[12316,12443],"content":"Select the transactions to invoice, or click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select all<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to invoice all the transactions in the list, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"Select the transactions to invoice, or click **Select all** to invoice all the transactions in the list, and then click **OK**."},{"content":"D","pos":[12465,12466]},{"pos":[12472,12505],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Intercompany invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page","source":"The **Intercompany invoice** page"},{"content":"The intercompany customer invoice proposal is shown.","pos":[12578,12630]},{"content":"E","pos":[12727,12728]},{"pos":[12734,12767],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Intercompany invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page","source":"The **Intercompany invoice** page"},{"pos":[12840,12855],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Post**."},{"pos":[12991,13050],"content":"Example 5: Post the vendor invoice and invoice the customer","linkify":"Example 5: Post the vendor invoice and invoice the customer","nodes":[{"content":"Example 5: Post the vendor invoice and invoice the customer","pos":[0,59]}]},{"content":"When the lending legal entity, USSI, posts the intercompany customer invoice, a matching pending vendor invoice is created in the borrowing legal entity, FRSI.","pos":[13051,13210]},{"content":"After this vendor invoice is posted, FRSI also invoices the project customer for the hours that USSI entered.","pos":[13211,13320]},{"content":"There are three entry points for the steps that are required for this task.","pos":[13321,13396]},{"content":"Step","pos":[13400,13404]},{"content":"Entry point","pos":[13407,13418]},{"content":"Description","pos":[13508,13519]},{"content":"A","pos":[13864,13865]},{"pos":[13871,13942],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounts payable<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Pending vendor invoices<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>","source":"**Accounts payable** &gt; **Invoices** &gt; **Pending vendor invoices**"},{"content":"Review the invoice to verify that the timesheet values are included, and then post the vendor invoice.","pos":[13972,14074]},{"content":"B","pos":[14096,14097]},{"pos":[14103,14201],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Project invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Project invoice proposals<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>","source":"**Project management and accounting** &gt; **Project invoices** &gt; **Project invoice proposals**"},{"content":"Create a new project invoice for the project, and verify that the hour transactions that were posted appear.","pos":[14204,14312]},{"content":"C","pos":[14328,14329]},{"pos":[14335,14363],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Project invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page","source":"The **Project invoice** page"},{"content":"Select the project invoice, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>View details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to review the cost and sales amount.","pos":[14436,14532],"source":"Select the project invoice, and then click **View details** to review the cost and sales amount."},{"content":"Then post the invoice.","pos":[14533,14555]}]}