{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Set up centralized payments\ndescription: Follow these steps to prepare to process payments in one legal entity on behalf of other legal entities in your organization.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/09/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerInterCompany\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 62243\nms.assetid: ffd17b5f-9aea-40e0-be49-d8702f615256\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kweekley\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Set up centralized payments\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nFollow these steps to prepare to process payments in one legal entity on behalf of other legal entities in your organization. Before you begin, the following setup must be completed:\n\n-   Create legal entities.\n-   Set up General ledger parameters and charts of accounts.\n-   Set up Accounts payable parameters and Accounts receivable parameters (depending on the modules that are using centralized payments).\n-   Set up intercompany accounting.\n\n## Set up an organizational hierarchy for centralized payments\nYou must set up an organizational hierarchy for centralized payments. The same organizational hierarchy is used to process centralized vendor payments and centralized customer payments. **Note:** For centralized payments, the structure of the hierarchy doesn't matter. Any legal entity in the hierarchy will be able to process payments on behalf of any other legal entity in the hierarchy. On the **Organization hierarchies** page, you can create a new organization hierarchy. In the **Purpose** field, you must select **Centralized payments**. \n\n## Set up an intercompany account for centralized payments\nWhen payment transactions in the current legal entity are settled against invoices in other legal entities, the appropriate due-to and due-from transactions are created for each legal entity. You must specify the legal entity where any applicable cash discounts and realized gain or loss amounts are posted. Before you begin, decide which legal entity you will use to process vendor and customer payments. If one legal entity processes vendor payments but another legal entity processes customer payments, you will have to switch to each legal entity. On the **Intercompany accounting** page, you can select an intercompany relationship record for a legal entity that you will process payments on behalf of. On the **Centralized payments** tab, you can select whether to post cash discounts to the legal entity of the payment (or other transaction that decreases the balance of the vendor account) or the legal entity of the invoice (or other transaction that increases the balance of the vendor account). This selection works together with the **Cash discount administration** field on the **Accounts payable parameters** and **Accounts receivable parameters** pages. For overpayments and penny difference tolerances, the setting in the legal entity of the payment is used. For underpayments and penny difference tolerances, the setting in the legal entity of the invoice is used.\n\n## Map vendor accounts across legal entities\nIf you pay a vendor from one legal entity and want to select invoices for that vendor in other legal entities, you must make sure that all the corresponding vendor accounts in each legal entity use the same address book ID. If you receive a payment from a customer that pays invoices in more than one legal entity, you must make sure that all the corresponding customer accounts in each legal entity use the same address book ID.\n\n## Set up posting profiles for centralized payments\nWhen you create a payment in one legal entity that settles invoices in other legal entities, the posting profile IDs must be the same in both legal entities. To help guarantee that payments are created correctly, in each legal entity of the invoice, set up a posting profile that corresponds to the posting profiles that are used in the legal entity of the payment. Switch to the first legal entity of the invoice, and then, on the **Vendor posting profiles** page, you can create a new posting profile or edit an existing posting profile. The selections that you make for the posting profile in the legal entity of the invoice don't have to match the setup of the posting profile in the legal entity of the payment.\n\n## Set up methods of payment for centralized payments\nWhen you create a payment in one legal entity that settles invoices in other legal entities, the method of payment IDs must be the same in both legal entities. To help guarantee that payments are created correctly, in each legal entity of the invoice, set up a method of payment that corresponds to the methods of payment that are used in the legal entity of the payment. Switch to the first legal entity of the invoice, and then, on the **Methods of payment** page, you can create a new method of payment or edit an existing method of payment. The selections that you make for the method of payment in the legal entity of the invoice don't have to match the setup of the method of payment in the legal entity of the payment.\n\n## Set up default descriptions\nYou can define default descriptions for intercompany settlement vouchers. The default description is included on the due-to and due-from transactions during the cross-company settlement process. On the **Default descriptions** page, you can create new descriptions for both **Intercompany customer settlement** and **Intercompany vendor settlement** by selecting a language and then entering text.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,743],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Set up centralized payments\ndescription: Follow these steps to prepare to process payments in one legal entity on behalf of other legal entities in your organization.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/09/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerInterCompany\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 62243\nms.assetid: ffd17b5f-9aea-40e0-be49-d8702f615256\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kweekley\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Set up centralized payments","nodes":[{"pos":[0,27],"content":"Set up centralized payments","nodes":[{"content":"Set up centralized payments","pos":[0,27]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"Follow these steps to prepare to process payments in one legal entity on behalf of other legal entities in your organization.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,125],"content":"Follow these steps to prepare to process payments in one legal entity on behalf of other legal entities in your organization.","nodes":[{"content":"Follow these steps to prepare to process payments in one legal entity on behalf of other legal entities in your organization.","pos":[0,125]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[751,778],"content":"Set up centralized payments","linkify":"Set up centralized payments","nodes":[{"content":"Set up centralized payments","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Follow these steps to prepare to process payments in one legal entity on behalf of other legal entities in your organization.","pos":[824,949]},{"content":"Before you begin, the following setup must be completed:","pos":[950,1006]},{"content":"Create legal entities.","pos":[1012,1034]},{"content":"Set up General ledger parameters and charts of accounts.","pos":[1039,1095]},{"content":"Set up Accounts payable parameters and Accounts receivable parameters (depending on the modules that are using centralized payments).","pos":[1100,1233]},{"content":"Set up intercompany accounting.","pos":[1238,1269]},{"pos":[1274,1333],"content":"Set up an organizational hierarchy for centralized payments","linkify":"Set up an organizational hierarchy for centralized payments","nodes":[{"content":"Set up an organizational hierarchy for centralized payments","pos":[0,59]}]},{"content":"You must set up an organizational hierarchy for centralized payments.","pos":[1334,1403]},{"content":"The same organizational hierarchy is used to process centralized vendor payments and centralized customer payments.","pos":[1404,1519]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> For centralized payments, the structure of the hierarchy doesn't matter.","pos":[1520,1602],"source":"**Note:** For centralized payments, the structure of the hierarchy doesn't matter."},{"content":"Any legal entity in the hierarchy will be able to process payments on behalf of any other legal entity in the hierarchy.","pos":[1603,1723]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Organization hierarchies<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can create a new organization hierarchy.","pos":[1724,1810],"source":" On the **Organization hierarchies** page, you can create a new organization hierarchy."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Purpose<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, you must select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Centralized payments<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[1811,1878],"source":" In the **Purpose** field, you must select **Centralized payments**."},{"pos":[1884,1939],"content":"Set up an intercompany account for centralized payments","linkify":"Set up an intercompany account for centralized payments","nodes":[{"content":"Set up an intercompany account for centralized payments","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"When payment transactions in the current legal entity are settled against invoices in other legal entities, the appropriate due-to and due-from transactions are created for each legal entity.","pos":[1940,2131]},{"content":"You must specify the legal entity where any applicable cash discounts and realized gain or loss amounts are posted.","pos":[2132,2247]},{"content":"Before you begin, decide which legal entity you will use to process vendor and customer payments.","pos":[2248,2345]},{"content":"If one legal entity processes vendor payments but another legal entity processes customer payments, you will have to switch to each legal entity.","pos":[2346,2491]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Intercompany accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can select an intercompany relationship record for a legal entity that you will process payments on behalf of.","pos":[2492,2647],"source":" On the **Intercompany accounting** page, you can select an intercompany relationship record for a legal entity that you will process payments on behalf of."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Centralized payments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you can select whether to post cash discounts to the legal entity of the payment (or other transaction that decreases the balance of the vendor account) or the legal entity of the invoice (or other transaction that increases the balance of the vendor account).","pos":[2648,2945],"source":" On the **Centralized payments** tab, you can select whether to post cash discounts to the legal entity of the payment (or other transaction that decreases the balance of the vendor account) or the legal entity of the invoice (or other transaction that increases the balance of the vendor account)."},{"content":"This selection works together with the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash discount administration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Accounts payable parameters<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Accounts receivable parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> pages.","pos":[2946,3108],"source":" This selection works together with the **Cash discount administration** field on the **Accounts payable parameters** and **Accounts receivable parameters** pages."},{"content":"For overpayments and penny difference tolerances, the setting in the legal entity of the payment is used.","pos":[3109,3214]},{"content":"For underpayments and penny difference tolerances, the setting in the legal entity of the invoice is used.","pos":[3215,3321]},{"pos":[3326,3367],"content":"Map vendor accounts across legal entities","linkify":"Map vendor accounts across legal entities","nodes":[{"content":"Map vendor accounts across legal entities","pos":[0,41]}]},{"content":"If you pay a vendor from one legal entity and want to select invoices for that vendor in other legal entities, you must make sure that all the corresponding vendor accounts in each legal entity use the same address book ID.","pos":[3368,3591]},{"content":"If you receive a payment from a customer that pays invoices in more than one legal entity, you must make sure that all the corresponding customer accounts in each legal entity use the same address book ID.","pos":[3592,3797]},{"pos":[3802,3850],"content":"Set up posting profiles for centralized payments","linkify":"Set up posting profiles for centralized payments","nodes":[{"content":"Set up posting profiles for centralized payments","pos":[0,48]}]},{"content":"When you create a payment in one legal entity that settles invoices in other legal entities, the posting profile IDs must be the same in both legal entities.","pos":[3851,4008]},{"content":"To help guarantee that payments are created correctly, in each legal entity of the invoice, set up a posting profile that corresponds to the posting profiles that are used in the legal entity of the payment.","pos":[4009,4216]},{"content":"Switch to the first legal entity of the invoice, and then, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Vendor posting profiles<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can create a new posting profile or edit an existing posting profile.","pos":[4217,4390],"source":" Switch to the first legal entity of the invoice, and then, on the **Vendor posting profiles** page, you can create a new posting profile or edit an existing posting profile."},{"content":"The selections that you make for the posting profile in the legal entity of the invoice don't have to match the setup of the posting profile in the legal entity of the payment.","pos":[4391,4567]},{"pos":[4572,4622],"content":"Set up methods of payment for centralized payments","linkify":"Set up methods of payment for centralized payments","nodes":[{"content":"Set up methods of payment for centralized payments","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"When you create a payment in one legal entity that settles invoices in other legal entities, the method of payment IDs must be the same in both legal entities.","pos":[4623,4782]},{"content":"To help guarantee that payments are created correctly, in each legal entity of the invoice, set up a method of payment that corresponds to the methods of payment that are used in the legal entity of the payment.","pos":[4783,4994]},{"content":"Switch to the first legal entity of the invoice, and then, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Methods of payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can create a new method of payment or edit an existing method of payment.","pos":[4995,5167],"source":" Switch to the first legal entity of the invoice, and then, on the **Methods of payment** page, you can create a new method of payment or edit an existing method of payment."},{"content":"The selections that you make for the method of payment in the legal entity of the invoice don't have to match the setup of the method of payment in the legal entity of the payment.","pos":[5168,5348]},{"pos":[5353,5380],"content":"Set up default descriptions","linkify":"Set up default descriptions","nodes":[{"content":"Set up default descriptions","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"You can define default descriptions for intercompany settlement vouchers.","pos":[5381,5454]},{"content":"The default description is included on the due-to and due-from transactions during the cross-company settlement process.","pos":[5455,5575]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Default descriptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can create new descriptions for both <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Intercompany customer settlement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Intercompany vendor settlement<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> by selecting a language and then entering text.","pos":[5576,5778],"source":" On the **Default descriptions** page, you can create new descriptions for both **Intercompany customer settlement** and **Intercompany vendor settlement** by selecting a language and then entering text."}]}