{"content":"--- \n# required metadata \n \ntitle: Create a request for quotation\ndescription: This procedure shows you how to create a request for quotation. \nauthor: mkirknel\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 11/02/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mkirknel\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 \n---\n# Create a request for quotation\n\n[!include[task guide banner](../../includes/task-guide-banner.md)]\n\nThis procedure shows you how to create a request for quotation. This would typically be done by a purchasing agent. You can use this procedure in demo data company USMF or on your own data. You need to have set up solicitation types before you start. Once you’ve completed this task and you’ve created and sent an RFQ you can then enter the replies per vendor, compare them, and award the contract.\n\n\n## Prepare a new RFQ\n1. Go to Procurement and sourcing > Requests for quotations > All requests for quotations.\n2. Click New.\n    * The following purchase types are available: Purchase order (this is the default): a document that confirms the offer to buy products, or the acceptance of an offer to sell products in exchange for payment. Purchase requisition: this type is automatically selected if you create an RFQ directly from a purchase requisition. If you manually select this option, you’ll get an error. Purchase agreement: an agreement to purchase a specific quantity or value of product over time. If you select this option, you must select the date range that applies to the purchase agreement.  \n3. In the Document title field, type a value.\n4. In the Solicitation type field, enter or select a value.\n    * If a scoring method is associated with the solicitation type, this will be the default scoring method for the RFQ that you’re creating. It is possible to change the scoring method later.  \n    * In the Delivery date field, enter a date.  \n    * Select the date by which you want to receive the items.  \n    * In the Expiration date and time field, enter a date and time.  \n    * Specify the date and time by which vendors must respond to the RFQ.  \n5. In the Warehouse field, enter or select a value.\n    * The delivery address will default to the warehouse address.  \n6. Click OK.\n\n## Add lines\n    * After you’ve specified the basic information about your RFQ, you specify the goods or services that you want vendors to bid on. Item is the default line type.   \n1. In the Item number field, enter or select a value.\n    * If you're using USMF, you can select T0020.  \n2. In the Quantity field, enter a number.\n3. Click Add line.\n4. In the Line type field, select 'Category'.\n    * You can use the Category line type to create RFQs for non-inventory goods or services. You then need to select the type of goods or services from a hierarchy of procurement categories.  \n5. In the Procurement category field, enter or select a value.\n6. In the Product name field, type a value.\n7. In the Quantity field, enter a number.\n8. In the Unit field, enter or select a value.\n\n## Add vendors\n1. Click Header to change from the Lines view to the Header view. \n2. Expand the Vendor section.\n3. Click Auto-add vendors.\n    * You can add vendors to the RFQ automatically, based on the procurement category of the items requested. If there are no vendors approved for the categories included in the lines you can add vendors manually.  \n4. Click Add.\n5. In the Vendor account field, enter or select a value.\n6. Click Add.\n7. In the Vendor account field, enter or select a value.\n    * Once you’ve selected a vendor, the status is Created. This means that the vendor information has been saved in the RFQ, but you have not sent the RFQ to the vendor. You can add a vendor to an RFQ regardless of the vendor status.  \n\n## Send the RFQ to vendors\n1. Click Send.\n    * In the Sending request for quotation page, check that the vendors in the list are the ones that you want to receive the RFQ.  \n2. Click Print.\n    * This dialog allows you to print the RFQ. If you choose to print a reply sheet, the contents of this are defined in Procurement and Sourcing parameters. To choose how to print reply sheets, once you’ve opened the Print dialog, click Advanced printing options. One RFQ will be printed for each vendor containing the lines that have the status of Created or Sent. Canceled lines and lines with registered replies will not be printed.   \n3. Click Cancel.\n4. Click OK.\n5. Close the page.\n6. Close the page.\n\n## View the RFQ journal\n1. Go to Procurement and sourcing > Requests for quotations > Request for quotations follow-up > Request for quotation journals.\n2. Click Preview/Print.\n3. Click Original preview.\n4. Close the page.\n5. Close the page.\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[5,601],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata \n \ntitle: Create a request for quotation\ndescription: This procedure shows you how to create a request for quotation. \nauthor: mkirknel\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 11/02/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mkirknel\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 ","nodes":[{"content":"Create a request for quotation","nodes":[{"pos":[0,30],"content":"Create a request for quotation","nodes":[{"content":"Create a request for quotation","pos":[0,30]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This procedure shows you how to create a request for quotation.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,63],"content":"This procedure shows you how to create a request for quotation.","nodes":[{"content":"This procedure shows you how to create a request for quotation.","pos":[0,63]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata \n","yml":true},{"pos":[608,638],"content":"Create a request for quotation","linkify":"Create a request for quotation","nodes":[{"content":"Create a request for quotation","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"This procedure shows you how to create a request for quotation.","pos":[708,771]},{"content":"This would typically be done by a purchasing agent.","pos":[772,823]},{"content":"You can use this procedure in demo data company USMF or on your own data.","pos":[824,897]},{"content":"You need to have set up solicitation types before you start.","pos":[898,958]},{"content":"Once you’ve completed this task and you’ve created and sent an RFQ you can then enter the replies per vendor, compare them, and award the contract.","pos":[959,1106]},{"pos":[1112,1129],"content":"Prepare a new RFQ","linkify":"Prepare a new RFQ","nodes":[{"content":"Prepare a new RFQ","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Go to Procurement and sourcing &gt; Requests for quotations &gt; All requests for quotations.","pos":[1133,1220],"source":"Go to Procurement and sourcing > Requests for quotations > All requests for quotations."},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[1224,1234]},{"content":"The following purchase types are available: Purchase order (this is the default): a document that confirms the offer to buy products, or the acceptance of an offer to sell products in exchange for payment.","pos":[1241,1446]},{"content":"Purchase requisition: this type is automatically selected if you create an RFQ directly from a purchase requisition.","pos":[1447,1563]},{"content":"If you manually select this option, you’ll get an error.","pos":[1564,1620]},{"content":"Purchase agreement: an agreement to purchase a specific quantity or value of product over time.","pos":[1621,1716]},{"content":"If you select this option, you must select the date range that applies to the purchase agreement.","pos":[1717,1814]},{"content":"In the Document title field, type a value.","pos":[1820,1862]},{"content":"In the Solicitation type field, enter or select a value.","pos":[1866,1922]},{"content":"If a scoring method is associated with the solicitation type, this will be the default scoring method for the RFQ that you’re creating.","pos":[1929,2064]},{"content":"It is possible to change the scoring method later.","pos":[2065,2115]},{"content":"In the Delivery date field, enter a date.","pos":[2124,2165]},{"content":"Select the date by which you want to receive the items.","pos":[2174,2229]},{"content":"In the Expiration date and time field, enter a date and time.","pos":[2238,2299]},{"content":"Specify the date and time by which vendors must respond to the RFQ.","pos":[2308,2375]},{"content":"In the Warehouse field, enter or select a value.","pos":[2381,2429]},{"content":"The delivery address will default to the warehouse address.","pos":[2436,2495]},{"content":"Click OK.","pos":[2501,2510]},{"pos":[2515,2524],"content":"Add lines","linkify":"Add lines","nodes":[{"content":"Add lines","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"After you’ve specified the basic information about your RFQ, you specify the goods or services that you want vendors to bid on.","pos":[2531,2658]},{"content":"Item is the default line type.","pos":[2659,2689]},{"content":"In the Item number field, enter or select a value.","pos":[2696,2746]},{"content":"If you're using USMF, you can select T0020.","pos":[2753,2796]},{"content":"In the Quantity field, enter a number.","pos":[2802,2840]},{"content":"Click Add line.","pos":[2844,2859]},{"content":"In the Line type field, select 'Category'.","pos":[2863,2905]},{"content":"You can use the Category line type to create RFQs for non-inventory goods or services.","pos":[2912,2998]},{"content":"You then need to select the type of goods or services from a hierarchy of procurement categories.","pos":[2999,3096]},{"content":"In the Procurement category field, enter or select a value.","pos":[3102,3161]},{"content":"In the Product name field, type a value.","pos":[3165,3205]},{"content":"In the Quantity field, enter a number.","pos":[3209,3247]},{"content":"In the Unit field, enter or select a value.","pos":[3251,3294]},{"pos":[3299,3310],"content":"Add vendors","linkify":"Add vendors","nodes":[{"content":"Add vendors","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"Click Header to change from the Lines view to the Header view.","pos":[3314,3376]},{"content":"Expand the Vendor section.","pos":[3381,3407]},{"content":"Click Auto-add vendors.","pos":[3411,3434]},{"content":"You can add vendors to the RFQ automatically, based on the procurement category of the items requested.","pos":[3441,3544]},{"content":"If there are no vendors approved for the categories included in the lines you can add vendors manually.","pos":[3545,3648]},{"content":"Click Add.","pos":[3654,3664]},{"content":"In the Vendor account field, enter or select a value.","pos":[3668,3721]},{"content":"Click Add.","pos":[3725,3735]},{"content":"In the Vendor account field, enter or select a value.","pos":[3739,3792]},{"content":"Once you’ve selected a vendor, the status is Created.","pos":[3799,3852]},{"content":"This means that the vendor information has been saved in the RFQ, but you have not sent the RFQ to the vendor.","pos":[3853,3963]},{"content":"You can add a vendor to an RFQ regardless of the vendor status.","pos":[3964,4027]},{"pos":[4034,4057],"content":"Send the RFQ to vendors","linkify":"Send the RFQ to vendors","nodes":[{"content":"Send the RFQ to vendors","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"Click Send.","pos":[4061,4072]},{"content":"In the Sending request for quotation page, check that the vendors in the list are the ones that you want to receive the RFQ.","pos":[4079,4203]},{"content":"Click Print.","pos":[4209,4221]},{"content":"This dialog allows you to print the RFQ.","pos":[4228,4268]},{"content":"If you choose to print a reply sheet, the contents of this are defined in Procurement and Sourcing parameters.","pos":[4269,4379]},{"content":"To choose how to print reply sheets, once you’ve opened the Print dialog, click Advanced printing options.","pos":[4380,4486]},{"content":"One RFQ will be printed for each vendor containing the lines that have the status of Created or Sent.","pos":[4487,4588]},{"content":"Canceled lines and lines with registered replies will not be printed.","pos":[4589,4658]},{"content":"Click Cancel.","pos":[4665,4678]},{"content":"Click OK.","pos":[4682,4691]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4695,4710]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4714,4729]},{"pos":[4734,4754],"content":"View the RFQ journal","linkify":"View the RFQ journal","nodes":[{"content":"View the RFQ journal","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Go to Procurement and sourcing &gt; Requests for quotations &gt; Request for quotations follow-up &gt; Request for quotation journals.","pos":[4758,4883],"source":"Go to Procurement and sourcing > Requests for quotations > Request for quotations follow-up > Request for quotation journals."},{"content":"Click Preview/Print.","pos":[4887,4907]},{"content":"Click Original preview.","pos":[4911,4934]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4938,4953]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4957,4972]}]}