{"content":"--- \n# required metadata \n \ntitle: Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away\ndescription: This procedure shows you how to set up a simple location directive. \nauthor: BibiSp\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 11/14/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Distribution\nms.author: bibis\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 \n---\n# Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away\n\n[!include[task guide banner](../../includes/task-guide-banner.md)]\n\nThis procedure shows you how to set up a simple location directive. The example that’s shown creates a location directive to be used to determine where to put items that have been received for a purchase order. You can play this task guide with the data mentioned using demo data company USMF. Pre-conditions: You need to create a disposition code. In this procedure we use a disposition code called Relabel. If you’re creating a location directive in your own data, you need to have set up advanced warehouse management for your warehouse and items.  This procedure is intended for the warehouse manager.\n\n1. Go to Warehouse management > Setup > Location directives.\n2. In the Work order type field, select 'Purchase orders'.\n\n## Create a location directive header\n1. Click New.\n2. In the Sequence number field, enter a number.\n    * This is the sequence in which the location directive is processed for the selected work type. You can also modify the sequence, if needed.  \n3. In the Name field, type a value.\n    * This is the unique identifier for this directive.  \n4. In the Work type field, select 'Put'.\n    * Select the type of work to be performed. For directive with work order type Purchase order, Put is the only supported value.  \n5. In the Site field, type a value.\n6. In the Warehouse field, type a value.\n    * Leave the Directive code blank.  Directive codes are used to link a work order line of type Put to a specific directive. For purchase orders, the location of the last work order line of type Put is resolved before the work template is determined. Therefore it is not possible to connect the last line of a work template to a specific directive.   \n7. In the Disposition code field, type a value.\n    * The Disposition code limits the use of the location directive, so the location directive is only used if the warehouse worker enters this specific value during registration of the item using a mobile device.  \n8. Click Save.\n\n## Edit the query for directive\n1. Click Edit query.\n    * The use of this directive is already limited to be used for items registered in the warehouse that you specified, and with the disposition code that you specified. You can add other constraints using the query.  \n2. Click OK.\n\n## Add directive lines\n1. Click New.\n    * This is the sequence in which the location directive lines are processed for the selected work type. You can also modify the sequence, if needed.  \n2. In the From quantity field, enter a number.\n    * This is the lowest quantity that this directive line is valid for.  \n3. In the To quantity field, enter a number.\n4. In the Unit field, type a value.\n    * The unit the From quantity and To quantity is expressed in. If you leave this field blank the inventory unit from the item is used.  \n5. In the Locate quantity field, select an option.\n    * None, or licence plate quantity: The quantity registered on each licence plate. Unitized quantity: The entire quantity that’s been registered. Remaining quantity: The quantity that is yet to be registered from the purchase order line. Expected quantity: The total quantity that is specified on the purchase order line.  \n6. Check or uncheck the Restrict by unit checkbox.\n    * If you select this option, and specify the unit on the Restrict by unit page, only items with that unit of measurement can be put into the location. For example, if the unit of measurement is PL (pallets), only items in pallets can be put into the specified location.  \n7. Check or uncheck the Allow split checkbox.\n    * This allows the directive to split the quantity across multiple locations.  \n8. Click Save.\n\n## Restrict the directive line to a specific unit\n1. Click Restrict by unit.\n    * This button is only available when you press Save after you have selected the Restrict by unit check box.  \n2. In the Unit field, type a value.\n3. Close the page.\n\n## Add a location directive action line\n1. Click New.\n    * This is the sequence in which the location directive action lines are processed for the selected work type. You can also modify the sequence, if needed.  \n2. In the Name field, type a value.\n    * This is the unique identifier for this directive action.  \n3. In the Fixed location usage field, select an option.\n    * Fixed and non-fixed locations: All non-fixed locations are valid as well as the product’s own fixed location, within the range specified in the query.  Only fixed location for the product: Fixed locations for the product are valid, and all product variants share the same set of fixed locations. Only fixed location for the product variants: Only fixed locations specified for each product variant are valid.  \n4. In the Strategy field, select an option.\n    * Work orders of type Purchase order support the following strategies: None: the item is placed at the first location that’s found. Consolidate: The item is placed in a location where similar items are already available. Empty location with no incoming work: the item is placed in the first empty location that’s found. A location is considered to be empty if it has no physical inventory and no expected incoming work.  \n5. Click Save.\n\n## Edit the query for directive action line\n1. Click Edit query.\n2. Click Add.\n3. In the Field field, type 'location profile ID'.\n    * In this example, we’ll restrict the possible locations using a location profile ID.  \n4. In the Criteria field, type a value.\n5. Click OK.\n    * You can continue to add directive lines and directive actions until you have covered all the possible scenarios in your warehouse.  \n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[5,635],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata \n \ntitle: Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away\ndescription: This procedure shows you how to set up a simple location directive. \nauthor: BibiSp\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 11/14/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: bibis\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Distribution\nms.author: bibis\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 ","nodes":[{"content":"Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away","nodes":[{"pos":[0,55],"content":"Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away","nodes":[{"content":"Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away","pos":[0,55]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This procedure shows you how to set up a simple location directive.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,67],"content":"This procedure shows you how to set up a simple location directive.","nodes":[{"content":"This procedure shows you how to set up a simple location directive.","pos":[0,67]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata \n","yml":true},{"pos":[642,697],"content":"Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away","linkify":"Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away","nodes":[{"content":"Set up a location directive for purchase order put-away","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"This procedure shows you how to set up a simple location directive.","pos":[767,834]},{"content":"The example that’s shown creates a location directive to be used to determine where to put items that have been received for a purchase order.","pos":[835,977]},{"content":"You can play this task guide with the data mentioned using demo data company USMF.","pos":[978,1060]},{"content":"Pre-conditions: You need to create a disposition code.","pos":[1061,1115]},{"content":"In this procedure we use a disposition code called Relabel.","pos":[1116,1175]},{"content":"If you’re creating a location directive in your own data, you need to have set up advanced warehouse management for your warehouse and items.","pos":[1176,1317]},{"content":"This procedure is intended for the warehouse manager.","pos":[1319,1372]},{"content":"Go to Warehouse management &gt; Setup &gt; Location directives.","pos":[1377,1434],"source":"Go to Warehouse management > Setup > Location directives."},{"content":"In the Work order type field, select 'Purchase orders'.","pos":[1438,1493]},{"pos":[1498,1532],"content":"Create a location directive header","linkify":"Create a location directive header","nodes":[{"content":"Create a location directive header","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[1536,1546]},{"content":"In the Sequence number field, enter a number.","pos":[1550,1595]},{"content":"This is the sequence in which the location directive is processed for the selected work type.","pos":[1602,1695]},{"content":"You can also modify the sequence, if needed.","pos":[1696,1740]},{"content":"In the Name field, type a value.","pos":[1746,1778]},{"content":"This is the unique identifier for this directive.","pos":[1785,1834]},{"content":"In the Work type field, select 'Put'.","pos":[1840,1877]},{"content":"Select the type of work to be performed.","pos":[1884,1924]},{"content":"For directive with work order type Purchase order, Put is the only supported value.","pos":[1925,2008]},{"content":"In the Site field, type a value.","pos":[2014,2046]},{"content":"In the Warehouse field, type a value.","pos":[2050,2087]},{"content":"Leave the Directive code blank.","pos":[2094,2125]},{"content":"Directive codes are used to link a work order line of type Put to a specific directive.","pos":[2127,2214]},{"content":"For purchase orders, the location of the last work order line of type Put is resolved before the work template is determined.","pos":[2215,2340]},{"content":"Therefore it is not possible to connect the last line of a work template to a specific directive.","pos":[2341,2438]},{"content":"In the Disposition code field, type a value.","pos":[2445,2489]},{"content":"The Disposition code limits the use of the location directive, so the location directive is only used if the warehouse worker enters this specific value during registration of the item using a mobile device.","pos":[2496,2703]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[2709,2720]},{"pos":[2725,2753],"content":"Edit the query for directive","linkify":"Edit the query for directive","nodes":[{"content":"Edit the query for directive","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"Click Edit query.","pos":[2757,2774]},{"content":"The use of this directive is already limited to be used for items registered in the warehouse that you specified, and with the disposition code that you specified.","pos":[2781,2944]},{"content":"You can add other constraints using the query.","pos":[2945,2991]},{"content":"Click OK.","pos":[2997,3006]},{"pos":[3011,3030],"content":"Add directive lines","linkify":"Add directive lines","nodes":[{"content":"Add directive lines","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[3034,3044]},{"content":"This is the sequence in which the location directive lines are processed for the selected work type.","pos":[3051,3151]},{"content":"You can also modify the sequence, if needed.","pos":[3152,3196]},{"content":"In the From quantity field, enter a number.","pos":[3202,3245]},{"content":"This is the lowest quantity that this directive line is valid for.","pos":[3252,3318]},{"content":"In the To quantity field, enter a number.","pos":[3324,3365]},{"content":"In the Unit field, type a value.","pos":[3369,3401]},{"content":"The unit the From quantity and To quantity is expressed in.","pos":[3408,3467]},{"content":"If you leave this field blank the inventory unit from the item is used.","pos":[3468,3539]},{"content":"In the Locate quantity field, select an option.","pos":[3545,3592]},{"content":"None, or licence plate quantity: The quantity registered on each licence plate.","pos":[3599,3678]},{"content":"Unitized quantity: The entire quantity that’s been registered.","pos":[3679,3741]},{"content":"Remaining quantity: The quantity that is yet to be registered from the purchase order line.","pos":[3742,3833]},{"content":"Expected quantity: The total quantity that is specified on the purchase order line.","pos":[3834,3917]},{"content":"Check or uncheck the Restrict by unit checkbox.","pos":[3923,3970]},{"content":"If you select this option, and specify the unit on the Restrict by unit page, only items with that unit of measurement can be put into the location.","pos":[3977,4125]},{"content":"For example, if the unit of measurement is PL (pallets), only items in pallets can be put into the specified location.","pos":[4126,4244]},{"content":"Check or uncheck the Allow split checkbox.","pos":[4250,4292]},{"content":"This allows the directive to split the quantity across multiple locations.","pos":[4299,4373]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[4379,4390]},{"pos":[4395,4441],"content":"Restrict the directive line to a specific unit","linkify":"Restrict the directive line to a specific unit","nodes":[{"content":"Restrict the directive line to a specific unit","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"Click Restrict by unit.","pos":[4445,4468]},{"content":"This button is only available when you press Save after you have selected the Restrict by unit check box.","pos":[4475,4580]},{"content":"In the Unit field, type a value.","pos":[4586,4618]},{"content":"Close the page.","pos":[4622,4637]},{"pos":[4642,4678],"content":"Add a location directive action line","linkify":"Add a location directive action line","nodes":[{"content":"Add a location directive action line","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[4682,4692]},{"content":"This is the sequence in which the location directive action lines are processed for the selected work type.","pos":[4699,4806]},{"content":"You can also modify the sequence, if needed.","pos":[4807,4851]},{"content":"In the Name field, type a value.","pos":[4857,4889]},{"content":"This is the unique identifier for this directive action.","pos":[4896,4952]},{"content":"In the Fixed location usage field, select an option.","pos":[4958,5010]},{"content":"Fixed and non-fixed locations: All non-fixed locations are valid as well as the product’s own fixed location, within the range specified in the query.","pos":[5017,5167]},{"content":"Only fixed location for the product: Fixed locations for the product are valid, and all product variants share the same set of fixed locations.","pos":[5169,5312]},{"content":"Only fixed location for the product variants: Only fixed locations specified for each product variant are valid.","pos":[5313,5425]},{"content":"In the Strategy field, select an option.","pos":[5431,5471]},{"content":"Work orders of type Purchase order support the following strategies: None: the item is placed at the first location that’s found.","pos":[5478,5607]},{"content":"Consolidate: The item is placed in a location where similar items are already available.","pos":[5608,5696]},{"content":"Empty location with no incoming work: the item is placed in the first empty location that’s found.","pos":[5697,5795]},{"content":"A location is considered to be empty if it has no physical inventory and no expected incoming work.","pos":[5796,5895]},{"content":"Click Save.","pos":[5901,5912]},{"pos":[5917,5957],"content":"Edit the query for directive action line","linkify":"Edit the query for directive action line","nodes":[{"content":"Edit the query for directive action line","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"Click Edit query.","pos":[5961,5978]},{"content":"Click Add.","pos":[5982,5992]},{"content":"In the Field field, type 'location profile ID'.","pos":[5996,6043]},{"content":"In this example, we’ll restrict the possible locations using a location profile ID.","pos":[6050,6133]},{"content":"In the Criteria field, type a value.","pos":[6139,6175]},{"content":"Click OK.","pos":[6179,6188]},{"content":"You can continue to add directive lines and directive actions until you have covered all the possible scenarios in your warehouse.","pos":[6195,6325]}]}