{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Create exchange rate providers\ndescription: This article describes how to set up an exchange rate provider. \nauthor: RobinARH\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 72153\nms.assetid: 24643037-f7a5-4acf-b3d6-9943642b618c\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: jbye\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Create exchange rate providers\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article describes how to set up an exchange rate provider. \n\nThis article describes the steps that are required in order to set up an exchange rate provider. For the purpose of illustration, the OANDA exchange rate service is used throughout this article. By following the steps that are described in this article, you will create a functional exchange rate provider. The code is production code. You can find the source in the **ExchangeRateProviderOanda** class. You can reference this class as you read through this article. To request an OANDA test account and receive information about the OANDA exchange rate service, go to <http://developer.oanda.com/exchange-rates-api/>.\n\n## Terminology\n-   **Import currency exchange rates** – The process that retrieves exchange rates from exchange rate providers and imports them. This process is a system operation that supports batch processing.\n-   **Exchange rate provider** – An X++ class that is responsible for retrieving exchange rates from external sources.\n-   **Exchange rate provider registration** – The process of enabling an exchange rate provider so that it can be used. By default, exchange rate providers aren't registered when they are deployed.\n-   **Exchange rate provider configuration** – The configuration settings of an exchange rate provider that determine how it will be used.\n-   **Exchange rate service** – A free or paid subscription service that provides a list of exchange rates that have been published. Foreign Exchange Rates Powered by OANDA is an example of a service that provides exchange rates.\n-   **The framework** – The import currency exchange rates framework that coordinates the retrieval of exchange rates from providers and appropriate storage of the exchange rates.\n\n## Conceptual/class model\nThe following illustration shows the main interfaces and classes that make up the exchange rate provider framework, and the relationships among them. New exchange rate providers should be derived from the **IExchangeRateProvider** interface. Exchange rate providers are written in X++. Because X++ is a .NET language, it's easy to use the Microsoft .NET Framework in our provider. [![Conceptual/class model of the exchange rate provider framework](./media/exchangerates.png)](./media/exchangerates.png) Here are the interfaces and classes that are shown in the illustration:\n\n-   **IExchangeRateProvider** – By implementing this interface, you enable the exchange rate provider framework to recognize a class as an exchange rate provider.\n-   **IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory** – This interface enables the exchange rate provider to construct various types of provider framework classes that represent some of the interfaces in the illustration.\n-   **IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions** – The exchange rate provider supports several options when rates are imported. The exchange rate provider uses this interface to inform the framework about the options that it supports.\n-   **IExchangeRateProviderConfig** – Each exchange rate provider can have a unique configuration. This interface enables the provider to retrieve this configuration.\n-   **IExchangeRateProviderConfigDefaults** – The exchange rate provider can create and provide default values for its configuration. The user can change these values on the **Configure exchange rate providers** page (**General ledger** &gt; **Currencies **&gt; **Configure exchange rate providers**).\n-   **IExchangeRateRequest** – This interface represents data that is specific to a request to import exchange rates. This data includes the date range, options, and the currency pairs to retrieve rates for.\n-   **IExchangeRateCalendar** – This interface represents an exchange rate calendar that is used to retrieve the next working day (Monday through Friday).\n-   **IExchangeRateResponse** – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store the currency pairs and the exchange rates that are returned from the service.\n-   **IExchangeRateResponseCurrencyPair** – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store the details for a specific currency pair that is returned from the service.\n-   **IExchangeRateResponseExchangeRate** – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store a specific exchange rate for a specific currency pair.\n-   **ExchangeRateProviderOanda** – This example of an exchange rate provider that is implemented by Microsoft connects to the OANDA service to return exchange rates.\n\n## Writing an exchange rate provider\nCode examples are taken from the **ExchangeRateProviderOanda** class. Follow these steps to create an exchange rate provider.\n\n1.  In the **Currency** model, create a class that implements the **IExchangeRateProvider** interface.\n\n        using Microsoft.Dynamics.ApplicationSuite.FinancialManagement.Currency.Framework;\n        using Microsoft.Dynamics.Currency.Instrumentation;\n        using System.Collections;\n        /// <summary>\n        /// The <c>ExchangeRateProviderOanda</c> class is an exchange rate provider for OANDA.\n        /// </summary>\n        class ExchangeRateProviderOanda implements IExchangeRateProvider\n        {\n        }\n\n2.  Add the following constants and variable declarations to the class.\n\n        private const ExchangeRateProviderPropertyKey ServiceURL = 'https://www.oanda.com/rates/api/v1/rates/%1.xml?quote=%2&start=%3&end=%4&fields=%5&decimal_places=%6';\n        private const ExchangeRateProviderId ProviderId = '795500B1-4258-4343-868C-433CE390848C';\n        private const str OANDADateFormat = 'yyyy-MM-dd';\n        private const str HttpWebRequestMethod = 'GET';\n        private const str HttpWebRequestContentType = 'application/xml';\n        private const str HttpHeaderAuthorization = 'Authorization';\n        private const str KeyTokenPrefix = 'Bearer ';\n        private const str XPathQuote = '//response/quotes/quote';\n        private const str XPathAverageBid = '//bid';\n        private const str XPathAverageAsk = '//ask';\n        private const str XPathLowBid = '//low_bid';\n        private const str XPathLowAsk = '//low_ask';\n        private const str XPathMidpoint = '//midpoint';\n        private const str XPathDate = '//quote/date';\n        private const str XPathHighBid = '//high_bid';\n        private const str XPathHighAsk = '//high_ask';\n        private const str QuoteParameterAverages = 'averages';\n        private const str QuoteParameterLows = 'lows';\n        private const str QuoteParameterMidPoint = 'midpoint';\n        private const str QuoteParameterHighs = 'highs';\n        IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory factory;\n\n3.  Implement the **get\\_Name** method. A label should be used to enable proper translation. A user can change the name that is provided here when that user sets up the provider’s configuration information.\n\n        public ExchangeRateProviderName get_Name()\n        {\n            return \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_OandaName\";\n        }\n\n4.  Implement the **get\\_Id** method. This method returns a globally unique identifier (GUID) that is used to uniquely identify this provider.\n\n        public ExchangeRateProviderId get_Id()\n        {\n            return ProviderId;\n        }\n\n5.  Implement the **set\\_Factory** method. The exchange rate provider framework will invoke this method to set an object that implements the **IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory** interface on your provider. This factory can be used to instantiate new objects that represent some of the interfaces from the previous illustration.\n\n        public void set_Factory(IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory _factory)\n        {\n            factory = _factory;\n        }\n\n6.  Implement the **GetSupportedOptions** method. This method indicates whether the exchange rate provider supports some framework features:\n\n    -   Set the **doesSupportSpecificCurrencyPairs** property to **true** only if the exchange rate service requires that a source and destination currency be passed to get an exchange rate. Many exchange rate services return rates for a fixed currency or a given set of currency pairs. For these services, the value of this option should be set to **false**. If prices that a service charges are based on quotas on the number of rates, a value of **true** will cause the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface to contain only those currency pairs that are configured for an exchange rate type on the **Exchange rate** page (**General ledger** &gt; **Currencies** &gt; **Exchange rates**). The provider can then specifically request these rates from the service and therefore lower the cost.\n    -   Set the **fixedBaseIsoCurrency** property to the three-character International Organization for Standardization (ISO) currency code that represents the fixed base currency of the exchange rates that are returned from the exchange rate service. If the exchange rate service doesn't support a fixed base currency, return an empty string. For example, the euro is often used as a fixed base currency. When you create a new provider, be sure to research the exchange rate service so that you can select the correct value.\n    -   Set the **singleRateForDateRange** property to **true** if the service can return a single rate that represents the whole date range. For example, you can use this setting to return a single exchange rate that represents the average exchange rate for a month. If the service doesn’t support this functionality, set this property to **false**.\n\n    <!-- -->\n\n        public IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions GetSupportedOptions()\n        {\n            IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions options = factory.CreateExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions();\n            options.set_doesSupportSpecificCurrencyPairs(true);\n            options.set_doesSupportSpecificDates(false);\n            options.set_fixedBaseIsoCurrency('');\n            options.set_singleRateForDateRange(true);\n        return options;\n\n7.  Implement the **GetConfigurationDefaults** method. Configuration defaults are name-value pairs that represent the default configuration settings for the exchange rate provider. These settings are automatically loaded when the provider is registered, but the user can change them. Take the required precautions when you convert these strings into usable values. The value field is stored as an encrypted field in SQL. Therefore, sensitive data such as an application programming interface (API) key will be more secure.\n\n        public IExchangeRateProviderConfigDefaults GetConfigurationDefaults()\n        {\n            IExchangeRateProviderConfigDefaults configurationDefaults = factory.CreateExchangeRateProviderConfigDefaults();\n            configurationDefaults.addNameValueConfigurationPair(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_ServiceTimeout\", '5000');\n            configurationDefaults.addNameValueConfigurationPair(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_OandaAPIKey\", '');\n            configurationDefaults.addNameValueConfigurationPair(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_DecimalPlaces\", '5');\n            configurationDefaults.addNameValueConfigurationPair(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_QuoteType\", '1');\n            return configurationDefaults;\n        }\n\n8.  Implement the **ValidateConfigurationDetail** method. This method enables the exchange rate provider to validate the configuration information that the user modified on the **Configure exchange rate providers** page.\n\n        public boolean ValidateConfigurationDetail(ExchangeRateProviderPropertyKey _key, ExchangeRateProviderPropertyValue _value)\n        {\n            boolean result = true;\n            switch (_key)\n            {\n                case \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_DecimalPlaces\":\n                    int decimals = str2Int(_value);\n                    if ((decimals > 12) || (decimals < 1))\n                    {\n                        CurrencyEventSource eventSource = CurrencyEventSource::Log;\n                        eventSource.ImportExchangeRateMark(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigMessage_DecimalPlacesInvalid\");\n                        error(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigMessage_DecimalPlacesInvalid\");\n                        result = false;\n                    }\n                    break;\n                case \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_OandaAPIKey\":\n                    if (_value == '')\n                    {\n                        CurrencyEventSource eventSource = CurrencyEventSource::Log;\n                        eventSource.ImportExchangeRateMark(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigMessage_OANDAKeyRequired\");\n                        warning(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigMessage_OANDAKeyRequired\");\n                    }\n                    break;\n            }\n            return result;\n        }\n\n9.  Implement the **EnumNameForLookup** method. This method enables the exchange rate provider to enable a lookup for a specific **ExchangeRateProviderPropertyKey** key. Just return the name of an existing enumerated type for the appropriate key. If this feature isn't required, return an empty string.\n\n        public str EnumNameForLookup(ExchangeRateProviderPropertyKey _key)\n        {\n            if (_key == \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_QuoteType\")\n            {\n                return enumStr(ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType);\n            }\n            return '';\n        }\n\n10. Implement the **GetExchangeRates** method. This method uses the configuration information and the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface that is provided to call out to the exchange rate service and return the appropriate instance of the **IExchangeRateResponse** class. When you write this method, consider these important points:\n\n    -   Any configuration information that is required should be retrieved from the **IExchangeRateProviderConfig** interface. A call to the **GetPropertyValue** method on that interface will provide the string representation of the property value for the property key that is provided. Take the required precautions when you convert this string value to another type.\n    -   Do any required validation up front. For example, OANDA requires that an API key be supplied on every service call. If this API key isn't set, the service will fail. Verify that the API key isn't set, and exit early to receive an appropriate error message.\n    -   Some providers require explicit currency pairs when exchange rates are requested. These providers are the same providers that set the **IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions.doesSupportSpecificCurrencyPairs** property to **true**. In this case, you must use the currency pairs that the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface provides to drive the retrieval process. The OANDA provider implementation that follows shows a good example of this type of provider. Typically, providers that don't support specific currency pairs return data for a fixed set of currency pairs. In this case, the currency pairs that the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface provides can be ignored. Providers should return all the rates that are available, and the framework will then import the correct rates, based on the user’s decision about whether to automatically create the required currency pairs. The CentralBankOfEuropeProvider provider is a good example of this type of provider.\n    -   The **IExchangeRateRequest** interface has a property that is named **ImportDateType**. This property indicates the dates that should be used to retrieve exchange rates from the service. The two values that are available are **CurrentDate** and **DateRange**.\n        -   **CurrentDate** retrieves the most current exchange rate from the exchange rate service. When this value is passed to the provider, the framework also sets **IExchangeRateRequest.FromDate** and **IExchangeRateRequest.ToDate** to the system date of the Application Object Server (AOS) computer that is making the request. If exchange rate services support the retrieval of exchange rates for specific dates, the date that the framework provides should be passed. However, if the exchange rate service instead provides a call to get the most current exchange rate (regardless of the date), the date that is returned must be validated to make sure that it's less than or equal to the requested date.\n        -   **DateRange** retrieves the exchange rates for a specific date range. Only exchange rates in the specified date range should be allowed. If an exchange rate service requires that specific dates be included in the request, this process is straightforward. However, if an exchange rate service instead returns a group of historical dates that might be outside the valid range of dates, the provider must filter out the dates that aren't relevant before it passes the dates back to the framework.\n    -   When exchange rates are returned, always use the date that the exchange rate service provides instead of the dates that the instance of the **IExchangeRateRequest** class supplies. In this manner, you help guarantee that the exchange rate that is returned is associated with the correct date, because an exchange rate service might occasionally return rates for dates that weren't expected. For example, if an exchange rate is requested for a date in the future, some providers return the most recent exchange rate instead of throwing an error or returning nothing.\n    -   If you encounter errors when you try to retrieve exchange rates from the exchange rate service, don't throw custom error messages. The framework will alert the user that there is an issue by throwing generic error messages that state that the expected currency pairs could not be retrieved from the provider. If you must log additional errors, use **CurrencyEventSource**. For an example, see the **catch** statement and the **if** condition for the **oandaKey** variable in the following code.\n\n    <!-- -->\n\n        public IExchangeRateResponse GetExchangeRates(IExchangeRateRequest _request, IExchangeRateProviderConfig _config)\n        {\n            System.Exception exception;\n            ExchangeRateProviderPropertyValue oandaKey = _config.GetPropertyValue(this.get_Id(), \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_OandaAPIKey\");\n            if (oandaKey == '')\n            {\n                CurrencyEventSource eventSource = CurrencyEventSource::Log;\n                eventSource.ImportRatesException(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigMessage_OANDAKeyRequired\", \"\");\n                throw error(\"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigMessage_OANDAKeyRequired\");\n            }\n            int decimalPlaces = str2Int(_config.GetPropertyValue(this.get_Id(), \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_DecimalPlaces\"));\n            int serviceTimeout = str2int(_config.getPropertyValue(this.get_Id(), \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_ServiceTimeout\"));\n            boolean singleRateForDateRange = _request.get_SingleRateForDateRange();\n            List rates = new List(Types::Real);\n            List dates = new List(Types::Date);\n            System.TimeZone localTimeZone = System.TimeZone::get_CurrentTimeZone();\n            IExchangeRateResponse response = factory.CreateExchangeRateResponse();\n            // Iterate over the requested currency pairs. This is only required for providers\n            // that support specific currency pairs.\n            IEnumerator currencyPairsEnumerator = _request.GetEnumerator();\n            while(currencyPairsEnumerator.MoveNext())\n            {\n                URL OandaUrl = ServiceURL;\n                // This loop will either execute once if singleRateForDateRange is true; otherwise, it will\n                // execute once for each day. If we make a single request for multiple dates\n                // then OANDA will return an average the rate for the date range.\n                System.DateTime fromDate = _request.get_FromDate();\n                int compareResult = fromDate.CompareTo(_request.get_ToDate());\n                while (compareResult <= 0)\n                {\n                    IExchangeRateRequestCurrencyPair currencyPairRequest = currencyPairsEnumerator.Current;\n                    IExchangeRateResponseCurrencyPair currencyPairResponse = factory.CreateExchangeRateResponseCurrencyPair();\n                    currencyPairResponse.set_FromCurrency(currencyPairRequest.get_FromCurrency());\n                    currencyPairResponse.set_ToCurrency(currencyPairRequest.get_ToCurrency());\n                    // All rates are requested with a display factor of 1 for this provider. If the rates\n                    // internally are represented using a different exchange rate display factor, the\n                    // framework will make the necessary adjustments when saving the exchange rates.\n                    currencyPairResponse.set_ExchangeRateDisplayFactor(ExchangeRateDisplayFactor::One);\n                    // convert to UTC which is required by OANDA\n                    System.DateTime fromUTCDate = localTimeZone.ToUniversalTime(fromDate);\n                    str fromDateForRequest = fromUTCDate.ToString(OANDADateFormat);\n                    System.DateTime toUTCDate = localTimeZone.ToUniversalTime(_request.get_ToDate());\n                    str toDateForRequest = toUTCDate.ToString(OANDADateFormat);\n                    // Build the request URL.\n                    str oandaRequestString;\n                    if (singleRateForDateRange)\n                    {\n                        // getting an average rate for the date range so we invoke the service\n                        // only once per currency pair using the from and to date\n                        oandaRequestString = strFmt(OandaUrl,\n                            currencyPairRequest.get_FromCurrency(),\n                            currencyPairRequest.get_ToCurrency(),\n                            fromDateForRequest,\n                            toDateForRequest,\n                            this.getQuoteTypeParameterForURL(_config),\n                            decimalPlaces);\n                    }\n                    else\n                    {\n                        // invoke the service once for each day.\n                        oandaRequestString = strFmt(OandaUrl,\n                            currencyPairRequest.get_FromCurrency(),\n                            currencyPairRequest.get_ToCurrency(),\n                            fromDateForRequest,\n                            fromDateForRequest,\n                            this.getQuoteTypeParameterForURL(_config),\n                            decimalPlaces);\n                    }\n                    // Configure the request for OANDA.\n                    System.Net.HttpWebRequest httpWebRequest = System.Net.WebRequest::CreateHttp(oandaRequestString);\n                    httpWebRequest.set_Method(HttpWebRequestMethod);\n                    httpWebRequest.set_ContentType(HttpWebRequestContentType);\n                    httpWebRequest.set_Timeout(serviceTimeout);\n                    // Authentication\n                    System.Net.WebHeaderCollection webCollection = httpWebRequest.get_Headers();\n                    webCollection.Add(HttpHeaderAuthorization, KeyTokenPrefix + oandaKey);\n                    try\n                    {\n                        // Invoke the service\n                        System.Net.WebResponse webResponse;\n                        webResponse = httpWebRequest.GetResponse();\n                        // Retrieve the XML response.\n                        System.IO.Stream stream = webResponse.GetResponseStream();\n                        System.IO.StreamReader streamReader = new System.IO.StreamReader(stream);\n                        str XMLOut = streamReader.ReadToEnd();\n                        // Parse the XML to retrieve the rate and date.\n                        this.processResult(_config, singleRateForDateRange, _request.get_FromDate(), XMLOut, rates, dates);\n                        ListEnumerator rateEnumerator = rates.getEnumerator();\n                        ListEnumerator dateEnumerator = dates.getEnumerator();\n                        // Create the Exchange Rate Provider Response.\n                        rateEnumerator.moveNext();\n                        dateEnumerator.moveNext();\n                        CurrencyExchangeRate exchangeRate = rateEnumerator.current();\n                        date currentDate = dateEnumerator.current();\n                        if (currentDate != dateNull() && exchangeRate)\n                        {\n                            IExchangeRateResponseExchangeRate exchangeRateResponse = factory.CreateExchangeRateResponseExchangeRate();\n                            exchangeRateResponse.set_ValidFrom(currentDate);\n                            exchangeRateResponse.set_ExchangeRate(exchangeRate);\n                            currencyPairResponse.addExchangeRate(exchangeRateResponse);\n                        }\n                    }\n                    catch(exception)\n                    {\n                        CurrencyEventSource eventSource = CurrencyEventSource::Log;\n                        eventSource.ImportRatesException(exception.Message, Exception.StackTrace);\n                    }\n                    response.addOrUpdateCurrencyPair(currencyPairResponse);\n                    rates = new List(Types::Real);\n                    dates = new List(Types::Date);\n                    fromDate = fromDate.AddDays(1);\n                    if (singleRateForDateRange)\n                    {\n                        // getting an average rate across the date range so we invoke the service\n                        // only once per currency pair\n                        compareResult = 1;\n                    }\n                    else\n                    {\n                        compareResult = fromDate.CompareTo(_request.get_ToDate());\n                    }\n                }\n            }\n            return response;\n        }\n\n11. Implement the following helper methods. These methods are specific to this example and aren't required for every provider.\n\n        private str getQuoteTypeParameterForURL(IExchangeRateProviderConfig _config)\n        {\n            ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType quoteType = \n                str2Int(_config.getPropertyValue(this.get_Id(), \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_QuoteType\"));\n            str quoteTypeParameter;\n            switch (quoteType)\n            {\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::AverageAsk:\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::AverageBid:\n                    quoteTypeParameter = QuoteParameterAverages;\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::LowAsk:\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::LowBid:\n                    quoteTypeParameter = QuoteParameterLows;\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::MidPoint:\n                    quoteTypeParameter = QuoteParameterMidPoint;\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::HighAsk:\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::HighBid:\n                    quoteTypeParameter = QuoteParameterHighs;\n                    break;\n            }\n            return quoteTypeParameter;\n        }\n        private void readRate(IExchangeRateProviderConfig _config, System.Xml.XmlNode _xmlQuoteNode, List _rates)\n        {\n            System.Xml.XmlNode xmlRateNode;\n            CurrencyExchangeRate exchangeRate;\n            str value;\n            ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType quoteType = str2Int(_config.getPropertyValue(this.get_Id(), \"@CurrencyExchange:Currency_ConfigField_QuoteType\"));\n            // Find the exchange rate\n            switch (quoteType)\n            {\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::AverageBid:\n                    xmlRateNode = _xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathAverageBid);\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::AverageAsk:\n                    xmlRateNode = _xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathAverageAsk);\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::LowBid:\n                    xmlRateNode = _xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathLowBid);\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::LowAsk:\n                    xmlRateNode = _xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathLowAsk);\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::MidPoint:\n                    xmlRateNode = _xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathMidpoint);\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::HighBid:\n                    xmlRateNode = _xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathHighBid);\n                    break;\n                case ExchangeRateProviderOANDAQuoteType::HighAsk:\n                    xmlRateNode = _xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathHighAsk);\n                    break;\n            }\n            if (xmlRateNode)\n            {\n                value = xmlRateNode.get_InnerText();\n                exchangeRate = str2num(value);\n                if (exchangeRate)\n                {\n                    _rates.addEnd(exchangeRate);\n                }\n            }\n        }\n        private void processResult(IExchangeRateProviderConfig _config, boolean _singleRateForDateRange, System.DateTime _defaultDate, \n            str _xmlString, List _rates, List _dates)\n        {\n            System.Xml.XmlDocument xmlDom = new System.Xml.XmlDocument();\n            System.Xml.XmlNode xmlQuoteNode, xmlDateNode;\n            ValidFromDate exchangeDate;\n            str value;\n            xmlDom.LoadXml(_xmlString);\n            // Find the Quote\n            xmlQuoteNode = xmlDom.SelectSingleNode(XPathQuote);\n            if (xmlQuoteNode)\n            {\n                this.readRate(_config, xmlQuoteNode, _rates);\n                // Find the date of the exchange rate.\n                xmlDateNode = xmlQuoteNode.SelectSingleNode(XPathDate);\n                if (xmlDateNode || _singleRateForDateRange)\n                {\n                    if (xmlDateNode)\n                    {\n                        value = xmlDateNode.get_InnerText();\n                    }    \n                    if (value)\n                    {\n                        // convert the date from UTC to local timezone.\n                        exchangeDate = System.DateTime::Parse(value, System.Globalization.CultureInfo::get_CurrentUICulture(),\n                            System.Globalization.DateTimeStyles::AssumeUniversal);\n                        if (exchangeDate)\n                        {\n                            _dates.addEnd(exchangeDate);\n                        }\n                    }\n                    else if (!value && _singleRateForDateRange)\n                    {\n                        exchangeDate = _defaultDate;\n                        _dates.addEnd(exchangeDate);\n                    }\n                }\n            }\n        }\n\n12. Compile the **ExchangeRateProviderOanda** class. The provider will be run as part of a SysOperation. It's helpful to understand the following framework classes and methods when you debug issues:\n    -   **ExchangeRateProviderFactory.initialize()** – This method creates instances of the exchange rate providers, and is called when exchange rates are registered or imported. If your provider isn't instantiated, start to debug here.\n    -   **ExchangeRateProviderRegistration.initialize()** – This method searches for providers, so that they can be registered. If you can't see your provider on the registration page, start to debug here.\n    -   **ExchangeRateImportOperation.import()** – This method drives the import process by calling the necessary provider and storing the exchange rates.\n    -   **ExchangeRateProviderConfig** – This class provides access to configuration information for the providers.\n\n## Things to consider\nBecause there are no limits to the method that the exchange rate providers use to get exchange rates, the framework enables some interesting scenarios. Here are some ideas that you might want to explore:\n\n-   **Providers that retrieve exchange rates from other exchange rate types** – This scenario would enable synchronization of exchange rates among various exchange rate types. This functionality could be useful in situations where many exchange rate types exist, to maintain isolation between different ledgers.\n-   **Providers that use Extensible Stylesheet Language Transformations (XSLT) to transform any format for an exchange rate service into an instance of the ExchangeRateResponse class** – If this scenario were implemented, users could add the XSLT transform that is required for their exchange rate service, and the application would support the service. Provider-specific code wouldn't be required.\n-   **Some exchange rate provider services charge for every rate that is consumed** – Consider combining the first idea in this list with a limit on the number of rates that you retrieve from the service, for scenarios where you're charged for each rate that is consumed from the service.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,646],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Create exchange rate providers\ndescription: This article describes how to set up an exchange rate provider. \nauthor: RobinARH\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 72153\nms.assetid: 24643037-f7a5-4acf-b3d6-9943642b618c\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: jbye\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Create exchange rate providers","nodes":[{"pos":[0,30],"content":"Create exchange rate providers","nodes":[{"content":"Create exchange rate providers","pos":[0,30]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article describes how to set up an exchange rate provider.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,63],"content":"This article describes how to set up an exchange rate provider.","nodes":[{"content":"This article describes how to set up an exchange rate provider.","pos":[0,63]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[654,684],"content":"Create exchange rate providers","linkify":"Create exchange rate providers","nodes":[{"content":"Create exchange rate providers","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"This article describes how to set up an exchange rate provider.","pos":[730,793]},{"content":"This article describes the steps that are required in order to set up an exchange rate provider.","pos":[796,892]},{"content":"For the purpose of illustration, the OANDA exchange rate service is used throughout this article.","pos":[893,990]},{"content":"By following the steps that are described in this article, you will create a functional exchange rate provider.","pos":[991,1102]},{"content":"The code is production code.","pos":[1103,1131]},{"content":"You can find the source in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderOanda<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class.","pos":[1132,1199],"source":" You can find the source in the **ExchangeRateProviderOanda** class."},{"content":"You can reference this class as you read through this article.","pos":[1200,1262]},{"content":"To request an OANDA test account and receive information about the OANDA exchange rate service, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;</bpt>http://developer.oanda.com/exchange-rates-api/<ept id=\"p1\">&gt;</ept>.","pos":[1263,1414],"source":" To request an OANDA test account and receive information about the OANDA exchange rate service, go to <http://developer.oanda.com/exchange-rates-api/>."},{"pos":[1419,1430],"content":"Terminology","linkify":"Terminology","nodes":[{"content":"Terminology","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import currency exchange rates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The process that retrieves exchange rates from exchange rate providers and imports them.","pos":[1435,1560],"source":"**Import currency exchange rates** – The process that retrieves exchange rates from exchange rate providers and imports them."},{"content":"This process is a system operation that supports batch processing.","pos":[1561,1627]},{"pos":[1632,1746],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Exchange rate provider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – An X++ class that is responsible for retrieving exchange rates from external sources.","source":"**Exchange rate provider** – An X++ class that is responsible for retrieving exchange rates from external sources."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Exchange rate provider registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The process of enabling an exchange rate provider so that it can be used.","pos":[1751,1866],"source":"**Exchange rate provider registration** – The process of enabling an exchange rate provider so that it can be used."},{"content":"By default, exchange rate providers aren't registered when they are deployed.","pos":[1867,1944]},{"pos":[1949,2083],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Exchange rate provider configuration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The configuration settings of an exchange rate provider that determine how it will be used.","source":"**Exchange rate provider configuration** – The configuration settings of an exchange rate provider that determine how it will be used."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Exchange rate service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – A free or paid subscription service that provides a list of exchange rates that have been published.","pos":[2088,2216],"source":"**Exchange rate service** – A free or paid subscription service that provides a list of exchange rates that have been published."},{"content":"Foreign Exchange Rates Powered by OANDA is an example of a service that provides exchange rates.","pos":[2217,2313]},{"pos":[2318,2493],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>The framework<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The import currency exchange rates framework that coordinates the retrieval of exchange rates from providers and appropriate storage of the exchange rates.","source":"**The framework** – The import currency exchange rates framework that coordinates the retrieval of exchange rates from providers and appropriate storage of the exchange rates."},{"pos":[2498,2520],"content":"Conceptual/class model","linkify":"Conceptual/class model","nodes":[{"content":"Conceptual/class model","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"The following illustration shows the main interfaces and classes that make up the exchange rate provider framework, and the relationships among them.","pos":[2521,2670]},{"content":"New exchange rate providers should be derived from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProvider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> interface.","pos":[2671,2762],"source":" New exchange rate providers should be derived from the **IExchangeRateProvider** interface."},{"content":"Exchange rate providers are written in X++.","pos":[2763,2806]},{"content":"Because X++ is a .NET language, it's easy to use the Microsoft .NET Framework in our provider.","pos":[2807,2901]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Conceptual/class model of the exchange rate provider framework<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/exchangerates.png)](./media/exchangerates.png)</ept> Here are the interfaces and classes that are shown in the illustration:","pos":[2902,3095],"source":"[![Conceptual/class model of the exchange rate provider framework](./media/exchangerates.png)](./media/exchangerates.png) Here are the interfaces and classes that are shown in the illustration:"},{"pos":[3101,3259],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProvider<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – By implementing this interface, you enable the exchange rate provider framework to recognize a class as an exchange rate provider.","source":"**IExchangeRateProvider** – By implementing this interface, you enable the exchange rate provider framework to recognize a class as an exchange rate provider."},{"pos":[3264,3473],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This interface enables the exchange rate provider to construct various types of provider framework classes that represent some of the interfaces in the illustration.","source":"**IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory** – This interface enables the exchange rate provider to construct various types of provider framework classes that represent some of the interfaces in the illustration."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The exchange rate provider supports several options when rates are imported.","pos":[3478,3598],"source":"**IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions** – The exchange rate provider supports several options when rates are imported."},{"content":"The exchange rate provider uses this interface to inform the framework about the options that it supports.","pos":[3599,3705]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProviderConfig<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Each exchange rate provider can have a unique configuration.","pos":[3710,3804],"source":"**IExchangeRateProviderConfig** – Each exchange rate provider can have a unique configuration."},{"content":"This interface enables the provider to retrieve this configuration.","pos":[3805,3872]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProviderConfigDefaults<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The exchange rate provider can create and provide default values for its configuration.","pos":[3877,4006],"source":"**IExchangeRateProviderConfigDefaults** – The exchange rate provider can create and provide default values for its configuration."},{"content":"The user can change these values on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure exchange rate providers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page (<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>General ledger<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> **Currencies **<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Configure exchange rate providers<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>).","pos":[4007,4174],"source":" The user can change these values on the **Configure exchange rate providers** page (**General ledger** &gt; **Currencies **&gt; **Configure exchange rate providers**)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This interface represents data that is specific to a request to import exchange rates.","pos":[4179,4292],"source":"**IExchangeRateRequest** – This interface represents data that is specific to a request to import exchange rates."},{"content":"This data includes the date range, options, and the currency pairs to retrieve rates for.","pos":[4293,4382]},{"pos":[4387,4537],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateCalendar<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This interface represents an exchange rate calendar that is used to retrieve the next working day (Monday through Friday).","source":"**IExchangeRateCalendar** – This interface represents an exchange rate calendar that is used to retrieve the next working day (Monday through Friday)."},{"pos":[4542,4703],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateResponse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store the currency pairs and the exchange rates that are returned from the service.","source":"**IExchangeRateResponse** – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store the currency pairs and the exchange rates that are returned from the service."},{"pos":[4708,4879],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateResponseCurrencyPair<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store the details for a specific currency pair that is returned from the service.","source":"**IExchangeRateResponseCurrencyPair** – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store the details for a specific currency pair that is returned from the service."},{"pos":[4884,5034],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateResponseExchangeRate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store a specific exchange rate for a specific currency pair.","source":"**IExchangeRateResponseExchangeRate** – The exchange rate provider uses this interface to store a specific exchange rate for a specific currency pair."},{"pos":[5039,5201],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderOanda<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This example of an exchange rate provider that is implemented by Microsoft connects to the OANDA service to return exchange rates.","source":"**ExchangeRateProviderOanda** – This example of an exchange rate provider that is implemented by Microsoft connects to the OANDA service to return exchange rates."},{"pos":[5206,5239],"content":"Writing an exchange rate provider","linkify":"Writing an exchange rate provider","nodes":[{"content":"Writing an exchange rate provider","pos":[0,33]}]},{"content":"Code examples are taken from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderOanda<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class.","pos":[5240,5309],"source":"Code examples are taken from the **ExchangeRateProviderOanda** class."},{"content":"Follow these steps to create an exchange rate provider.","pos":[5310,5365]},{"pos":[5371,5469],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Currency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> model, create a class that implements the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProvider<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> interface.","source":"In the **Currency** model, create a class that implements the **IExchangeRateProvider** interface."},{"content":"Add the following constants and variable declarations to the class.","pos":[5892,5959]},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>get<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[7336,7371],"source":"Implement the **get\\_Name** method."},{"content":"A label should be used to enable proper translation.","pos":[7372,7424]},{"content":"A user can change the name that is provided here when that user sets up the provider’s configuration information.","pos":[7425,7538]},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>get<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Id<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[7687,7720],"source":"Implement the **get\\_Id** method."},{"content":"This method returns a globally unique identifier (GUID) that is used to uniquely identify this provider.","pos":[7721,7825]},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>set<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Factory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[7930,7968],"source":"Implement the **set\\_Factory** method."},{"content":"The exchange rate provider framework will invoke this method to set an object that implements the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> interface on your provider.","pos":[7969,8136],"source":" The exchange rate provider framework will invoke this method to set an object that implements the **IExchangeRateProviderFrameworkFactory** interface on your provider."},{"content":"This factory can be used to instantiate new objects that represent some of the interfaces from the previous illustration.","pos":[8137,8258]},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GetSupportedOptions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[8397,8442],"source":"Implement the **GetSupportedOptions** method."},{"content":"This method indicates whether the exchange rate provider supports some framework features:","pos":[8443,8533]},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>doesSupportSpecificCurrencyPairs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>true<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> only if the exchange rate service requires that a source and destination currency be passed to get an exchange rate.","pos":[8543,8725],"source":"Set the **doesSupportSpecificCurrencyPairs** property to **true** only if the exchange rate service requires that a source and destination currency be passed to get an exchange rate."},{"content":"Many exchange rate services return rates for a fixed currency or a given set of currency pairs.","pos":[8726,8821]},{"content":"For these services, the value of this option should be set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>false<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[8822,8894],"source":" For these services, the value of this option should be set to **false**."},{"content":"If prices that a service charges are based on quotas on the number of rates, a value of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>true<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> will cause the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> interface to contain only those currency pairs that are configured for an exchange rate type on the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Exchange rate<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page (<bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>General ledger<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Currencies<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Exchange rates<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept>).","pos":[8895,9220],"source":" If prices that a service charges are based on quotas on the number of rates, a value of **true** will cause the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface to contain only those currency pairs that are configured for an exchange rate type on the **Exchange rate** page (**General ledger** &gt; **Currencies** &gt; **Exchange rates**)."},{"content":"The provider can then specifically request these rates from the service and therefore lower the cost.","pos":[9221,9322]},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>fixedBaseIsoCurrency<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property to the three-character International Organization for Standardization (ISO) currency code that represents the fixed base currency of the exchange rates that are returned from the exchange rate service.","pos":[9331,9574],"source":"Set the **fixedBaseIsoCurrency** property to the three-character International Organization for Standardization (ISO) currency code that represents the fixed base currency of the exchange rates that are returned from the exchange rate service."},{"content":"If the exchange rate service doesn't support a fixed base currency, return an empty string.","pos":[9575,9666]},{"content":"For example, the euro is often used as a fixed base currency.","pos":[9667,9728]},{"content":"When you create a new provider, be sure to research the exchange rate service so that you can select the correct value.","pos":[9729,9848]},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>singleRateForDateRange<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>true<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> if the service can return a single rate that represents the whole date range.","pos":[9857,9990],"source":"Set the **singleRateForDateRange** property to **true** if the service can return a single rate that represents the whole date range."},{"content":"For example, you can use this setting to return a single exchange rate that represents the average exchange rate for a month.","pos":[9991,10116]},{"content":"If the service doesn’t support this functionality, set this property to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>false<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[10117,10199],"source":" If the service doesn’t support this functionality, set this property to **false**."},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GetConfigurationDefaults<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[10668,10718],"source":"Implement the **GetConfigurationDefaults** method."},{"content":"Configuration defaults are name-value pairs that represent the default configuration settings for the exchange rate provider.","pos":[10719,10844]},{"content":"These settings are automatically loaded when the provider is registered, but the user can change them.","pos":[10845,10947]},{"content":"Take the required precautions when you convert these strings into usable values.","pos":[10948,11028]},{"content":"The value field is stored as an encrypted field in SQL.","pos":[11029,11084]},{"content":"Therefore, sensitive data such as an application programming interface (API) key will be more secure.","pos":[11085,11186]},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ValidateConfigurationDetail<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[11958,12011],"source":"Implement the **ValidateConfigurationDetail** method."},{"content":"This method enables the exchange rate provider to validate the configuration information that the user modified on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Configure exchange rate providers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[12012,12174],"source":" This method enables the exchange rate provider to validate the configuration information that the user modified on the **Configure exchange rate providers** page."},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>EnumNameForLookup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[13535,13578],"source":"Implement the **EnumNameForLookup** method."},{"content":"This method enables the exchange rate provider to enable a lookup for a specific <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderPropertyKey<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> key.","pos":[13579,13700],"source":" This method enables the exchange rate provider to enable a lookup for a specific **ExchangeRateProviderPropertyKey** key."},{"content":"Just return the name of an existing enumerated type for the appropriate key.","pos":[13701,13777]},{"content":"If this feature isn't required, return an empty string.","pos":[13778,13833]},{"content":"Implement the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GetExchangeRates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method.","pos":[14130,14172],"source":"Implement the **GetExchangeRates** method."},{"content":"This method uses the configuration information and the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> interface that is provided to call out to the exchange rate service and return the appropriate instance of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateResponse<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> class.","pos":[14173,14396],"source":" This method uses the configuration information and the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface that is provided to call out to the exchange rate service and return the appropriate instance of the **IExchangeRateResponse** class."},{"content":"When you write this method, consider these important points:","pos":[14397,14457]},{"content":"Any configuration information that is required should be retrieved from the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProviderConfig<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> interface.","pos":[14467,14585],"source":"Any configuration information that is required should be retrieved from the **IExchangeRateProviderConfig** interface."},{"content":"A call to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>GetPropertyValue<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method on that interface will provide the string representation of the property value for the property key that is provided.","pos":[14586,14745],"source":" A call to the **GetPropertyValue** method on that interface will provide the string representation of the property value for the property key that is provided."},{"content":"Take the required precautions when you convert this string value to another type.","pos":[14746,14827]},{"content":"Do any required validation up front.","pos":[14836,14872]},{"content":"For example, OANDA requires that an API key be supplied on every service call.","pos":[14873,14951]},{"content":"If this API key isn't set, the service will fail.","pos":[14952,15001]},{"content":"Verify that the API key isn't set, and exit early to receive an appropriate error message.","pos":[15002,15092]},{"content":"Some providers require explicit currency pairs when exchange rates are requested.","pos":[15101,15182]},{"content":"These providers are the same providers that set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions.doesSupportSpecificCurrencyPairs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> property to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>true<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[15183,15331],"source":" These providers are the same providers that set the **IExchangeRateProviderSupportedOptions.doesSupportSpecificCurrencyPairs** property to **true**."},{"content":"In this case, you must use the currency pairs that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> interface provides to drive the retrieval process.","pos":[15332,15462],"source":" In this case, you must use the currency pairs that the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface provides to drive the retrieval process."},{"content":"The OANDA provider implementation that follows shows a good example of this type of provider.","pos":[15463,15556]},{"content":"Typically, providers that don't support specific currency pairs return data for a fixed set of currency pairs.","pos":[15557,15667]},{"content":"In this case, the currency pairs that the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> interface provides can be ignored.","pos":[15668,15769],"source":" In this case, the currency pairs that the **IExchangeRateRequest** interface provides can be ignored."},{"content":"Providers should return all the rates that are available, and the framework will then import the correct rates, based on the user’s decision about whether to automatically create the required currency pairs.","pos":[15770,15977]},{"content":"The CentralBankOfEuropeProvider provider is a good example of this type of provider.","pos":[15978,16062]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> interface has a property that is named <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ImportDateType<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[16071,16158],"source":"The **IExchangeRateRequest** interface has a property that is named **ImportDateType**."},{"content":"This property indicates the dates that should be used to retrieve exchange rates from the service.","pos":[16159,16257]},{"content":"The two values that are available are <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CurrentDate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>DateRange<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[16258,16330],"source":" The two values that are available are **CurrentDate** and **DateRange**."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CurrentDate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> retrieves the most current exchange rate from the exchange rate service.","pos":[16343,16431],"source":"**CurrentDate** retrieves the most current exchange rate from the exchange rate service."},{"content":"When this value is passed to the provider, the framework also sets <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest.FromDate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest.ToDate<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to the system date of the Application Object Server (AOS) computer that is making the request.","pos":[16432,16663],"source":" When this value is passed to the provider, the framework also sets **IExchangeRateRequest.FromDate** and **IExchangeRateRequest.ToDate** to the system date of the Application Object Server (AOS) computer that is making the request."},{"content":"If exchange rate services support the retrieval of exchange rates for specific dates, the date that the framework provides should be passed.","pos":[16664,16804]},{"content":"However, if the exchange rate service instead provides a call to get the most current exchange rate (regardless of the date), the date that is returned must be validated to make sure that it's less than or equal to the requested date.","pos":[16805,17039]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DateRange<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> retrieves the exchange rates for a specific date range.","pos":[17052,17121],"source":"**DateRange** retrieves the exchange rates for a specific date range."},{"content":"Only exchange rates in the specified date range should be allowed.","pos":[17122,17188]},{"content":"If an exchange rate service requires that specific dates be included in the request, this process is straightforward.","pos":[17189,17306]},{"content":"However, if an exchange rate service instead returns a group of historical dates that might be outside the valid range of dates, the provider must filter out the dates that aren't relevant before it passes the dates back to the framework.","pos":[17307,17545]},{"content":"When exchange rates are returned, always use the date that the exchange rate service provides instead of the dates that the instance of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>IExchangeRateRequest<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class supplies.","pos":[17554,17734],"source":"When exchange rates are returned, always use the date that the exchange rate service provides instead of the dates that the instance of the **IExchangeRateRequest** class supplies."},{"content":"In this manner, you help guarantee that the exchange rate that is returned is associated with the correct date, because an exchange rate service might occasionally return rates for dates that weren't expected.","pos":[17735,17944]},{"content":"For example, if an exchange rate is requested for a date in the future, some providers return the most recent exchange rate instead of throwing an error or returning nothing.","pos":[17945,18119]},{"content":"If you encounter errors when you try to retrieve exchange rates from the exchange rate service, don't throw custom error messages.","pos":[18128,18258]},{"content":"The framework will alert the user that there is an issue by throwing generic error messages that state that the expected currency pairs could not be retrieved from the provider.","pos":[18259,18436]},{"content":"If you must log additional errors, use <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>CurrencyEventSource<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[18437,18500],"source":" If you must log additional errors, use **CurrencyEventSource**."},{"content":"For an example, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>catch<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> statement and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>if<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> condition for the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>oandaKey<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> variable in the following code.","pos":[18501,18622],"source":" For an example, see the **catch** statement and the **if** condition for the **oandaKey** variable in the following code."},{"content":"Implement the following helper methods.","pos":[26670,26709]},{"content":"These methods are specific to this example and aren't required for every provider.","pos":[26710,26792]},{"content":"Compile the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderOanda<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> class.","pos":[31797,31845],"source":"Compile the **ExchangeRateProviderOanda** class."},{"content":"The provider will be run as part of a SysOperation.","pos":[31846,31897]},{"content":"It's helpful to understand the following framework classes and methods when you debug issues:","pos":[31898,31991]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderFactory.initialize()<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This method creates instances of the exchange rate providers, and is called when exchange rates are registered or imported.","pos":[32000,32170],"source":"**ExchangeRateProviderFactory.initialize()** – This method creates instances of the exchange rate providers, and is called when exchange rates are registered or imported."},{"content":"If your provider isn't instantiated, start to debug here.","pos":[32171,32228]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderRegistration.initialize()<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This method searches for providers, so that they can be registered.","pos":[32237,32356],"source":"**ExchangeRateProviderRegistration.initialize()** – This method searches for providers, so that they can be registered."},{"content":"If you can't see your provider on the registration page, start to debug here.","pos":[32357,32434]},{"pos":[32443,32589],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateImportOperation.import()<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This method drives the import process by calling the necessary provider and storing the exchange rates.","source":"**ExchangeRateImportOperation.import()** – This method drives the import process by calling the necessary provider and storing the exchange rates."},{"pos":[32598,32705],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ExchangeRateProviderConfig<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This class provides access to configuration information for the providers.","source":"**ExchangeRateProviderConfig** – This class provides access to configuration information for the providers."},{"pos":[32710,32728],"content":"Things to consider","linkify":"Things to consider","nodes":[{"content":"Things to consider","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"Because there are no limits to the method that the exchange rate providers use to get exchange rates, the framework enables some interesting scenarios.","pos":[32729,32880]},{"content":"Here are some ideas that you might want to explore:","pos":[32881,32932]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Providers that retrieve exchange rates from other exchange rate types<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – This scenario would enable synchronization of exchange rates among various exchange rate types.","pos":[32938,33109],"source":"**Providers that retrieve exchange rates from other exchange rate types** – This scenario would enable synchronization of exchange rates among various exchange rate types."},{"content":"This functionality could be useful in situations where many exchange rate types exist, to maintain isolation between different ledgers.","pos":[33110,33245]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Providers that use Extensible Stylesheet Language Transformations (XSLT) to transform any format for an exchange rate service into an instance of the ExchangeRateResponse class<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If this scenario were implemented, users could add the XSLT transform that is required for their exchange rate service, and the application would support the service.","pos":[33250,33599],"source":"**Providers that use Extensible Stylesheet Language Transformations (XSLT) to transform any format for an exchange rate service into an instance of the ExchangeRateResponse class** – If this scenario were implemented, users could add the XSLT transform that is required for their exchange rate service, and the application would support the service."},{"content":"Provider-specific code wouldn't be required.","pos":[33600,33644]},{"pos":[33649,33933],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Some exchange rate provider services charge for every rate that is consumed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Consider combining the first idea in this list with a limit on the number of rates that you retrieve from the service, for scenarios where you're charged for each rate that is consumed from the service.","source":"**Some exchange rate provider services charge for every rate that is consumed** – Consider combining the first idea in this list with a limit on the number of rates that you retrieve from the service, for scenarios where you're charged for each rate that is consumed from the service."}]}