{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)\ndescription: This article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS). It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: dynamics-ax-2012 \nms.service:\nms.technology: ax-2012\n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: kfend\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 18941\nms.assetid: 6634d000-b031-40d7-ad2a-c6626e4cbdc2\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: manado\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)\n\n[!include[banner](../../includes/banner.md)]\n\nThis article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS). It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.\n\nProjects are the main organizer of your experience in LCS. The methodology that is associated with a project determines the default phases and tasks that are included in that project.\n\n## Key features\n| Feature              | Description                                                                                                                                                                                |\n|----------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Invite who you want. | Customers and partners can invite each other to participate in projects. You also can invite prospects. If you use Cloud-powered support, you can also invite Microsoft support engineers. |\n| Change ownership.    | You can change the ownership of a project as you require. For example, you can change the ownership from a partner to a customer, or to a different person at a customer.                  |\n\nYou must follow the methodology in your implementation project. The methodology framework is designed to guide you through the implementation. As you perform actions in LCS, you can begin to mark the phases and tasks as completed. Locked methodology tasks can be marked as completed after you complete the prerequisite. You can click the lock icon to learn what you must complete before you can mark a task as completed. As you work through the phases and tasks in the methodology, environments become available for you to configure. \n\n## Delete a project \nWhen you have LCS opened, you have a view on recent projects. Click the option 'All projects'. You then have a view on all projects in a list style. Select a project and click the Trashbin icon. The project with all related information will be deleted.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,785],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)\ndescription: This article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS). It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: dynamics-ax-2012 \nms.service:\nms.technology: ax-2012\n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: kfend\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 18941\nms.assetid: 6634d000-b031-40d7-ad2a-c6626e4cbdc2\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: manado\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)","nodes":[{"pos":[0,36],"content":"Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)","nodes":[{"content":"Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)","pos":[0,36]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS). It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,188],"content":"This article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS). It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS). It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.","pos":[0,188],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).","pos":[0,96]},{"content":"It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.","pos":[97,188]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[793,829],"content":"Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)","linkify":"Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)","nodes":[{"content":"Projects in Lifecycle Services (LCS)","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"This article provides information about projects in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).","pos":[877,973]},{"content":"It describes some important features and also explains the role of the project methodology.","pos":[974,1065]},{"content":"Projects are the main organizer of your experience in LCS.","pos":[1067,1125]},{"content":"The methodology that is associated with a project determines the default phases and tasks that are included in that project.","pos":[1126,1250]},{"pos":[1255,1267],"content":"Key features","linkify":"Key features","nodes":[{"content":"Key features","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"Feature","pos":[1270,1277]},{"content":"Description","pos":[1293,1304]},{"content":"Invite who you want.","pos":[1698,1718]},{"content":"Customers and partners can invite each other to participate in projects.","pos":[1721,1793]},{"content":"You also can invite prospects.","pos":[1794,1824]},{"content":"If you use Cloud-powered support, you can also invite Microsoft support engineers.","pos":[1825,1907]},{"content":"Change ownership.","pos":[1912,1929]},{"content":"You can change the ownership of a project as you require.","pos":[1935,1992]},{"content":"For example, you can change the ownership from a partner to a customer, or to a different person at a customer.","pos":[1993,2104]},{"content":"You must follow the methodology in your implementation project.","pos":[2125,2188]},{"content":"The methodology framework is designed to guide you through the implementation.","pos":[2189,2267]},{"content":"As you perform actions in LCS, you can begin to mark the phases and tasks as completed.","pos":[2268,2355]},{"content":"Locked methodology tasks can be marked as completed after you complete the prerequisite.","pos":[2356,2444]},{"content":"You can click the lock icon to learn what you must complete before you can mark a task as completed.","pos":[2445,2545]},{"content":"As you work through the phases and tasks in the methodology, environments become available for you to configure.","pos":[2546,2658]},{"pos":[2664,2680],"content":"Delete a project","linkify":"Delete a project","nodes":[{"content":"Delete a project","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"When you have LCS opened, you have a view on recent projects.","pos":[2682,2743]},{"content":"Click the option 'All projects'.","pos":[2744,2776]},{"content":"You then have a view on all projects in a list style.","pos":[2777,2830]},{"content":"Select a project and click the Trashbin icon.","pos":[2831,2876]},{"content":"The project with all related information will be deleted.","pos":[2877,2934]}]}