{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)\ndescription: \nauthor: MargoC\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: dynamics-ax-2012 \nms.service: \nms.technology: ax-2012\n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: AX 2012, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 13352\nms.assetid: be08d43a-f05e-4580-ac75-52710d06a1d7\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: aamiral\nms.search.validFrom: \nms.dyn365.ops.version: 2012\n\n---\n\n# Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)\n\n[!include[banner](../../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\n\n\nThis article explains how to deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Microsoft Azure. To deploy the environment, you’ll use the Cloud-hosted environments tool in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services.\n\n## Prerequisites\nBefore you complete the procedures in this article, make sure that the following prerequisites are in place.\n\n| Category       | Prerequisite                                                                                                                                            |\n|----------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Required tasks | [Plan your Microsoft Dynamics AX deployment on Azure](plan-2012-r3-deployment-azure.md) |\n\n## 1. Log on to Lifecycle Services\nMicrosoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services provides a cloud-based collaborative workspace that customers and partners can use to manage Microsoft Dynamics AX projects. You’ll use this website to deploy Dynamics AX on Azure. Lifecycle Services is available to customers and partners as part of their support plans. You can access it with your CustomerSource or PartnerSource credentials. [Log on to Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com/)\n\n## 2. Create a project\nAfter you log in to Lifecycle Services, open an existing project, or create a new project. Projects are the key organizer of your experience in Lifecycle Services. The methodology associated with a project determines which phases and tasks are included in the project by default.\n\n## 3. Connect the project to your Azure subscription\nConnect the Lifecycle Services project to your Azure subscription. This will enable Lifecycle Services to deploy a Dynamics AX environment to the subscription. To connect the project to your Azure subscription, complete the following procedure. Keep in mind that a project can be connected to only one Azure subscription. If you have multiple Azure subscriptions, be sure to identify which subscription you want to use before you complete this procedure.\n1.  Click **Cloud-hosted environments**. The **Cloud-hosted environments** page is displayed.\n2.  The **Microsoft Azure setup** panel is displayed on the side of the screen. If it is not displayed, click **Microsoft Azure settings**.\n3.  Enter your Azure subscription ID. If you need to find your subscription ID, complete the following steps:\n    1.  Open another instance of your browser.\n    2.  Log on to the [Azure management portal](https://manage.windowsazure.com/).\n    3.  In the navigation pane on the left, click **Settings.** (You may have to scroll to the bottom of the navigation pane to see the **Settings** link.) The **Settings** page is displayed.\n    4.  Copy your subscription ID, and then paste it into the **Azure subscription ID** field in Lifecycle Services (which is currently displayed in another browser instance).\n\n4.  Click **Next**.\n5.  Click **Download** to download a management certificate. This management certificate enables Lifecycle Services to communicate with Azure on your behalf. By default, the management certificate is saved to the **Downloads** folder on your computer and is named **LifecycleServicesDeployment.cer.**\n6.  Upload the management certificate to Azure. To do so, complete the following steps:\n    1.  Open another instance of your browser. (Or, go to the browser instance that you may have opened in step 3.)\n    2.  Log on to the [Azure management portal](https://manage.windowsazure.com/).\n    3.  In the navigation pane on the left, click **Settings**. The **Settings** page is displayed.\n    4.  Click **Management certificates**.\n    5.  Click **Upload** at the bottom of the page.\n    6.  In the **Upload a management certificate** window, browse to the management certificate that you downloaded in step 5. Then click the check mark.\n\n7.  Go back to the browser that displays the **Microsoft Azure setup** panel in Lifecycle Services. Click **Next**.\n8.  Select the region that is closest to you. The AX 2012 R3 environment will be deployed to a datacenter in this region.\n9.  Click **Connect**. The project is now connected to the Azure subscription that you specified. If you discover that you connected the project to the wrong Azure subscription (that is, assuming you have multiple Azure subscriptions), you’ll need to delete the project, create a new project, and then repeat this procedure to connect the new project to the appropriate Azure subscription.\n\n## 4. Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure\nComplete the following procedure to deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure.\n\n1.  On the **Cloud-hosted environments** page, click the **Add** (+) icon.\n2.  In the **Select environment topology** panel, select **Demo**.\n3.  Click **Retail essentials demo.**\n4.  In the **Environment name** field, enter a name for the environment that will be deployed.\n5.  Click **Advanced settings**.\n6.  To customize virtual machine names, click **Customize virtual machine names**. In order to support common IT naming guidelines, the ability to name virtual machines is provided through the **Advanced settings** option on most deployment topologies. In addition to defining the name, a starting index can be selected for each virtual machine type. The index is incremented for each instance of the virtual machine type that is deployed.Virtual machine names must be 13 characters or less. The index is separated from the machine name by a hyphen (-), followed by the index that supports a maximum of 2 digits. Example: ACustomVMName-99. When virtual machine instances are added to an environment after the initial deployment, the deployment service will start incrementing the virtual machine name where it left off. For example, if you deployed four AOS virtual machines with a starting index of 2, then the last AOS instance name will be AOS-6. If you add two more AOS instances, they will be AOS-7 and AOS-8.If one of the virtual machine types in your deployment is customized, then all of the virtual machine names must be customized. This is done to ensure that a long deployment does not occur because a virtual machine name was accidentally missed.\n7.  To customize virtual network settings, click **Customize virtual network** settings. Then use the following table to enter information.\n\n    <table>\n    <colgroup>\n    <col width=\"50%\" />\n    <col width=\"50%\" />\n    </colgroup>\n    <thead>\n    <tr class=\"header\">\n    <th>If you want to:</th>\n    <th>Do this:</th>\n    </tr>\n    </thead>\n    <tbody>\n    <tr class=\"odd\">\n    <td>Create a new virtual network in Azure for the environment</td>\n    <td><ol>\n    <li>Click <strong><span class=\"label\">New virtual network</span></strong>.</li>\n    <li>Enter a name for the virtual network.</li>\n    </ol></td>\n    </tr>\n    <tr class=\"even\">\n    <td>Add the environment to an existing virtual network in Azure</td>\n    <td><ol>\n    <li>Click <strong><span class=\"label\">Existing virtual network</span></strong>.</li>\n    <li>Select the name of the existing virtual network that you want to use. The <span class=\"label\"><strong>Application subnet</strong> <strong>name</strong></span> and <strong><span class=\"label\">Address space</span></strong> fields will automatically display the appropriate information based on the virtual network that you selected. If you want to verify the information in these fields, do this:\n    <ol>\n    <li>Log on to the <a href=\"https://manage.windowsazure.com/\">Azure management portal</a>.</li>\n    <li>In the navigation pane on the left, click <strong><span class=\"label\">Networks</span></strong>.</li>\n    <li>Click the name of the virtual network that you’re going to use.</li>\n    <li>Click <strong><span class=\"label\">Configure</span></strong>. Details about the virtual network are listed on the page.</li>\n    <li>Click <strong><span class=\"label\">Done</span></strong>. The <strong><span class=\"label\">Deploy environment</span></strong> panel is redisplayed.</li>\n    <li>The number and size of each virtual machine that will be deployed is listed. Change the number and size of the virtual machines, as needed.</li>\n    </ol></li>\n    </ol></td>\n    </tr>\n    </tbody>\n    </table>\n\n    -   For information about the software installed on each virtual machine in this environment, see [Plan your Microsoft Dynamics AX deployment on Azure](plan-2012-r3-deployment-azure.md).\n    -   For sizing and pricing details about virtual machines, see [Virtual machines pricing details](http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/pricing/details/virtual-machines/).\n\n8.  Click **Software License Terms** to review the licensing terms and conditions. Then select the check box to indicate that you agree to the terms.\n9.  Click **Next**.\n10. Click **Deploy** to confirm that you’re ready to deploy the environment. The deployment may take a few hours to complete. When the deployment is done, the Deployment Status column on the **Cloud-hosted environments** page will display **Deployed**. (You may need to refresh your browser to see this.)If the deployment fails, you may see an error message right away. If the error occurs later in the deployment process, error details will be displayed in the details pane on the right-side of the page.\n\n## 5. Open the Dynamics AX client\nComplete the following procedure to connect to the virtual machine where the Dynamics AX client is installed.\n\n1.  On the **Cloud-hosted environments page**, select the Retail essentials environment that you just deployed.\n2.  Scroll to the right side of the page to view the properties of the environment.\n3.  Click the **DEMO-&lt;GUID&gt;** link.\n4.  At the bottom of the page, click **Open** to open the .rdp file.\n5.  When prompted for credentials, enter the user name and password for the &lt;DomainName&gt;Administrator account. You can find the password for this account on the **Cloud-hosted environments** page for this environment.\n6.  When the virtual machine’s desktop is displayed, click the **Microsoft Dynamics AX** icon to open the Microsoft Dynamics AX client.\n\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,599],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)\ndescription: \nauthor: MargoC\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: dynamics-ax-2012 \nms.service: \nms.technology: ax-2012\n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: AX 2012, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 13352\nms.assetid: be08d43a-f05e-4580-ac75-52710d06a1d7\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: aamiral\nms.search.validFrom: \nms.dyn365.ops.version: 2012\n","nodes":[{"content":"Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)","nodes":[{"pos":[0,62],"content":"Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)","nodes":[{"content":"Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)","pos":[0,62]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[607,669],"content":"Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)","linkify":"Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)","nodes":[{"content":"Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure (AX 2012)","pos":[0,62]}]},{"content":"This article explains how to deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Microsoft Azure.","pos":[720,812]},{"content":"To deploy the environment, you’ll use the Cloud-hosted environments tool in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services.","pos":[813,927]},{"pos":[932,945],"content":"Prerequisites","linkify":"Prerequisites","nodes":[{"content":"Prerequisites","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"Before you complete the procedures in this article, make sure that the following prerequisites are in place.","pos":[946,1054]},{"content":"Category","pos":[1058,1066]},{"content":"Prerequisite","pos":[1075,1087]},{"content":"Required tasks","pos":[1404,1418]},{"pos":[1421,1508],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Plan your Microsoft Dynamics AX deployment on Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](plan-2012-r3-deployment-azure.md)</ept>","source":"[Plan your Microsoft Dynamics AX deployment on Azure](plan-2012-r3-deployment-azure.md)"},{"pos":[1515,1546],"content":"1. Log on to Lifecycle Services","linkify":"1. Log on to Lifecycle Services","nodes":[{"content":"1. Log on to Lifecycle Services","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services provides a cloud-based collaborative workspace that customers and partners can use to manage Microsoft Dynamics AX projects.","pos":[1547,1709]},{"content":"You’ll use this website to deploy Dynamics AX on Azure.","pos":[1710,1765]},{"content":"Lifecycle Services is available to customers and partners as part of their support plans.","pos":[1766,1855]},{"content":"You can access it with your CustomerSource or PartnerSource credentials.","pos":[1856,1928]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Log on to Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">](https://lcs.dynamics.com/)</ept>","pos":[1929,1986],"source":"[Log on to Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com/)"},{"pos":[1991,2010],"content":"2. Create a project","linkify":"2. Create a project","nodes":[{"content":"2. Create a project","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"After you log in to Lifecycle Services, open an existing project, or create a new project.","pos":[2011,2101]},{"content":"Projects are the key organizer of your experience in Lifecycle Services.","pos":[2102,2174]},{"content":"The methodology associated with a project determines which phases and tasks are included in the project by default.","pos":[2175,2290]},{"pos":[2295,2344],"content":"3. Connect the project to your Azure subscription","linkify":"3. Connect the project to your Azure subscription","nodes":[{"content":"3. Connect the project to your Azure subscription","pos":[0,49]}]},{"content":"Connect the Lifecycle Services project to your Azure subscription.","pos":[2345,2411]},{"content":"This will enable Lifecycle Services to deploy a Dynamics AX environment to the subscription.","pos":[2412,2504]},{"content":"To connect the project to your Azure subscription, complete the following procedure.","pos":[2505,2589]},{"content":"Keep in mind that a project can be connected to only one Azure subscription.","pos":[2590,2666]},{"content":"If you have multiple Azure subscriptions, be sure to identify which subscription you want to use before you complete this procedure.","pos":[2667,2799]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud-hosted environments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2804,2840],"source":"Click **Cloud-hosted environments**."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud-hosted environments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page is displayed.","pos":[2841,2893],"source":" The **Cloud-hosted environments** page is displayed."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Azure setup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> panel is displayed on the side of the screen.","pos":[2898,2973],"source":"The **Microsoft Azure setup** panel is displayed on the side of the screen."},{"content":"If it is not displayed, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Azure settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2974,3033],"source":" If it is not displayed, click **Microsoft Azure settings**."},{"content":"Enter your Azure subscription ID.","pos":[3038,3071]},{"content":"If you need to find your subscription ID, complete the following steps:","pos":[3072,3143]},{"content":"Open another instance of your browser.","pos":[3152,3190]},{"pos":[3199,3273],"content":"Log on to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure management portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://manage.windowsazure.com/)</ept>.","source":"Log on to the [Azure management portal](https://manage.windowsazure.com/)."},{"content":"In the navigation pane on the left, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[3282,3337],"source":"In the navigation pane on the left, click **Settings.**"},{"content":"(You may have to scroll to the bottom of the navigation pane to see the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> link.) The <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page is displayed.","pos":[3338,3465],"source":" (You may have to scroll to the bottom of the navigation pane to see the **Settings** link.) The **Settings** page is displayed."},{"pos":[3474,3641],"content":"Copy your subscription ID, and then paste it into the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure subscription ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field in Lifecycle Services (which is currently displayed in another browser instance).","source":"Copy your subscription ID, and then paste it into the **Azure subscription ID** field in Lifecycle Services (which is currently displayed in another browser instance)."},{"pos":[3647,3662],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Next**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to download a management certificate.","pos":[3667,3723],"source":"Click **Download** to download a management certificate."},{"content":"This management certificate enables Lifecycle Services to communicate with Azure on your behalf.","pos":[3724,3820]},{"content":"By default, the management certificate is saved to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Downloads<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> folder on your computer and is named <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>LifecycleServicesDeployment.cer.<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>","pos":[3821,3963],"source":" By default, the management certificate is saved to the **Downloads** folder on your computer and is named **LifecycleServicesDeployment.cer.**"},{"content":"Upload the management certificate to Azure.","pos":[3968,4011]},{"content":"To do so, complete the following steps:","pos":[4012,4051]},{"content":"Open another instance of your browser.","pos":[4060,4098]},{"content":"(Or, go to the browser instance that you may have opened in step 3.)","pos":[4099,4167]},{"pos":[4176,4250],"content":"Log on to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure management portal<ept id=\"p1\">](https://manage.windowsazure.com/)</ept>.","source":"Log on to the [Azure management portal](https://manage.windowsazure.com/)."},{"content":"In the navigation pane on the left, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4259,4314],"source":"In the navigation pane on the left, click **Settings**."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page is displayed.","pos":[4315,4350],"source":" The **Settings** page is displayed."},{"pos":[4359,4393],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Management certificates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Management certificates**."},{"pos":[4402,4445],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Upload<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the bottom of the page.","source":"Click **Upload** at the bottom of the page."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Upload a management certificate<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window, browse to the management certificate that you downloaded in step 5.","pos":[4454,4572],"source":"In the **Upload a management certificate** window, browse to the management certificate that you downloaded in step 5."},{"content":"Then click the check mark.","pos":[4573,4599]},{"content":"Go back to the browser that displays the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Azure setup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> panel in Lifecycle Services.","pos":[4605,4700],"source":"Go back to the browser that displays the **Microsoft Azure setup** panel in Lifecycle Services."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4701,4716],"source":" Click **Next**."},{"content":"Select the region that is closest to you.","pos":[4721,4762]},{"content":"The AX 2012 R3 environment will be deployed to a datacenter in this region.","pos":[4763,4838]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connect<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4843,4861],"source":"Click **Connect**."},{"content":"The project is now connected to the Azure subscription that you specified.","pos":[4862,4936]},{"content":"If you discover that you connected the project to the wrong Azure subscription (that is, assuming you have multiple Azure subscriptions), you’ll need to delete the project, create a new project, and then repeat this procedure to connect the new project to the appropriate Azure subscription.","pos":[4937,5228]},{"pos":[5233,5288],"content":"4. Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure","linkify":"4. Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure","nodes":[{"content":"4. Deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"Complete the following procedure to deploy a Retail essentials demo environment on Azure.","pos":[5289,5378]},{"pos":[5384,5454],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud-hosted environments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> (+) icon.","source":"On the **Cloud-hosted environments** page, click the **Add** (+) icon."},{"pos":[5459,5521],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select environment topology<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> panel, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Demo<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"In the **Select environment topology** panel, select **Demo**."},{"pos":[5526,5559],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail essentials demo.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"Click **Retail essentials demo.**"},{"pos":[5564,5654],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Environment name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter a name for the environment that will be deployed.","source":"In the **Environment name** field, enter a name for the environment that will be deployed."},{"pos":[5659,5687],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advanced settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Advanced settings**."},{"content":"To customize virtual machine names, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customize virtual machine names<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[5692,5770],"source":"To customize virtual machine names, click **Customize virtual machine names**."},{"content":"In order to support common IT naming guidelines, the ability to name virtual machines is provided through the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advanced settings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option on most deployment topologies.","pos":[5771,5940],"source":" In order to support common IT naming guidelines, the ability to name virtual machines is provided through the **Advanced settings** option on most deployment topologies."},{"content":"In addition to defining the name, a starting index can be selected for each virtual machine type.","pos":[5941,6038]},{"content":"The index is incremented for each instance of the virtual machine type that is deployed.Virtual machine names must be 13 characters or less.","pos":[6039,6179]},{"content":"The index is separated from the machine name by a hyphen (-), followed by the index that supports a maximum of 2 digits.","pos":[6180,6300]},{"content":"Example: ACustomVMName-99.","pos":[6301,6327]},{"content":"When virtual machine instances are added to an environment after the initial deployment, the deployment service will start incrementing the virtual machine name where it left off.","pos":[6328,6507]},{"content":"For example, if you deployed four AOS virtual machines with a starting index of 2, then the last AOS instance name will be AOS-6.","pos":[6508,6637]},{"content":"If you add two more AOS instances, they will be AOS-7 and AOS-8.If one of the virtual machine types in your deployment is customized, then all of the virtual machine names must be customized.","pos":[6638,6829]},{"content":"This is done to ensure that a long deployment does not occur because a virtual machine name was accidentally missed.","pos":[6830,6946]},{"content":"To customize virtual network settings, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customize virtual network<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> settings.","pos":[6951,7035],"source":"To customize virtual network settings, click **Customize virtual network** settings."},{"content":"Then use the following table to enter information.","pos":[7036,7086]},{"content":"If you want to:","pos":[7223,7238]},{"content":"Do this:","pos":[7252,7260]},{"content":"Create a new virtual network in Azure for the environment","pos":[7330,7387]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt>New virtual network<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[7414,7484],"source":"Click <strong><span class=\"label\">New virtual network</span></strong>."},{"content":"Enter a name for the virtual network.","pos":[7498,7535]},{"content":"Add the environment to an existing virtual network in Azure","pos":[7596,7655]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt>Existing virtual network<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[7682,7757],"source":"Click <strong><span class=\"label\">Existing virtual network</span></strong>."},{"content":"Select the name of the existing virtual network that you want to use.","pos":[7771,7840]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Application subnet<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>name<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt>Address space<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> fields will automatically display the appropriate information based on the virtual network that you selected.","pos":[7841,8101],"source":" The <span class=\"label\"><strong>Application subnet</strong> <strong>name</strong></span> and <strong><span class=\"label\">Address space</span></strong> fields will automatically display the appropriate information based on the virtual network that you selected."},{"content":"If you want to verify the information in these fields, do this:","pos":[8102,8169],"source":" If you want to verify the information in these fields, do this:\n    "},{"content":"Log on to the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://manage.windowsazure.com/\"&gt;</bpt>Azure management portal<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>.","pos":[8183,8268],"source":"Log on to the <a href=\"https://manage.windowsazure.com/\">Azure management portal</a>."},{"content":"In the navigation pane on the left, click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt>Networks<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[8282,8377],"source":"In the navigation pane on the left, click <strong><span class=\"label\">Networks</span></strong>."},{"content":"Click the name of the virtual network that you’re going to use.","pos":[8391,8454]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt>Configure<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[8468,8528],"source":"Click <strong><span class=\"label\">Configure</span></strong>."},{"content":"Details about the virtual network are listed on the page.","pos":[8529,8586]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt>Done<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[8600,8655],"source":"Click <strong><span class=\"label\">Done</span></strong>."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt><bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;span class=\"label\"&gt;</bpt>Deploy environment<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/span&gt;</ept><ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> panel is redisplayed.","pos":[8656,8744],"source":" The <strong><span class=\"label\">Deploy environment</span></strong> panel is redisplayed."},{"content":"The number and size of each virtual machine that will be deployed is listed.","pos":[8758,8834]},{"content":"Change the number and size of the virtual machines, as needed.","pos":[8835,8897]},{"pos":[8978,9160],"content":"For information about the software installed on each virtual machine in this environment, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Plan your Microsoft Dynamics AX deployment on Azure<ept id=\"p1\">](plan-2012-r3-deployment-azure.md)</ept>.","source":"For information about the software installed on each virtual machine in this environment, see [Plan your Microsoft Dynamics AX deployment on Azure](plan-2012-r3-deployment-azure.md)."},{"pos":[9169,9331],"content":"For sizing and pricing details about virtual machines, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Virtual machines pricing details<ept id=\"p1\">](http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/pricing/details/virtual-machines/)</ept>.","source":"For sizing and pricing details about virtual machines, see [Virtual machines pricing details](http://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/pricing/details/virtual-machines/)."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Software License Terms<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to review the licensing terms and conditions.","pos":[9337,9415],"source":"Click **Software License Terms** to review the licensing terms and conditions."},{"content":"Then select the check box to indicate that you agree to the terms.","pos":[9416,9482]},{"pos":[9487,9502],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Next**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deploy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to confirm that you’re ready to deploy the environment.","pos":[9507,9579],"source":"Click **Deploy** to confirm that you’re ready to deploy the environment."},{"content":"The deployment may take a few hours to complete.","pos":[9580,9628]},{"content":"When the deployment is done, the Deployment Status column on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud-hosted environments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page will display <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Deployed<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[9629,9755],"source":" When the deployment is done, the Deployment Status column on the **Cloud-hosted environments** page will display **Deployed**."},{"content":"(You may need to refresh your browser to see this.)If the deployment fails, you may see an error message right away.","pos":[9756,9872]},{"content":"If the error occurs later in the deployment process, error details will be displayed in the details pane on the right-side of the page.","pos":[9873,10008]},{"pos":[10013,10043],"content":"5. Open the Dynamics AX client","linkify":"5. Open the Dynamics AX client","nodes":[{"content":"5. Open the Dynamics AX client","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"Complete the following procedure to connect to the virtual machine where the Dynamics AX client is installed.","pos":[10044,10153]},{"pos":[10159,10266],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud-hosted environments page<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select the Retail essentials environment that you just deployed.","source":"On the **Cloud-hosted environments page**, select the Retail essentials environment that you just deployed."},{"content":"Scroll to the right side of the page to view the properties of the environment.","pos":[10271,10350]},{"pos":[10355,10392],"content":"Click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>DEMO-<ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;lt;</ph>GUID<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> link.","source":"Click the **DEMO-&lt;GUID&gt;** link."},{"pos":[10397,10461],"content":"At the bottom of the page, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open the .rdp file.","source":"At the bottom of the page, click **Open** to open the .rdp file."},{"content":"When prompted for credentials, enter the user name and password for the <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;lt;</ph>DomainName<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph>Administrator account.","pos":[10466,10578],"source":"When prompted for credentials, enter the user name and password for the &lt;DomainName&gt;Administrator account."},{"content":"You can find the password for this account on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cloud-hosted environments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page for this environment.","pos":[10579,10685],"source":" You can find the password for this account on the **Cloud-hosted environments** page for this environment."},{"pos":[10690,10821],"content":"When the virtual machine’s desktop is displayed, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics AX<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> icon to open the Microsoft Dynamics AX client.","source":"When the virtual machine’s desktop is displayed, click the **Microsoft Dynamics AX** icon to open the Microsoft Dynamics AX client."}]}