{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated\ndescription: This topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated. \nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 21881\nms.assetid: 26793616-9b3f-41f5-8500-6983769c51d8\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sericks\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-08-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 2\n\n---\n\n# Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated. \n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Feature</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Intelligent Data Management Framework (IDMF)</td>\n<td>IDMF is an add-on tool that lets system administrators optimize the performance of Microsoft Dynamics AX installations. IDMF assesses the health of the application, analyzes current usage patterns, and helps reduce database size.</td>\n</tr><tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Alerts</td>\n<td>Implementation of the alerts functionality is planned for a future update. Alerts help users keep track of data changes in the system.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td><strong>Graphics</strong> tab in the <strong>Fixed asset value model</strong> and <strong>Depreciation book profile</strong> forms</td>\n<td>The chart shows the depreciation, accumulated depreciation, and net book value over time. Users can click the <strong>Data</strong> tab to view more detailed information than the chart shows. This chart will be redesigned in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Generate an electronic file to communicate payment advice information. The file can be sent to a vendor.</td>\n<td>From the vendor payment journal, you can generate payment advice as either a report or a file. The payment advice is used to inform the vendor about the list of invoices that are being paid. The payment advice report is still available in the current version, but you can no longer generate this information in an electronic file format. That functionality depended on Application Integration Framework (AIF), which has been deprecated.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Vendor portal</td>\n<td>Vendor portal lets you certify and validate suppliers as claims users through identity providers such as Microsoft account or Yahoo. It also supports unsolicited vendor sign-up. Vendor portal lets vendors review purchase orders, update their own (supplier) data, review product receipts to generate invoices, and upload and maintain a product catalog. Vendor portal lets you collaborate with or notify a supplier, and also lets you upload requests for quotation (RFQs) and allow vendors to respond to them. A vendor portal interface will be available in the web client, for Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) users who have a dedicated security role. These users can review, confirm, and reject purchase orders, and can view confirmed orders.\n<p>The ability for the vendor to view and respond to purchase orders, and to create draft invoices has been included in Dynamics 365 for Financials and Operations in recent releases. So has the ability to initiate a Vendor user request workflow, to onboard new external (AAD account) users defined as contact persons for the vendor. </p>\n</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Employee self-service (ESS)</td>\n<td>ESS lets you enter requisitions for employees through a procurement site, view the status of an order (created, received, or receipt confirmed), and request onboarding of a new vendor. ESS also lets you configure security and punch-out to external catalogs. In the current version, procurement catalog capabilities are reduced and are used only to limit the products that can be ordered for an organization on a requisition. Additionally, the ability to approve a vendor invoice and the functionality for confirming receipts that are associated with requisitions that lead to purchases aren't currently available.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Customer self-service (CSS)</td>\n<td>CSS lets you create approved customer records, and lets users view selected product catalogs, order items, and view the status of invoices. It also provides the ability to create and follow return orders.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Cost accounting</td>\n<td>The <strong>Cost accounting</strong> module is designed to meet the requirements of internal costs and profitability reports at multiple organizational levels. To define the cost object level, the module depends on a correct mapping of financial dimensions. The module lets you perform advanced allocations of cost origin from expenditures that are registered in the general ledger or budget, and also lets you compare realized costs and budgeted costs.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Absence management in Human resources</td>\n<td>Functionality for entering absence transactions through both ESS and the client isn't included. Additionally, functionality for approving those absence transactions as a manager isn't included. In a future update, the current functionality will be enhanced to support a wider range of scenarios. Setup capabilities that are required for integration with other modules are available through the <strong>Human Resources 2</strong> configuration key.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>US Payroll</td>\n<td>US Payroll isn't included. Limited initial setup capabilities will be available through the <strong>Human Resources 1</strong> &gt; <strong>Payroll</strong> configuration key.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>External questionnaire and recruiting functionality</td>\n<td>Functionality for externally posting questionnaires and open jobs will be added in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Main account allocations for accounting distributions</td>\n<td>Allocation rules that are defined for a main account won't be applied on accounting distributions. In a future update, main allocation rules will be applied during journalization.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Client right-to-left (RTL) layout</td>\n<td>The web client uses only left-to-right (LTR) layout for controls and labels. The ability to use RTL layout for Arabic and Hebrew languages will be added in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Client drag-and-drop</td>\n<td>The web client controls have application programming interfaces (APIs) for drag-and-drop operations, but these APIs are based on the deprecated desktop client technology and must be redesigned to work on the new web client platform. APIs to support drag-and-drop operations will be reviewed for inclusion in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Vendor catalog import</td>\n<td>Vendor catalog import is available and uses the new data management capabilities for import. However, this feature doesn't support the import of product images and attributes. It also doesn't let you generate schema files per vendor catalog. This functionality will be added in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>General budget reservations</td>\n<td>This document is sometimes referred to as a commitment. Public sector entities often use this document to set aside or earmark budgeted funds so that they aren't available for other purposes. This functionality will be added in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Electronic data exchange</td>\n<td>The electronic exchange of documents, such as order confirmations and similar supply chain management (SCM) documents that were previously enabled as AIF documents, isn't supported. This functionality will be added in a future update.</td>\n\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Microsoft Project client integration</td>\n<td>The Microsoft Project client is integrated with projects.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Specifications for Electronic reporting (ER) payment formats</td>\n<td>Currently, payment format specifications must be entered manually. In a future update, you will be able to select payment format specifications in a list. Currently, the following payment specifications are supported per payment format.\n<p><strong>Note:</strong> Values for these supported payment specifications are used as payment specification parameters in the <strong>Payment specification</strong> form for a selected method of payment.</p>\n<p><strong>BTL91 for the Netherlands</strong></p>\n<table>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Payment specification (used in ER)</th>\n<th>Export format description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>ChqBen</td>\n<td>Cheque, Begunstigde</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>ChqOff</td>\n<td>Cheque, Kantoor opdrachtgever</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>ChqPri</td>\n<td>Cheque, Opdrachtgever</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>TrfBenBen</td>\n<td>Overboeking Begunstigde/Begunstigde</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>TrfBenBenUrg</td>\n<td>Overboeking Begunstigde/Begunstigde Spoed</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>TrfEurBen</td>\n<td>Overboeking Euro/Begunstigde</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>TrfEurBenUrg</td>\n<td>Overboeking Euro/Begunstigde Spoed</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>TrfEurEur</td>\n<td>Overboeking Euro/Euro</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>TrfEurEurUrg</td>\n<td>Overboeking Euro/Euro Spoed</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>TrfForBen</td>\n<td>Overboeking VV-rekening/Begunstigde</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>TrfForBenUrg</td>\n<td>Overboeking VV-rekening/Begunstigde Spoed</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>TrfForFor</td>\n<td>Overboeking VV-rekening/VV-rekening</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>TrfForForUrg</td>\n<td>Overboeking VV-rekening/VV-rekening Spoed</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<p><strong>Betalingsservice for Denmark</strong></p>\n<table>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Payment specification (used in ER)</th>\n<th>Export format description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>B0112</td>\n<td>BS-B 0112: Lang tekst &amp; adresse</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>B0113</td>\n<td>BS-B 0113: Erstat. bet. lang tekst</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>T0112</td>\n<td>BS-T 0112: Lang tekst &amp; adresse</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>T0117</td>\n<td>BS-T 0117:FIK;kort frist;lang tekst&amp;adr.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<p><strong>Nordea vendor for Denmark</strong></p>\n<table>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Payment specification (used in ER)</th>\n<th>Export format description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>56</td>\n<td>Currency account transfer between Nordea accounts in Denmark</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>47</td>\n<td>Domestic check</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>45</td>\n<td>Domestic transfer</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>50</td>\n<td>Express transfer</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>55</td>\n<td>Intercompany transfer (domestic)</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>51</td>\n<td>Intercompany transfer to a foreign bank</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>54</td>\n<td>International check</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>52</td>\n<td>Nordea intercompany payment</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>43</td>\n<td>Request for transfer</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>46</td>\n<td>Transfer form/giro payment</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<p><strong>ISO20022 Credit transfer (CH)</strong></p>\n<table>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Payment specification (used in ER)</th>\n<th>Export format description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Tp1.ESROPS</td>\n<td>Type 1 - ESR orange payment slip</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Tp21.ISR1SPS</td>\n<td>Type 2.1 - IS red 1 stage payment slip</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Tp22.ISR2SPS</td>\n<td>Type 2.2 - IS red 2 stage payment slip</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Tp7.Dmstc</td>\n<td>Type 7 - Domestic postal order</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>TpE1.PSWR</td>\n<td>Type E1 - Payment slip with reference</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>TpE2.PSWN</td>\n<td>Type E2 - Payment slip with notifications</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Fiscal printers for Poland</td>\n<td>Integration with Polish fiscal printers, such as the Posnet Thermal and Elzab Omega printer types, enables the required information to be sent to the fiscal printer in the correct format during invoice posting. This feature will be available in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Bank payment order for Latvia and Lithuania</td>\n<td>You can print a payment order for Latvia and Lithuania. This feature will be available in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Bankgirot AP return format for Sweden</td>\n<td>The Bankgirot return format is used to import bank return messages. This feature will be available in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Secure global address book</td>\n<td>The ability to secure the global address book by legal entity and address book has not yet been implemented. This feature will be available in a future update.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,891],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated\ndescription: This topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated. \nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 21881\nms.assetid: 26793616-9b3f-41f5-8500-6983769c51d8\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sericks\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-08-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 2\n","nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated","nodes":[{"pos":[0,77],"content":"Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated","nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated","pos":[0,77]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,238],"content":"This topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated.","pos":[0,238],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[0,160]},{"content":"Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated.","pos":[161,238]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[899,976],"content":"Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated","linkify":"Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated","nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't been implemented but aren't deprecated","pos":[0,77]}]},{"content":"This topic lists Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 features that haven't yet been implemented in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[1022,1182]},{"content":"Although these features haven't yet been implemented, they aren't deprecated.","pos":[1183,1260]},{"content":"Feature","pos":[1366,1373]},{"content":"Description","pos":[1383,1394]},{"content":"Intelligent Data Management Framework (IDMF)","pos":[1444,1488]},{"content":"IDMF is an add-on tool that lets system administrators optimize the performance of Microsoft Dynamics AX installations.","pos":[1498,1617]},{"content":"IDMF assesses the health of the application, analyzes current usage patterns, and helps reduce database size.","pos":[1618,1727]},{"content":"Alerts","pos":[1759,1765]},{"content":"Implementation of the alerts functionality is planned for a future update.","pos":[1775,1849]},{"content":"Alerts help users keep track of data changes in the system.","pos":[1850,1909]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Graphics<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Fixed asset value model<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Depreciation book profile<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> forms","pos":[1943,2073],"source":"<strong>Graphics</strong> tab in the <strong>Fixed asset value model</strong> and <strong>Depreciation book profile</strong> forms"},{"content":"The chart shows the depreciation, accumulated depreciation, and net book value over time.","pos":[2083,2172]},{"content":"Users can click the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Data<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab to view more detailed information than the chart shows.","pos":[2173,2274],"source":" Users can click the <strong>Data</strong> tab to view more detailed information than the chart shows."},{"content":"This chart will be redesigned in a future update.","pos":[2275,2324]},{"content":"Generate an electronic file to communicate payment advice information.","pos":[2357,2427]},{"content":"The file can be sent to a vendor.","pos":[2428,2461]},{"content":"From the vendor payment journal, you can generate payment advice as either a report or a file.","pos":[2471,2565]},{"content":"The payment advice is used to inform the vendor about the list of invoices that are being paid.","pos":[2566,2661]},{"content":"The payment advice report is still available in the current version, but you can no longer generate this information in an electronic file format.","pos":[2662,2808]},{"content":"That functionality depended on Application Integration Framework (AIF), which has been deprecated.","pos":[2809,2907]},{"content":"Vendor portal","pos":[2940,2953]},{"content":"Vendor portal lets you certify and validate suppliers as claims users through identity providers such as Microsoft account or Yahoo.","pos":[2963,3095]},{"content":"It also supports unsolicited vendor sign-up.","pos":[3096,3140]},{"content":"Vendor portal lets vendors review purchase orders, update their own (supplier) data, review product receipts to generate invoices, and upload and maintain a product catalog.","pos":[3141,3314]},{"content":"Vendor portal lets you collaborate with or notify a supplier, and also lets you upload requests for quotation (RFQs) and allow vendors to respond to them.","pos":[3315,3469]},{"content":"A vendor portal interface will be available in the web client, for Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) users who have a dedicated security role.","pos":[3470,3622]},{"content":"These users can review, confirm, and reject purchase orders, and can view confirmed orders.","pos":[3623,3714]},{"content":"The ability for the vendor to view and respond to purchase orders, and to create draft invoices has been included in Dynamics 365 for Financials and Operations in recent releases.","pos":[3718,3897]},{"content":"So has the ability to initiate a Vendor user request workflow, to onboard new external (AAD account) users defined as contact persons for the vendor.","pos":[3898,4047]},{"content":"Employee self-service (ESS)","pos":[4087,4114]},{"content":"ESS lets you enter requisitions for employees through a procurement site, view the status of an order (created, received, or receipt confirmed), and request onboarding of a new vendor.","pos":[4124,4308]},{"content":"ESS also lets you configure security and punch-out to external catalogs.","pos":[4309,4381]},{"content":"In the current version, procurement catalog capabilities are reduced and are used only to limit the products that can be ordered for an organization on a requisition.","pos":[4382,4548]},{"content":"Additionally, the ability to approve a vendor invoice and the functionality for confirming receipts that are associated with requisitions that lead to purchases aren't currently available.","pos":[4549,4737]},{"content":"Customer self-service (CSS)","pos":[4770,4797]},{"content":"CSS lets you create approved customer records, and lets users view selected product catalogs, order items, and view the status of invoices.","pos":[4807,4946]},{"content":"It also provides the ability to create and follow return orders.","pos":[4947,5011]},{"content":"Cost accounting","pos":[5045,5060]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Cost accounting<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> module is designed to meet the requirements of internal costs and profitability reports at multiple organizational levels.","pos":[5070,5229],"source":"The <strong>Cost accounting</strong> module is designed to meet the requirements of internal costs and profitability reports at multiple organizational levels."},{"content":"To define the cost object level, the module depends on a correct mapping of financial dimensions.","pos":[5230,5327]},{"content":"The module lets you perform advanced allocations of cost origin from expenditures that are registered in the general ledger or budget, and also lets you compare realized costs and budgeted costs.","pos":[5328,5523]},{"content":"Absence management in Human resources","pos":[5557,5594]},{"content":"Functionality for entering absence transactions through both ESS and the client isn't included.","pos":[5604,5699]},{"content":"Additionally, functionality for approving those absence transactions as a manager isn't included.","pos":[5700,5797]},{"content":"In a future update, the current functionality will be enhanced to support a wider range of scenarios.","pos":[5798,5899]},{"content":"Setup capabilities that are required for integration with other modules are available through the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Human Resources 2<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> configuration key.","pos":[5900,6051],"source":" Setup capabilities that are required for integration with other modules are available through the <strong>Human Resources 2</strong> configuration key."},{"content":"US Payroll","pos":[6084,6094]},{"content":"US Payroll isn't included.","pos":[6104,6130]},{"content":"Limited initial setup capabilities will be available through the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Human Resources 1<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payroll<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> configuration key.","pos":[6131,6279],"source":" Limited initial setup capabilities will be available through the <strong>Human Resources 1</strong> &gt; <strong>Payroll</strong> configuration key."},{"content":"External questionnaire and recruiting functionality","pos":[6313,6364]},{"content":"Functionality for externally posting questionnaires and open jobs will be added in a future update.","pos":[6374,6473]},{"content":"Main account allocations for accounting distributions","pos":[6506,6559]},{"content":"Allocation rules that are defined for a main account won't be applied on accounting distributions.","pos":[6569,6667]},{"content":"In a future update, main allocation rules will be applied during journalization.","pos":[6668,6748]},{"content":"Client right-to-left (RTL) layout","pos":[6782,6815]},{"content":"The web client uses only left-to-right (LTR) layout for controls and labels.","pos":[6825,6901]},{"content":"The ability to use RTL layout for Arabic and Hebrew languages will be added in a future update.","pos":[6902,6997]},{"content":"Client drag-and-drop","pos":[7030,7050]},{"content":"The web client controls have application programming interfaces (APIs) for drag-and-drop operations, but these APIs are based on the deprecated desktop client technology and must be redesigned to work on the new web client platform.","pos":[7060,7292]},{"content":"APIs to support drag-and-drop operations will be reviewed for inclusion in a future update.","pos":[7293,7384]},{"content":"Vendor catalog import","pos":[7418,7439]},{"content":"Vendor catalog import is available and uses the new data management capabilities for import.","pos":[7449,7541]},{"content":"However, this feature doesn't support the import of product images and attributes.","pos":[7542,7624]},{"content":"It also doesn't let you generate schema files per vendor catalog.","pos":[7625,7690]},{"content":"This functionality will be added in a future update.","pos":[7691,7743]},{"content":"General budget reservations","pos":[7776,7803]},{"content":"This document is sometimes referred to as a commitment.","pos":[7813,7868]},{"content":"Public sector entities often use this document to set aside or earmark budgeted funds so that they aren't available for other purposes.","pos":[7869,8004]},{"content":"This functionality will be added in a future update.","pos":[8005,8057]},{"content":"Electronic data exchange","pos":[8091,8115]},{"content":"The electronic exchange of documents, such as order confirmations and similar supply chain management (SCM) documents that were previously enabled as AIF documents, isn't supported.","pos":[8125,8306]},{"content":"This functionality will be added in a future update.","pos":[8307,8359]},{"content":"Microsoft Project client integration","pos":[8388,8424]},{"content":"The Microsoft Project client is integrated with projects.","pos":[8434,8491]},{"content":"Specifications for Electronic reporting (ER) payment formats","pos":[8524,8584]},{"content":"Currently, payment format specifications must be entered manually.","pos":[8594,8660]},{"content":"In a future update, you will be able to select payment format specifications in a list.","pos":[8661,8748]},{"content":"Currently, the following payment specifications are supported per payment format.","pos":[8749,8830]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> Values for these supported payment specifications are used as payment specification parameters in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payment specification<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> form for a selected method of payment.","pos":[8834,9036],"source":"<strong>Note:</strong> Values for these supported payment specifications are used as payment specification parameters in the <strong>Payment specification</strong> form for a selected method of payment."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>BTL91 for the Netherlands<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>","pos":[9044,9086],"source":"<strong>BTL91 for the Netherlands</strong>"},{"content":"Payment specification (used in ER)","pos":[9131,9165]},{"content":"Export format description","pos":[9175,9200]},{"content":"ChqBen","pos":[9250,9256]},{"content":"Cheque, Begunstigde","pos":[9266,9285]},{"content":"ChqOff","pos":[9319,9325]},{"content":"Cheque, Kantoor opdrachtgever","pos":[9335,9364]},{"content":"ChqPri","pos":[9397,9403]},{"content":"Cheque, Opdrachtgever","pos":[9413,9434]},{"content":"TrfBenBen","pos":[9468,9477]},{"content":"Overboeking Begunstigde/Begunstigde","pos":[9487,9522]},{"content":"TrfBenBenUrg","pos":[9555,9567]},{"content":"Overboeking Begunstigde/Begunstigde Spoed","pos":[9577,9618]},{"content":"TrfEurBen","pos":[9652,9661]},{"content":"Overboeking Euro/Begunstigde","pos":[9671,9699]},{"content":"TrfEurBenUrg","pos":[9732,9744]},{"content":"Overboeking Euro/Begunstigde Spoed","pos":[9754,9788]},{"content":"TrfEurEur","pos":[9822,9831]},{"content":"Overboeking Euro/Euro","pos":[9841,9862]},{"content":"TrfEurEurUrg","pos":[9895,9907]},{"content":"Overboeking Euro/Euro Spoed","pos":[9917,9944]},{"content":"TrfForBen","pos":[9978,9987]},{"content":"Overboeking VV-rekening/Begunstigde","pos":[9997,10032]},{"content":"TrfForBenUrg","pos":[10065,10077]},{"content":"Overboeking VV-rekening/Begunstigde Spoed","pos":[10087,10128]},{"content":"TrfForFor","pos":[10162,10171]},{"content":"Overboeking VV-rekening/VV-rekening","pos":[10181,10216]},{"content":"TrfForForUrg","pos":[10249,10261]},{"content":"Overboeking VV-rekening/VV-rekening Spoed","pos":[10271,10312]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Betalingsservice for Denmark<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>","pos":[10345,10390],"source":"<strong>Betalingsservice for Denmark</strong>"},{"content":"Payment specification (used in ER)","pos":[10435,10469]},{"content":"Export format description","pos":[10479,10504]},{"content":"B0112","pos":[10554,10559]},{"content":"BS-B 0112: Lang tekst <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;amp;</ph> adresse","pos":[10569,10604],"source":"BS-B 0112: Lang tekst &amp; adresse"},{"content":"B0113","pos":[10638,10643]},{"content":"BS-B 0113: Erstat.","pos":[10653,10671]},{"content":"bet.","pos":[10672,10676]},{"content":"lang tekst","pos":[10677,10687]},{"content":"T0112","pos":[10720,10725]},{"content":"BS-T 0112: Lang tekst <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;amp;</ph> adresse","pos":[10735,10770],"source":"BS-T 0112: Lang tekst &amp; adresse"},{"content":"T0117","pos":[10804,10809]},{"content":"BS-T 0117:FIK;kort frist;lang tekst<ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;amp;</ph>adr.","pos":[10819,10863],"source":"BS-T 0117:FIK;kort frist;lang tekst&amp;adr."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Nordea vendor for Denmark<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>","pos":[10896,10938],"source":"<strong>Nordea vendor for Denmark</strong>"},{"content":"Payment specification (used in ER)","pos":[10983,11017]},{"content":"Export format description","pos":[11027,11052]},{"content":"56","pos":[11102,11104]},{"content":"Currency account transfer between Nordea accounts in Denmark","pos":[11114,11174]},{"content":"47","pos":[11208,11210]},{"content":"Domestic check","pos":[11220,11234]},{"content":"45","pos":[11267,11269]},{"content":"Domestic transfer","pos":[11279,11296]},{"content":"50","pos":[11330,11332]},{"content":"Express transfer","pos":[11342,11358]},{"content":"55","pos":[11391,11393]},{"content":"Intercompany transfer (domestic)","pos":[11403,11435]},{"content":"51","pos":[11469,11471]},{"content":"Intercompany transfer to a foreign bank","pos":[11481,11520]},{"content":"54","pos":[11553,11555]},{"content":"International check","pos":[11565,11584]},{"content":"52","pos":[11618,11620]},{"content":"Nordea intercompany payment","pos":[11630,11657]},{"content":"43","pos":[11690,11692]},{"content":"Request for transfer","pos":[11702,11722]},{"content":"46","pos":[11756,11758]},{"content":"Transfer form/giro payment","pos":[11768,11794]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>ISO20022 Credit transfer (CH)<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>","pos":[11827,11873],"source":"<strong>ISO20022 Credit transfer (CH)</strong>"},{"content":"Payment specification (used in ER)","pos":[11918,11952]},{"content":"Export format description","pos":[11962,11987]},{"content":"Tp1.ESROPS","pos":[12037,12047]},{"content":"Type 1 - ESR orange payment slip","pos":[12057,12089]},{"content":"Tp21.ISR1SPS","pos":[12123,12135]},{"content":"Type 2.1 - IS red 1 stage payment slip","pos":[12145,12183]},{"content":"Tp22.ISR2SPS","pos":[12216,12228]},{"content":"Type 2.2 - IS red 2 stage payment slip","pos":[12238,12276]},{"content":"Tp7.Dmstc","pos":[12310,12319]},{"content":"Type 7 - Domestic postal order","pos":[12329,12359]},{"content":"TpE1.PSWR","pos":[12392,12401]},{"content":"Type E1 - Payment slip with reference","pos":[12411,12448]},{"content":"TpE2.PSWN","pos":[12482,12491]},{"content":"Type E2 - Payment slip with notifications","pos":[12501,12542]},{"content":"Fiscal printers for Poland","pos":[12605,12631]},{"content":"Integration with Polish fiscal printers, such as the Posnet Thermal and Elzab Omega printer types, enables the required information to be sent to the fiscal printer in the correct format during invoice posting.","pos":[12641,12851]},{"content":"This feature will be available in a future update.","pos":[12852,12902]},{"content":"Bank payment order for Latvia and Lithuania","pos":[12935,12978]},{"content":"You can print a payment order for Latvia and Lithuania.","pos":[12988,13043]},{"content":"This feature will be available in a future update.","pos":[13044,13094]},{"content":"Bankgirot AP return format for Sweden","pos":[13128,13165]},{"content":"The Bankgirot return format is used to import bank return messages.","pos":[13175,13242]},{"content":"This feature will be available in a future update.","pos":[13243,13293]},{"content":"Secure global address book","pos":[13326,13352]},{"content":"The ability to secure the global address book by legal entity and address book has not yet been implemented.","pos":[13362,13470]},{"content":"This feature will be available in a future update.","pos":[13471,13521]}]}