{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Issue worker payments\ndescription: This topic explains how to submit pay statements, generate checks or electronic payments, generate a positive pay file for payroll, and post the payment journal.\nauthor: rschloma\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 222324\nms.assetid: 64c9c810-23ff-4af6-a282-a4db4c60c0d5\nms.search.region: USA\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: brpotter\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Issue worker payments\n\n[!include[banner](../../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic explains how to submit pay statements, generate checks or electronic payments, generate a positive pay file for payroll, and post the payment journal.\n\nYou can pay workers by check or by electronic payment. When you submit pay statements, an invoice is created and posted to the general ledger for the sum of the worker’s net pay for the payroll vendor that is set up on the **Payroll parameters** page. A payment journal that has lines is created, so that you can generate and post payments. When you submit payments, you can optionally post the payroll costs that are associated with workers to the general journal.\n\n## Prerequisites\nThe following table shows the prerequisites that must be in place before you start.\n\n<table>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Category</th>\n<th>Prerequisite</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Country/region</td>\n<td>(USA) The primary address for the legal entity must be in the United States.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Related configuration tasks</td>\n<td>You must complete these tasks before you can post payroll and generate vendor invoices:\n<ul>\n<li>Set the <strong>Payroll clearing account</strong> field on the <strong>Calculation settings</strong> tab on the <strong>Payroll parameters</strong> page.</li>\n<li>Set the <strong>Check method of payment</strong>, <strong>Vendor account for worker payments</strong>, <strong>Payment journal name</strong>, and <strong>Procurement category</strong> fields on the <strong>Payment issuance</strong> tab on the <strong>Payroll parameters</strong> page.</li>\n<li>Before you can generate a positive pay file for payroll, you must set up positive pay.</li>\n<li>If you generate electronic payments, make sure that the <strong>Electronic method of payment</strong> field is set on the on the <strong>Payment issuance</strong> tab on the <strong>Payroll parameters</strong> page. Additionally, make sure that you’ve entered the bank account disbursements for each worker.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nFor more information, see [Set up and generate positive pay](/dynamics365/unified-operations/financials/accounts-payable/set-up-generate-positive-pay-files).\n\n## Submit pay statements for multiple workers in a pay period\nUse this procedure to create a payment journal for multiple pay statements at the same time. Before you generate pay statements, you must generate and release earnings. For more information, see [Generate earnings](noam-usa-generate-earnings.md). \n\nTo submit pay statements for multiple workers at the same time, follow these steps.\n\n1.  Generate pay statements, so that earnings, benefits, and taxes are calculated. For more information, see [Work with pay statements](noam-usa-pay-statements.md). \n    -  **Tip:** Before you generate pay statements, we recommend that you view the **Pay statements to recalculate** list page to verify that no pay statements must be recalculated. For more information, see “Modify pay statements” in [Work with pay statements](noam-usa-pay-statements.md).\n2.  On the **Submit pay statements** page, in the **Pay cycle** field, select the same pay cycle that you selected when you generated and released earnings.\n3.  In the **Pay period** field, select the same pay period that you selected when you generated and released earnings. The list includes only the pay periods that are available for the pay cycle. The default pay period is the first open pay period, but you can select any open pay period in the list.\n4.  Click **OK** to submit the pay statements. A vendor invoice for the sum of the net pay for all pay statements is created and posted. A payment journal that has lines is also created and posted, so that you can generate and post payments.\n5.  When you receive a message that states that the payment journal was successfully generated, and that a voucher and invoice details were created, close the message. The **Submitted pay statements** page shows a list of submitted statements. An icon in the first column of the **Pay statement** grid indicates that the payment was submitted.\n6.  View the payment journal, and then generate checks and electronic payments by using the **Payment journal** page.\n\n## Submit individual pay statements\nTo create a payment journal for an individual pay statement, follow these steps.\n\n1.  Generate pay statements, so that earnings, benefits, and taxes are calculated. For more information, see [Work with pay statements](noam-usa-pay-statements.md).\n2.  On the **Calculated pay statements** page, select the worker pay statement to create the payment journal for, and then click **Submit for payment**. The **Submit for payment** button is also available on the **Pay statement** page.\n3.  Optional: Select the **Post the selected pay statement** check box to post the pay statement. You can post the pay statements as a separate step at any time by using the **Post pay statements** page.\n4.  Click **Submit** to submit the pay statements. A vendor invoice for the net pay of the pay statement is created and posted. A payment journal that has lines is also created, so that you can generate and post the payment.\n5.  When you receive a message that states that the payment journal was successfully generated, and that a voucher and invoice details were created, close the message. On the **Submitted pay statements** page, an icon in the first column of the **Pay statement** grid indicates that the payment was submitted.\n6.  View the payment journal, and then generate checks and electronic payments by using the **Payment journal** page.\n\nContinue with the next section, “Generate checks or electronic payments for a payment journal.”\n\n## Generate checks or electronic payments for a payment journal\nTo generate checks and electronic payments for workers, follow these steps after you submit the pay statements and generate the payment journal. \n\n**Caution:** If you didn’t finish the bank account disbursements before the pay statements were generated, the workers will be paid by check.\n\n1.  On the **Payment journal** page, select the payment journal, and then, on the Action Pane, click **Lines** to open the **Journal voucher** page.\n2.  Verify that the number of vouchers is correct. There is one journal voucher line for each check pay statement, and one or more journal voucher lines for each electronic pay statement.\n3.  On the **Functions** menu, click **Generate payments**. \n    -  **Note:** You must generate electronic payments and check payments separately. Therefore, if you’re generating both electronic payments and check payments, you must complete this step two times.\n4.  On the **Generate payments** page, select the method of payment and the bank account.\n5.  Click **OK** to generate the payment for the records that match the method of payment and the bank account.\n    -   If you selected the check method of payment, the **Payroll check payment** page opens. In the **From** field, verify the starting check number, verify the printing destination, and then click **OK** to print the checks.\n    -   If you selected the electronic method of payment, the **Payroll electronic (Direct deposit)** page opens. Enter the path where the ACH file should be created. (The path that you enter must include the file name.) Enter an effective date and the printing destination, and optionally select the **Pay statement** check box to print the pay statements. Click **OK** to create the ACH file. \n    - **Tip:** You can print pay statements later, from the **Reports** menu.\n\n    The payment status is set to **Sent** for every payment that was generated.\n\n## Generate a positive pay file for payroll\nYou can generate an electronic list of payroll checks that is provided to the bank. When a payroll check is presented to the bank, the bank compares it to the list. If the check matches a check in the list, the bank clears the check. Otherwise, the bank holds the check for review. \n\nTo generate a positive pay file for payroll, follow these steps.\n\n1.  On the **Payroll positive pay** page, in the **Cut-off date** field, enter the last check date to include in the positive pay file. All checks that haven’t been included in a positive pay file through this check date are included in the file.\n2.  Click **OK**.\n\n## Confirm a positive pay file for payroll\nAfter the checks that are listed in a payroll positive pay file are paid, you receive a confirmation number from the bank. You can then confirm the positive pay file in your organization's data. When you confirm a positive pay file, you record the confirmation number that you received from the bank. \n\nTo confirm a positive pay file, follow these steps.\n\n1.  On the **Payroll positive pay file summary** page, select a payroll positive pay file that has a status of **Created**.\n2.  Click **Confirmation**.\n3.  Enter the confirmation number that you received from the bank, and then click **OK**.\n\n## If required: Recall a positive pay file\nIf you must change a payroll positive pay file, you can recall it. When you recall a positive pay file, the field that indicates whether each check has been included in a positive pay file is reset. You can then create a new positive pay file. \n\nTo recall a positive pay file, follow these steps.\n\n1.  On the **Payroll positive pay file summary** page, select a payroll positive pay file that has a status of **Created**.\n2.  Click **Recall**. You receive a message that states that the recall process was successful.\n\n## Post a payment journal\nYou can post a payment journal after you generate checks and electronic payments as described earlier in this topic. \n\nTo post a payment journal, follow these steps.\n\n1.  On the **Payment journal** page, select the payment journal, and then, on the Action Pane, click **Lines** to open the **Journal voucher** page.\n2.  On the **Post** menu, click **Post**. The payment journal lines are settled to the vendor invoice that was created and posted. You receive a message that indicates the number of vouchers that were posted.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,749],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Issue worker payments\ndescription: This topic explains how to submit pay statements, generate checks or electronic payments, generate a positive pay file for payroll, and post the payment journal.\nauthor: rschloma\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 222324\nms.assetid: 64c9c810-23ff-4af6-a282-a4db4c60c0d5\nms.search.region: USA\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: brpotter\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n","nodes":[{"content":"Issue worker payments","nodes":[{"pos":[0,21],"content":"Issue worker payments","nodes":[{"content":"Issue worker payments","pos":[0,21]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic explains how to submit pay statements, generate checks or electronic payments, generate a positive pay file for payroll, and post the payment journal.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,161],"content":"This topic explains how to submit pay statements, generate checks or electronic payments, generate a positive pay file for payroll, and post the payment journal.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how to submit pay statements, generate checks or electronic payments, generate a positive pay file for payroll, and post the payment journal.","pos":[0,161]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[757,778],"content":"Issue worker payments","linkify":"Issue worker payments","nodes":[{"content":"Issue worker payments","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"This topic explains how to submit pay statements, generate checks or electronic payments, generate a positive pay file for payroll, and post the payment journal.","pos":[827,988]},{"content":"You can pay workers by check or by electronic payment.","pos":[990,1044]},{"content":"When you submit pay statements, an invoice is created and posted to the general ledger for the sum of the worker’s net pay for the payroll vendor that is set up on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[1045,1241],"source":" When you submit pay statements, an invoice is created and posted to the general ledger for the sum of the worker’s net pay for the payroll vendor that is set up on the **Payroll parameters** page."},{"content":"A payment journal that has lines is created, so that you can generate and post payments.","pos":[1242,1330]},{"content":"When you submit payments, you can optionally post the payroll costs that are associated with workers to the general journal.","pos":[1331,1455]},{"pos":[1460,1473],"content":"Prerequisites","linkify":"Prerequisites","nodes":[{"content":"Prerequisites","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"The following table shows the prerequisites that must be in place before you start.","pos":[1474,1557]},{"content":"Category","pos":[1599,1607]},{"content":"Prerequisite","pos":[1617,1629]},{"content":"Country/region","pos":[1679,1693]},{"content":"(USA) The primary address for the legal entity must be in the United States.","pos":[1703,1779]},{"content":"Related configuration tasks","pos":[1813,1840]},{"content":"You must complete these tasks before you can post payroll and generate vendor invoices:","pos":[1850,1937],"source":"You must complete these tasks before you can post payroll and generate vendor invoices:\n"},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payroll clearing account<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Calculation settings<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab on the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payroll parameters<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[1947,2100],"source":"Set the <strong>Payroll clearing account</strong> field on the <strong>Calculation settings</strong> tab on the <strong>Payroll parameters</strong> page."},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Check method of payment<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Vendor account for worker payments<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payment journal name<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Procurement category<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> fields on the <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payment issuance<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab on the <bpt id=\"p6\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payroll parameters<ept id=\"p6\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[2110,2394],"source":"Set the <strong>Check method of payment</strong>, <strong>Vendor account for worker payments</strong>, <strong>Payment journal name</strong>, and <strong>Procurement category</strong> fields on the <strong>Payment issuance</strong> tab on the <strong>Payroll parameters</strong> page."},{"content":"Before you can generate a positive pay file for payroll, you must set up positive pay.","pos":[2404,2490]},{"content":"If you generate electronic payments, make sure that the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Electronic method of payment<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set on the on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payment issuance<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab on the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Payroll parameters<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[2500,2715],"source":"If you generate electronic payments, make sure that the <strong>Electronic method of payment</strong> field is set on the on the <strong>Payment issuance</strong> tab on the <strong>Payroll parameters</strong> page."},{"content":"Additionally, make sure that you’ve entered the bank account disbursements for each worker.","pos":[2716,2807]},{"pos":[2849,3006],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up and generate positive pay<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/financials/accounts-payable/set-up-generate-positive-pay-files)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Set up and generate positive pay](/dynamics365/unified-operations/financials/accounts-payable/set-up-generate-positive-pay-files)."},{"pos":[3011,3069],"content":"Submit pay statements for multiple workers in a pay period","linkify":"Submit pay statements for multiple workers in a pay period","nodes":[{"content":"Submit pay statements for multiple workers in a pay period","pos":[0,58]}]},{"content":"Use this procedure to create a payment journal for multiple pay statements at the same time.","pos":[3070,3162]},{"content":"Before you generate pay statements, you must generate and release earnings.","pos":[3163,3238]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Generate earnings<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-generate-earnings.md)</ept>.","pos":[3239,3316],"source":" For more information, see [Generate earnings](noam-usa-generate-earnings.md)."},{"content":"To submit pay statements for multiple workers at the same time, follow these steps.","pos":[3319,3402]},{"content":"Generate pay statements, so that earnings, benefits, and taxes are calculated.","pos":[3408,3486]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Work with pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-pay-statements.md)</ept>.","pos":[3487,3568],"source":" For more information, see [Work with pay statements](noam-usa-pay-statements.md)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Before you generate pay statements, we recommend that you view the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pay statements to recalculate<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> list page to verify that no pay statements must be recalculated.","pos":[3577,3751],"source":"**Tip:** Before you generate pay statements, we recommend that you view the **Pay statements to recalculate** list page to verify that no pay statements must be recalculated."},{"content":"For more information, see “Modify pay statements” in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Work with pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-pay-statements.md)</ept>.","pos":[3752,3860],"source":" For more information, see “Modify pay statements” in [Work with pay statements](noam-usa-pay-statements.md)."},{"pos":[3865,4017],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Submit pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pay cycle<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field, select the same pay cycle that you selected when you generated and released earnings.","source":"On the **Submit pay statements** page, in the **Pay cycle** field, select the same pay cycle that you selected when you generated and released earnings."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pay period<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select the same pay period that you selected when you generated and released earnings.","pos":[4022,4137],"source":"In the **Pay period** field, select the same pay period that you selected when you generated and released earnings."},{"content":"The list includes only the pay periods that are available for the pay cycle.","pos":[4138,4214]},{"content":"The default pay period is the first open pay period, but you can select any open pay period in the list.","pos":[4215,4319]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to submit the pay statements.","pos":[4324,4366],"source":"Click **OK** to submit the pay statements."},{"content":"A vendor invoice for the sum of the net pay for all pay statements is created and posted.","pos":[4367,4456]},{"content":"A payment journal that has lines is also created and posted, so that you can generate and post payments.","pos":[4457,4561]},{"content":"When you receive a message that states that the payment journal was successfully generated, and that a voucher and invoice details were created, close the message.","pos":[4566,4729]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Submitted pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page shows a list of submitted statements.","pos":[4730,4805],"source":" The **Submitted pay statements** page shows a list of submitted statements."},{"content":"An icon in the first column of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pay statement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> grid indicates that the payment was submitted.","pos":[4806,4905],"source":" An icon in the first column of the **Pay statement** grid indicates that the payment was submitted."},{"pos":[4910,5023],"content":"View the payment journal, and then generate checks and electronic payments by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment journal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"View the payment journal, and then generate checks and electronic payments by using the **Payment journal** page."},{"pos":[5028,5060],"content":"Submit individual pay statements","linkify":"Submit individual pay statements","nodes":[{"content":"Submit individual pay statements","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"To create a payment journal for an individual pay statement, follow these steps.","pos":[5061,5141]},{"content":"Generate pay statements, so that earnings, benefits, and taxes are calculated.","pos":[5147,5225]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Work with pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-pay-statements.md)</ept>.","pos":[5226,5307],"source":" For more information, see [Work with pay statements](noam-usa-pay-statements.md)."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Calculated pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select the worker pay statement to create the payment journal for, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Submit for payment<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[5312,5460],"source":"On the **Calculated pay statements** page, select the worker pay statement to create the payment journal for, and then click **Submit for payment**."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Submit for payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button is also available on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pay statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[5461,5543],"source":" The **Submit for payment** button is also available on the **Pay statement** page."},{"content":"Optional: Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post the selected pay statement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box to post the pay statement.","pos":[5548,5641],"source":"Optional: Select the **Post the selected pay statement** check box to post the pay statement."},{"content":"You can post the pay statements as a separate step at any time by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[5642,5747],"source":" You can post the pay statements as a separate step at any time by using the **Post pay statements** page."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Submit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to submit the pay statements.","pos":[5752,5798],"source":"Click **Submit** to submit the pay statements."},{"content":"A vendor invoice for the net pay of the pay statement is created and posted.","pos":[5799,5875]},{"content":"A payment journal that has lines is also created, so that you can generate and post the payment.","pos":[5876,5972]},{"content":"When you receive a message that states that the payment journal was successfully generated, and that a voucher and invoice details were created, close the message.","pos":[5977,6140]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Submitted pay statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, an icon in the first column of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pay statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> grid indicates that the payment was submitted.","pos":[6141,6282],"source":" On the **Submitted pay statements** page, an icon in the first column of the **Pay statement** grid indicates that the payment was submitted."},{"pos":[6287,6400],"content":"View the payment journal, and then generate checks and electronic payments by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment journal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"View the payment journal, and then generate checks and electronic payments by using the **Payment journal** page."},{"content":"Continue with the next section, “Generate checks or electronic payments for a payment journal.”","pos":[6402,6497]},{"pos":[6502,6562],"content":"Generate checks or electronic payments for a payment journal","linkify":"Generate checks or electronic payments for a payment journal","nodes":[{"content":"Generate checks or electronic payments for a payment journal","pos":[0,60]}]},{"content":"To generate checks and electronic payments for workers, follow these steps after you submit the pay statements and generate the payment journal.","pos":[6563,6707]},{"pos":[6710,6851],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Caution:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you didn’t finish the bank account disbursements before the pay statements were generated, the workers will be paid by check.","source":"**Caution:** If you didn’t finish the bank account disbursements before the pay statements were generated, the workers will be paid by check."},{"pos":[6857,7001],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment journal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select the payment journal, and then, on the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Lines<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Journal voucher<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page.","source":"On the **Payment journal** page, select the payment journal, and then, on the Action Pane, click **Lines** to open the **Journal voucher** page."},{"content":"Verify that the number of vouchers is correct.","pos":[7006,7052]},{"content":"There is one journal voucher line for each check pay statement, and one or more journal voucher lines for each electronic pay statement.","pos":[7053,7189]},{"pos":[7194,7249],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Functions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Generate payments<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Functions** menu, click **Generate payments**."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> You must generate electronic payments and check payments separately.","pos":[7258,7336],"source":"**Note:** You must generate electronic payments and check payments separately."},{"content":"Therefore, if you’re generating both electronic payments and check payments, you must complete this step two times.","pos":[7337,7452]},{"pos":[7457,7542],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Generate payments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select the method of payment and the bank account.","source":"On the **Generate payments** page, select the method of payment and the bank account."},{"pos":[7547,7654],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to generate the payment for the records that match the method of payment and the bank account.","source":"Click **OK** to generate the payment for the records that match the method of payment and the bank account."},{"content":"If you selected the check method of payment, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll check payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page opens.","pos":[7663,7749],"source":"If you selected the check method of payment, the **Payroll check payment** page opens."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>From<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, verify the starting check number, verify the printing destination, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to print the checks.","pos":[7750,7882],"source":" In the **From** field, verify the starting check number, verify the printing destination, and then click **OK** to print the checks."},{"content":"If you selected the electronic method of payment, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll electronic (Direct deposit)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page opens.","pos":[7891,7996],"source":"If you selected the electronic method of payment, the **Payroll electronic (Direct deposit)** page opens."},{"content":"Enter the path where the ACH file should be created.","pos":[7997,8049]},{"content":"(The path that you enter must include the file name.) Enter an effective date and the printing destination, and optionally select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pay statement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> check box to print the pay statements.","pos":[8050,8240],"source":" (The path that you enter must include the file name.) Enter an effective date and the printing destination, and optionally select the **Pay statement** check box to print the pay statements."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to create the ACH file.","pos":[8241,8277],"source":" Click **OK** to create the ACH file."},{"pos":[8285,8356],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> You can print pay statements later, from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Reports<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> menu.","source":"**Tip:** You can print pay statements later, from the **Reports** menu."},{"pos":[8362,8437],"content":"The payment status is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sent<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> for every payment that was generated.","source":"The payment status is set to **Sent** for every payment that was generated."},{"pos":[8442,8482],"content":"Generate a positive pay file for payroll","linkify":"Generate a positive pay file for payroll","nodes":[{"content":"Generate a positive pay file for payroll","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"You can generate an electronic list of payroll checks that is provided to the bank.","pos":[8483,8566]},{"content":"When a payroll check is presented to the bank, the bank compares it to the list.","pos":[8567,8647]},{"content":"If the check matches a check in the list, the bank clears the check.","pos":[8648,8716]},{"content":"Otherwise, the bank holds the check for review.","pos":[8717,8764]},{"content":"To generate a positive pay file for payroll, follow these steps.","pos":[8767,8831]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll positive pay<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Cut-off date<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field, enter the last check date to include in the positive pay file.","pos":[8837,8968],"source":"On the **Payroll positive pay** page, in the **Cut-off date** field, enter the last check date to include in the positive pay file."},{"content":"All checks that haven’t been included in a positive pay file through this check date are included in the file.","pos":[8969,9079]},{"pos":[9084,9097],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **OK**."},{"pos":[9102,9141],"content":"Confirm a positive pay file for payroll","linkify":"Confirm a positive pay file for payroll","nodes":[{"content":"Confirm a positive pay file for payroll","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"After the checks that are listed in a payroll positive pay file are paid, you receive a confirmation number from the bank.","pos":[9142,9264]},{"content":"You can then confirm the positive pay file in your organization's data.","pos":[9265,9336]},{"content":"When you confirm a positive pay file, you record the confirmation number that you received from the bank.","pos":[9337,9442]},{"content":"To confirm a positive pay file, follow these steps.","pos":[9445,9496]},{"pos":[9502,9621],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll positive pay file summary<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select a payroll positive pay file that has a status of <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Created<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Payroll positive pay file summary** page, select a payroll positive pay file that has a status of **Created**."},{"pos":[9626,9649],"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirmation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Click **Confirmation**."},{"pos":[9654,9739],"content":"Enter the confirmation number that you received from the bank, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Enter the confirmation number that you received from the bank, and then click **OK**."},{"pos":[9744,9783],"content":"If required: Recall a positive pay file","linkify":"If required: Recall a positive pay file","nodes":[{"content":"If required: Recall a positive pay file","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"If you must change a payroll positive pay file, you can recall it.","pos":[9784,9850]},{"content":"When you recall a positive pay file, the field that indicates whether each check has been included in a positive pay file is reset.","pos":[9851,9982]},{"content":"You can then create a new positive pay file.","pos":[9983,10027]},{"content":"To recall a positive pay file, follow these steps.","pos":[10030,10080]},{"pos":[10086,10205],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payroll positive pay file summary<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select a payroll positive pay file that has a status of <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Created<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Payroll positive pay file summary** page, select a payroll positive pay file that has a status of **Created**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recall<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[10210,10227],"source":"Click **Recall**."},{"content":"You receive a message that states that the recall process was successful.","pos":[10228,10301]},{"pos":[10306,10328],"content":"Post a payment journal","linkify":"Post a payment journal","nodes":[{"content":"Post a payment journal","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"You can post a payment journal after you generate checks and electronic payments as described earlier in this topic.","pos":[10329,10445]},{"content":"To post a payment journal, follow these steps.","pos":[10448,10494]},{"pos":[10500,10644],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Payment journal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select the payment journal, and then, on the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Lines<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Journal voucher<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page.","source":"On the **Payment journal** page, select the payment journal, and then, on the Action Pane, click **Lines** to open the **Journal voucher** page."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Post<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[10649,10686],"source":"On the **Post** menu, click **Post**."},{"content":"The payment journal lines are settled to the vendor invoice that was created and posted.","pos":[10687,10775]},{"content":"You receive a message that indicates the number of vouchers that were posted.","pos":[10776,10853]}]}