{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Printing in Finance and Operations applications\ndescription: In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device. This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.\nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 69161\nms.assetid: 7815bddd-c4f4-4bc3-a29b-315458065374\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tjvass\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Printing in Finance and Operations applications\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nIn Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device. This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.\n\nPrinting overview\n-----------------\n\nMicrosoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations provides integrated services and client applications that make it easy to generate, store, and distribute documents that support business activity. In Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device. In addition, you can export Finance and Operations pages and reports directly from the client, as PDF files or Microsoft Office documents. Finally, the distributed workload lets you print business documents directly from a mobile device by using network resources. Although printing requirements might vary, all industries typically must create hard copies of business documents by using Finance and Operations. Printing documents on network devices from hosted applications presents a unique set of challenges. Here are some examples:\n\n-   Print drivers might not be available on the user's device.\n-   The user’s device might not be connected to the corporate network.\n\nBy using a dedicated host and following a few easy steps, system administrators can configure deployments so that users can print directly from business applications on network devices.\n\n### Printing scenarios in Finance and Operations applications\n\nThe following table describes the three primary printing scenarios in Finance and Operations applications.\n\n| Scenario                        | Goal                                                      | Solution                                                                                                            |\n|---------------------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| 1. Printing what you see        | Print what is currently shown in the browser.             | A “print-friendly” version of the webpage is generated for the browser.                                             |\n| 2. Interactive printing         | Print a precision document on a locally connected device. | You can export a PDF version of the report and download it to the browser.                                          |\n| 3. Printing on a network device | Send a precision document to a domain printer device.     | A precision document is sent to a client application that runs on a server that is hosted in the customer’s domain. |\n\nBecause the solution varies, depending on the scenario, Finance and Operations applications provide built-in services and tooling to help users accomplish their goals:\n\n-   **Scenario 1** is supported by the browser’s rendering of the HTML5 client.\n-   **Scenario 2** uses client applications and Microsoft Office 365 services.\n-   **Scenario 3** requires support from client applications and from services that are hosted in Microsoft Azure.\n\nIn addition to the platform that is deployed to the Azure subscription, Finance and Operations applications provide customers with an integrated, first-party Azure application that helps them more easily use domain-hosted devices to print documents.\n\n## Service overview\nWhile documents that are produced by the hosted applications are waiting to be printed on a network-connected device, they are stored in Azure blob storage. The [Document Routing Agent](install-document-routing-agent.md) uses Azure authentication to establish a secure channel to the Azure services. **Execution sequence**\n\n1.  The report is generated by Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) and stored in Azure blob storage. Attached printer settings are stored together with the document.\n2.  The Document Routing Agent queries the Azure Service Bus queue for active jobs.\n3.  The document is downloaded by the Document Routing Agent and spooled to the network printer.\n\nThe client-based solution lets customers manage the scale of their printing needs. Customers who have heavy-volume printing workloads can install many Document Routing Agents to increase the number of concurrent printing operations. Alternatively, some customers require very few installations of the Document Routing Agent to handle their anticipated printing needs.\n\n### Service components for network printing\n\nThe following diagram shows the basic components that help support network printing operations. [![service-components-for-network-printing\\_2016](./media/service-components-for-network-printing_2016.png)](./media/service-components-for-network-printing_2016.png) Note that a single printer can be registered with multiple Document Routing Agents. To resolve the printer preferences, the hosted service uses the network path that uniquely identifies every network printer. As a result, even when a printer is registered by multiple clients, it appears as a single selection in the list of printers available in Finance and Operations applications.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,805],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Printing in Finance and Operations applications\ndescription: In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device. This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.\nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 69161\nms.assetid: 7815bddd-c4f4-4bc3-a29b-315458065374\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tjvass\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Printing in Finance and Operations applications","nodes":[{"pos":[0,47],"content":"Printing in Finance and Operations applications","nodes":[{"content":"Printing in Finance and Operations applications","pos":[0,47]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device. This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,204],"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device. This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.","nodes":[{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device. This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.","pos":[0,204],"nodes":[{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device.","pos":[0,140]},{"content":"This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.","pos":[141,204]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[813,860],"content":"Printing in Finance and Operations applications","linkify":"Printing in Finance and Operations applications","nodes":[{"content":"Printing in Finance and Operations applications","pos":[0,47]}]},{"content":"In Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device.","pos":[906,1046]},{"content":"This article provides an overview of how documents are printed.","pos":[1047,1110]},{"pos":[1112,1129],"content":"Printing overview","linkify":"Printing overview","nodes":[{"content":"Printing overview","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations provides integrated services and client applications that make it easy to generate, store, and distribute documents that support business activity.","pos":[1149,1346]},{"content":"In Finance and Operations, you can print documents by using either a local printer or a network-connected device.","pos":[1347,1460]},{"content":"In addition, you can export Finance and Operations pages and reports directly from the client, as PDF files or Microsoft Office documents.","pos":[1461,1599]},{"content":"Finally, the distributed workload lets you print business documents directly from a mobile device by using network resources.","pos":[1600,1725]},{"content":"Although printing requirements might vary, all industries typically must create hard copies of business documents by using Finance and Operations.","pos":[1726,1872]},{"content":"Printing documents on network devices from hosted applications presents a unique set of challenges.","pos":[1873,1972]},{"content":"Here are some examples:","pos":[1973,1996]},{"content":"Print drivers might not be available on the user's device.","pos":[2002,2060]},{"content":"The user’s device might not be connected to the corporate network.","pos":[2065,2131]},{"content":"By using a dedicated host and following a few easy steps, system administrators can configure deployments so that users can print directly from business applications on network devices.","pos":[2133,2318]},{"pos":[2324,2381],"content":"Printing scenarios in Finance and Operations applications","linkify":"Printing scenarios in Finance and Operations applications","nodes":[{"content":"Printing scenarios in Finance and Operations applications","pos":[0,57]}]},{"content":"The following table describes the three primary printing scenarios in Finance and Operations applications.","pos":[2383,2489]},{"content":"Scenario","pos":[2493,2501]},{"content":"Goal","pos":[2527,2531]},{"content":"Solution","pos":[2587,2595]},{"content":"1. Printing what you see","pos":[2921,2945]},{"content":"Print what is currently shown in the browser.","pos":[2955,3000]},{"content":"A “print-friendly” version of the webpage is generated for the browser.","pos":[3015,3086]},{"content":"2. Interactive printing","pos":[3135,3158]},{"content":"Print a precision document on a locally connected device.","pos":[3169,3226]},{"content":"You can export a PDF version of the report and download it to the browser.","pos":[3229,3303]},{"content":"3. Printing on a network device","pos":[3349,3380]},{"content":"Send a precision document to a domain printer device.","pos":[3383,3436]},{"content":"A precision document is sent to a client application that runs on a server that is hosted in the customer’s domain.","pos":[3443,3558]},{"content":"Because the solution varies, depending on the scenario, Finance and Operations applications provide built-in services and tooling to help users accomplish their goals:","pos":[3562,3729]},{"pos":[3735,3810],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Scenario 1<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is supported by the browser’s rendering of the HTML5 client.","source":"**Scenario 1** is supported by the browser’s rendering of the HTML5 client."},{"pos":[3815,3889],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Scenario 2<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> uses client applications and Microsoft Office 365 services.","source":"**Scenario 2** uses client applications and Microsoft Office 365 services."},{"pos":[3894,4004],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Scenario 3<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> requires support from client applications and from services that are hosted in Microsoft Azure.","source":"**Scenario 3** requires support from client applications and from services that are hosted in Microsoft Azure."},{"content":"In addition to the platform that is deployed to the Azure subscription, Finance and Operations applications provide customers with an integrated, first-party Azure application that helps them more easily use domain-hosted devices to print documents.","pos":[4006,4255]},{"pos":[4260,4276],"content":"Service overview","linkify":"Service overview","nodes":[{"content":"Service overview","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"While documents that are produced by the hosted applications are waiting to be printed on a network-connected device, they are stored in Azure blob storage.","pos":[4277,4433]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Document Routing Agent<ept id=\"p1\">](install-document-routing-agent.md)</ept> uses Azure authentication to establish a secure channel to the Azure services.","pos":[4434,4576],"source":" The [Document Routing Agent](install-document-routing-agent.md) uses Azure authentication to establish a secure channel to the Azure services."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Execution sequence<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[4577,4599],"source":"**Execution sequence**"},{"content":"The report is generated by Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) and stored in Azure blob storage.","pos":[4605,4712]},{"content":"Attached printer settings are stored together with the document.","pos":[4713,4777]},{"content":"The Document Routing Agent queries the Azure Service Bus queue for active jobs.","pos":[4782,4861]},{"content":"The document is downloaded by the Document Routing Agent and spooled to the network printer.","pos":[4866,4958]},{"content":"The client-based solution lets customers manage the scale of their printing needs.","pos":[4960,5042]},{"content":"Customers who have heavy-volume printing workloads can install many Document Routing Agents to increase the number of concurrent printing operations.","pos":[5043,5192]},{"content":"Alternatively, some customers require very few installations of the Document Routing Agent to handle their anticipated printing needs.","pos":[5193,5327]},{"pos":[5333,5372],"content":"Service components for network printing","linkify":"Service components for network printing","nodes":[{"content":"Service components for network printing","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"The following diagram shows the basic components that help support network printing operations.","pos":[5374,5469]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>service-components-for-network-printing<ph id=\"ph2\">\\_</ph>2016<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/service-components-for-network-printing_2016.png)](./media/service-components-for-network-printing_2016.png)</ept> Note that a single printer can be registered with multiple Document Routing Agents.","pos":[5470,5720],"source":"[![service-components-for-network-printing\\_2016](./media/service-components-for-network-printing_2016.png)](./media/service-components-for-network-printing_2016.png) Note that a single printer can be registered with multiple Document Routing Agents."},{"content":"To resolve the printer preferences, the hosted service uses the network path that uniquely identifies every network printer.","pos":[5721,5845]},{"content":"As a result, even when a printer is registered by multiple clients, it appears as a single selection in the list of printers available in Finance and Operations applications.","pos":[5846,6020]}]}