{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Batch processing overview\ndescription: This article provides an overview of batch processing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.\nauthor: maertenm\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 62333\nms.assetid: 6135bcf7-bf8f-42ae-b2c6-458f6538e6a4\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: maertenm\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Batch processing overview\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article provides an overview of batch processing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.\n\nMany tasks in Finance and Operations can be run as part of batch jobs. For example, batch jobs can include tasks for printing reports, performing maintenance, or sending electronic documents. By using batch jobs, you can avoid slowing down your computer or the server during typical working hours. \n\nThe tasks in a batch job can run either sequentially or at the same time. Additionally, you can create dependencies between tasks. In other words, the sequence of tasks can differ, depending on whether an earlier task succeeds or fails. \n\nYou can set up recurrence patterns for batch jobs. For example, you can set up a job to process invoices automatically at the end of every month. \n\nTo monitor batch jobs, you can set up alerts. Alerts can be sent when the batch job succeeds, fails, or has finished running. \n\nAfter a batch job has been processed, you can view the history. The history includes any messages that were encountered while the job was running. \n\nUse batch groups to categorize batch tasks and run them on specific servers. The servers in your environment might have different software installed, or they might be available at different times of the day. Batch groups are used to direct batch tasks to the most appropriate server. Tasks in the same batch job can belong to different batch groups. \n\nFor example, server A is set up to print reports, and server B is set up to send electronic documents. You can use batch groups to make sure that reporting tasks are run on server A and electronic documents are processed by server B.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,690],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Batch processing overview\ndescription: This article provides an overview of batch processing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.\nauthor: maertenm\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 62333\nms.assetid: 6135bcf7-bf8f-42ae-b2c6-458f6538e6a4\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: maertenm\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Batch processing overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,25],"content":"Batch processing overview","nodes":[{"content":"Batch processing overview","pos":[0,25]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides an overview of batch processing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,107],"content":"This article provides an overview of batch processing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides an overview of batch processing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[0,107]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[698,723],"content":"Batch processing overview","linkify":"Batch processing overview","nodes":[{"content":"Batch processing overview","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"This article provides an overview of batch processing in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[769,876]},{"content":"Many tasks in Finance and Operations can be run as part of batch jobs.","pos":[878,948]},{"content":"For example, batch jobs can include tasks for printing reports, performing maintenance, or sending electronic documents.","pos":[949,1069]},{"content":"By using batch jobs, you can avoid slowing down your computer or the server during typical working hours.","pos":[1070,1175]},{"content":"The tasks in a batch job can run either sequentially or at the same time.","pos":[1178,1251]},{"content":"Additionally, you can create dependencies between tasks.","pos":[1252,1308]},{"content":"In other words, the sequence of tasks can differ, depending on whether an earlier task succeeds or fails.","pos":[1309,1414]},{"content":"You can set up recurrence patterns for batch jobs.","pos":[1417,1467]},{"content":"For example, you can set up a job to process invoices automatically at the end of every month.","pos":[1468,1562]},{"content":"To monitor batch jobs, you can set up alerts.","pos":[1565,1610]},{"content":"Alerts can be sent when the batch job succeeds, fails, or has finished running.","pos":[1611,1690]},{"content":"After a batch job has been processed, you can view the history.","pos":[1693,1756]},{"content":"The history includes any messages that were encountered while the job was running.","pos":[1757,1839]},{"content":"Use batch groups to categorize batch tasks and run them on specific servers.","pos":[1842,1918]},{"content":"The servers in your environment might have different software installed, or they might be available at different times of the day.","pos":[1919,2049]},{"content":"Batch groups are used to direct batch tasks to the most appropriate server.","pos":[2050,2125]},{"content":"Tasks in the same batch job can belong to different batch groups.","pos":[2126,2191]},{"content":"For example, server A is set up to print reports, and server B is set up to send electronic documents.","pos":[2194,2296]},{"content":"You can use batch groups to make sure that reporting tasks are run on server A and electronic documents are processed by server B.","pos":[2297,2427]}]}