{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Chinese vouchers\ndescription: This topic describes Chinese vouchers and how they are used in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerVoucherType_CN, VoucherTypeWizard_CN\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 261454\nms.search.region: China (PRC)\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: shylaw\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Chinese vouchers\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic describes Chinese vouchers and how they are used in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.\n\nYou must create a voucher document for every posted journal. You can print a paper voucher and a posted journal. Based on your requirements, you can use the Voucher type setup wizard to set up the **Get**, **Pay** and **Transfer** voucher types that are often used, or you can create new voucher types on the **Voucher type setup** page. You can use booking vouchers to enter and group transactions into the Receipt voucher, Payment voucher, or Transfer voucher. \n\nA continuous number sequence that begins from the first day of every monthly period should be assigned to each voucher type. You can define a Chinese voucher type for ledger accounts only. You can assign the voucher types to specific ledger accounts. Then, on the **Voucher type setup** page, you can define validation rules for posting voucher transactions to the specified ledger accounts. During voucher posting, validation is run, based on the rules that are specified on the **Voucher type setup** page. You receive a message if the voucher type that is selected for the selected ledger account is incorrect. \n\nFor example, you select a ledger account of the **Credit** type for the **Get** voucher type. However, the validation rule that you defined for the **Get** voucher type specifies that the ledger account must be a debit account. In this case, you receive a message that states that the Chinese voucher type isn't valid. You can then make the appropriate changes and post the voucher again. \n\nFor more information, see [Set up Chinese vouchers](./tasks/set-up-chinese-vouchers.md).\n\n## Voucher creation methods\nYou can create voucher transactions on the **General journal** page by using the **Simple** or **Advanced** method. If you create journal vouchers of a single voucher type by using the **Simple** method, the voucher type that is selected on all the journal lines should be the same. The **Advanced** method lets you create multiple journal lines of different voucher types. \n\n## Check for continuity in voucher numbers\nThe Chinese voucher number should be sequential, and there should be no gaps in the fiscal period. You can run a batch process to determine whether there are gaps in the Chinese voucher numbers. The batch process verifies the transaction dates and then renumbers the vouchers for continuity. For tracking purposes, you can generate the **Chinese voucher continuity check** report. This report shows the history of renumbered Chinese vouchers. For more information, see [Verify the continuity of vouchers](./tasks/chinese-voucher-continuity-check.md).\n\n## Printing a Chinese voucher\nYou can print a Chinese voucher either before or after you post the voucher. The printed voucher shows information such as the history of renumbered Chinese vouchers, and tax information before or after the voucher was posted. You can review the printed information to verify that the information is the same before and after posting, and that the information is correct. For example, if you select sales tax in a journal voucher, the final voucher information includes the sales tax. However, the sales tax might differ from the sales tax that was part of the journal. The printed result must be accurate, and it must be the same as the result that is generated after the final posting. Therefore, you can print a Chinese voucher that has the correct information from both the journal voucher and the voucher transactions. You can also print Chinese vouchers in a batch after you filter the information by Chinese voucher type and fiscal period.\n\n## Additional resources\n- [Post vouchers from the general journal](./tasks/post-vouchers-general-journal.md)\n- [Post vouchers from other modules](./tasks/post-vouchers-other-modules-like-sales-invoices.md)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,716],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Chinese vouchers\ndescription: This topic describes Chinese vouchers and how they are used in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: LedgerVoucherType_CN, VoucherTypeWizard_CN\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 261454\nms.search.region: China (PRC)\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: shylaw\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n","nodes":[{"content":"Chinese vouchers","nodes":[{"pos":[0,16],"content":"Chinese vouchers","nodes":[{"content":"Chinese vouchers","pos":[0,16]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic describes Chinese vouchers and how they are used in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,133],"content":"This topic describes Chinese vouchers and how they are used in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes Chinese vouchers and how they are used in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[0,133]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[724,740],"content":"Chinese vouchers","linkify":"Chinese vouchers","nodes":[{"content":"Chinese vouchers","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"This topic describes Chinese vouchers and how they are used in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[786,919]},{"content":"You must create a voucher document for every posted journal.","pos":[921,981]},{"content":"You can print a paper voucher and a posted journal.","pos":[982,1033]},{"content":"Based on your requirements, you can use the Voucher type setup wizard to set up the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pay<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Transfer<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> voucher types that are often used, or you can create new voucher types on the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Voucher type setup<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> page.","pos":[1034,1258],"source":" Based on your requirements, you can use the Voucher type setup wizard to set up the **Get**, **Pay** and **Transfer** voucher types that are often used, or you can create new voucher types on the **Voucher type setup** page."},{"content":"You can use booking vouchers to enter and group transactions into the Receipt voucher, Payment voucher, or Transfer voucher.","pos":[1259,1383]},{"content":"A continuous number sequence that begins from the first day of every monthly period should be assigned to each voucher type.","pos":[1386,1510]},{"content":"You can define a Chinese voucher type for ledger accounts only.","pos":[1511,1574]},{"content":"You can assign the voucher types to specific ledger accounts.","pos":[1575,1636]},{"content":"Then, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Voucher type setup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can define validation rules for posting voucher transactions to the specified ledger accounts.","pos":[1637,1777],"source":" Then, on the **Voucher type setup** page, you can define validation rules for posting voucher transactions to the specified ledger accounts."},{"content":"During voucher posting, validation is run, based on the rules that are specified on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Voucher type setup<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[1778,1894],"source":" During voucher posting, validation is run, based on the rules that are specified on the **Voucher type setup** page."},{"content":"You receive a message if the voucher type that is selected for the selected ledger account is incorrect.","pos":[1895,1999]},{"content":"For example, you select a ledger account of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Credit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> type for the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Get<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> voucher type.","pos":[2002,2095],"source":"For example, you select a ledger account of the **Credit** type for the **Get** voucher type."},{"content":"However, the validation rule that you defined for the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> voucher type specifies that the ledger account must be a debit account.","pos":[2096,2229],"source":" However, the validation rule that you defined for the **Get** voucher type specifies that the ledger account must be a debit account."},{"content":"In this case, you receive a message that states that the Chinese voucher type isn't valid.","pos":[2230,2320]},{"content":"You can then make the appropriate changes and post the voucher again.","pos":[2321,2390]},{"pos":[2393,2481],"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Set up Chinese vouchers<ept id=\"p1\">](./tasks/set-up-chinese-vouchers.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information, see [Set up Chinese vouchers](./tasks/set-up-chinese-vouchers.md)."},{"pos":[2486,2510],"content":"Voucher creation methods","linkify":"Voucher creation methods","nodes":[{"content":"Voucher creation methods","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"You can create voucher transactions on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General journal<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page by using the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Simple<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Advanced<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> method.","pos":[2511,2626],"source":"You can create voucher transactions on the **General journal** page by using the **Simple** or **Advanced** method."},{"content":"If you create journal vouchers of a single voucher type by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Simple<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method, the voucher type that is selected on all the journal lines should be the same.","pos":[2627,2793],"source":" If you create journal vouchers of a single voucher type by using the **Simple** method, the voucher type that is selected on all the journal lines should be the same."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Advanced<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method lets you create multiple journal lines of different voucher types.","pos":[2794,2884],"source":" The **Advanced** method lets you create multiple journal lines of different voucher types."},{"pos":[2890,2929],"content":"Check for continuity in voucher numbers","linkify":"Check for continuity in voucher numbers","nodes":[{"content":"Check for continuity in voucher numbers","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"The Chinese voucher number should be sequential, and there should be no gaps in the fiscal period.","pos":[2930,3028]},{"content":"You can run a batch process to determine whether there are gaps in the Chinese voucher numbers.","pos":[3029,3124]},{"content":"The batch process verifies the transaction dates and then renumbers the vouchers for continuity.","pos":[3125,3221]},{"content":"For tracking purposes, you can generate the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Chinese voucher continuity check<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report.","pos":[3222,3310],"source":" For tracking purposes, you can generate the **Chinese voucher continuity check** report."},{"content":"This report shows the history of renumbered Chinese vouchers.","pos":[3311,3372]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Verify the continuity of vouchers<ept id=\"p1\">](./tasks/chinese-voucher-continuity-check.md)</ept>.","pos":[3373,3480],"source":" For more information, see [Verify the continuity of vouchers](./tasks/chinese-voucher-continuity-check.md)."},{"pos":[3485,3511],"content":"Printing a Chinese voucher","linkify":"Printing a Chinese voucher","nodes":[{"content":"Printing a Chinese voucher","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"You can print a Chinese voucher either before or after you post the voucher.","pos":[3512,3588]},{"content":"The printed voucher shows information such as the history of renumbered Chinese vouchers, and tax information before or after the voucher was posted.","pos":[3589,3738]},{"content":"You can review the printed information to verify that the information is the same before and after posting, and that the information is correct.","pos":[3739,3883]},{"content":"For example, if you select sales tax in a journal voucher, the final voucher information includes the sales tax.","pos":[3884,3996]},{"content":"However, the sales tax might differ from the sales tax that was part of the journal.","pos":[3997,4081]},{"content":"The printed result must be accurate, and it must be the same as the result that is generated after the final posting.","pos":[4082,4199]},{"content":"Therefore, you can print a Chinese voucher that has the correct information from both the journal voucher and the voucher transactions.","pos":[4200,4335]},{"content":"You can also print Chinese vouchers in a batch after you filter the information by Chinese voucher type and fiscal period.","pos":[4336,4458]},{"pos":[4463,4483],"content":"Additional resources","linkify":"Additional resources","nodes":[{"content":"Additional resources","pos":[0,20]}]},{"pos":[4486,4568],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Post vouchers from the general journal<ept id=\"p1\">](./tasks/post-vouchers-general-journal.md)</ept>","source":"[Post vouchers from the general journal](./tasks/post-vouchers-general-journal.md)"},{"pos":[4571,4665],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Post vouchers from other modules<ept id=\"p1\">](./tasks/post-vouchers-other-modules-like-sales-invoices.md)</ept>","source":"[Post vouchers from other modules](./tasks/post-vouchers-other-modules-like-sales-invoices.md)"}]}