{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Italian sales tax books\ndescription: The topic describes how to set up and use Italian sales tax books and Italian sales tax book sections.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: CustParameters, LedgerJournalSetup, ProjJournalName, TaxBook, TaxBookSection, TaxBookSectionLookupVoucherSeries, TaxBookStatus, TaxBookTable, VendParameters\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 268654\nms.search.region: Italy\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: ilyako\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Italian sales tax books\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThe topic describes how to set up and use Italian sales tax books and Italian sales tax book sections.\n\nAccording to Italian fiscal legislation, every value-added tax (VAT) transaction must belong to a tax book (*Libro IVA*) that will be used for tax reporting. To fulfill these legislative requirements, Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition implements Italian sales tax books. Sales tax books can be of different types. You must specify the sales tax book type to help guarantee that all sales and purchase transactions are included on the **Italian sales tax payment** report. You can keep as many sales tax books of the **Sales** and **Purchase** types as you require. Every tax book can be divided into multiple tax book sections (*Sezionale IVA*). All sales tax transactions must be sequentially numbered (without gaps) and ordered by posting date. A tax book section is equivalent to a number sequence for the Italian sales tax voucher number (*Protocollo IVA*) that must always be applied during posting to help guarantee chronological order by posting date.\n\n## Prerequisites\nThe following table shows the prerequisites that must be in place before you start.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Category</th>\n<th>Prerequisite</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td><strong>Setup:</strong> Legal entity</td>\n<td>The primary address of the legal entity must be in Italy. (Click <strong>Organization administration</strong> &gt; <strong>Organizations</strong> &gt; <strong>Legal entities</strong> &gt; <strong>Addresses</strong> &gt; <strong>Country/region</strong>.)</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td><strong>Setup:</strong> Number sequences</td>\n<td>Set up as many number sequences as you require to cover all the required types of sales tax transactions. (Click <strong>Organization administration</strong> &gt; <strong>Number sequences</strong> &gt; <strong>Number sequences</strong>.) All these number sequences must be continuous and must have <strong>Company</strong> scope.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td><strong>Setup:</strong> Journal names</td>\n<td>Set up the required journal names. (Click <strong>General Ledger</strong> &gt; <strong>Journal setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Journal names</strong> or <strong>Project management and accounting</strong> &gt; <strong>Setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Journals</strong> &gt; <strong>Journal names</strong>.) On the <strong>General</strong> FastTab, in the <strong>Sales tax</strong> section, in the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field, specify one of the following values:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Not included</strong> – Select this value for invoices and credit notes that come from countries/regions that are outside the European community.</li>\n<li><strong>Purchase</strong> – Select this value for purchase invoices and credit notes.</li>\n<li><strong>Sales</strong> – Select this value for sales invoices and credit notes.</li>\n<li><strong>Empty</strong> – Select this value for all other types of transactions.</li>\n</ul>\nIn some cases, the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field is set automatically, based on the <strong>Journal type</strong> value. For example, if the <strong>Journal type</strong> field is set to <strong>Invoice register</strong>, the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field is set to <strong>Purchase</strong> by default.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td><strong>Setup:</strong> Module parameters</td>\n<td>For vouchers to follow the number sequences of the related invoices and credit notes, you must select the <strong>Reuse numbers</strong> check box when you define the number sequences for those invoices and credit notes. You can find this check box on the <strong>Number sequences</strong> tab of the following pages:\n<ul>\n<li>Accounts receivable parameters</li>\n<li>Accounts payable parameters</li>\n<li>Project management and accounting parameters</li>\n</ul>\nFor example, on the <strong>Accounts receivable parameters</strong> page, on the <strong>Number sequences</strong> tab, select the <strong>Reuse numbers</strong> check box for <strong>Free text invoice voucher</strong> to synchronize number allocation for free text invoice vouchers and free text invoices.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n## Set up sales tax books\nSales tax books are used for sales tax reporting. To set up Italian sales tax books, click **Tax** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Italian sales tax books**. The following table describes the fields that are available on the **Italian sales tax books** page.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Sales tax book</td>\n<td>Enter the ID of the sales tax book.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Name</td>\n<td>Enter a description of the sales tax book.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Sales tax book type</td>\n<td>Select the nature of the operations that will be performed through the sales tax book sections that you will attach to the sales tax book. The following values are available:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Purchase</strong> – Select this value for purchase invoices and credit notes.</li>\n<li><strong>Sales</strong> – Select this value for sales invoices and credit notes.</li>\n<li><strong>Not included</strong> – Select this value for invoices and credit notes that come from countries/regions that are outside the European community. This type is used only for statistical purposes and won't be included on the final fiscal tax book reports.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Settlement period</td>\n<td>Select an existing sales tax settlement period. When a sales tax book is printed, if the <strong>Update</strong> check box is selected on the <strong>Sales tax payment</strong> page, the date in the <strong>From date</strong> field is compared to the selected settlement period. The settlement period is also used to identify which sales tax books and sales tax book sections must be closed when a sales tax settlement is updated for a settlement period.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Closed to</td>\n<td>The latest closing date from the related sales tax book sections that belong to the selected sales tax book.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>EU sales</td>\n<td>Select a sales tax book of the <strong>Sales</strong> type, and attach it to the current sales tax book of the <strong>Purchase</strong> type. This field is used if the selected sales tax book must include European Union (EU) purchase transactions from the current book on sales tax reports. This field is unavailable for sales tax books of the <strong>Sales</strong> and <strong>Not included</strong> types.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>ATECOFIN Code</td>\n<td>Select the tax code for reporting.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Print summary and payment</td>\n<td>Select this option to print the summary and payment report. This field is available only for sales tax books of the <strong>Sales</strong> type.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n## Set up sales tax book sections\nSales tax book sections are a repository where ledger transactions are posted according to their nature. The voucher numbering is driven by the sales tax book sections. To set up Italian sales tax book sections, click **Tax** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Italian sales tax book sections**. The following table describes the fields that are available on the **Italian sales tax book sections** page.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Sales tax book</td>\n<td>Select one of the existing sales tax books that the sales tax book section is attached to.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Sales tax book section</td>\n<td>Enter the ID of sales tax book section.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Name</td>\n<td>Enter a description of the sales tax book section.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Number sequence code</td>\n<td>Select the number sequence code for the sales tax book section. The number sequence code that you select depends on the type of sales tax book that the sales tax book section is attached to:\n<ul>\n<li>For a sales tax book of the <strong>Purchase</strong> type: Select number sequence codes that are defined for purchase invoice vouchers or purchase credit note vouchers on the <strong>Accounts payable parameters</strong> page, or number sequence codes that are used on the <strong>Journal names</strong> page for vouchers that have the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field set to <strong>Purchase</strong>.</li>\n<li>For a sales tax book of the <strong>Sales</strong> type: Select number sequence codes that are defined for sales invoice vouchers or sales credit note vouchers or free text invoice vouchers or free text credit note vouchers on the <strong>Accounts receivable</strong> <strong>parameters</strong> page, or number sequence codes that are used on the <strong>Journal names</strong> page for vouchers that have the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field set to <strong>Sales</strong>.</li>\n<li>For a sales tax book of the <strong>Not included</strong> type: Select any suitable number sequence code.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Closed to</td>\n<td>Enter the end date of the last closed sales tax settlement period. This field is used to filter data on the sales tax report.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Close Italian sales tax book section</td>\n<td>The closing date of the Italian sales tax book for a tax period. You can't post or reverse an invoice that has a date that is earlier than the closing date of the tax period. This field is updated with the closing date of the tax period. The <strong>Update</strong> check box must also be selected on the <strong>Sales tax payment</strong> page.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nThe following button is also available.\n\n| Button | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n|--------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Create | Automatically create all the required sales tax book sections for existing sales tax books of the **Sales** and **Purchase** types. Sales tax book sections are created for every number sequence that is defined for purchase invoice vouchers or purchase credit note vouchers or sales invoice vouchers or sales credit note vouchers or free text invoice vouchers or free text credit note vouchers on the **Accounts payable parameters**, **Accounts receivable parameters**, or **Project management and accounting parameters** page, and for every number sequence that is used on the **Journal names** page for vouchers that have the **Italian sales tax book** field set to **Purchase** or **Sales**. Every sales tax book section that is created is automatically attached to the default sales tax book. (The sales tax book must be created before the sales tax book sections.) If several sales tax books of the same sales tax book type (**Sales** or **Purchase**) exist, the first sales tax book is used by default. However, you can manually change this attachment. If no sales tax book exists, no sales tax book sections are automatically created. |\n\n## Sales tax book status\nWhen a new sales tax period is created, sales tax book lines are automatically set up for every sales tax book that exists. If an additional sales tax book is created, lines can be manually created for existing periods that haven't been closed. Click **Tax** &gt; **Indirect taxes** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Sales tax settlement periods**, and then click **Sales tax book status**. The following table describes the tabs on the **Sales tax book status** page.\n\n| Tab      | Description                                                                                               |\n|----------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Overview | View the page status of the sales tax books. All the fields are locked for manual updates.                |\n| General  | View the same information that appears on the **Overview** tab, but only for the selected sales tax book. |\n\nThe following table describes the fields that are available.\n\n| Field             | Description                                                                                      |\n|-------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Sales tax book    | Select the sales tax book ID that you set up on the **Italian sales tax books** page.            |\n| Name              | Enter the name of the tax book.                                                                  |\n| First page number | The first page number that will be used on the final sales tax report for this sales tax period. |\n| Changed to        | The page number that is specified in the **Change first page number** dialog box.                |\n| Last page number  | The last page number that will be used on the final sales tax report for this sales tax period.  |\n| Settlement period | The settlement period that is used in the sales tax book.                                        |\n| From date         | The start date for the settlement period.                                                        |\n| To date           | The end date for the settlement period.                                                          |\n\nThe following button is also available.\n\n| Button                   | Description                                                                                                                                            |\n|--------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Change first page number | Open the **Change first page number** dialog box, where you can change the first page number that will be used for the current open settlement period. |\n\n### Change first page number dialog box\n\nUse the **Change first page number** dialog box to change the number of the first page on the final sales tax report for this sales tax settlement period. The page number then appears in the **Changed to** column on the **Sales tax book status** page and is used as the first page number of the final sales tax report that is printed for the current tax period. The following table describes the fields that are available in the **Change first page number** dialog box.\n\n| Field             | Description                                                           |\n|-------------------|-----------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| First page number | The current first page number for the selected sales tax book.        |\n| Changed to        | Enter the new first page number to use on the final sales tax report. |\n\n## Using sales tax books\nWhen the setup is completed, the sales tax book sections appear on the **Number sequences** tab of the following pages:\n\n-   Accounts receivable parameters\n-   Accounts payable parameters\n-   Project management and accounting parameters\n\nVoucher numbers that are assigned during posting must be sequentially ordered by posting date, and the sales tax transactions that use the same number sequence code must be posted in order. If the voucher numbers aren't sequentially ordered, the user receives an error message. In addition, posting is interrupted if a sales tax transaction isn't assigned to any sales tax book section when the user updates an invoice. Whenever a voucher is posted through a sales tax book section, the identifiers of the related sales tax book and sales tax book section are saved in the tax transactions. (Click **Tax** &gt; **Sales tax inquiries** &gt; **Posted sales tax**, and then click the **Posting** tab.) This data can then be used during further sales tax reporting. Italian sales tax books are used for filtering, grouping, and sorting on the report that is accessed at **Tax** &gt; **Declarations** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Sales Tax (Italy)**.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,800],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Italian sales tax books\ndescription: The topic describes how to set up and use Italian sales tax books and Italian sales tax book sections.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: CustParameters, LedgerJournalSetup, ProjJournalName, TaxBook, TaxBookSection, TaxBookSectionLookupVoucherSeries, TaxBookStatus, TaxBookTable, VendParameters\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 268654\nms.search.region: Italy\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: ilyako\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n","nodes":[{"content":"Italian sales tax books","nodes":[{"pos":[0,23],"content":"Italian sales tax books","nodes":[{"content":"Italian sales tax books","pos":[0,23]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"The topic describes how to set up and use Italian sales tax books and Italian sales tax book sections.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,102],"content":"The topic describes how to set up and use Italian sales tax books and Italian sales tax book sections.","nodes":[{"content":"The topic describes how to set up and use Italian sales tax books and Italian sales tax book sections.","pos":[0,102]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[808,831],"content":"Italian sales tax books","linkify":"Italian sales tax books","nodes":[{"content":"Italian sales tax books","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"The topic describes how to set up and use Italian sales tax books and Italian sales tax book sections.","pos":[877,979]},{"content":"According to Italian fiscal legislation, every value-added tax (VAT) transaction must belong to a tax book (<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Libro IVA<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>) that will be used for tax reporting.","pos":[981,1138],"source":"According to Italian fiscal legislation, every value-added tax (VAT) transaction must belong to a tax book (*Libro IVA*) that will be used for tax reporting."},{"content":"To fulfill these legislative requirements, Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition implements Italian sales tax books.","pos":[1139,1287]},{"content":"Sales tax books can be of different types.","pos":[1288,1330]},{"content":"You must specify the sales tax book type to help guarantee that all sales and purchase transactions are included on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Italian sales tax payment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> report.","pos":[1331,1488],"source":" You must specify the sales tax book type to help guarantee that all sales and purchase transactions are included on the **Italian sales tax payment** report."},{"content":"You can keep as many sales tax books of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> types as you require.","pos":[1489,1581],"source":" You can keep as many sales tax books of the **Sales** and **Purchase** types as you require."},{"content":"Every tax book can be divided into multiple tax book sections (<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Sezionale IVA<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>).","pos":[1582,1662],"source":" Every tax book can be divided into multiple tax book sections (*Sezionale IVA*)."},{"content":"All sales tax transactions must be sequentially numbered (without gaps) and ordered by posting date.","pos":[1663,1763]},{"content":"A tax book section is equivalent to a number sequence for the Italian sales tax voucher number (<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Protocollo IVA<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>) that must always be applied during posting to help guarantee chronological order by posting date.","pos":[1764,1975],"source":" A tax book section is equivalent to a number sequence for the Italian sales tax voucher number (*Protocollo IVA*) that must always be applied during posting to help guarantee chronological order by posting date."},{"pos":[1980,1993],"content":"Prerequisites","linkify":"Prerequisites","nodes":[{"content":"Prerequisites","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"The following table shows the prerequisites that must be in place before you start.","pos":[1994,2077]},{"content":"Category","pos":[2182,2190]},{"content":"Prerequisite","pos":[2200,2212]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Setup:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> Legal entity","pos":[2262,2298],"source":"<strong>Setup:</strong> Legal entity"},{"content":"The primary address of the legal entity must be in Italy.","pos":[2308,2365]},{"content":"(Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Organization administration<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Organizations<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Legal entities<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Addresses<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph4\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Country/region<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.)","pos":[2366,2561],"source":" (Click <strong>Organization administration</strong> &gt; <strong>Organizations</strong> &gt; <strong>Legal entities</strong> &gt; <strong>Addresses</strong> &gt; <strong>Country/region</strong>.)"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Setup:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> Number sequences","pos":[2595,2635],"source":"<strong>Setup:</strong> Number sequences"},{"content":"Set up as many number sequences as you require to cover all the required types of sales tax transactions.","pos":[2645,2750]},{"content":"(Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Organization administration<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Number sequences<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Number sequences<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.) All these number sequences must be continuous and must have <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Company<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> scope.","pos":[2751,2974],"source":" (Click <strong>Organization administration</strong> &gt; <strong>Number sequences</strong> &gt; <strong>Number sequences</strong>.) All these number sequences must be continuous and must have <strong>Company</strong> scope."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Setup:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> Journal names","pos":[3007,3044],"source":"<strong>Setup:</strong> Journal names"},{"content":"Set up the required journal names.","pos":[3054,3088]},{"content":"(Click <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>General Ledger<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journal setup<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journal names<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> or <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Project management and accounting<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph4\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p6\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journals<ept id=\"p6\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <ph id=\"ph5\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p7\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journal names<ept id=\"p7\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.) On the <bpt id=\"p8\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>General<ept id=\"p8\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> FastTab, in the <bpt id=\"p9\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales tax<ept id=\"p9\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> section, in the <bpt id=\"p10\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Italian sales tax book<ept id=\"p10\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, specify one of the following values:","pos":[3089,3525],"source":" (Click <strong>General Ledger</strong> &gt; <strong>Journal setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Journal names</strong> or <strong>Project management and accounting</strong> &gt; <strong>Setup</strong> &gt; <strong>Journals</strong> &gt; <strong>Journal names</strong>.) On the <strong>General</strong> FastTab, in the <strong>Sales tax</strong> section, in the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field, specify one of the following values:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Not included<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this value for invoices and credit notes that come from countries/regions that are outside the European community.","pos":[3535,3688],"source":"<strong>Not included</strong> – Select this value for invoices and credit notes that come from countries/regions that are outside the European community."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this value for purchase invoices and credit notes.","pos":[3698,3783],"source":"<strong>Purchase</strong> – Select this value for purchase invoices and credit notes."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this value for sales invoices and credit notes.","pos":[3793,3872],"source":"<strong>Sales</strong> – Select this value for sales invoices and credit notes."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Empty<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this value for all other types of transactions.","pos":[3882,3961],"source":"<strong>Empty</strong> – Select this value for all other types of transactions."},{"content":"In some cases, the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Italian sales tax book<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set automatically, based on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journal type<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> value.","pos":[3973,4109],"source":"\nIn some cases, the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field is set automatically, based on the <strong>Journal type</strong> value."},{"content":"For example, if the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journal type<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Invoice register<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Italian sales tax book<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> by default.","pos":[4110,4308],"source":" For example, if the <strong>Journal type</strong> field is set to <strong>Invoice register</strong>, the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field is set to <strong>Purchase</strong> by default."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Setup:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> Module parameters","pos":[4342,4383],"source":"<strong>Setup:</strong> Module parameters"},{"content":"For vouchers to follow the number sequences of the related invoices and credit notes, you must select the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Reuse numbers<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> check box when you define the number sequences for those invoices and credit notes.","pos":[4393,4613],"source":"For vouchers to follow the number sequences of the related invoices and credit notes, you must select the <strong>Reuse numbers</strong> check box when you define the number sequences for those invoices and credit notes."},{"content":"You can find this check box on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Number sequences<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab of the following pages:","pos":[4614,4710],"source":" You can find this check box on the <strong>Number sequences</strong> tab of the following pages:\n"},{"content":"Accounts receivable parameters","pos":[4720,4750]},{"content":"Accounts payable parameters","pos":[4760,4787]},{"content":"Project management and accounting parameters","pos":[4797,4841]},{"content":"For example, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accounts receivable parameters<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page, on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Number sequences<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> tab, select the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Reuse numbers<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> check box for <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Free text invoice voucher<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> to synchronize number allocation for free text invoice vouchers and free text invoices.","pos":[4853,5159],"source":"\nFor example, on the <strong>Accounts receivable parameters</strong> page, on the <strong>Number sequences</strong> tab, select the <strong>Reuse numbers</strong> check box for <strong>Free text invoice voucher</strong> to synchronize number allocation for free text invoice vouchers and free text invoices."},{"pos":[5193,5215],"content":"Set up sales tax books","linkify":"Set up sales tax books","nodes":[{"content":"Set up sales tax books","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"Sales tax books are used for sales tax reporting.","pos":[5216,5265]},{"content":"To set up Italian sales tax books, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Sales tax<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Italian sales tax books<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[5266,5382],"source":" To set up Italian sales tax books, click **Tax** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Italian sales tax books**."},{"content":"The following table describes the fields that are available on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Italian sales tax books<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[5383,5483],"source":" The following table describes the fields that are available on the **Italian sales tax books** page."},{"content":"Field","pos":[5588,5593]},{"content":"Description","pos":[5603,5614]},{"content":"Sales tax book","pos":[5664,5678]},{"content":"Enter the ID of the sales tax book.","pos":[5688,5723]},{"content":"Name","pos":[5757,5761]},{"content":"Enter a description of the sales tax book.","pos":[5771,5813]},{"content":"Sales tax book type","pos":[5846,5865]},{"content":"Select the nature of the operations that will be performed through the sales tax book sections that you will attach to the sales tax book.","pos":[5875,6013]},{"content":"The following values are available:","pos":[6014,6049],"source":" The following values are available:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this value for purchase invoices and credit notes.","pos":[6059,6144],"source":"<strong>Purchase</strong> – Select this value for purchase invoices and credit notes."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this value for sales invoices and credit notes.","pos":[6154,6233],"source":"<strong>Sales</strong> – Select this value for sales invoices and credit notes."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Not included<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this value for invoices and credit notes that come from countries/regions that are outside the European community.","pos":[6243,6396],"source":"<strong>Not included</strong> – Select this value for invoices and credit notes that come from countries/regions that are outside the European community."},{"content":"This type is used only for statistical purposes and won't be included on the final fiscal tax book reports.","pos":[6397,6504]},{"content":"Settlement period","pos":[6549,6566]},{"content":"Select an existing sales tax settlement period.","pos":[6576,6623]},{"content":"When a sales tax book is printed, if the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Update<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> check box is selected on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales tax payment<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page, the date in the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>From date<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is compared to the selected settlement period.","pos":[6624,6854],"source":" When a sales tax book is printed, if the <strong>Update</strong> check box is selected on the <strong>Sales tax payment</strong> page, the date in the <strong>From date</strong> field is compared to the selected settlement period."},{"content":"The settlement period is also used to identify which sales tax books and sales tax book sections must be closed when a sales tax settlement is updated for a settlement period.","pos":[6855,7030]},{"content":"Closed to","pos":[7063,7072]},{"content":"The latest closing date from the related sales tax book sections that belong to the selected sales tax book.","pos":[7082,7190]},{"content":"EU sales","pos":[7224,7232]},{"content":"Select a sales tax book of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type, and attach it to the current sales tax book of the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type.","pos":[7242,7384],"source":"Select a sales tax book of the <strong>Sales</strong> type, and attach it to the current sales tax book of the <strong>Purchase</strong> type."},{"content":"This field is used if the selected sales tax book must include European Union (EU) purchase transactions from the current book on sales tax reports.","pos":[7385,7533]},{"content":"This field is unavailable for sales tax books of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Not included<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> types.","pos":[7534,7650],"source":" This field is unavailable for sales tax books of the <strong>Sales</strong> and <strong>Not included</strong> types."},{"content":"ATECOFIN Code","pos":[7683,7696]},{"content":"Select the tax code for reporting.","pos":[7706,7740]},{"content":"Print summary and payment","pos":[7774,7799]},{"content":"Select this option to print the summary and payment report.","pos":[7809,7868]},{"content":"This field is available only for sales tax books of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type.","pos":[7869,7953],"source":" This field is available only for sales tax books of the <strong>Sales</strong> type."},{"pos":[7987,8017],"content":"Set up sales tax book sections","linkify":"Set up sales tax book sections","nodes":[{"content":"Set up sales tax book sections","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"Sales tax book sections are a repository where ledger transactions are posted according to their nature.","pos":[8018,8122]},{"content":"The voucher numbering is driven by the sales tax book sections.","pos":[8123,8186]},{"content":"To set up Italian sales tax book sections, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Sales tax<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Italian sales tax book sections<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[8187,8319],"source":" To set up Italian sales tax book sections, click **Tax** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Italian sales tax book sections**."},{"content":"The following table describes the fields that are available on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Italian sales tax book sections<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[8320,8428],"source":" The following table describes the fields that are available on the **Italian sales tax book sections** page."},{"content":"Field","pos":[8533,8538]},{"content":"Description","pos":[8548,8559]},{"content":"Sales tax book","pos":[8609,8623]},{"content":"Select one of the existing sales tax books that the sales tax book section is attached to.","pos":[8633,8723]},{"content":"Sales tax book section","pos":[8757,8779]},{"content":"Enter the ID of sales tax book section.","pos":[8789,8828]},{"content":"Name","pos":[8861,8865]},{"content":"Enter a description of the sales tax book section.","pos":[8875,8925]},{"content":"Number sequence code","pos":[8959,8979]},{"content":"Select the number sequence code for the sales tax book section.","pos":[8989,9052]},{"content":"The number sequence code that you select depends on the type of sales tax book that the sales tax book section is attached to:","pos":[9053,9179],"source":" The number sequence code that you select depends on the type of sales tax book that the sales tax book section is attached to:\n"},{"content":"For a sales tax book of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type: Select number sequence codes that are defined for purchase invoice vouchers or purchase credit note vouchers on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accounts payable parameters<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page, or number sequence codes that are used on the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journal names<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page for vouchers that have the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Italian sales tax book<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field set to <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[9189,9604],"source":"For a sales tax book of the <strong>Purchase</strong> type: Select number sequence codes that are defined for purchase invoice vouchers or purchase credit note vouchers on the <strong>Accounts payable parameters</strong> page, or number sequence codes that are used on the <strong>Journal names</strong> page for vouchers that have the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field set to <strong>Purchase</strong>."},{"content":"For a sales tax book of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type: Select number sequence codes that are defined for sales invoice vouchers or sales credit note vouchers or free text invoice vouchers or free text credit note vouchers on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Accounts receivable<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>parameters<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page, or number sequence codes that are used on the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Journal names<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page for vouchers that have the <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Italian sales tax book<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field set to <bpt id=\"p6\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p6\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[9614,10101],"source":"For a sales tax book of the <strong>Sales</strong> type: Select number sequence codes that are defined for sales invoice vouchers or sales credit note vouchers or free text invoice vouchers or free text credit note vouchers on the <strong>Accounts receivable</strong> <strong>parameters</strong> page, or number sequence codes that are used on the <strong>Journal names</strong> page for vouchers that have the <strong>Italian sales tax book</strong> field set to <strong>Sales</strong>."},{"content":"For a sales tax book of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Not included<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type: Select any suitable number sequence code.","pos":[10111,10216],"source":"For a sales tax book of the <strong>Not included</strong> type: Select any suitable number sequence code."},{"content":"Closed to","pos":[10260,10269]},{"content":"Enter the end date of the last closed sales tax settlement period.","pos":[10279,10345]},{"content":"This field is used to filter data on the sales tax report.","pos":[10346,10404]},{"content":"Close Italian sales tax book section","pos":[10438,10474]},{"content":"The closing date of the Italian sales tax book for a tax period.","pos":[10484,10548]},{"content":"You can't post or reverse an invoice that has a date that is earlier than the closing date of the tax period.","pos":[10549,10658]},{"content":"This field is updated with the closing date of the tax period.","pos":[10659,10721]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Update<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> check box must also be selected on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales tax payment<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[10722,10829],"source":" The <strong>Update</strong> check box must also be selected on the <strong>Sales tax payment</strong> page."},{"content":"The following button is also available.","pos":[10860,10899]},{"content":"Button","pos":[10903,10909]},{"content":"Description","pos":[10912,10923]},{"content":"Create","pos":[13211,13217]},{"content":"Automatically create all the required sales tax book sections for existing sales tax books of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> types.","pos":[13220,13351],"source":"Automatically create all the required sales tax book sections for existing sales tax books of the **Sales** and **Purchase** types."},{"content":"Sales tax book sections are created for every number sequence that is defined for purchase invoice vouchers or purchase credit note vouchers or sales invoice vouchers or sales credit note vouchers or free text invoice vouchers or free text credit note vouchers on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounts payable parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Accounts receivable parameters<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Project management and accounting parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page, and for every number sequence that is used on the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Journal names<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> page for vouchers that have the <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Italian sales tax book<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept> field set to <bpt id=\"p6\">**</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p6\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p7\">**</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p7\">**</ept>.","pos":[13352,13913],"source":" Sales tax book sections are created for every number sequence that is defined for purchase invoice vouchers or purchase credit note vouchers or sales invoice vouchers or sales credit note vouchers or free text invoice vouchers or free text credit note vouchers on the **Accounts payable parameters**, **Accounts receivable parameters**, or **Project management and accounting parameters** page, and for every number sequence that is used on the **Journal names** page for vouchers that have the **Italian sales tax book** field set to **Purchase** or **Sales**."},{"content":"Every sales tax book section that is created is automatically attached to the default sales tax book.","pos":[13914,14015]},{"content":"(The sales tax book must be created before the sales tax book sections.) If several sales tax books of the same sales tax book type (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sales<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Purchase<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>) exist, the first sales tax book is used by default.","pos":[14016,14227],"source":" (The sales tax book must be created before the sales tax book sections.) If several sales tax books of the same sales tax book type (**Sales** or **Purchase**) exist, the first sales tax book is used by default."},{"content":"However, you can manually change this attachment.","pos":[14228,14277]},{"content":"If no sales tax book exists, no sales tax book sections are automatically created.","pos":[14278,14360]},{"pos":[14367,14388],"content":"Sales tax book status","linkify":"Sales tax book status","nodes":[{"content":"Sales tax book status","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"When a new sales tax period is created, sales tax book lines are automatically set up for every sales tax book that exists.","pos":[14389,14512]},{"content":"If an additional sales tax book is created, lines can be manually created for existing periods that haven't been closed.","pos":[14513,14633]},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Indirect taxes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Sales tax<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Sales tax settlement periods<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>, and then click <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Sales tax book status<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>.","pos":[14634,14771],"source":" Click **Tax** &gt; **Indirect taxes** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Sales tax settlement periods**, and then click **Sales tax book status**."},{"content":"The following table describes the tabs on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sales tax book status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[14772,14849],"source":" The following table describes the tabs on the **Sales tax book status** page."},{"content":"Tab","pos":[14853,14856]},{"content":"Description","pos":[14864,14875]},{"content":"Overview","pos":[15095,15103]},{"content":"View the page status of the sales tax books.","pos":[15106,15150]},{"content":"All the fields are locked for manual updates.","pos":[15151,15196]},{"content":"General","pos":[15216,15223]},{"pos":[15227,15332],"content":"View the same information that appears on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Overview<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, but only for the selected sales tax book.","source":"View the same information that appears on the **Overview** tab, but only for the selected sales tax book."},{"content":"The following table describes the fields that are available.","pos":[15336,15396]},{"content":"Field","pos":[15400,15405]},{"content":"Description","pos":[15420,15431]},{"content":"Sales tax book","pos":[15642,15656]},{"pos":[15662,15747],"content":"Select the sales tax book ID that you set up on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Italian sales tax books<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"Select the sales tax book ID that you set up on the **Italian sales tax books** page."},{"content":"Name","pos":[15763,15767]},{"content":"Enter the name of the tax book.","pos":[15783,15814]},{"content":"First page number","pos":[15884,15901]},{"content":"The first page number that will be used on the final sales tax report for this sales tax period.","pos":[15904,16000]},{"content":"Changed to","pos":[16005,16015]},{"pos":[16025,16106],"content":"The page number that is specified in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change first page number<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box.","source":"The page number that is specified in the **Change first page number** dialog box."},{"content":"Last page number","pos":[16126,16142]},{"content":"The last page number that will be used on the final sales tax report for this sales tax period.","pos":[16146,16241]},{"content":"Settlement period","pos":[16247,16264]},{"content":"The settlement period that is used in the sales tax book.","pos":[16267,16324]},{"content":"From date","pos":[16368,16377]},{"content":"The start date for the settlement period.","pos":[16388,16429]},{"content":"To date","pos":[16489,16496]},{"content":"The end date for the settlement period.","pos":[16509,16548]},{"content":"The following button is also available.","pos":[16609,16648]},{"content":"Button","pos":[16652,16658]},{"content":"Description","pos":[16679,16690]},{"content":"Change first page number","pos":[17016,17040]},{"pos":[17043,17193],"content":"Open the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change first page number<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box, where you can change the first page number that will be used for the current open settlement period.","source":"Open the **Change first page number** dialog box, where you can change the first page number that will be used for the current open settlement period."},{"pos":[17201,17236],"content":"Change first page number dialog box","linkify":"Change first page number dialog box","nodes":[{"content":"Change first page number dialog box","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change first page number<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box to change the number of the first page on the final sales tax report for this sales tax settlement period.","pos":[17238,17392],"source":"Use the **Change first page number** dialog box to change the number of the first page on the final sales tax report for this sales tax settlement period."},{"content":"The page number then appears in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Changed to<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Sales tax book status<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page and is used as the first page number of the final sales tax report that is printed for the current tax period.","pos":[17393,17599],"source":" The page number then appears in the **Changed to** column on the **Sales tax book status** page and is used as the first page number of the final sales tax report that is printed for the current tax period."},{"content":"The following table describes the fields that are available in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change first page number<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box.","pos":[17600,17707],"source":" The following table describes the fields that are available in the **Change first page number** dialog box."},{"content":"Field","pos":[17711,17716]},{"content":"Description","pos":[17731,17742]},{"content":"First page number","pos":[17899,17916]},{"content":"The current first page number for the selected sales tax book.","pos":[17919,17981]},{"content":"Changed to","pos":[17993,18003]},{"content":"Enter the new first page number to use on the final sales tax report.","pos":[18013,18082]},{"pos":[18089,18110],"content":"Using sales tax books","linkify":"Using sales tax books","nodes":[{"content":"Using sales tax books","pos":[0,21]}]},{"pos":[18111,18230],"content":"When the setup is completed, the sales tax book sections appear on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Number sequences<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the following pages:","source":"When the setup is completed, the sales tax book sections appear on the **Number sequences** tab of the following pages:"},{"content":"Accounts receivable parameters","pos":[18236,18266]},{"content":"Accounts payable parameters","pos":[18271,18298]},{"content":"Project management and accounting parameters","pos":[18303,18347]},{"content":"Voucher numbers that are assigned during posting must be sequentially ordered by posting date, and the sales tax transactions that use the same number sequence code must be posted in order.","pos":[18349,18538]},{"content":"If the voucher numbers aren't sequentially ordered, the user receives an error message.","pos":[18539,18626]},{"content":"In addition, posting is interrupted if a sales tax transaction isn't assigned to any sales tax book section when the user updates an invoice.","pos":[18627,18768]},{"content":"Whenever a voucher is posted through a sales tax book section, the identifiers of the related sales tax book and sales tax book section are saved in the tax transactions.","pos":[18769,18939]},{"content":"(Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Sales tax inquiries<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Posted sales tax<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>, and then click the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Posting<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> tab.) This data can then be used during further sales tax reporting.","pos":[18940,19110],"source":" (Click **Tax** &gt; **Sales tax inquiries** &gt; **Posted sales tax**, and then click the **Posting** tab.) This data can then be used during further sales tax reporting."},{"content":"Italian sales tax books are used for filtering, grouping, and sorting on the report that is accessed at <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tax<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Declarations<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Sales tax<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Sales Tax (Italy)<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[19111,19291],"source":" Italian sales tax books are used for filtering, grouping, and sorting on the report that is accessed at **Tax** &gt; **Declarations** &gt; **Sales tax** &gt; **Sales Tax (Italy)**."}]}