{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Accessibility in forms, products, and controls\ndescription: This article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control. An accessibility checklist is also included.\nauthor: RobinARH\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 104943\nms.assetid: 5b97c471-212a-4487-baef-120d01063319\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tlefor\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-05-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 1\n\n---\n\n# Accessibility in forms, products, and controls\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control. An accessibility checklist is also included.\n\nAccessibility is about inclusion, that is, a person with a disability can perform the same task as a person without that disability. Making an accessible control or form should be as fundamental as making it secure, high-performing, or easy-to-understand.\n\n## Keyboard\nThe bedrock of accessibility is keyboard-only access. When you can use the keyboard to perform all the actions of a form, then it can be utilized by a non-sighted person or a person with restricted or limited use of their hands. This means that all controls can be reached via the tab sequence, direct action (such as Ctrl+S for Save), or through some other shortcut key that enables the user to move to a control, such as Navigation Pane, App Bar, Message Center, or Message Bar. A simple test is to simply disconnect your mouse and complete all core and secondary scenarios using only the keyboard.\n\n## Color\nThe use of color is encouraged and is a common way to express state or status of a record or other piece of information. However, color cannot be the only way that state or status is communicated. An accompanying symbol, help text, or additional column should include a textual description of the state or status. A simple test is to identify all use of color in your system and ensure that color isn't being used to express a state or status. A common example is to use the color red to indicate \"needs attention,\" or the color green to mean an \"OK\" status.\n\n## Images\nWhen showing an image there should be a label that describes the image. If the image expresses state or status of a record, then accompanying help text or an additional column should include a textual description of the state or status. If the image is symbolic, like a logo, then it doesn’t require a textual description. If you have an image on a form or grid to convey a status, such as \"in progress\", ensure that the image has a tooltip that can then be read to a sight-impaired user who is utilizing a screen reader.\n\n```\npublic display container statusImageDataMethod()\n{\nImageReference statusImage;\nif (this.Status == NoYes::Yes)\n{\nstatusImage = ImageReference::constructForSymbol(ImageReferenceSymbol::Accept, \"Accept\");    \n// a product ready example would use a label in place of an embedded string\n }\n else\n  {\n statusImage = ImageReference::constructForSymbol(ImageReferenceSymbol::Cancel, \"Cancel\");  \n// a product ready example would use a label in place of an embedded string\n }\n return statusImage.pack();\n}\n```\n\n## Extensible controls\nExtensible controls are simply an extension of the controls that are provided by the framework, but require the same usability and accessibility. In addition, widgets or other visually rich controls, such as segmented entry controls or charts, should provide an Accessible Rich Internet Applications (ARIA) tag that is hidden from the sighted user, but provides an introduction to the blind user through a screen reader that describes the use of the control. Every action in an extensible control must be possible with a keyboard.\n\n## Layout and dynamic management of forms\nA visually impaired or blind user cannot be surprised by significant or unexpected re-laying out of a form based on an action such as selecting a value or entering input.\n\n### Accessibility checklist\n\n|                                       |                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    |                                                                                                                                                                                    |                   |\n|---------------------------------------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|-------------------|\n| **Measure**                           | **Description**                                                                                                                                                                                                                    | **Success criteria**                                                                                                                                                               | **Validated (x)** |\n| Keyboard-only access to all functions | Drill downs, lookups, hyperlinks, data input actions, and shortcut keys.                                                                                                                                                           | All action may be completed without the use of a mouse.                                                                                                                            |                   |\n| Visible focus indicator               |                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    | It’s always apparent which control has focus.                                                                                                                                      |                   |\n| Focus order                           | Cannot “jump to” a non-logical location.                                                                                                                                                                                           | Tabbing doesn’t jump to a non-logical portion or unexpected portion of the form.                                                                                                   |                   |\n| Focus trapping                        | Cannot be “trapped” in a control, focus must be able to move out of control using the keyboard.                                                                                                                                    | Tabbing into a control should allow tabbing out or a keyboard equivalent that lets them escape.                                                                                    |                   |\n| Images of text                        | Cannot use an image to display text.                                                                                                                                                                                               | For example, you cannot have a button label that is an image of text. Logo’s are exempt.                                                                                           |                   |\n| Using color                           | Color alone cannot be used to convey status or state.                                                                                                                                                                              | All status indicators on a form or grid must have unique shape or texture for each color. See the \"Color\" section in this document for more information.                           |                   |\n| Text contrast                         | Minimum 4.5:1 ratio.                                                                                                                                                                                                               | Extensible controls should use framework color theming to ensure compliance.                                                                                                       |                   |\n| User input instructions               | Widgets or other multi-step controls must have a usability overview label or help text (can be embedded in ARIA tag).                                                                                                              | When using a screen reader, the control must be introduced and its label or purpose described.                                                                                     |                   |\n| Change of context                     | Changing the setting of, or entering data into any UI component must not automatically cause an unexpected change of context that might disorient the user without first notifying the user that the change of context will occur. | For example, selecting a value in a drop-down box or clicking a check box shouldn’t change the layout of the form unexpectedly or in a non-standard way.                           |                   |\n| Consistent UI                         | Widgets or other elements must work consistently across the product. There cannot be two similar looking or modeled elements that behave differently.                                                                              | For example, selecting a check box shouldn’t open a window.                                                                                                                        |                   |\n| Fine motor control                    | Cannot require use of the mouse. Must support “sticky keys.”                                                                                                                                                                       | User cannot be forced to click a moving target (pull right) or any other action that requires a mouse. The same action must also be possible with the keyboard.                    |                   |\n| Use of video                          | Video (with audio) must have accompanied text.                                                                                                                                                                                     | When showing pre-recorded content, the deaf person must have supporting text to consume the content.                                                                               |                   |\n| Use of images                         |                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    | All images must be accompanied by text that describes the specific content. For example, a “tooltip” or secondary column in a grid that describes and matches the state or status. |                   |\n| Communication                         | Use of VoIP or other telecommunication device or software, such as Skype, must be accessible and usable from the keyboard.                                                                                                         | Any use of VoIP or telecommunication is a legal obligation.                                                                                                                        |                   |\n| Navigation                            |                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    | Navigation controls must communitate that navigation will occur if executed.                                                                                                       |                   |\n\n## Extensible controls – Insights for accessibility\nAn extensible control is simply an extension of the framework. The interaction of the extensible control should be considered no different than any other framework control. When the control is a visually-rich widget that offers mouse actions, the author needs to ensure that equivalent, keyboard access functionality is available. A widget may not run in an “accessible mode” that is different than the standard presentation. Instead the widget must offer similar functionality without the need to activate or toggle state of the control. All uses of color should be based on themed colors so that when the mode is “High Contrast” your color scheme matches the theme change. The World Wide Web Consortium (WC3) website provides guidance for \"Supported States and Properties\" ([www.w3.org/TR/wai aria/states\\_and\\_properties\\#state\\_prop\\_def](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#state_prop_def)). This site is a helpful resource for ARIA tags and provides the definitions that you see below.\n\n### Control should\n\n##### **Introduce itself**\n\nImportantly, your control should not only identify itself by name, but (using a label or ARIA tag) give a brief introduction on how it works. Aria-describedby. Make sure your descriptive text is supplied via a framework label for localization. ******\n\n[aria-describedby](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-describedby) - Identifies the element (or elements) that describes the object.\n\n***Example***\n\n    <http://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20-TECHS/ARIA1.html>\n    <button aria-label=\"Close\" aria-describedby=\"descriptionClose\" onclick=\"myDialog.close()\"></button>\n    <div id=\"descriptionClose\">Closing this window will discard any information entered and return you to the main page</div>\n\n**Indicate when it is busy** It may not always be clear to the visually-impaired user why the control isn’t responsive. Providing a “busy” message helps in these cases.\n\n[aria-busy (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-busy) - Indicates whether an element, and its subtree, are currently being updated.\n\n***Example***\n\n    <p aria-live=”polite” aria-busy=”true”></p>\n\n**Indicate that the contents have been validated and are invalid** The async nature will result in a dynamic field state change. The message bar will introduce itself to the visually-impaired user, and the control itself should express an invalid state.\n\n[aria-invalid (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-invalid) - Indicates the entered value does not conform to the format expected by the application.\n\n**Indicate when a field is readonly**\n\n[aria-readonly](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-readonly) - Indicates that the element is not editable, but is otherwise operable. See related aria-disabled.\n\n**Indicate that the field requires input (mandatory)** The sighted user understands that a field is mandatory through a visual symbol. The non-sighted user will need an identifying tag.\n\n[aria-required](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-required) indicates that user input is required on the element before a form may be submitted.\n\n**Describe the state of a toggled value** A toggle control has a toggled state. This tag will express that state.\n\n[aria-pressed (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-pressed) - Indicates the current \"pressed\" state of toggle buttons. See related aria-checked and aria-selected.\n\n[aria-valuenow](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuenow) - Defines the current value for a range widget. See related aria-valuetext.\n\n[aria-valuetext](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuetext) - Defines the human readable text alternative of aria-valuenow for a range widget.\n\n### Control could\n\n**Indicate an expanded state** Complex interactions can be learned, but current state isn’t always easy to determine without experimentation. When using an aria-expanded tag, the control describes its current state. An example is tabbing to a tab or FastTab section of a control.\n\n[aria-expanded (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-expanded) - Indicates whether the element, or another grouping element it controls, is currently expanded or collapsed.\n\n**Describe applicable context menu** Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition provides a context menu. When the application author has provided functionality to the current control or context, you can announce that functionality.\n\n[aria-haspopup](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-haspopup) - Indicates that the element has a pop-up context menu or sub-level menu.\n\n**Other Misc**\n\n[aria-live](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-live) indicates that an element will be updated, and describes the types of updates the user agents, assistive technologies, and user can expect from the live region.\n\n[aria-multiline](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-multiline) - Indicates whether a text box accepts multiple lines of input or only a single line.\n\n[aria-multiselectable](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-multiselectable) - Indicates that the user may select more than one item from the current selectable descendants.\n\n[aria-orientation](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-orientation) - Indicates whether the element and orientation is horizontal or vertical.\n\n[aria-setsize](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-setsize) - Defines the number of items in the current set of listitems or treeitems. Not required if all elements in the set are present in the DOM. See related aria-posinset.\n\n[aria-sort-](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-sort) Indicates if items in a table or grid are sorted in ascending or descending order.\n\n[aria-valuemax](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuemax) - Defines the maximum allowed value for a range widget.\n\n[aria-valuemin](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuemin) - Defines the minimum allowed value for a range widget.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,768],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Accessibility in forms, products, and controls\ndescription: This article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control. An accessibility checklist is also included.\nauthor: RobinARH\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 104943\nms.assetid: 5b97c471-212a-4487-baef-120d01063319\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tlefor\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-05-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 1\n","nodes":[{"content":"Accessibility in forms, products, and controls","nodes":[{"pos":[0,46],"content":"Accessibility in forms, products, and controls","nodes":[{"content":"Accessibility in forms, products, and controls","pos":[0,46]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control. An accessibility checklist is also included.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,144],"content":"This article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control. An accessibility checklist is also included.","nodes":[{"content":"This article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control. An accessibility checklist is also included.","pos":[0,144],"nodes":[{"content":"This article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control.","pos":[0,99]},{"content":"An accessibility checklist is also included.","pos":[100,144]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[776,822],"content":"Accessibility in forms, products, and controls","linkify":"Accessibility in forms, products, and controls","nodes":[{"content":"Accessibility in forms, products, and controls","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"This article describes best practices for enabling accessibility in your form, product, or control.","pos":[868,967]},{"content":"An accessibility checklist is also included.","pos":[968,1012]},{"content":"Accessibility is about inclusion, that is, a person with a disability can perform the same task as a person without that disability.","pos":[1014,1146]},{"content":"Making an accessible control or form should be as fundamental as making it secure, high-performing, or easy-to-understand.","pos":[1147,1269]},{"pos":[1274,1282],"content":"Keyboard","linkify":"Keyboard","nodes":[{"content":"Keyboard","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"The bedrock of accessibility is keyboard-only access.","pos":[1283,1336]},{"content":"When you can use the keyboard to perform all the actions of a form, then it can be utilized by a non-sighted person or a person with restricted or limited use of their hands.","pos":[1337,1511]},{"content":"This means that all controls can be reached via the tab sequence, direct action (such as Ctrl+S for Save), or through some other shortcut key that enables the user to move to a control, such as Navigation Pane, App Bar, Message Center, or Message Bar.","pos":[1512,1763]},{"content":"A simple test is to simply disconnect your mouse and complete all core and secondary scenarios using only the keyboard.","pos":[1764,1883]},{"pos":[1888,1893],"content":"Color","linkify":"Color","nodes":[{"content":"Color","pos":[0,5]}]},{"content":"The use of color is encouraged and is a common way to express state or status of a record or other piece of information.","pos":[1894,2014]},{"content":"However, color cannot be the only way that state or status is communicated.","pos":[2015,2090]},{"content":"An accompanying symbol, help text, or additional column should include a textual description of the state or status.","pos":[2091,2207]},{"content":"A simple test is to identify all use of color in your system and ensure that color isn't being used to express a state or status.","pos":[2208,2337]},{"content":"A common example is to use the color red to indicate \"needs attention,\" or the color green to mean an \"OK\" status.","pos":[2338,2452]},{"pos":[2457,2463],"content":"Images","linkify":"Images","nodes":[{"content":"Images","pos":[0,6]}]},{"content":"When showing an image there should be a label that describes the image.","pos":[2464,2535]},{"content":"If the image expresses state or status of a record, then accompanying help text or an additional column should include a textual description of the state or status.","pos":[2536,2700]},{"content":"If the image is symbolic, like a logo, then it doesn’t require a textual description.","pos":[2701,2786]},{"content":"If you have an image on a form or grid to convey a status, such as \"in progress\", ensure that the image has a tooltip that can then be read to a sight-impaired user who is utilizing a screen reader.","pos":[2787,2985]},{"pos":[3496,3515],"content":"Extensible controls","linkify":"Extensible controls","nodes":[{"content":"Extensible controls","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Extensible controls are simply an extension of the controls that are provided by the framework, but require the same usability and accessibility.","pos":[3516,3661]},{"content":"In addition, widgets or other visually rich controls, such as segmented entry controls or charts, should provide an Accessible Rich Internet Applications (ARIA) tag that is hidden from the sighted user, but provides an introduction to the blind user through a screen reader that describes the use of the control.","pos":[3662,3974]},{"content":"Every action in an extensible control must be possible with a keyboard.","pos":[3975,4046]},{"pos":[4051,4089],"content":"Layout and dynamic management of forms","linkify":"Layout and dynamic management of forms","nodes":[{"content":"Layout and dynamic management of forms","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"A visually impaired or blind user cannot be surprised by significant or unexpected re-laying out of a form based on an action such as selecting a value or entering input.","pos":[4090,4260]},{"pos":[4266,4289],"content":"Accessibility checklist","linkify":"Accessibility checklist","nodes":[{"content":"Accessibility checklist","pos":[0,23]}]},{"pos":[5237,5248],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Measure<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Measure**"},{"pos":[5277,5292],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Description<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Description**"},{"pos":[5506,5526],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Success criteria<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Success criteria**"},{"pos":[5687,5704],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Validated (x)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Validated (x)**"},{"content":"Keyboard-only access to all functions","pos":[5709,5746]},{"content":"Drill downs, lookups, hyperlinks, data input actions, and shortcut keys.","pos":[5749,5821]},{"content":"All action may be completed without the use of a mouse.","pos":[5978,6033]},{"content":"Visible focus indicator","pos":[6181,6204]},{"content":"It’s always apparent which control has focus.","pos":[6450,6495]},{"content":"Focus order","pos":[6653,6664]},{"content":"Cannot “jump to” a non-logical location.","pos":[6693,6733]},{"content":"Tabbing doesn’t jump to a non-logical portion or unexpected portion of the form.","pos":[6922,7002]},{"content":"Focus trapping","pos":[7125,7139]},{"content":"Cannot be “trapped” in a control, focus must be able to move out of control using the keyboard.","pos":[7165,7260]},{"content":"Tabbing into a control should allow tabbing out or a keyboard equivalent that lets them escape.","pos":[7394,7489]},{"content":"Images of text","pos":[7597,7611]},{"content":"Cannot use an image to display text.","pos":[7637,7673]},{"content":"For example, you cannot have a button label that is an image of text.","pos":[7866,7935]},{"content":"Logo’s are exempt.","pos":[7936,7954]},{"content":"Using color","pos":[8069,8080]},{"content":"Color alone cannot be used to convey status or state.","pos":[8109,8162]},{"content":"All status indicators on a form or grid must have unique shape or texture for each color.","pos":[8338,8427]},{"content":"See the \"Color\" section in this document for more information.","pos":[8428,8490]},{"content":"Text contrast","pos":[8541,8554]},{"content":"Minimum 4.5:1 ratio.","pos":[8581,8601]},{"content":"Extensible controls should use framework color theming to ensure compliance.","pos":[8810,8886]},{"content":"User input instructions","pos":[9013,9036]},{"content":"Widgets or other multi-step controls must have a usability overview label or help text (can be embedded in ARIA tag).","pos":[9053,9170]},{"content":"When using a screen reader, the control must be introduced and its label or purpose described.","pos":[9282,9376]},{"content":"Change of context","pos":[9485,9502]},{"content":"Changing the setting of, or entering data into any UI component must not automatically cause an unexpected change of context that might disorient the user without first notifying the user that the change of context will occur.","pos":[9525,9751]},{"content":"For example, selecting a value in a drop-down box or clicking a check box shouldn’t change the layout of the form unexpectedly or in a non-standard way.","pos":[9754,9906]},{"content":"Consistent UI","pos":[9957,9970]},{"content":"Widgets or other elements must work consistently across the product.","pos":[9997,10065]},{"content":"There cannot be two similar looking or modeled elements that behave differently.","pos":[10066,10146]},{"content":"For example, selecting a check box shouldn’t open a window.","pos":[10226,10285]},{"content":"Fine motor control","pos":[10429,10447]},{"content":"Cannot require use of the mouse.","pos":[10469,10501]},{"content":"Must support “sticky keys.”","pos":[10502,10529]},{"content":"User cannot be forced to click a moving target (pull right) or any other action that requires a mouse.","pos":[10698,10800]},{"content":"The same action must also be possible with the keyboard.","pos":[10801,10857]},{"content":"Use of video","pos":[10901,10913]},{"content":"Video (with audio) must have accompanied text.","pos":[10941,10987]},{"content":"When showing pre-recorded content, the deaf person must have supporting text to consume the content.","pos":[11170,11270]},{"content":"Use of images","pos":[11373,11386]},{"content":"All images must be accompanied by text that describes the specific content.","pos":[11642,11717]},{"content":"For example, a “tooltip” or secondary column in a grid that describes and matches the state or status.","pos":[11718,11820]},{"content":"Communication","pos":[11845,11858]},{"content":"Use of VoIP or other telecommunication device or software, such as Skype, must be accessible and usable from the keyboard.","pos":[11885,12007]},{"content":"Any use of VoIP or telecommunication is a legal obligation.","pos":[12114,12173]},{"content":"Navigation","pos":[12317,12327]},{"content":"Navigation controls must communitate that navigation will occur if executed.","pos":[12586,12662]},{"pos":[12791,12839],"content":"Extensible controls – Insights for accessibility","linkify":"Extensible controls – Insights for accessibility","nodes":[{"content":"Extensible controls – Insights for accessibility","pos":[0,48]}]},{"content":"An extensible control is simply an extension of the framework.","pos":[12840,12902]},{"content":"The interaction of the extensible control should be considered no different than any other framework control.","pos":[12903,13012]},{"content":"When the control is a visually-rich widget that offers mouse actions, the author needs to ensure that equivalent, keyboard access functionality is available.","pos":[13013,13170]},{"content":"A widget may not run in an “accessible mode” that is different than the standard presentation.","pos":[13171,13265]},{"content":"Instead the widget must offer similar functionality without the need to activate or toggle state of the control.","pos":[13266,13378]},{"content":"All uses of color should be based on themed colors so that when the mode is “High Contrast” your color scheme matches the theme change.","pos":[13379,13514]},{"content":"The World Wide Web Consortium (WC3) website provides guidance for \"Supported States and Properties\" (<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>www.w3.org/TR/wai aria/states<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>and<ph id=\"ph2\">\\_</ph>properties<ph id=\"ph3\">\\#</ph>state<ph id=\"ph4\">\\_</ph>prop<ph id=\"ph5\">\\_</ph>def<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#state_prop_def)</ept>).","pos":[13515,13752],"source":" The World Wide Web Consortium (WC3) website provides guidance for \"Supported States and Properties\" ([www.w3.org/TR/wai aria/states\\_and\\_properties\\#state\\_prop\\_def](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#state_prop_def))."},{"content":"This site is a helpful resource for ARIA tags and provides the definitions that you see below.","pos":[13753,13847]},{"pos":[13853,13867],"content":"Control should","linkify":"Control should","nodes":[{"content":"Control should","pos":[0,14]}]},{"pos":[13875,13895],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Introduce itself<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","linkify":"**Introduce itself**","source":"**Introduce itself**"},{"content":"Importantly, your control should not only identify itself by name, but (using a label or ARIA tag) give a brief introduction on how it works.","pos":[13897,14038]},{"content":"Aria-describedby.","pos":[14039,14056]},{"content":"Make sure your descriptive text is supplied via a framework label for localization.","pos":[14057,14140]},{"pos":[14149,14303],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-describedby<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-describedby)</ept> - Identifies the element (or elements) that describes the object.","source":"[aria-describedby](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-describedby) - Identifies the element (or elements) that describes the object."},{"pos":[14305,14318],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">***</bpt>Example<ept id=\"p1\">***</ept>","source":"***Example***"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Indicate when it is busy<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> It may not always be clear to the visually-impaired user why the control isn’t responsive.","pos":[14602,14721],"source":"**Indicate when it is busy** It may not always be clear to the visually-impaired user why the control isn’t responsive."},{"content":"Providing a “busy” message helps in these cases.","pos":[14722,14770]},{"pos":[14772,14932],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-busy (state)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-busy)</ept> - Indicates whether an element, and its subtree, are currently being updated.","source":"[aria-busy (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-busy) - Indicates whether an element, and its subtree, are currently being updated."},{"pos":[14934,14947],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">***</bpt>Example<ept id=\"p1\">***</ept>","source":"***Example***"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Indicate that the contents have been validated and are invalid<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The async nature will result in a dynamic field state change.","pos":[14998,15126],"source":"**Indicate that the contents have been validated and are invalid** The async nature will result in a dynamic field state change."},{"content":"The message bar will introduce itself to the visually-impaired user, and the control itself should express an invalid state.","pos":[15127,15251]},{"pos":[15253,15431],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-invalid (state)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-invalid)</ept> - Indicates the entered value does not conform to the format expected by the application.","source":"[aria-invalid (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-invalid) - Indicates the entered value does not conform to the format expected by the application."},{"pos":[15433,15470],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Indicate when a field is readonly<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Indicate when a field is readonly**"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-readonly<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-readonly)</ept> - Indicates that the element is not editable, but is otherwise operable.","pos":[15472,15627],"source":"[aria-readonly](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-readonly) - Indicates that the element is not editable, but is otherwise operable."},{"content":"See related aria-disabled.","pos":[15628,15654]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Indicate that the field requires input (mandatory)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The sighted user understands that a field is mandatory through a visual symbol.","pos":[15656,15790],"source":"**Indicate that the field requires input (mandatory)** The sighted user understands that a field is mandatory through a visual symbol."},{"content":"The non-sighted user will need an identifying tag.","pos":[15791,15841]},{"pos":[15843,16010],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-required<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-required)</ept> indicates that user input is required on the element before a form may be submitted.","source":"[aria-required](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-required) indicates that user input is required on the element before a form may be submitted."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Describe the state of a toggled value<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> A toggle control has a toggled state.","pos":[16012,16091],"source":"**Describe the state of a toggled value** A toggle control has a toggled state."},{"content":"This tag will express that state.","pos":[16092,16125]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-pressed (state)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-pressed)</ept> - Indicates the current \"pressed\" state of toggle buttons.","pos":[16127,16274],"source":"[aria-pressed (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-pressed) - Indicates the current \"pressed\" state of toggle buttons."},{"content":"See related aria-checked and aria-selected.","pos":[16275,16318]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-valuenow<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuenow)</ept> - Defines the current value for a range widget.","pos":[16320,16450],"source":"[aria-valuenow](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuenow) - Defines the current value for a range widget."},{"content":"See related aria-valuetext.","pos":[16451,16478]},{"pos":[16480,16647],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-valuetext<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuetext)</ept> - Defines the human readable text alternative of aria-valuenow for a range widget.","source":"[aria-valuetext](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuetext) - Defines the human readable text alternative of aria-valuenow for a range widget."},{"pos":[16653,16666],"content":"Control could","linkify":"Control could","nodes":[{"content":"Control could","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Indicate an expanded state<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Complex interactions can be learned, but current state isn’t always easy to determine without experimentation.","pos":[16668,16809],"source":"**Indicate an expanded state** Complex interactions can be learned, but current state isn’t always easy to determine without experimentation."},{"content":"When using an aria-expanded tag, the control describes its current state.","pos":[16810,16883]},{"content":"An example is tabbing to a tab or FastTab section of a control.","pos":[16884,16947]},{"pos":[16949,17149],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-expanded (state)<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-expanded)</ept> - Indicates whether the element, or another grouping element it controls, is currently expanded or collapsed.","source":"[aria-expanded (state)](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-expanded) - Indicates whether the element, or another grouping element it controls, is currently expanded or collapsed."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Describe applicable context menu<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition provides a context menu.","pos":[17151,17282],"source":"**Describe applicable context menu** Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition provides a context menu."},{"content":"When the application author has provided functionality to the current control or context, you can announce that functionality.","pos":[17283,17409]},{"pos":[17411,17567],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-haspopup<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-haspopup)</ept> - Indicates that the element has a pop-up context menu or sub-level menu.","source":"[aria-haspopup](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-haspopup) - Indicates that the element has a pop-up context menu or sub-level menu."},{"pos":[17569,17583],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Other Misc<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Other Misc**"},{"pos":[17585,17820],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-live<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-live)</ept> indicates that an element will be updated, and describes the types of updates the user agents, assistive technologies, and user can expect from the live region.","source":"[aria-live](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-live) indicates that an element will be updated, and describes the types of updates the user agents, assistive technologies, and user can expect from the live region."},{"pos":[17822,17992],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-multiline<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-multiline)</ept> - Indicates whether a text box accepts multiple lines of input or only a single line.","source":"[aria-multiline](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-multiline) - Indicates whether a text box accepts multiple lines of input or only a single line."},{"pos":[17994,18187],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-multiselectable<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-multiselectable)</ept> - Indicates that the user may select more than one item from the current selectable descendants.","source":"[aria-multiselectable](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-multiselectable) - Indicates that the user may select more than one item from the current selectable descendants."},{"pos":[18189,18352],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-orientation<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-orientation)</ept> - Indicates whether the element and orientation is horizontal or vertical.","source":"[aria-orientation](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-orientation) - Indicates whether the element and orientation is horizontal or vertical."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-setsize<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-setsize)</ept> - Defines the number of items in the current set of listitems or treeitems.","pos":[18354,18510],"source":"[aria-setsize](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-setsize) - Defines the number of items in the current set of listitems or treeitems."},{"content":"Not required if all elements in the set are present in the DOM.","pos":[18511,18574]},{"content":"See related aria-posinset.","pos":[18575,18601]},{"pos":[18603,18761],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-sort-<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-sort)</ept> Indicates if items in a table or grid are sorted in ascending or descending order.","source":"[aria-sort-](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-sort) Indicates if items in a table or grid are sorted in ascending or descending order."},{"pos":[18763,18901],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-valuemax<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuemax)</ept> - Defines the maximum allowed value for a range widget.","source":"[aria-valuemax](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuemax) - Defines the maximum allowed value for a range widget."},{"pos":[18903,19041],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>aria-valuemin<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuemin)</ept> - Defines the minimum allowed value for a range widget.","source":"[aria-valuemin](http://www.w3.org/TR/wai-aria/states_and_properties#aria-valuemin) - Defines the minimum allowed value for a range widget."}]}