{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Development tools overview\ndescription: Visual Studio 2015 is the exclusive integrated development environment (IDE) for development.\nauthor: robadawy\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/24/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 23401\nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: robadawy\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Development tools overview\n\n# What are the development tools?\nA notable change from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 is that Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition does not include a rich-client application (ax32.exe). From a development perspective, this means that the Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 development environment, MorphX, is no longer used. In its place, the application development is carried out exclusively in Visual Studio. The development tools support all of the development tasks, including debugging and local testing scenarios. A primary goal of the development experience is to keep familiar Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 concepts, and seamlessly adapt them to the Visual Studio framework and paradigms.\n\nVisual Studio 2015 is the exclusive integrated development environment (IDE) for development. All of your application development work will be performed with it. This section is an overview of the main features that are added to Visual Studio when the development tools are installed.\n\n## Application Explorer\nIn Visual Studio, the model store is represented by the Application Explorer. On the **View** menu, click **Application** **Explorer** to open it. The Application Explorer corresponds to the Application Object Tree (AOT) that you may be familiar with in Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012. Use the Application Explorer to browse and interact with the elements in the model store that define the applications. The following illustration shows the Application Explorer. For more details, see [Application Explorer](application-explorer.md).\n\n![Application Explorer](media/1_devotoolsconcept.png)\n\n## The project template\nEven a simple application can have a large number of elements in its model. The **Operations Project** template has been added to Visual Studio to help you organize and manage the elements that you are working with for a model. You will use the project to design, build, and test model elements. It’s common to have several projects within a single Visual Studio solution. The following illustration shows three projects in a Visual Studio solution. For more details, see [Projects](projects.md).\n\n![Solution Explorer](media/2_devotoolsconcept.png)\n\n## Element designers\nThe Visual Studio tools contain designers for each kind of element in the application. You will use these designers when you create or modify elements. The following illustration shows the element designer for a form element. For more details, see [Element designers](element-designers.md).\n\n![Element designer](media/3_devotoolsconcept.png)\n\n## Code editor\nThe X++ code is written in the code editor for Visual Studio. The standard features that a developer expects from the code editor are supported. For example, sections of code are collapsible. IntelliSense provides guidance as you write or modify code. For more details, see [Code editor](code-editor.md).\n\n![Code editor](media/4_devotoolsconcept.png)\n\n## Dynamics 365 menu\nThe tools add the **Dynamics 365** menu to Visual Studio. Several tools that you will use during the development process are found here. For example, the tools for managing models are accessed from the menu.\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,639],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Development tools overview\ndescription: Visual Studio 2015 is the exclusive integrated development environment (IDE) for development.\nauthor: robadawy\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 05/24/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 23401\nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: robadawy\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Development tools overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,26],"content":"Development tools overview","nodes":[{"content":"Development tools overview","pos":[0,26]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"Visual Studio 2015 is the exclusive integrated development environment (IDE) for development.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,93],"content":"Visual Studio 2015 is the exclusive integrated development environment (IDE) for development.","nodes":[{"content":"Visual Studio 2015 is the exclusive integrated development environment (IDE) for development.","pos":[0,93]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[647,673],"content":"Development tools overview","linkify":"Development tools overview","nodes":[{"content":"Development tools overview","pos":[0,26]}]},{"pos":[677,708],"content":"What are the development tools?","linkify":"What are the development tools?","nodes":[{"content":"What are the development tools?","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"A notable change from Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 is that Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition does not include a rich-client application (ax32.exe).","pos":[709,890]},{"content":"From a development perspective, this means that the Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 development environment, MorphX, is no longer used.","pos":[891,1021]},{"content":"In its place, the application development is carried out exclusively in Visual Studio.","pos":[1022,1108]},{"content":"The development tools support all of the development tasks, including debugging and local testing scenarios.","pos":[1109,1217]},{"content":"A primary goal of the development experience is to keep familiar Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 concepts, and seamlessly adapt them to the Visual Studio framework and paradigms.","pos":[1218,1391]},{"content":"Visual Studio 2015 is the exclusive integrated development environment (IDE) for development.","pos":[1393,1486]},{"content":"All of your application development work will be performed with it.","pos":[1487,1554]},{"content":"This section is an overview of the main features that are added to Visual Studio when the development tools are installed.","pos":[1555,1677]},{"pos":[1682,1702],"content":"Application Explorer","linkify":"Application Explorer","nodes":[{"content":"Application Explorer","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"In Visual Studio, the model store is represented by the Application Explorer.","pos":[1703,1780]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>View<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Application<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Explorer<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to open it.","pos":[1781,1849],"source":" On the **View** menu, click **Application** **Explorer** to open it."},{"content":"The Application Explorer corresponds to the Application Object Tree (AOT) that you may be familiar with in Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012.","pos":[1850,1984]},{"content":"Use the Application Explorer to browse and interact with the elements in the model store that define the applications.","pos":[1985,2103]},{"content":"The following illustration shows the Application Explorer.","pos":[2104,2162]},{"content":"For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Application Explorer<ept id=\"p1\">](application-explorer.md)</ept>.","pos":[2163,2233],"source":" For more details, see [Application Explorer](application-explorer.md)."},{"content":"Application Explorer","pos":[2237,2257]},{"pos":[2293,2313],"content":"The project template","linkify":"The project template","nodes":[{"content":"The project template","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Even a simple application can have a large number of elements in its model.","pos":[2314,2389]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operations Project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> template has been added to Visual Studio to help you organize and manage the elements that you are working with for a model.","pos":[2390,2541],"source":" The **Operations Project** template has been added to Visual Studio to help you organize and manage the elements that you are working with for a model."},{"content":"You will use the project to design, build, and test model elements.","pos":[2542,2609]},{"content":"It’s common to have several projects within a single Visual Studio solution.","pos":[2610,2686]},{"content":"The following illustration shows three projects in a Visual Studio solution.","pos":[2687,2763]},{"content":"For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Projects<ept id=\"p1\">](projects.md)</ept>.","pos":[2764,2810],"source":" For more details, see [Projects](projects.md)."},{"content":"Solution Explorer","pos":[2814,2831]},{"pos":[2867,2884],"content":"Element designers","linkify":"Element designers","nodes":[{"content":"Element designers","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"The Visual Studio tools contain designers for each kind of element in the application.","pos":[2885,2971]},{"content":"You will use these designers when you create or modify elements.","pos":[2972,3036]},{"content":"The following illustration shows the element designer for a form element.","pos":[3037,3110]},{"content":"For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Element designers<ept id=\"p1\">](element-designers.md)</ept>.","pos":[3111,3175],"source":" For more details, see [Element designers](element-designers.md)."},{"content":"Element designer","pos":[3179,3195]},{"pos":[3231,3242],"content":"Code editor","linkify":"Code editor","nodes":[{"content":"Code editor","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"The X++ code is written in the code editor for Visual Studio.","pos":[3243,3304]},{"content":"The standard features that a developer expects from the code editor are supported.","pos":[3305,3387]},{"content":"For example, sections of code are collapsible.","pos":[3388,3434]},{"content":"IntelliSense provides guidance as you write or modify code.","pos":[3435,3494]},{"content":"For more details, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Code editor<ept id=\"p1\">](code-editor.md)</ept>.","pos":[3495,3547],"source":" For more details, see [Code editor](code-editor.md)."},{"content":"Code editor","pos":[3551,3562]},{"pos":[3598,3615],"content":"Dynamics 365 menu","linkify":"Dynamics 365 menu","nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics 365 menu","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"The tools add the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Dynamics 365<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu to Visual Studio.","pos":[3616,3673],"source":"The tools add the **Dynamics 365** menu to Visual Studio."},{"content":"Several tools that you will use during the development process are found here.","pos":[3674,3752]},{"content":"For example, the tools for managing models are accessed from the menu.","pos":[3753,3823]}]}