{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide\ndescription: This topic provides information about the tools that are available in Lifecycle Services (LCS) and when to use them as you move through the phases of your work in LCS.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: kfend\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 6034\nms.assetid: 3bebecd6-a72e-48b2-9eec-8c19eafe5dad\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kfend\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nLifecycle Services (LCS) provides regularly updated services. The goal of LCS is to deliver the right information, at the right time, to the right people, and to help ensure repeatable, predictable success with each roll-out of an implementation, update, or upgrade. LCS is available to customers and partners as part of their support plans. If you're a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 customer, you can sign in by using your CustomerSource or PartnerSource credentials. If you're a customer of the newest version of Finance and Operations, you can sign in by using your Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials. [Go to LCS](https://lcs.dynamics.com/Logon/Index).\n\n## Tools that are provided in LCS\nThe following table lists the tools that are provided in LCS and describes the phases that each tool applies to.\n\n| Tool                                     | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                       |\n|------------------------------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| [Projects](ax-2012/projects-lcs.md)                                 | Projects are the key organizer for your experience in LCS. Projects let you invite your partners to collaborate with you, and they also let you track progress.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| [Methodologies](ax-2012/methodologies-lcs.md)                            | Methodologies provide a tool that you can use to ensure more repeatable, predictable implementation projects. You can use one of our methodologies or create your own. By using a methodology, you can easily track and report on your progress.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| [Business process modeler](business-process-modeler-lcs.md)                 | Business process modeler lets you create, view, and modify standard process flows. By using Business process modeler, you can achieve the following goals: standardize process flows; align your business processes with industry-standard processes, as described by the American Productivity & Quality Center (APQC); identify fit and gaps between user requirements and the default functionality that Microsoft Dynamics products provides.                                                                 |\n| [Cloud-hosted environments](ax-2012/cloud-hosted-environments-lcs.md)                | Cloud-hosted environments is a tool that you can use to deploy Microsoft Dynamics environments on Microsoft Azure. When you use Cloud-hosted environments , you must select the type of environment to deploy, such as a demo, developer/test, or production environment. Based on your selection, the Cloud-hosted environments tool provisions the appropriate number of virtual machines (VMs) in Azure. These VMs have Microsoft Dynamics components (and all their prerequisites) already installed on them. |\n| [Cloud-powered support](cloud-powered-support-lcs.md)                    | Cloud-powered support helps you manage support incidents. It lets you create a VM in Azure that has the same hotfixes installed as your local environment. You can reproduce and record an incident on the VM, and then submit the incident to our support team. Support follows up by investigating and, if possible, testing a fix on the VM, and then sends the fix back to you for verification.                                                                                                              |\n| [Configuration and data manager (preview)](configuration-manager-lcs.md) | Configuration and data manager (preview) lets you copy a configuration from one instance to another. You can copy from and to environments that meet the following criteria: they are managed as part of an LCS project; they run the Data Import/Export Framework.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| [Customization analysis](ax-2012/customization-analysis-lcs.md)                   | Customization analysis validates model files against best practices and provides a report of potential areas for improvement.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |\n| [Issue search](issue-search-lcs.md)                             | Issue search helps you find existing solutions and workarounds for known issues in Microsoft Dynamics products. You can see which issues have been fixed, which issues remain open, and which issues have been resolved as “won’t fix.”                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n| [License sizing estimator](ax-2012/license-sizing-estimator-lcs.md)                 | License sizing estimator helps you estimate the number of licenses that are required. It provides a shared workspace that lets you model default and customized roles, and then automatically calculate the required client access licenses (CALs).                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| [RFP responses](ax-2012/rfp-responses-lcs.md)                            | The RFP responses page helps partners respond to requests for proposals (RFPs).                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| [System diagnostics](ax-2012/system-diagnostics-lcs.md)                       | System diagnostics helps administrators monitor Microsoft Dynamics environments.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |\n| [Updates](ax-2012/update-2012-r3-lcs.md)                                  | The Updates page hosts the details about updates that are available for an environment. It also provides access to groups of updates that can be used for slipstream installations.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                               |\n| [Upgrade analysis](ax-2012/upgrade-analysis-lcs.md)                         | Upgrade analysis helps you plan your upgrade to the latest version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations by analyzing code artifacts from Microsoft Dynamics AX 4.0, Dynamics AX 2009, or Dynamics AX 2012.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    |\n| [Usage profiler](ax-2012/usage-profiler-lcs.md)                           | Usage profiler is a data-gathering tool that helps you describe your projected or current usage of an. The usage profile that is generated can be used for various purposes, such as hardware sizing and support.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n| [Downloadable tools](ax-2012/lcs-downloadable-tools-formerly-informationsource.md)                       | The Downloadable tools page provides a set of tools that were previously hosted on Microsoft Dynamics InformationSource.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |\n\nThe LCS team is also blogging at the [Lifecycle Services Engineering blog](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/lcs/). Subscribe to our RSS feed to keep up with our posts and announcements.\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com/)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,767],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide\ndescription: This topic provides information about the tools that are available in Lifecycle Services (LCS) and when to use them as you move through the phases of your work in LCS.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: kfend\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 6034\nms.assetid: 3bebecd6-a72e-48b2-9eec-8c19eafe5dad\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kfend\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide","nodes":[{"pos":[0,38],"content":"Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide","nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide","pos":[0,38]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic provides information about the tools that are available in Lifecycle Services (LCS) and when to use them as you move through the phases of your work in LCS.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,167],"content":"This topic provides information about the tools that are available in Lifecycle Services (LCS) and when to use them as you move through the phases of your work in LCS.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic provides information about the tools that are available in Lifecycle Services (LCS) and when to use them as you move through the phases of your work in LCS.","pos":[0,167]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[775,813],"content":"Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide","linkify":"Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide","nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics Lifecycle Services user guide","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"Lifecycle Services (LCS) provides regularly updated services.","pos":[859,920]},{"content":"The goal of LCS is to deliver the right information, at the right time, to the right people, and to help ensure repeatable, predictable success with each roll-out of an implementation, update, or upgrade.","pos":[921,1125]},{"content":"LCS is available to customers and partners as part of their support plans.","pos":[1126,1200]},{"content":"If you're a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 customer, you can sign in by using your CustomerSource or PartnerSource credentials.","pos":[1201,1324]},{"content":"If you're a customer of the newest version of Finance and Operations, you can sign in by using your Microsoft Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials.","pos":[1325,1481]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Go to LCS<ept id=\"p1\">](https://lcs.dynamics.com/Logon/Index)</ept>.","pos":[1482,1532],"source":"[Go to LCS](https://lcs.dynamics.com/Logon/Index)."},{"pos":[1537,1567],"content":"Tools that are provided in LCS","linkify":"Tools that are provided in LCS","nodes":[{"content":"Tools that are provided in LCS","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"The following table lists the tools that are provided in LCS and describes the phases that each tool applies to.","pos":[1568,1680]},{"content":"Tool","pos":[1684,1688]},{"content":"Description","pos":[1727,1738]},{"pos":[2774,2809],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Projects<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/projects-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Projects](ax-2012/projects-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Projects are the key organizer for your experience in LCS.","pos":[2844,2902]},{"content":"Projects let you invite your partners to collaborate with you, and they also let you track progress.","pos":[2903,3003]},{"pos":[3346,3391],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Methodologies<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/methodologies-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Methodologies](ax-2012/methodologies-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Methodologies provide a tool that you can use to ensure more repeatable, predictable implementation projects.","pos":[3421,3530]},{"content":"You can use one of our methodologies or create your own.","pos":[3531,3587]},{"content":"By using a methodology, you can easily track and report on your progress.","pos":[3588,3661]},{"pos":[3923,3982],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Business process modeler<ept id=\"p1\">](business-process-modeler-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Business process modeler](business-process-modeler-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Business process modeler lets you create, view, and modify standard process flows.","pos":[4001,4083]},{"content":"By using Business process modeler, you can achieve the following goals: standardize process flows; align your business processes with industry-standard processes, as described by the American Productivity &amp; Quality Center (APQC); identify fit and gaps between user requirements and the default functionality that Microsoft Dynamics products provides.","pos":[4084,4434],"source":" By using Business process modeler, you can achieve the following goals: standardize process flows; align your business processes with industry-standard processes, as described by the American Productivity & Quality Center (APQC); identify fit and gaps between user requirements and the default functionality that Microsoft Dynamics products provides."},{"pos":[4503,4572],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Cloud-hosted environments<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/cloud-hosted-environments-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Cloud-hosted environments](ax-2012/cloud-hosted-environments-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Cloud-hosted environments is a tool that you can use to deploy Microsoft Dynamics environments on Microsoft Azure.","pos":[4590,4704]},{"content":"When you use Cloud-hosted environments , you must select the type of environment to deploy, such as a demo, developer/test, or production environment.","pos":[4705,4855]},{"content":"Based on your selection, the Cloud-hosted environments tool provisions the appropriate number of virtual machines (VMs) in Azure.","pos":[4856,4985]},{"content":"These VMs have Microsoft Dynamics components (and all their prerequisites) already installed on them.","pos":[4986,5087]},{"pos":[5092,5145],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Cloud-powered support<ept id=\"p1\">](cloud-powered-support-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Cloud-powered support](cloud-powered-support-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Cloud-powered support helps you manage support incidents.","pos":[5167,5224]},{"content":"It lets you create a VM in Azure that has the same hotfixes installed as your local environment.","pos":[5225,5321]},{"content":"You can reproduce and record an incident on the VM, and then submit the incident to our support team.","pos":[5322,5423]},{"content":"Support follows up by investigating and, if possible, testing a fix on the VM, and then sends the fix back to you for verification.","pos":[5424,5555]},{"pos":[5669,5741],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Configuration and data manager (preview)<ept id=\"p1\">](configuration-manager-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Configuration and data manager (preview)](configuration-manager-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Configuration and data manager (preview) lets you copy a configuration from one instance to another.","pos":[5744,5844]},{"content":"You can copy from and to environments that meet the following criteria: they are managed as part of an LCS project; they run the Data Import/Export Framework.","pos":[5845,6003]},{"pos":[6246,6309],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Customization analysis<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/customization-analysis-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Customization analysis](ax-2012/customization-analysis-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Customization analysis validates model files against best practices and provides a report of potential areas for improvement.","pos":[6330,6455]},{"pos":[6832,6867],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Issue search<ept id=\"p1\">](issue-search-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Issue search](issue-search-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Issue search helps you find existing solutions and workarounds for known issues in Microsoft Dynamics products.","pos":[6898,7009]},{"content":"You can see which issues have been fixed, which issues remain open, and which issues have been resolved as “won’t fix.”","pos":[7010,7129]},{"pos":[7400,7467],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>License sizing estimator<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/license-sizing-estimator-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[License sizing estimator](ax-2012/license-sizing-estimator-lcs.md)"},{"content":"License sizing estimator helps you estimate the number of licenses that are required.","pos":[7486,7571]},{"content":"It provides a shared workspace that lets you model default and customized roles, and then automatically calculate the required client access licenses (CALs).","pos":[7572,7729]},{"pos":[7988,8033],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>RFP responses<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/rfp-responses-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[RFP responses](ax-2012/rfp-responses-lcs.md)"},{"content":"The RFP responses page helps partners respond to requests for proposals (RFPs).","pos":[8063,8142]},{"pos":[8565,8620],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>System diagnostics<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/system-diagnostics-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[System diagnostics](ax-2012/system-diagnostics-lcs.md)"},{"content":"System diagnostics helps administrators monitor Microsoft Dynamics environments.","pos":[8645,8725]},{"pos":[9147,9187],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Updates<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/update-2012-r3-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Updates](ax-2012/update-2012-r3-lcs.md)"},{"content":"The Updates page hosts the details about updates that are available for an environment.","pos":[9223,9310]},{"content":"It also provides access to groups of updates that can be used for slipstream installations.","pos":[9311,9402]},{"pos":[9725,9776],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Upgrade analysis<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/upgrade-analysis-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Upgrade analysis](ax-2012/upgrade-analysis-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Upgrade analysis helps you plan your upgrade to the latest version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations by analyzing code artifacts from Microsoft Dynamics AX 4.0, Dynamics AX 2009, or Dynamics AX 2012.","pos":[9803,10021]},{"pos":[10317,10364],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Usage profiler<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/usage-profiler-lcs.md)</ept>","source":"[Usage profiler](ax-2012/usage-profiler-lcs.md)"},{"content":"Usage profiler is a data-gathering tool that helps you describe your projected or current usage of an.","pos":[10393,10495]},{"content":"The usage profile that is generated can be used for various purposes, such as hardware sizing and support.","pos":[10496,10602]},{"pos":[10895,10977],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Downloadable tools<ept id=\"p1\">](ax-2012/lcs-downloadable-tools-formerly-informationsource.md)</ept>","source":"[Downloadable tools](ax-2012/lcs-downloadable-tools-formerly-informationsource.md)"},{"content":"The Downloadable tools page provides a set of tools that were previously hosted on Microsoft Dynamics InformationSource.","pos":[11002,11122]},{"content":"The LCS team is also blogging at the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Lifecycle Services Engineering blog<ept id=\"p1\">](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/lcs/)</ept>.","pos":[11503,11608],"source":"The LCS team is also blogging at the [Lifecycle Services Engineering blog](http://blogs.msdn.com/b/lcs/)."},{"content":"Subscribe to our RSS feed to keep up with our posts and announcements.","pos":[11609,11679]},{"pos":[11681,11689],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[11700,11747],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">](https://lcs.dynamics.com/)</ept>","source":"[Lifecycle Services](https://lcs.dynamics.com/)"}]}