{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Upgrade - Prepare for go-live\ndescription: This topic describes how you can help guarantee that the source AX 2012 system and the upgrade process remain stable and consistent for go-live.\nauthor: tariqbell\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: margoc\nms.search.scope:  Operations, UnifiedOperations, Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \n# ms.custom: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tabell\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-06-16\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 8\n---\n\n# Upgrade - Prepare for go-live\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n[!include[upgrade banner](../includes/upgrade-banner.md)]\n\nAs the go-live date approaches, it's important that you implement this series of steps to help guarantee that the source Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 system and the upgrade process both remain stable and consistent for go-live.\n\nAs part of this process, you must lock down any further code changes or application setup changes before you run the final cutover test.\n\n## Code freeze\n\nAll code changes in the AX 2012 environment should be frozen. Implement an escalation process to handle any critical issues that appear in AX 2012. By default, any new code changes that are required should be implemented only in the new system, not in the AX 2012 environment. Implementation of proposed code changes in the AX 2012 environment should be discussed at the management level. If a code change is made in AX 2012, the same change must be made in the new system. In that case, another iteration of cutover testing and functional testing might be required.\n\n## Application configuration freeze\n\nAll application configuration changes should be frozen in the AX 2012 environment, because these changes could affect how the new system behaves or how the data upgrade scripts behave. Configuration changes are changes in the AX 2012 application that are related to the configuration of system functionality. By freezing these changes, you help guarantee the stability of the data upgrade process.\n\nBecause configuration changes are typically controlled by the AX 2012 system administrator or a small group of trusted super users, we don't recommend that you enforce the freeze by changing security access. Instead, implement the freeze through a business process that is communicated to those users. Changes to security access might require a code change (changes to the role definitions themselves) or a configuration change (reassignment of users), and these changes could affect the upgrade process.\n\n## Running the final cutover test\n\nAfter no further code or setup changes will occur, run a final cutover test to make sure that all data and code upgrade tasks still run as expected.\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> You must complete this step even if you freeze code and setup changes at the beginning of the upgrade project, because the data itself changes every day. This final cutover test also validates that the current data is upgraded successfully.\n\nMake sure that functional testing is performed against this last upgraded copy.\n\nAt this point in the upgrade project, we recommend that you categorize any bugs that are found:\n- **Blocking** – The upgrade project can't proceed until every bug of this type is fixed. The upgrade must be postponed, and can proceed only after the bug is remediated and the cutover test is run again. For a bug to be classified as blocking, it must meet these conditions:\n\n    - It prevents a critical business process from being completed.\n    - No workaround or mitigation is available for it.\n\n- **Non-blocking** – The upgrade project can proceed. Bugs of this type can be fixed in the upgraded system.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,682],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Upgrade - Prepare for go-live\ndescription: This topic describes how you can help guarantee that the source AX 2012 system and the upgrade process remain stable and consistent for go-live.\nauthor: tariqbell\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: margoc\nms.search.scope:  Operations, UnifiedOperations, Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \n# ms.custom: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tabell\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-06-16\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 8","nodes":[{"content":"Upgrade - Prepare for go-live","nodes":[{"pos":[0,29],"content":"Upgrade - Prepare for go-live","nodes":[{"content":"Upgrade - Prepare for go-live","pos":[0,29]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic describes how you can help guarantee that the source AX 2012 system and the upgrade process remain stable and consistent for go-live.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,144],"content":"This topic describes how you can help guarantee that the source AX 2012 system and the upgrade process remain stable and consistent for go-live.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes how you can help guarantee that the source AX 2012 system and the upgrade process remain stable and consistent for go-live.","pos":[0,144]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[690,719],"content":"Upgrade - Prepare for go-live","linkify":"Upgrade - Prepare for go-live","nodes":[{"content":"Upgrade - Prepare for go-live","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"As the go-live date approaches, it's important that you implement this series of steps to help guarantee that the source Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 system and the upgrade process both remain stable and consistent for go-live.","pos":[823,1048]},{"content":"As part of this process, you must lock down any further code changes or application setup changes before you run the final cutover test.","pos":[1050,1186]},{"pos":[1191,1202],"content":"Code freeze","linkify":"Code freeze","nodes":[{"content":"Code freeze","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"All code changes in the AX 2012 environment should be frozen.","pos":[1204,1265]},{"content":"Implement an escalation process to handle any critical issues that appear in AX 2012.","pos":[1266,1351]},{"content":"By default, any new code changes that are required should be implemented only in the new system, not in the AX 2012 environment.","pos":[1352,1480]},{"content":"Implementation of proposed code changes in the AX 2012 environment should be discussed at the management level.","pos":[1481,1592]},{"content":"If a code change is made in AX 2012, the same change must be made in the new system.","pos":[1593,1677]},{"content":"In that case, another iteration of cutover testing and functional testing might be required.","pos":[1678,1770]},{"pos":[1775,1807],"content":"Application configuration freeze","linkify":"Application configuration freeze","nodes":[{"content":"Application configuration freeze","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"All application configuration changes should be frozen in the AX 2012 environment, because these changes could affect how the new system behaves or how the data upgrade scripts behave.","pos":[1809,1993]},{"content":"Configuration changes are changes in the AX 2012 application that are related to the configuration of system functionality.","pos":[1994,2117]},{"content":"By freezing these changes, you help guarantee the stability of the data upgrade process.","pos":[2118,2206]},{"content":"Because configuration changes are typically controlled by the AX 2012 system administrator or a small group of trusted super users, we don't recommend that you enforce the freeze by changing security access.","pos":[2208,2415]},{"content":"Instead, implement the freeze through a business process that is communicated to those users.","pos":[2416,2509]},{"content":"Changes to security access might require a code change (changes to the role definitions themselves) or a configuration change (reassignment of users), and these changes could affect the upgrade process.","pos":[2510,2712]},{"pos":[2717,2747],"content":"Running the final cutover test","linkify":"Running the final cutover test","nodes":[{"content":"Running the final cutover test","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"After no further code or setup changes will occur, run a final cutover test to make sure that all data and code upgrade tasks still run as expected.","pos":[2749,2897]},{"pos":[2901,3151],"content":"[!NOTE]\nYou must complete this step even if you freeze code and setup changes at the beginning of the upgrade project, because the data itself changes every day. This final cutover test also validates that the current data is upgraded successfully.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"You must complete this step even if you freeze code and setup changes at the beginning of the upgrade project, because the data itself changes every day. This final cutover test also validates that the current data is upgraded successfully.","pos":[8,248],"nodes":[{"content":"You must complete this step even if you freeze code and setup changes at the beginning of the upgrade project, because the data itself changes every day.","pos":[0,153]},{"content":"This final cutover test also validates that the current data is upgraded successfully.","pos":[154,240]}]}]},{"content":"Make sure that functional testing is performed against this last upgraded copy.","pos":[3153,3232]},{"content":"At this point in the upgrade project, we recommend that you categorize any bugs that are found:","pos":[3234,3329]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Blocking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The upgrade project can't proceed until every bug of this type is fixed.","pos":[3332,3419],"source":"**Blocking** – The upgrade project can't proceed until every bug of this type is fixed."},{"content":"The upgrade must be postponed, and can proceed only after the bug is remediated and the cutover test is run again.","pos":[3420,3534]},{"content":"For a bug to be classified as blocking, it must meet these conditions:","pos":[3535,3605]},{"content":"It prevents a critical business process from being completed.","pos":[3613,3674]},{"content":"No workaround or mitigation is available for it.","pos":[3681,3729]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Non-blocking<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The upgrade project can proceed.","pos":[3733,3784],"source":"**Non-blocking** – The upgrade project can proceed."},{"content":"Bugs of this type can be fixed in the upgraded system.","pos":[3785,3839]}]}