{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Separate localization models\ndescription: As part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type. This article provides information about this requirement.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/17/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 27561\nms.assetid: 49b634ab-d7f7-4e34-a7e9-7350548bf1a0\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: filatovm\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Separate localization models\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nAs part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type. This article provides information about this requirement.\n\nMultinational customers must comply with regulatory requirements in all countries/regions where they deploy Finance and Operations. At the same time, these customers want to minimize the cost of code maintenance. Therefore, if a localization solution for previous versions of Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, the solution must be split into separate models, so that customers can adopt and deploy the features that they require. An effort has been made to split the Application foundation and Application suite of the Finance and Operations stack into multiple models. \n\nThe number of models is expected to grow over time. Splitting a monolithic code base provides many benefits, such as better scalability, manageability, and serviceability. The localization requirement to split a localization solution into more granular models builds on this effort. The goal is to provide the same benefits to multinational customers of Finance and Operations. \n\nAfter you've classified features as either regulatory or competitive, as described in [Classify localization features](classify-localization-features.md), split the code for these features into at least two models, one model for the regulatory features and at least one model for the competitive features. If the competitive features can be split further (for example, into features that are related to Retail and features that are related to Fixed assets), it's a good idea to split them. However, further splitting isn't mandatory. For more information about how to split the Finance and Operations stack into multiple models, see [Understanding the model split](../dev-tools/model-split.md).\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,983],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Separate localization models\ndescription: As part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type. This article provides information about this requirement.\nauthor: ShylaThompson\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/17/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: shylaw\nms.search.scope: AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 27561\nms.assetid: 49b634ab-d7f7-4e34-a7e9-7350548bf1a0\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: filatovm\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Separate localization models","nodes":[{"pos":[0,28],"content":"Separate localization models","nodes":[{"content":"Separate localization models","pos":[0,28]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"As part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type. This article provides information about this requirement.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,394],"content":"As part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type. This article provides information about this requirement.","nodes":[{"content":"As part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type. This article provides information about this requirement.","pos":[0,394],"nodes":[{"content":"As part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type.","pos":[0,336]},{"content":"This article provides information about this requirement.","pos":[337,394]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[991,1019],"content":"Separate localization models","linkify":"Separate localization models","nodes":[{"content":"Separate localization models","pos":[0,28]}]},{"content":"As part of the requirements for LCS solutions for localization and translation, if a localization solution for previous versions of Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition contains both regulatory and competitive features, localization ISV solution providers must split the solution into separate models for each feature type.","pos":[1065,1421]},{"content":"This article provides information about this requirement.","pos":[1422,1479]},{"content":"Multinational customers must comply with regulatory requirements in all countries/regions where they deploy Finance and Operations.","pos":[1481,1612]},{"content":"At the same time, these customers want to minimize the cost of code maintenance.","pos":[1613,1693]},{"content":"Therefore, if a localization solution for previous versions of Finance and Operations contains both regulatory and competitive features, the solution must be split into separate models, so that customers can adopt and deploy the features that they require.","pos":[1694,1950]},{"content":"An effort has been made to split the Application foundation and Application suite of the Finance and Operations stack into multiple models.","pos":[1951,2090]},{"content":"The number of models is expected to grow over time.","pos":[2093,2144]},{"content":"Splitting a monolithic code base provides many benefits, such as better scalability, manageability, and serviceability.","pos":[2145,2264]},{"content":"The localization requirement to split a localization solution into more granular models builds on this effort.","pos":[2265,2375]},{"content":"The goal is to provide the same benefits to multinational customers of Finance and Operations.","pos":[2376,2470]},{"content":"After you've classified features as either regulatory or competitive, as described in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Classify localization features<ept id=\"p1\">](classify-localization-features.md)</ept>, split the code for these features into at least two models, one model for the regulatory features and at least one model for the competitive features.","pos":[2473,2778],"source":"After you've classified features as either regulatory or competitive, as described in [Classify localization features](classify-localization-features.md), split the code for these features into at least two models, one model for the regulatory features and at least one model for the competitive features."},{"content":"If the competitive features can be split further (for example, into features that are related to Retail and features that are related to Fixed assets), it's a good idea to split them.","pos":[2779,2962]},{"content":"However, further splitting isn't mandatory.","pos":[2963,3006]},{"content":"For more information about how to split the Finance and Operations stack into multiple models, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Understanding the model split<ept id=\"p1\">](../dev-tools/model-split.md)</ept>.","pos":[3007,3167],"source":" For more information about how to split the Finance and Operations stack into multiple models, see [Understanding the model split](../dev-tools/model-split.md)."}]}