{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Extensibility FAQ\ndescription: This topic provides answers to some frequently asked questions about extensibility.\nauthor: dfroslieMSFT\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89563\nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: dfroslie\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-07/01\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 9\n---\n\n# Extensibility FAQ\n\n## Will source code be available after the hard seal?\n\nYes, source code will be available after the hard seal, because it's required for effective implementation and debugging.\n\n## How long will bug fixes and regulatory updates be made for the next major product update? \n\nPer the Modern support policy, bug fixes and regulatory updates will be made for three years.\n\n## How do I contact Microsoft if I have an extensibility request?\n\nThere is a special extensibility request form on the Connect site. You must sign a non-disclosure form to gain access to the Connect site.\n\n## Where can I ask questions about extensibility patterns?\n\nWhen you gain access to the Connect site, you will also gain access to the Operations Extensibility group in Yammer. Operations Extensibility is an active group that has a significant amount of partner engagement.\n\n## Where can I find documentation about extensibility patterns?\n\nDocumentation about extensibility patterns is available from the [Extensibility home page](extensibility-home-page.md).\n\n## Where can I get information about extensibility training?\n\nWe will announce training sessions in multiple ways. AppSource partners might receive direct invitations for some sessions. We will also announce workshops in the Operations Extensibility Yammer group and other forums.  \n\n## What is behind the goal to seal the application?\n\nThe application is being sealed as a step toward reducing upgrade costs in the ecosystem, so that customers can stay current on new releases. Customers can take advantage of new innovations that come from Microsoft and partners.\n\nExtension packages enable better performance at design time, much faster build automation, and unit testing. They also provide more efficient distribution and installation of models from independent software vendors (ISVs) and customers across different systems.\n\n## What specifically is Microsoft working on to support this move?\n\nThere are several areas where the product team is working to improve the extensibility of the product. This work ranges from platform changes that have broad impact to refactored application code that provides additional hook points. For details, see the Operations Extensibility Yammer group and the product release notes.\n\n## After the application is sealed, what should customers do in a critical situation where they must make a quick change?\n\nThis scenario is very similar to a scenario where a critical bug fix is required, and the same process should be followed. As a required first step, you must create a case for support.\n\n## Can I overlayer an ISV solution after the hard seal of the application code?\n\nWe recommend that ISVs also seal their models. This step helps achieve the broader goal of reducing upgrade costs. \n\n## Will I be able to overlayer an on-premises solution?\n\nOn-premises solutions will follow the same patterns as cloud solutions. Therefore, no overlayering of Microsoft code will be supported.\n    \n## How often will Microsoft provide external updates so that partners can see what extensibility enhancements have been made?\n\nWe plan to provide monthly Community Technology Previews (CTPs) after Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,626],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Extensibility FAQ\ndescription: This topic provides answers to some frequently asked questions about extensibility.\nauthor: dfroslieMSFT\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89563\nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: dfroslie\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-07/01\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 9","nodes":[{"content":"Extensibility FAQ","nodes":[{"pos":[0,17],"content":"Extensibility FAQ","nodes":[{"content":"Extensibility FAQ","pos":[0,17]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic provides answers to some frequently asked questions about extensibility.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,83],"content":"This topic provides answers to some frequently asked questions about extensibility.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic provides answers to some frequently asked questions about extensibility.","pos":[0,83]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[634,651],"content":"Extensibility FAQ","linkify":"Extensibility FAQ","nodes":[{"content":"Extensibility FAQ","pos":[0,17]}]},{"pos":[656,706],"content":"Will source code be available after the hard seal?","linkify":"Will source code be available after the hard seal?","nodes":[{"content":"Will source code be available after the hard seal?","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"Yes, source code will be available after the hard seal, because it's required for effective implementation and debugging.","pos":[708,829]},{"pos":[834,923],"content":"How long will bug fixes and regulatory updates be made for the next major product update?","linkify":"How long will bug fixes and regulatory updates be made for the next major product update?","nodes":[{"content":"How long will bug fixes and regulatory updates be made for the next major product update?","pos":[0,89]}]},{"content":"Per the Modern support policy, bug fixes and regulatory updates will be made for three years.","pos":[926,1019]},{"pos":[1024,1086],"content":"How do I contact Microsoft if I have an extensibility request?","linkify":"How do I contact Microsoft if I have an extensibility request?","nodes":[{"content":"How do I contact Microsoft if I have an extensibility request?","pos":[0,62]}]},{"content":"There is a special extensibility request form on the Connect site.","pos":[1088,1154]},{"content":"You must sign a non-disclosure form to gain access to the Connect site.","pos":[1155,1226]},{"pos":[1231,1286],"content":"Where can I ask questions about extensibility patterns?","linkify":"Where can I ask questions about extensibility patterns?","nodes":[{"content":"Where can I ask questions about extensibility patterns?","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"When you gain access to the Connect site, you will also gain access to the Operations Extensibility group in Yammer.","pos":[1288,1404]},{"content":"Operations Extensibility is an active group that has a significant amount of partner engagement.","pos":[1405,1501]},{"pos":[1506,1566],"content":"Where can I find documentation about extensibility patterns?","linkify":"Where can I find documentation about extensibility patterns?","nodes":[{"content":"Where can I find documentation about extensibility patterns?","pos":[0,60]}]},{"pos":[1568,1687],"content":"Documentation about extensibility patterns is available from the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Extensibility home page<ept id=\"p1\">](extensibility-home-page.md)</ept>.","source":"Documentation about extensibility patterns is available from the [Extensibility home page](extensibility-home-page.md)."},{"pos":[1692,1749],"content":"Where can I get information about extensibility training?","linkify":"Where can I get information about extensibility training?","nodes":[{"content":"Where can I get information about extensibility training?","pos":[0,57]}]},{"content":"We will announce training sessions in multiple ways.","pos":[1751,1803]},{"content":"AppSource partners might receive direct invitations for some sessions.","pos":[1804,1874]},{"content":"We will also announce workshops in the Operations Extensibility Yammer group and other forums.","pos":[1875,1969]},{"pos":[1976,2024],"content":"What is behind the goal to seal the application?","linkify":"What is behind the goal to seal the application?","nodes":[{"content":"What is behind the goal to seal the application?","pos":[0,48]}]},{"content":"The application is being sealed as a step toward reducing upgrade costs in the ecosystem, so that customers can stay current on new releases.","pos":[2026,2167]},{"content":"Customers can take advantage of new innovations that come from Microsoft and partners.","pos":[2168,2254]},{"content":"Extension packages enable better performance at design time, much faster build automation, and unit testing.","pos":[2256,2364]},{"content":"They also provide more efficient distribution and installation of models from independent software vendors (ISVs) and customers across different systems.","pos":[2365,2518]},{"pos":[2523,2586],"content":"What specifically is Microsoft working on to support this move?","linkify":"What specifically is Microsoft working on to support this move?","nodes":[{"content":"What specifically is Microsoft working on to support this move?","pos":[0,63]}]},{"content":"There are several areas where the product team is working to improve the extensibility of the product.","pos":[2588,2690]},{"content":"This work ranges from platform changes that have broad impact to refactored application code that provides additional hook points.","pos":[2691,2821]},{"content":"For details, see the Operations Extensibility Yammer group and the product release notes.","pos":[2822,2911]},{"pos":[2916,3034],"content":"After the application is sealed, what should customers do in a critical situation where they must make a quick change?","linkify":"After the application is sealed, what should customers do in a critical situation where they must make a quick change?","nodes":[{"content":"After the application is sealed, what should customers do in a critical situation where they must make a quick change?","pos":[0,118]}]},{"content":"This scenario is very similar to a scenario where a critical bug fix is required, and the same process should be followed.","pos":[3036,3158]},{"content":"As a required first step, you must create a case for support.","pos":[3159,3220]},{"pos":[3225,3301],"content":"Can I overlayer an ISV solution after the hard seal of the application code?","linkify":"Can I overlayer an ISV solution after the hard seal of the application code?","nodes":[{"content":"Can I overlayer an ISV solution after the hard seal of the application code?","pos":[0,76]}]},{"content":"We recommend that ISVs also seal their models.","pos":[3303,3349]},{"content":"This step helps achieve the broader goal of reducing upgrade costs.","pos":[3350,3417]},{"pos":[3423,3475],"content":"Will I be able to overlayer an on-premises solution?","linkify":"Will I be able to overlayer an on-premises solution?","nodes":[{"content":"Will I be able to overlayer an on-premises solution?","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"On-premises solutions will follow the same patterns as cloud solutions.","pos":[3477,3548]},{"content":"Therefore, no overlayering of Microsoft code will be supported.","pos":[3549,3612]},{"pos":[3621,3743],"content":"How often will Microsoft provide external updates so that partners can see what extensibility enhancements have been made?","linkify":"How often will Microsoft provide external updates so that partners can see what extensibility enhancements have been made?","nodes":[{"content":"How often will Microsoft provide external updates so that partners can see what extensibility enhancements have been made?","pos":[0,122]}]},{"content":"We plan to provide monthly Community Technology Previews (CTPs) after Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition July 2017 update.","pos":[3745,3902]}]}