{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Set up earning codes and earning code groups\ndescription: This topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups. Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive. They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.\nauthor: rschloma\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: PayrollEarningCode, PayrollEarningCodeGroup\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 221384\nms.assetid: df18e3bb-bfad-45fb-8a6e-a3479e57b8df\nms.search.region: USA\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: brpotter\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n\n---\n\n# Set up earning codes and earning code groups\n\n[!include[banner](../../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups. Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive. They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.\n\nEarning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive. They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability. Earning codes are also used to calculate various amounts that are used by the payroll system. For example, earning codes are required in order to determine the following amounts:\n\n-   Deductions and contributions for certain benefits\n-   Balances in benefit accrual plans\n-   Disposable income\n\n**Tip:** During the initial configuration, you will be instructed to add earning codes to the various Payroll entities where they are required. Whenever you create or modify earning codes after the initial configuration, consider all the places that the earning code should be used, and update all Payroll entities that are affected. After you create earning codes, you can assign them to workers or earning code groups. You can also manually enter the earning codes on earnings statements. Earning codes are assigned to workers in the following situations:\n\n-   An earning is received on a recurring basis, such as every pay period.\n-   An earning has a unique flat amount for a worker position.\n-   An earning has a unique rate for a worker position.\n\nYou don’t have to assign an earning code to a worker to enter that earning code on the worker’s earnings statement. For example, earning codes for vacation or overtime hours aren't usually assigned to workers. Earning codes are assigned to earning code groups in the following situations:\n\n-   It's convenient to group similar earning codes for administrative purposes. For example, you might want to include all earning codes that are used for benefit accrual plans in one group, so that you can easily identify the codes when you update the plans.\n-   A group of earning codes is used by a payroll process. For example, before a regular-rate-of-pay premium can be calculated, all earning codes that are used for nondiscretionary earnings must be included in a single group.\n\n## Develop a list of the earning codes that you need\nBecause earning codes are used to uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive for their services, most organizations use many earning codes. A typical set of earning codes includes codes for at least the following types of earnings:\n\n-   **Base pay hourly earnings** – If you have workers on multiple shifts, you must have a separate earning code for each shift.\n-   **Salaried earnings** – You must have a separate earning code for each fixed compensation plan.\n-   **Premiums** – If premiums are paid based on other earnings, such as shift differentials or overtime earnings, or on a worker's characteristics, such as bonuses based on credentials, you must have additional earning codes. For more information, see [Premium earning setup tasks](noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md).\n-   **Leave** – You must have separate earning codes for jury duty, bereavement leave, and any other type of leave that your organization offers.\n-   **Benefit accruals** – You must have a separate earning code for every benefit accrual plan. The earning code for a benefit accrual plan is used to verify the available balance in the plan and reduce the balance when a pay statement line that includes the earning code is submitted for payment. For more information, see [Benefit accrual plan tasks](noam-usa-benefit-accrual-plan-tasks.md).\n-   **Retroactive earnings** – We recommend that you create a retroactive earning code for every type of earning that can be paid retroactively. It's helpful if the names of the two codes resemble each other. For example, if the regular earning code is named **Hourly union 1st shift**, the retroactive earning code might be named **Hourly union 1st shift retro**.\n-   **Miscellaneous or occasional earnings** – Many organizations provide car allowances, reimbursement of relocation expenses, and other miscellaneous earnings. You must have a separate earning code for each type of miscellaneous or occasional earning.\n\nEarning codes are shared across legal entities. However, the information on the **Accounting** tab isn't shared. That information applies only to the legal entity that you specify when you enter the information on the tab. For details, see the later sections of this topic.\n\n## Create earning codes\nEach earning type should have a unique earning code. The following information is entered on the **Earning codes** page.\n\n<table>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Fields</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Earning code</td>\n<td>Enter the name of the earning code. You might want to use a naming convention, so that similar earning codes are grouped together.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Unit of measure</td>\n<td>Select the unit of measure that is used to record the unit of work. The following options are available:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Hours</strong> – Select this option for earnings that are paid by the hour.</li>\n<li><strong>Pieces</strong> – Select this option for earning codes that are paid for each piece produced.</li>\n<li><strong>Each</strong> – Select this option for all earning codes where the earnings amount isn’t determined by the number of hours that are worked or the number of pieces that are produced.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Productive</td>\n<td>Select this option if the earning code is used for productive hours. Productive hours represent regular work hours, whereas nonproductive hours represent hours that weren't actually worked, such as vacation and sick pay hours. Hours that are worked, but that are accounted for under another earning code, are also considered nonproductive. This information is used in several benefit and tax calculations, such as the calculation of the regular-rate-of-pay premium that is required for overtime hours under the Fair Labor Standards Act (FLSA). For more information about premium earnings, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Description</td>\n<td>Enter a description of the earning code.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Include in payment run type</td>\n<td>Select a payment run type for this earning code. When you generate pay statements, you select a run type for each payment run. Earning codes that are included in the selected payment run type are processed in that payment run. The following options are available:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Primary</strong> – Include this earning code only in primary payment runs, such as weekly or biweekly runs. These runs are used for earnings such as regular pay, holiday pay, or vacation pay. <strong>Tip:</strong> An earning code of the <strong>Primary</strong> type can be used in only one payment run in each pay period. This restriction can cause issues if, for example, you make a mistake that you must correct in the same payment run. Earning codes of the <strong>Primary and additional</strong> type can be used more than one time in a pay period. Therefore, you should consider selecting <strong>Primary and additional</strong> instead of <strong>Primary</strong> for the earning codes that will be used for your primary payment runs.</li>\n<li><strong>Additional</strong> – Include this earning code only in additional payment runs, such as runs that are used for bonuses or travel reimbursement.</li>\n<li><strong>Primary and additional</strong> – Include this earning code in both primary and additional payment runs. <strong>Tip:</strong> When you select this payment run type, the earning code is processed in the first payment run in the pay period that is either primary or additional. You can’t reserve or hold the earning code for a specific run type.</li>\n<li><strong>Gross up</strong> – Include this earning code in gross-up payment runs, which are most often used for awards or reimbursements where the worker should receive a specific amount after taxes. If you select this option, you must select an earning code in the <strong>Gross up earning code</strong> field. The earning codes that are available in that field have a payment run type of <strong>Automatic</strong>.</li>\n<li><strong>Automatic</strong> – Use this earning code in gross-up payment runs. Gross-up payment runs use earning codes of two payment run types: <strong>Gross up</strong> and <strong>Automatic</strong>. The earning code of the <strong>Gross up</strong> payment run type is used for the earning that must be grossed up. (This earning is often an award or a reimbursement.) The earning code of the <strong>Automatic</strong> payment run type is used for the earnings that cover the taxes, so that the final amount of the gross up earning is correct. Earning lines that use earning codes of the <strong>Automatic</strong> payment run type are generated automatically when gross-up earning codes are processed.</li>\n</ul>\n<strong>Note:</strong> When you select <strong>Gross up</strong> or <strong>Automatic</strong>, the <strong>Tax method</strong>, <strong>Base earnings component</strong>, <strong>Rate basis</strong>, and <strong>Unit of measure</strong> fields are set to predefined values that can’t be changed.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Base earnings component</td>\n<td>If you select this option, the earnings that are calculated by using this earning code are included when worker base pay is determined. Base pay settings are used to generate earnings for salaried workers, and base pay figures are used to calculate and determine benefits that are based on pay.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nThe following information is entered on the **General** tab.\n\n<table>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Rate basis</td>\n<td>This field is used together with the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field to determine the earnings amount.\n<ul>\n<li>If you select <strong>Flat amount</strong>, the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> value is treated as a currency amount. Flat amounts are used when the earnings amount isn’t based on a worker’s fixed compensation. Here are some examples:\n<ul>\n<li>To pay a worker a recurring $500.00 car allowance, select <strong>Flat amount</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>500.00</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field.</li>\n<li>To pay a worker 25 cents for each piece that is produced, select <strong>Flat amount</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>.25</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field.</li>\n</ul></li>\n<li>If you select <strong>Hourly</strong>, <strong>Pay period</strong>, <strong>Monthly</strong>, or <strong>Annually</strong>, the earning rate is calculated by using the workers’ compensation settings. This calculation is based on the time frame of the rate basis. The calculated fixed compensation for the worker is multiplied by the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> value to determine the earning rate. The rate is then multiplied by the quantity on the earnings statement line to determine the amount. Here are some examples:\n<ul>\n<li>To set up an earning code for double-time pay for hourly workers, select <strong>Hourly</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>2</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field. If the calculated hourly equivalent for the worker on the <strong>Employee fixed compensation</strong> page is $35.00, the worker receives 70.00 for each hour that is logged for this earning code.</li>\n<li>To set up a 1-percent uniform allowance that is paid each pay period, select <strong>Pay period</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>.01</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field. The worker then receives 1 percent of his or her pay each pay period.</li>\n</ul></li>\n<li>If <strong>Retroactive</strong> is selected, the earning code is set up for retroactive pay. This option is available only if the <strong>Retroactive earning</strong> option is selected.</li>\n<li>If <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, or <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong> is selected, select an earning code group in the <strong>Basis earning code group</strong> field. These rate bases are most often used to generate premium earnings. For more information, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Amount or multiplier</td>\n<td>Enter the multiplier that is used to calculate earnings, unless the rate basis is a flat amount.\n<ul>\n<li>If the rate basis is a flat amount, the value in this field is treated as a currency amount. For example, if you enter <strong>500</strong> in this field, the value is considered a flat amount of 500.00.</li>\n<li>When the rate basis is <strong>Hourly</strong>, <strong>Pay period</strong>, <strong>Monthly</strong>, or <strong>Annually</strong>, this field is used together with the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field to determine the earnings amount. The rate basis method determines the appropriate compensation rate for workers. Workers who have different hourly rates can use the same hourly earning code, because the correct hourly rate is calculated for each worker and position. For example, if the compensation rate is $24,000 per year, and the worker’s pay cycle is monthly, select <strong>Pay period</strong> as the rate basis, and enter a multiplier of <strong>1</strong>. The generated earnings will be $2,000.</li>\n<li>For information about the value that you should use when the rate basis is <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, or <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong>, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>.</li>\n</ul>\n<strong>Note:</strong> This field is ignored when retroactive earning codes are calculated.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Basis earning code group</td>\n<td>The group of earning codes that are used to calculate the amount of an earnings statement line that uses the selected earning code. This field is available only when the rate basis is <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, or <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong>. These rate bases are most often used for premium earnings. The earning code group is used differently, depending on the rate basis that is selected:\n<ul>\n<li>If the rate basis is <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible hours. The earning code adds an additional amount for each eligible hour.</li>\n<li>If the rate basis is <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible earnings. The earning code adds an additional percentage to the eligible amount.</li>\n<li>If the rate basis is <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible earnings. The earning code adds an amount that is based on the sum of all eligible earnings during a work period. This option is most often used to calculate the amount of the overtime premium that is required by the FLSA.</li>\n</ul>\nFor information about how to use earning code groups to generate premium earnings, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Retroactive earning</td>\n<td>If you select this option, this earning code is set up as a retroactive earning code. This field isn’t available if <strong>Gross up</strong> or <strong>Automatic</strong> is selected in the <strong>Include in payment run type</strong> field. When a retroactive earning code is created, the <strong>Rate basis</strong>, <strong>Productive</strong>, <strong>Unit of measure</strong>, and <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> fields are set to predefined values that can’t be changed. <strong>Note:</strong> If you select this option and then clear it, the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field is set to <strong>Flat amount</strong>.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Tax method</td>\n<td>The tax rate that is used to determine the amount of tax that is withheld for this earning code. The following options are available:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Regular</strong> – Taxes are calculated by using the standard rate.</li>\n<li><strong>Supplemental</strong> – Taxes are calculated at a supplemental rate.</li>\n<li><strong>Exempt</strong> – No tax is charged on earnings that are calculated by using this earning code.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Fringe benefit type</td>\n<td>The benefits that the worker is taxed on, even if the worker doesn't receive any direct compensation for them, such as life insurance and health benefits.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Retroactive earning code</td>\n<td>This field is used to associate a non-retroactive earning code with an earning code that will retroactively adjust the processed earning lines that use this code. <strong>Note:</strong> This field is optional. It's available only if the <strong>Retroactive earning</strong> option is cleared.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Gross up earning code</td>\n<td>Select an earning code to use in a gross-up payment run for the earnings that cover the taxes, so that the final amount of the gross-up earning is correct. This field is available only if <strong>Gross up</strong> is selected in the <strong>Include in payment run type</strong> field. The earning codes that you can select in this field have a value of <strong>Automatic</strong> in the <strong>Include in payment run type</strong> field.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Allow editing of earning statement rates</td>\n<td>Select this option to let users change the rate on earning statement lines that are generated by using this earning code. If you plan to enter beginning balances during the initial payroll setup, select this option for all earning codes when you create them. After you enter the beginning balances, you can clear this option to prevent rates from being changed during typical payroll processing. <strong>Note:</strong> If a salary line is generated by using an automated process, the rate on that line can’t be changed, even if this option is selected. If you manually add a salary line, you can change the rate on the line if this option is selected.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Base definition</td>\n<td>Select how the earning code is used to calculate workers’ compensation and general liability insurance. The following options are available:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Not applicable</strong> – The earnings that are associated with this earning code aren't used in the calculation.</li>\n<li><strong>Base time</strong> – The calculations use 100 percent of the earnings.</li>\n<li><strong>Time and a half</strong> – The calculations use 150 percent of the earnings.</li>\n<li><strong>Double time</strong> – The calculations use 200 percent of the earnings.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\nThe following information is entered on the **Accounting** tab. This tab stores financial dimensions and posting rules that are applied when the selected earning code is assigned to a worker. Earning codes are shared across legal entities, but the settings on the **Accounting** tab are specific to the selected legal entity.\n\n| Field                        | Description     |\n|------------------------------|------------------------------------------|\n| Legal entity                 | The legal entity for the dimension template, default dimensions, accounting rules, and project category that are used together with the earning code.                             |\n| Project category             | The project category that the earnings are charged to, if the earnings are charged to a project category. **Note:** If the **Unit of measure** field is set to **Hours** for this earning code, this list is limited to project categories that bill hourly. Otherwise, the list contains only projects that are billed as expenses.      |\n| Distribution template        | The template that is used to determine the default dimension values and percentages for earning distributions. This information can be changed on individual earning lines. **Note:** If you select a template in this field, this setting overrides the template that is assigned to the position when you create earnings statement lines.                    |\n| Default financial dimensions | The default financial dimensions for the main account. When you select a financial dimension value, the **Where the %1 dimension is used** field group shows where the dimension is used in account structures and advanced rule structures. **Note:** The dimension values from the earning code and the position are added to the earning line and can be changed. When a value for the same dimension is specified for both the earning code and the position, the dimension value for the earning code is used. |\n| Posting rules                | The accounting rules that are applied when earnings that are generated for this earning code are posted. The main account for distributions is based on the department, job, and worker selections for each posting rule. **Note:** The main account can’t be changed on the earning lines.                        |\n\nThe following information is entered on the **Reporting** tab. This tab contains tax-related information that is required by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).\n\n| Field                 | Description                                                                                      |\n|-----------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Form W-2 control data | The box number and label on Form W-2 that are used to report tax-related information to the IRS. |\n\nThe following information is entered on the **Earning code groups** tab. This tab shows the earning code groups that the selected earning code is assigned to. You can also add earning code groups to the earning code and remove earning code groups from the earning code. \n\nYou can create earning code groups on the **Earning code groups** page.\n\n| Field  | Description                                                                                                                                                                         |\n|--------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Add    | Select the earning code group to assign the earning code to. Earning code groups that already include the earning code aren’t available.                                            |\n| Remove | Select the earning code group to remove the earning code from, and then click **Remove**. The earning code group still exists, but it no longer includes the selected earning code. |\n\n## If required: Create earning code groups\nEarning code groups are required when you select **Percent of earnings**, **Hours of earnings**, or **Regular rate of pay** as the rate basis. \n\n**Caution:** If you use regular-rate-of-pay earning codes to calculate and pay the overtime premiums that are required by FLSA, every earning code for nondiscretionary earnings must be included in the earning code group that is used by the regular-rate-of-pay earning codes. If any earning codes are omitted from the earning code group, the overtime premium won’t be calculated correctly. \n\nEarning code groups can also make it easier for you to manage earning codes. For example, you can create a group that contains all earning codes that apply to union members. If changes in the union contract require that you update these earning codes, the earning code group makes it easy to identify the earning codes that are affected. \n\nYou can assign earning codes to groups when you create them, or you can assign an earning code to a group on the **Earning code groups** tab of the **Earning codes** page.\n\n## Optional: View the groups that include an earning code and add earning codes to the group\nOn the **Earning code groups** tab of the **Earning codes** page, you can see each group that an earning code belongs to. Additionally, on the **Earning codes** tab of the **Earning code groups** page, you can see each earning code that belongs to the selected group.\n\n## Next step\nThe next step is to set up schedules, leave types, and benefit accrual plans. For more information, see [Work schedule and leave tasks](noam-usa-work-schedule-leave-tasks.md) and [Benefit accrual plan tasks](noam-usa-benefit-accrual-plan-tasks.md).  \n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Generate earnings](noam-usa-generate-earnings.md)\n\n[Generate payroll reports](noam-usa-generate-payroll-reports.md)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,939],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Set up earning codes and earning code groups\ndescription: This topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups. Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive. They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.\nauthor: rschloma\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: PayrollEarningCode, PayrollEarningCodeGroup\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 221384\nms.assetid: df18e3bb-bfad-45fb-8a6e-a3479e57b8df\nms.search.region: USA\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: brpotter\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-11-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611\n","nodes":[{"content":"Set up earning codes and earning code groups","nodes":[{"pos":[0,44],"content":"Set up earning codes and earning code groups","nodes":[{"content":"Set up earning codes and earning code groups","pos":[0,44]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups. Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive. They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,287],"content":"This topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups. Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive. They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups. Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive. They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.","pos":[0,287],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups.","pos":[0,72]},{"content":"Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive.","pos":[73,148]},{"content":"They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.","pos":[149,287]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[947,991],"content":"Set up earning codes and earning code groups","linkify":"Set up earning codes and earning code groups","nodes":[{"content":"Set up earning codes and earning code groups","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":"This topic explains how to set up earning codes and earning code groups.","pos":[1040,1112]},{"content":"Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive.","pos":[1113,1188]},{"content":"They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.","pos":[1189,1327]},{"content":"Earning codes uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive.","pos":[1329,1404]},{"content":"They include parameters that are related to earnings, such as accounting rules, tax laws, reporting requirements, and gross-up capability.","pos":[1405,1543]},{"content":"Earning codes are also used to calculate various amounts that are used by the payroll system.","pos":[1544,1637]},{"content":"For example, earning codes are required in order to determine the following amounts:","pos":[1638,1722]},{"content":"Deductions and contributions for certain benefits","pos":[1728,1777]},{"content":"Balances in benefit accrual plans","pos":[1782,1815]},{"content":"Disposable income","pos":[1820,1837]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Tip:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> During the initial configuration, you will be instructed to add earning codes to the various Payroll entities where they are required.","pos":[1839,1982],"source":"**Tip:** During the initial configuration, you will be instructed to add earning codes to the various Payroll entities where they are required."},{"content":"Whenever you create or modify earning codes after the initial configuration, consider all the places that the earning code should be used, and update all Payroll entities that are affected.","pos":[1983,2172]},{"content":"After you create earning codes, you can assign them to workers or earning code groups.","pos":[2173,2259]},{"content":"You can also manually enter the earning codes on earnings statements.","pos":[2260,2329]},{"content":"Earning codes are assigned to workers in the following situations:","pos":[2330,2396]},{"content":"An earning is received on a recurring basis, such as every pay period.","pos":[2402,2472]},{"content":"An earning has a unique flat amount for a worker position.","pos":[2477,2535]},{"content":"An earning has a unique rate for a worker position.","pos":[2540,2591]},{"content":"You don’t have to assign an earning code to a worker to enter that earning code on the worker’s earnings statement.","pos":[2593,2708]},{"content":"For example, earning codes for vacation or overtime hours aren't usually assigned to workers.","pos":[2709,2802]},{"content":"Earning codes are assigned to earning code groups in the following situations:","pos":[2803,2881]},{"content":"It's convenient to group similar earning codes for administrative purposes.","pos":[2887,2962]},{"content":"For example, you might want to include all earning codes that are used for benefit accrual plans in one group, so that you can easily identify the codes when you update the plans.","pos":[2963,3142]},{"content":"A group of earning codes is used by a payroll process.","pos":[3147,3201]},{"content":"For example, before a regular-rate-of-pay premium can be calculated, all earning codes that are used for nondiscretionary earnings must be included in a single group.","pos":[3202,3368]},{"pos":[3373,3422],"content":"Develop a list of the earning codes that you need","linkify":"Develop a list of the earning codes that you need","nodes":[{"content":"Develop a list of the earning codes that you need","pos":[0,49]}]},{"content":"Because earning codes are used to uniquely identify every type of earning that workers receive for their services, most organizations use many earning codes.","pos":[3423,3580]},{"content":"A typical set of earning codes includes codes for at least the following types of earnings:","pos":[3581,3672]},{"pos":[3678,3802],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Base pay hourly earnings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If you have workers on multiple shifts, you must have a separate earning code for each shift.","source":"**Base pay hourly earnings** – If you have workers on multiple shifts, you must have a separate earning code for each shift."},{"pos":[3807,3902],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Salaried earnings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You must have a separate earning code for each fixed compensation plan.","source":"**Salaried earnings** – You must have a separate earning code for each fixed compensation plan."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Premiums<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If premiums are paid based on other earnings, such as shift differentials or overtime earnings, or on a worker's characteristics, such as bonuses based on credentials, you must have additional earning codes.","pos":[3907,4129],"source":"**Premiums** – If premiums are paid based on other earnings, such as shift differentials or overtime earnings, or on a worker's characteristics, such as bonuses based on credentials, you must have additional earning codes."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Premium earning setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md)</ept>.","pos":[4130,4227],"source":" For more information, see [Premium earning setup tasks](noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md)."},{"pos":[4232,4373],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Leave<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You must have separate earning codes for jury duty, bereavement leave, and any other type of leave that your organization offers.","source":"**Leave** – You must have separate earning codes for jury duty, bereavement leave, and any other type of leave that your organization offers."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Benefit accruals<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You must have a separate earning code for every benefit accrual plan.","pos":[4378,4470],"source":"**Benefit accruals** – You must have a separate earning code for every benefit accrual plan."},{"content":"The earning code for a benefit accrual plan is used to verify the available balance in the plan and reduce the balance when a pay statement line that includes the earning code is submitted for payment.","pos":[4471,4672]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Benefit accrual plan tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-benefit-accrual-plan-tasks.md)</ept>.","pos":[4673,4768],"source":" For more information, see [Benefit accrual plan tasks](noam-usa-benefit-accrual-plan-tasks.md)."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retroactive earnings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – We recommend that you create a retroactive earning code for every type of earning that can be paid retroactively.","pos":[4773,4913],"source":"**Retroactive earnings** – We recommend that you create a retroactive earning code for every type of earning that can be paid retroactively."},{"content":"It's helpful if the names of the two codes resemble each other.","pos":[4914,4977]},{"content":"For example, if the regular earning code is named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Hourly union 1st shift<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, the retroactive earning code might be named <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Hourly union 1st shift retro<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[4978,5133],"source":" For example, if the regular earning code is named **Hourly union 1st shift**, the retroactive earning code might be named **Hourly union 1st shift retro**."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Miscellaneous or occasional earnings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Many organizations provide car allowances, reimbursement of relocation expenses, and other miscellaneous earnings.","pos":[5138,5295],"source":"**Miscellaneous or occasional earnings** – Many organizations provide car allowances, reimbursement of relocation expenses, and other miscellaneous earnings."},{"content":"You must have a separate earning code for each type of miscellaneous or occasional earning.","pos":[5296,5387]},{"content":"Earning codes are shared across legal entities.","pos":[5389,5436]},{"content":"However, the information on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab isn't shared.","pos":[5437,5501],"source":" However, the information on the **Accounting** tab isn't shared."},{"content":"That information applies only to the legal entity that you specify when you enter the information on the tab.","pos":[5502,5611]},{"content":"For details, see the later sections of this topic.","pos":[5612,5662]},{"pos":[5667,5687],"content":"Create earning codes","linkify":"Create earning codes","nodes":[{"content":"Create earning codes","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Each earning type should have a unique earning code.","pos":[5688,5740]},{"content":"The following information is entered on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning codes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[5741,5808],"source":" The following information is entered on the **Earning codes** page."},{"content":"Fields","pos":[5850,5856]},{"content":"Description","pos":[5866,5877]},{"content":"Earning code","pos":[5927,5939]},{"content":"Enter the name of the earning code.","pos":[5949,5984]},{"content":"You might want to use a naming convention, so that similar earning codes are grouped together.","pos":[5985,6079]},{"content":"Unit of measure","pos":[6113,6128]},{"content":"Select the unit of measure that is used to record the unit of work.","pos":[6138,6205]},{"content":"The following options are available:","pos":[6206,6242],"source":" The following options are available:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hours<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this option for earnings that are paid by the hour.","pos":[6252,6335],"source":"<strong>Hours</strong> – Select this option for earnings that are paid by the hour."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Pieces<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this option for earning codes that are paid for each piece produced.","pos":[6345,6446],"source":"<strong>Pieces</strong> – Select this option for earning codes that are paid for each piece produced."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Each<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select this option for all earning codes where the earnings amount isn’t determined by the number of hours that are worked or the number of pieces that are produced.","pos":[6456,6645],"source":"<strong>Each</strong> – Select this option for all earning codes where the earnings amount isn’t determined by the number of hours that are worked or the number of pieces that are produced."},{"content":"Productive","pos":[6689,6699]},{"content":"Select this option if the earning code is used for productive hours.","pos":[6709,6777]},{"content":"Productive hours represent regular work hours, whereas nonproductive hours represent hours that weren't actually worked, such as vacation and sick pay hours.","pos":[6778,6935]},{"content":"Hours that are worked, but that are accounted for under another earning code, are also considered nonproductive.","pos":[6936,7048]},{"content":"This information is used in several benefit and tax calculations, such as the calculation of the regular-rate-of-pay premium that is required for overtime hours under the Fair Labor Standards Act (FLSA).","pos":[7049,7252]},{"content":"For more information about premium earnings, see <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\"&gt;</bpt>Premium earning setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>.","pos":[7253,7384],"source":" For more information about premium earnings, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>."},{"content":"Description","pos":[7418,7429]},{"content":"Enter a description of the earning code.","pos":[7439,7479]},{"content":"Include in payment run type","pos":[7512,7539]},{"content":"Select a payment run type for this earning code.","pos":[7549,7597]},{"content":"When you generate pay statements, you select a run type for each payment run.","pos":[7598,7675]},{"content":"Earning codes that are included in the selected payment run type are processed in that payment run.","pos":[7676,7775]},{"content":"The following options are available:","pos":[7776,7812],"source":" The following options are available:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Primary<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Include this earning code only in primary payment runs, such as weekly or biweekly runs.","pos":[7822,7937],"source":"<strong>Primary</strong> – Include this earning code only in primary payment runs, such as weekly or biweekly runs."},{"content":"These runs are used for earnings such as regular pay, holiday pay, or vacation pay.","pos":[7938,8021]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Tip:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> An earning code of the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Primary<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type can be used in only one payment run in each pay period.","pos":[8022,8152],"source":"<strong>Tip:</strong> An earning code of the <strong>Primary</strong> type can be used in only one payment run in each pay period."},{"content":"This restriction can cause issues if, for example, you make a mistake that you must correct in the same payment run.","pos":[8153,8269]},{"content":"Earning codes of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Primary and additional<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> type can be used more than one time in a pay period.","pos":[8270,8383],"source":" Earning codes of the <strong>Primary and additional</strong> type can be used more than one time in a pay period."},{"content":"Therefore, you should consider selecting <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Primary and additional<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> instead of <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Primary<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> for the earning codes that will be used for your primary payment runs.","pos":[8384,8571],"source":" Therefore, you should consider selecting <strong>Primary and additional</strong> instead of <strong>Primary</strong> for the earning codes that will be used for your primary payment runs."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Additional<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Include this earning code only in additional payment runs, such as runs that are used for bonuses or travel reimbursement.","pos":[8581,8733],"source":"<strong>Additional</strong> – Include this earning code only in additional payment runs, such as runs that are used for bonuses or travel reimbursement."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Primary and additional<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Include this earning code in both primary and additional payment runs.","pos":[8743,8855],"source":"<strong>Primary and additional</strong> – Include this earning code in both primary and additional payment runs."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Tip:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> When you select this payment run type, the earning code is processed in the first payment run in the pay period that is either primary or additional.","pos":[8856,9027],"source":"<strong>Tip:</strong> When you select this payment run type, the earning code is processed in the first payment run in the pay period that is either primary or additional."},{"content":"You can’t reserve or hold the earning code for a specific run type.","pos":[9028,9095]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Gross up<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Include this earning code in gross-up payment runs, which are most often used for awards or reimbursements where the worker should receive a specific amount after taxes.","pos":[9105,9302],"source":"<strong>Gross up</strong> – Include this earning code in gross-up payment runs, which are most often used for awards or reimbursements where the worker should receive a specific amount after taxes."},{"content":"If you select this option, you must select an earning code in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Gross up earning code<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[9303,9414],"source":" If you select this option, you must select an earning code in the <strong>Gross up earning code</strong> field."},{"content":"The earning codes that are available in that field have a payment run type of <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[9415,9520],"source":" The earning codes that are available in that field have a payment run type of <strong>Automatic</strong>."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Use this earning code in gross-up payment runs.","pos":[9530,9606],"source":"<strong>Automatic</strong> – Use this earning code in gross-up payment runs."},{"content":"Gross-up payment runs use earning codes of two payment run types: <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Gross up<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[9607,9730],"source":" Gross-up payment runs use earning codes of two payment run types: <strong>Gross up</strong> and <strong>Automatic</strong>."},{"content":"The earning code of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Gross up<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> payment run type is used for the earning that must be grossed up.","pos":[9731,9846],"source":" The earning code of the <strong>Gross up</strong> payment run type is used for the earning that must be grossed up."},{"content":"(This earning is often an award or a reimbursement.) The earning code of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> payment run type is used for the earnings that cover the taxes, so that the final amount of the gross up earning is correct.","pos":[9847,10075],"source":" (This earning is often an award or a reimbursement.) The earning code of the <strong>Automatic</strong> payment run type is used for the earnings that cover the taxes, so that the final amount of the gross up earning is correct."},{"content":"Earning lines that use earning codes of the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> payment run type are generated automatically when gross-up earning codes are processed.","pos":[10076,10234],"source":" Earning lines that use earning codes of the <strong>Automatic</strong> payment run type are generated automatically when gross-up earning codes are processed."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">\n&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> When you select <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Gross up<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> or <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Tax method<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Base earnings component<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p6\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p6\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p7\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Unit of measure<ept id=\"p7\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> fields are set to predefined values that can’t be changed.","pos":[10245,10541],"source":"\n<strong>Note:</strong> When you select <strong>Gross up</strong> or <strong>Automatic</strong>, the <strong>Tax method</strong>, <strong>Base earnings component</strong>, <strong>Rate basis</strong>, and <strong>Unit of measure</strong> fields are set to predefined values that can’t be changed."},{"content":"Base earnings component","pos":[10575,10598]},{"content":"If you select this option, the earnings that are calculated by using this earning code are included when worker base pay is determined.","pos":[10608,10743]},{"content":"Base pay settings are used to generate earnings for salaried workers, and base pay figures are used to calculate and determine benefits that are based on pay.","pos":[10744,10902]},{"pos":[10933,10993],"content":"The following information is entered on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>General<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.","source":"The following information is entered on the **General** tab."},{"content":"Field","pos":[11035,11040]},{"content":"Description","pos":[11050,11061]},{"content":"Rate basis","pos":[11111,11121]},{"content":"This field is used together with the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field to determine the earnings amount.","pos":[11131,11245],"source":"This field is used together with the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field to determine the earnings amount."},{"content":"If you select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Flat amount<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> value is treated as a currency amount.","pos":[11255,11379],"source":"If you select <strong>Flat amount</strong>, the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> value is treated as a currency amount."},{"content":"Flat amounts are used when the earnings amount isn’t based on a worker’s fixed compensation.","pos":[11380,11472]},{"content":"Here are some examples:","pos":[11473,11496],"source":" Here are some examples:\n"},{"content":"To pay a worker a recurring $500.00 car allowance, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Flat amount<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, and enter <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>500.00<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[11506,11720],"source":"To pay a worker a recurring $500.00 car allowance, select <strong>Flat amount</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>500.00</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field."},{"content":"To pay a worker 25 cents for each piece that is produced, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Flat amount<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, and enter <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>.25<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[11730,11948],"source":"To pay a worker 25 cents for each piece that is produced, select <strong>Flat amount</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>.25</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field."},{"content":"If you select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hourly<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Pay period<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Monthly<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Annually<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, the earning rate is calculated by using the workers’ compensation settings.","pos":[11969,12168],"source":"If you select <strong>Hourly</strong>, <strong>Pay period</strong>, <strong>Monthly</strong>, or <strong>Annually</strong>, the earning rate is calculated by using the workers’ compensation settings."},{"content":"This calculation is based on the time frame of the rate basis.","pos":[12169,12231]},{"content":"The calculated fixed compensation for the worker is multiplied by the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> value to determine the earning rate.","pos":[12232,12376],"source":" The calculated fixed compensation for the worker is multiplied by the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> value to determine the earning rate."},{"content":"The rate is then multiplied by the quantity on the earnings statement line to determine the amount.","pos":[12377,12476]},{"content":"Here are some examples:","pos":[12477,12500],"source":" Here are some examples:\n"},{"content":"To set up an earning code for double-time pay for hourly workers, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hourly<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, and enter <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>2<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[12510,12729],"source":"To set up an earning code for double-time pay for hourly workers, select <strong>Hourly</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>2</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field."},{"content":"If the calculated hourly equivalent for the worker on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Employee fixed compensation<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page is $35.00, the worker receives 70.00 for each hour that is logged for this earning code.","pos":[12730,12926],"source":" If the calculated hourly equivalent for the worker on the <strong>Employee fixed compensation</strong> page is $35.00, the worker receives 70.00 for each hour that is logged for this earning code."},{"content":"To set up a 1-percent uniform allowance that is paid each pay period, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Pay period<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field, and enter <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>.01<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[12936,13165],"source":"To set up a 1-percent uniform allowance that is paid each pay period, select <strong>Pay period</strong> in the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field, and enter <strong>.01</strong> in the <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> field."},{"content":"The worker then receives 1 percent of his or her pay each pay period.","pos":[13166,13235]},{"content":"If <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Retroactive<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> is selected, the earning code is set up for retroactive pay.","pos":[13256,13348],"source":"If <strong>Retroactive</strong> is selected, the earning code is set up for retroactive pay."},{"content":"This option is available only if the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Retroactive earning<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> option is selected.","pos":[13349,13442],"source":" This option is available only if the <strong>Retroactive earning</strong> option is selected."},{"content":"If <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hours of earnings<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Regular rate of pay<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> is selected, select an earning code group in the <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Basis earning code group<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[13452,13666],"source":"If <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, or <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong> is selected, select an earning code group in the <strong>Basis earning code group</strong> field."},{"content":"These rate bases are most often used to generate premium earnings.","pos":[13667,13733]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\"&gt;</bpt>Premium earning setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>.","pos":[13734,13842],"source":" For more information, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>."},{"content":"Amount or multiplier","pos":[13887,13907]},{"content":"Enter the multiplier that is used to calculate earnings, unless the rate basis is a flat amount.","pos":[13917,14013]},{"content":"If the rate basis is a flat amount, the value in this field is treated as a currency amount.","pos":[14023,14115]},{"content":"For example, if you enter <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>500<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in this field, the value is considered a flat amount of 500.00.","pos":[14116,14226],"source":" For example, if you enter <strong>500</strong> in this field, the value is considered a flat amount of 500.00."},{"content":"When the rate basis is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hourly<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Pay period<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Monthly<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Annually<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, this field is used together with the <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field to determine the earnings amount.","pos":[14236,14473],"source":"When the rate basis is <strong>Hourly</strong>, <strong>Pay period</strong>, <strong>Monthly</strong>, or <strong>Annually</strong>, this field is used together with the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field to determine the earnings amount."},{"content":"The rate basis method determines the appropriate compensation rate for workers.","pos":[14474,14553]},{"content":"Workers who have different hourly rates can use the same hourly earning code, because the correct hourly rate is calculated for each worker and position.","pos":[14554,14707]},{"content":"For example, if the compensation rate is $24,000 per year, and the worker’s pay cycle is monthly, select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Pay period<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> as the rate basis, and enter a multiplier of <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>1<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[14708,14905],"source":" For example, if the compensation rate is $24,000 per year, and the worker’s pay cycle is monthly, select <strong>Pay period</strong> as the rate basis, and enter a multiplier of <strong>1</strong>."},{"content":"The generated earnings will be $2,000.","pos":[14906,14944]},{"content":"For information about the value that you should use when the rate basis is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hours of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Regular rate of pay<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, see <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\"&gt;</bpt>Premium earning setup tasks<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>.","pos":[14954,15230],"source":"For information about the value that you should use when the rate basis is <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, or <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong>, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">\n&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> This field is ignored when retroactive earning codes are calculated.","pos":[15241,15333],"source":"\n<strong>Note:</strong> This field is ignored when retroactive earning codes are calculated."},{"content":"Basis earning code group","pos":[15366,15390]},{"content":"The group of earning codes that are used to calculate the amount of an earnings statement line that uses the selected earning code.","pos":[15400,15531]},{"content":"This field is available only when the rate basis is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hours of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Regular rate of pay<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[15532,15698],"source":" This field is available only when the rate basis is <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, or <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong>."},{"content":"These rate bases are most often used for premium earnings.","pos":[15699,15757]},{"content":"The earning code group is used differently, depending on the rate basis that is selected:","pos":[15758,15847],"source":" The earning code group is used differently, depending on the rate basis that is selected:\n"},{"content":"If the rate basis is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Hours of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible hours.","pos":[15857,15999],"source":"If the rate basis is <strong>Hours of earnings</strong>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible hours."},{"content":"The earning code adds an additional amount for each eligible hour.","pos":[16000,16066]},{"content":"If the rate basis is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible earnings.","pos":[16076,16223],"source":"If the rate basis is <strong>Percent of earnings</strong>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible earnings."},{"content":"The earning code adds an additional percentage to the eligible amount.","pos":[16224,16294]},{"content":"If the rate basis is <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Regular rate of pay<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible earnings.","pos":[16304,16451],"source":"If the rate basis is <strong>Regular rate of pay</strong>, the line uses the earning codes in the earning code group to identify eligible earnings."},{"content":"The earning code adds an amount that is based on the sum of all eligible earnings during a work period.","pos":[16452,16555]},{"content":"This option is most often used to calculate the amount of the overtime premium that is required by the FLSA.","pos":[16556,16664]},{"content":"For information about how to use earning code groups to generate premium earnings, see <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\"&gt;</bpt>Premium earning setup tasks<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>.","pos":[16676,16845],"source":"\nFor information about how to use earning code groups to generate premium earnings, see <a href=\"noam-usa-premium-earning-setup-tasks.md\">Premium earning setup tasks</a>."},{"content":"Retroactive earning","pos":[16879,16898]},{"content":"If you select this option, this earning code is set up as a retroactive earning code.","pos":[16908,16993]},{"content":"This field isn’t available if <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Gross up<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> is selected in the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Include in payment run type<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[16994,17150],"source":" This field isn’t available if <strong>Gross up</strong> or <strong>Automatic</strong> is selected in the <strong>Include in payment run type</strong> field."},{"content":"When a retroactive earning code is created, the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Productive<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Unit of measure<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, and <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Amount or multiplier<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> fields are set to predefined values that can’t be changed.","pos":[17151,17391],"source":" When a retroactive earning code is created, the <strong>Rate basis</strong>, <strong>Productive</strong>, <strong>Unit of measure</strong>, and <strong>Amount or multiplier</strong> fields are set to predefined values that can’t be changed."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> If you select this option and then clear it, the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Rate basis<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Flat amount<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>.","pos":[17392,17537],"source":"<strong>Note:</strong> If you select this option and then clear it, the <strong>Rate basis</strong> field is set to <strong>Flat amount</strong>."},{"content":"Tax method","pos":[17570,17580]},{"content":"The tax rate that is used to determine the amount of tax that is withheld for this earning code.","pos":[17590,17686]},{"content":"The following options are available:","pos":[17687,17723],"source":" The following options are available:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Regular<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Taxes are calculated by using the standard rate.","pos":[17733,17808],"source":"<strong>Regular</strong> – Taxes are calculated by using the standard rate."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Supplemental<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Taxes are calculated at a supplemental rate.","pos":[17818,17894],"source":"<strong>Supplemental</strong> – Taxes are calculated at a supplemental rate."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Exempt<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – No tax is charged on earnings that are calculated by using this earning code.","pos":[17904,18007],"source":"<strong>Exempt</strong> – No tax is charged on earnings that are calculated by using this earning code."},{"content":"Fringe benefit type","pos":[18052,18071]},{"content":"The benefits that the worker is taxed on, even if the worker doesn't receive any direct compensation for them, such as life insurance and health benefits.","pos":[18081,18235]},{"content":"Retroactive earning code","pos":[18268,18292]},{"content":"This field is used to associate a non-retroactive earning code with an earning code that will retroactively adjust the processed earning lines that use this code.","pos":[18302,18464]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> This field is optional.","pos":[18465,18511],"source":"<strong>Note:</strong> This field is optional."},{"content":"It's available only if the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Retroactive earning<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> option is cleared.","pos":[18512,18594],"source":" It's available only if the <strong>Retroactive earning</strong> option is cleared."},{"content":"Gross up earning code","pos":[18628,18649]},{"content":"Select an earning code to use in a gross-up payment run for the earnings that cover the taxes, so that the final amount of the gross-up earning is correct.","pos":[18659,18814]},{"content":"This field is available only if <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Gross up<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> is selected in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Include in payment run type<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[18815,18943],"source":" This field is available only if <strong>Gross up</strong> is selected in the <strong>Include in payment run type</strong> field."},{"content":"The earning codes that you can select in this field have a value of <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Include in payment run type<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[18944,19097],"source":" The earning codes that you can select in this field have a value of <strong>Automatic</strong> in the <strong>Include in payment run type</strong> field."},{"content":"Allow editing of earning statement rates","pos":[19130,19170]},{"content":"Select this option to let users change the rate on earning statement lines that are generated by using this earning code.","pos":[19180,19301]},{"content":"If you plan to enter beginning balances during the initial payroll setup, select this option for all earning codes when you create them.","pos":[19302,19438]},{"content":"After you enter the beginning balances, you can clear this option to prevent rates from being changed during typical payroll processing.","pos":[19439,19575]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> If a salary line is generated by using an automated process, the rate on that line can’t be changed, even if this option is selected.","pos":[19576,19732],"source":"<strong>Note:</strong> If a salary line is generated by using an automated process, the rate on that line can’t be changed, even if this option is selected."},{"content":"If you manually add a salary line, you can change the rate on the line if this option is selected.","pos":[19733,19831]},{"content":"Base definition","pos":[19865,19880]},{"content":"Select how the earning code is used to calculate workers’ compensation and general liability insurance.","pos":[19890,19993]},{"content":"The following options are available:","pos":[19994,20030],"source":" The following options are available:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Not applicable<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The earnings that are associated with this earning code aren't used in the calculation.","pos":[20040,20161],"source":"<strong>Not applicable</strong> – The earnings that are associated with this earning code aren't used in the calculation."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Base time<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The calculations use 100 percent of the earnings.","pos":[20171,20249],"source":"<strong>Base time</strong> – The calculations use 100 percent of the earnings."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Time and a half<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The calculations use 150 percent of the earnings.","pos":[20259,20343],"source":"<strong>Time and a half</strong> – The calculations use 150 percent of the earnings."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Double time<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The calculations use 200 percent of the earnings.","pos":[20353,20433],"source":"<strong>Double time</strong> – The calculations use 200 percent of the earnings."},{"content":"The following information is entered on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[20475,20538],"source":"The following information is entered on the **Accounting** tab."},{"content":"This tab stores financial dimensions and posting rules that are applied when the selected earning code is assigned to a worker.","pos":[20539,20666]},{"content":"Earning codes are shared across legal entities, but the settings on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab are specific to the selected legal entity.","pos":[20667,20800],"source":" Earning codes are shared across legal entities, but the settings on the **Accounting** tab are specific to the selected legal entity."},{"content":"Field","pos":[20804,20809]},{"content":"Description","pos":[20835,20846]},{"content":"Legal entity","pos":[20931,20943]},{"content":"The legal entity for the dimension template, default dimensions, accounting rules, and project category that are used together with the earning code.","pos":[20962,21111]},{"content":"Project category","pos":[21144,21160]},{"content":"The project category that the earnings are charged to, if the earnings are charged to a project category.","pos":[21175,21280]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Unit of measure<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field is set to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Hours<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> for this earning code, this list is limited to project categories that bill hourly.","pos":[21281,21427],"source":"**Note:** If the **Unit of measure** field is set to **Hours** for this earning code, this list is limited to project categories that bill hourly."},{"content":"Otherwise, the list contains only projects that are billed as expenses.","pos":[21428,21499]},{"content":"Distribution template","pos":[21509,21530]},{"content":"The template that is used to determine the default dimension values and percentages for earning distributions.","pos":[21540,21650]},{"content":"This information can be changed on individual earning lines.","pos":[21651,21711]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you select a template in this field, this setting overrides the template that is assigned to the position when you create earnings statement lines.","pos":[21712,21872],"source":"**Note:** If you select a template in this field, this setting overrides the template that is assigned to the position when you create earnings statement lines."},{"content":"Default financial dimensions","pos":[21896,21924]},{"content":"The default financial dimensions for the main account.","pos":[21927,21981]},{"content":"When you select a financial dimension value, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Where the %1 dimension is used<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field group shows where the dimension is used in account structures and advanced rule structures.","pos":[21982,22163],"source":" When you select a financial dimension value, the **Where the %1 dimension is used** field group shows where the dimension is used in account structures and advanced rule structures."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The dimension values from the earning code and the position are added to the earning line and can be changed.","pos":[22164,22283],"source":"**Note:** The dimension values from the earning code and the position are added to the earning line and can be changed."},{"content":"When a value for the same dimension is specified for both the earning code and the position, the dimension value for the earning code is used.","pos":[22284,22426]},{"content":"Posting rules","pos":[22431,22444]},{"content":"The accounting rules that are applied when earnings that are generated for this earning code are posted.","pos":[22462,22566]},{"content":"The main account for distributions is based on the department, job, and worker selections for each posting rule.","pos":[22567,22679]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The main account can’t be changed on the earning lines.","pos":[22680,22745],"source":"**Note:** The main account can’t be changed on the earning lines."},{"content":"The following information is entered on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reporting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[22772,22834],"source":"The following information is entered on the **Reporting** tab."},{"content":"This tab contains tax-related information that is required by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS).","pos":[22835,22932]},{"content":"Field","pos":[22936,22941]},{"content":"Description","pos":[22960,22971]},{"content":"Form W-2 control data","pos":[23186,23207]},{"content":"The box number and label on Form W-2 that are used to report tax-related information to the IRS.","pos":[23210,23306]},{"content":"The following information is entered on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning code groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[23310,23382],"source":"The following information is entered on the **Earning code groups** tab."},{"content":"This tab shows the earning code groups that the selected earning code is assigned to.","pos":[23383,23468]},{"content":"You can also add earning code groups to the earning code and remove earning code groups from the earning code.","pos":[23469,23579]},{"pos":[23582,23653],"content":"You can create earning code groups on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning code groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"You can create earning code groups on the **Earning code groups** page."},{"content":"Field","pos":[23657,23662]},{"content":"Description","pos":[23666,23677]},{"content":"Add","pos":[24043,24046]},{"content":"Select the earning code group to assign the earning code to.","pos":[24052,24112]},{"content":"Earning code groups that already include the earning code aren’t available.","pos":[24113,24188]},{"content":"Remove","pos":[24236,24242]},{"content":"Select the earning code group to remove the earning code from, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Remove<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[24245,24334],"source":"Select the earning code group to remove the earning code from, and then click **Remove**."},{"content":"The earning code group still exists, but it no longer includes the selected earning code.","pos":[24335,24424]},{"pos":[24431,24470],"content":"If required: Create earning code groups","linkify":"If required: Create earning code groups","nodes":[{"content":"If required: Create earning code groups","pos":[0,39]}]},{"pos":[24471,24613],"content":"Earning code groups are required when you select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Percent of earnings<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Hours of earnings<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Regular rate of pay<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> as the rate basis.","source":"Earning code groups are required when you select **Percent of earnings**, **Hours of earnings**, or **Regular rate of pay** as the rate basis."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Caution:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> If you use regular-rate-of-pay earning codes to calculate and pay the overtime premiums that are required by FLSA, every earning code for nondiscretionary earnings must be included in the earning code group that is used by the regular-rate-of-pay earning codes.","pos":[24616,24890],"source":"**Caution:** If you use regular-rate-of-pay earning codes to calculate and pay the overtime premiums that are required by FLSA, every earning code for nondiscretionary earnings must be included in the earning code group that is used by the regular-rate-of-pay earning codes."},{"content":"If any earning codes are omitted from the earning code group, the overtime premium won’t be calculated correctly.","pos":[24891,25004]},{"content":"Earning code groups can also make it easier for you to manage earning codes.","pos":[25007,25083]},{"content":"For example, you can create a group that contains all earning codes that apply to union members.","pos":[25084,25180]},{"content":"If changes in the union contract require that you update these earning codes, the earning code group makes it easy to identify the earning codes that are affected.","pos":[25181,25344]},{"pos":[25347,25518],"content":"You can assign earning codes to groups when you create them, or you can assign an earning code to a group on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning code groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Earning codes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","source":"You can assign earning codes to groups when you create them, or you can assign an earning code to a group on the **Earning code groups** tab of the **Earning codes** page."},{"pos":[25523,25612],"content":"Optional: View the groups that include an earning code and add earning codes to the group","linkify":"Optional: View the groups that include an earning code and add earning codes to the group","nodes":[{"content":"Optional: View the groups that include an earning code and add earning codes to the group","pos":[0,89]}]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning code groups<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Earning codes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page, you can see each group that an earning code belongs to.","pos":[25613,25734],"source":"On the **Earning code groups** tab of the **Earning codes** page, you can see each group that an earning code belongs to."},{"content":"Additionally, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Earning codes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Earning code groups<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page, you can see each earning code that belongs to the selected group.","pos":[25735,25880],"source":" Additionally, on the **Earning codes** tab of the **Earning code groups** page, you can see each earning code that belongs to the selected group."},{"pos":[25885,25894],"content":"Next step","linkify":"Next step","nodes":[{"content":"Next step","pos":[0,9]}]},{"content":"The next step is to set up schedules, leave types, and benefit accrual plans.","pos":[25895,25972]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Work schedule and leave tasks<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-work-schedule-leave-tasks.md)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Benefit accrual plan tasks<ept id=\"p2\">](noam-usa-benefit-accrual-plan-tasks.md)</ept>.","pos":[25973,26143],"source":" For more information, see [Work schedule and leave tasks](noam-usa-work-schedule-leave-tasks.md) and [Benefit accrual plan tasks](noam-usa-benefit-accrual-plan-tasks.md)."},{"pos":[26147,26155],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[26166,26216],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Generate earnings<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-generate-earnings.md)</ept>","source":"[Generate earnings](noam-usa-generate-earnings.md)"},{"pos":[26218,26282],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Generate payroll reports<ept id=\"p1\">](noam-usa-generate-payroll-reports.md)</ept>","source":"[Generate payroll reports](noam-usa-generate-payroll-reports.md)"}]}