{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Naming guidelines for model extensions\ndescription: This topic describes the naming guidelines for model extensions. An element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time. \nauthor: LarsBlaaberg\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89563\nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: pvillads\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-07-01\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 9\n---\n\n# Naming guidelines for model extensions\n\n## Naming model elements\nEvery element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time. However, at installation time, you don't know the names of all the models that your model might be installed together with. To accommodate this situation, every element name should include a prefix that is specific to your solution. By including this prefix when you name elements in your model, you significantly reduce the risk of naming conflicts.\n\n+ If a model contains multiple solutions, each solution in the model can be identified by a different prefix. \n+ You must carefully choose the prefix to minimize the risk that other models from other parties use the same prefix for their elements.\n\nWhen you extend functionality in other models, elements that are being extended already contain a prefix. However, you should not add your prefix to the extension elements, so that the names include multiple successive prefixes. Instead, you should include your prefix or another term or abbreviation as an infix when you name extension elements.\n\n## Naming extensions\n\nAn extension element, such as a table extension, view extension, or form extension, must have a unique name that minimizes the risk of conflicts with extensions in other models. To minimize the risk of conflicts, the name should include a term, abbreviation, or infix that distinguishes the extension from other extensions to the same element in other models.\n\n+ Include either the name of the model where the extension element resides or the prefix that the extension is associated with. For example, a Warehousing module extends the HCMWorker table and uses the **WHS** prefix in the name of all other elements. In this case, the extension might be named **HCMWorker.WHSExtension**. Notice that the prefix that is used to name other elements in the module is inserted as an infix in the name. As another example, an extension of the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model might be named **ContactPerson.ApplicationSuiteExtension** if the extension is intended to contain all extensions to the ContactPerson table from the ApplicationSuite model.\n+ Suffix the name with the term **Extension**. For example, an extension of the InventLocation table should follow the pattern **InventLocation.&lt;Model&gt;Extension**.\n+ Don't name the extension just **&lt;Element that is being extended&gt;.Extension**. For example, an extension of the InventLocation table must not be named **InventLocation.Extension**, because the risk of conflicts is too high.\n\n## Naming extension classes\n\nExtension classes that are used to augment the logic on tables, classes, or other elements must have a name that is unique across all types in all models. Preferably, the extension class should include the name of the type that is being extended. However, the name must also include a term, abbreviation, or prefix that distinguishes the class from other types.\n\n+ Start the name of the extension class with the name of the type that is being augmented, and end the name with the term **\\_Extension**.\nTherefore, an extension class that augments the ContactPerson table should start with the name **ContactPerson** and end with **\\_Extension**. For example, one extension class might be named **ContactPersonWHS\\_Extension**.\n+ Include either the name of the model where the extension element resides or the prefix that the extension is associated with. For example, a Warehousing module uses an extension class to augment the ContactPerson table and uses the **WHS** prefix in the name of all other elements. In this case, the extension class might be named **ContactPersonWHS\\_Extension**. Notice that the prefix that is used to name other elements in the module is inserted as an infix in the name. As another example, an extension class that augments the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model might be named **ContactPersonApplicationSuite\\_Extension** if the extension class is intended to contain all extensions to the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model.\n+ Don't name the extension just **&lt;Element that is being extended&gt;\\_Extension**. For example, an extension class that augments the InventLocation table must not be named **InventLocation\\_Extension**, because the risk of conflicts is too high.\n\n## Naming fields, field groups, indexes, relations, and other metadata nodes in extension elements\n\nFields, indexes, relations, and other metadata elements on extension elements must have a name that is unique across both the element that is being extended and other extension elements. Therefore, these metadata nodes must include a term, abbreviation, or prefix that minimizes the risk of conflicts across models.\n\n+ Include a prefix, term, or abbreviation at the beginning of the name of the metadata node. For example, an approving worker foreign key field is added as part of a table extension, and **WHS** is one of prefixes that are dedicated to other elements in the hosting model. In this case, the field might be named **WHSApprovingWorker**.\n\n## Naming members in extension classes\nClass-level variables, and methods on extension classes, must have a name that is unique across both the type that is being augmented and all other extension classes that augment the same type.\n\n+ Include a prefix, term, or abbreviation at the beginning of the member name. For example, an approving worker class-level variable might be named **WHSApprovingWorker** if **WHS** is one of the prefixes that are used by other elements in the model. An **approveWork** method might be named **WHSApproveWork** if **WHS** is one of the prefixes that are used by other elements in the hosting model.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,723],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Naming guidelines for model extensions\ndescription: This topic describes the naming guidelines for model extensions. An element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time. \nauthor: LarsBlaaberg\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89563\nms.assetid: \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: pvillads\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-07-01\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 9","nodes":[{"content":"Naming guidelines for model extensions","nodes":[{"pos":[0,38],"content":"Naming guidelines for model extensions","nodes":[{"content":"Naming guidelines for model extensions","pos":[0,38]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic describes the naming guidelines for model extensions. An element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,158],"content":"This topic describes the naming guidelines for model extensions. An element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes the naming guidelines for model extensions. An element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time.","pos":[0,158],"nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes the naming guidelines for model extensions.","pos":[0,64]},{"content":"An element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time.","pos":[65,158]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[731,769],"content":"Naming guidelines for model extensions","linkify":"Naming guidelines for model extensions","nodes":[{"content":"Naming guidelines for model extensions","pos":[0,38]}]},{"pos":[774,795],"content":"Naming model elements","linkify":"Naming model elements","nodes":[{"content":"Naming model elements","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"Every element in a model must have a name that is unique across all models at installation time.","pos":[796,892]},{"content":"However, at installation time, you don't know the names of all the models that your model might be installed together with.","pos":[893,1016]},{"content":"To accommodate this situation, every element name should include a prefix that is specific to your solution.","pos":[1017,1125]},{"content":"By including this prefix when you name elements in your model, you significantly reduce the risk of naming conflicts.","pos":[1126,1243]},{"content":"If a model contains multiple solutions, each solution in the model can be identified by a different prefix.","pos":[1247,1354]},{"content":"You must carefully choose the prefix to minimize the risk that other models from other parties use the same prefix for their elements.","pos":[1358,1492]},{"content":"When you extend functionality in other models, elements that are being extended already contain a prefix.","pos":[1494,1599]},{"content":"However, you should not add your prefix to the extension elements, so that the names include multiple successive prefixes.","pos":[1600,1722]},{"content":"Instead, you should include your prefix or another term or abbreviation as an infix when you name extension elements.","pos":[1723,1840]},{"pos":[1845,1862],"content":"Naming extensions","linkify":"Naming extensions","nodes":[{"content":"Naming extensions","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"An extension element, such as a table extension, view extension, or form extension, must have a unique name that minimizes the risk of conflicts with extensions in other models.","pos":[1864,2041]},{"content":"To minimize the risk of conflicts, the name should include a term, abbreviation, or infix that distinguishes the extension from other extensions to the same element in other models.","pos":[2042,2223]},{"content":"Include either the name of the model where the extension element resides or the prefix that the extension is associated with.","pos":[2227,2352]},{"content":"For example, a Warehousing module extends the HCMWorker table and uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WHS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> prefix in the name of all other elements.","pos":[2353,2477],"source":" For example, a Warehousing module extends the HCMWorker table and uses the **WHS** prefix in the name of all other elements."},{"content":"In this case, the extension might be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>HCMWorker.WHSExtension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2478,2548],"source":" In this case, the extension might be named **HCMWorker.WHSExtension**."},{"content":"Notice that the prefix that is used to name other elements in the module is inserted as an infix in the name.","pos":[2549,2658]},{"content":"As another example, an extension of the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model might be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ContactPerson.ApplicationSuiteExtension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if the extension is intended to contain all extensions to the ContactPerson table from the ApplicationSuite model.","pos":[2659,2922],"source":" As another example, an extension of the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model might be named **ContactPerson.ApplicationSuiteExtension** if the extension is intended to contain all extensions to the ContactPerson table from the ApplicationSuite model."},{"content":"Suffix the name with the term <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2925,2969],"source":"Suffix the name with the term **Extension**."},{"content":"For example, an extension of the InventLocation table should follow the pattern <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>InventLocation.<ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;lt;</ph>Model<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[2970,3092],"source":" For example, an extension of the InventLocation table should follow the pattern **InventLocation.&lt;Model&gt;Extension**."},{"content":"Don't name the extension just <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;lt;</ph>Element that is being extended<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph>.Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3095,3178],"source":"Don't name the extension just **&lt;Element that is being extended&gt;.Extension**."},{"content":"For example, an extension of the InventLocation table must not be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>InventLocation.Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, because the risk of conflicts is too high.","pos":[3179,3323],"source":" For example, an extension of the InventLocation table must not be named **InventLocation.Extension**, because the risk of conflicts is too high."},{"pos":[3328,3352],"content":"Naming extension classes","linkify":"Naming extension classes","nodes":[{"content":"Naming extension classes","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"Extension classes that are used to augment the logic on tables, classes, or other elements must have a name that is unique across all types in all models.","pos":[3354,3508]},{"content":"Preferably, the extension class should include the name of the type that is being extended.","pos":[3509,3600]},{"content":"However, the name must also include a term, abbreviation, or prefix that distinguishes the class from other types.","pos":[3601,3715]},{"content":"Start the name of the extension class with the name of the type that is being augmented, and end the name with the term <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3719,3855],"source":"Start the name of the extension class with the name of the type that is being augmented, and end the name with the term **\\_Extension**."},{"content":"Therefore, an extension class that augments the ContactPerson table should start with the name <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ContactPerson<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and end with <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3856,3998],"source":"\nTherefore, an extension class that augments the ContactPerson table should start with the name **ContactPerson** and end with **\\_Extension**."},{"content":"For example, one extension class might be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ContactPersonWHS<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3999,4079],"source":" For example, one extension class might be named **ContactPersonWHS\\_Extension**."},{"content":"Include either the name of the model where the extension element resides or the prefix that the extension is associated with.","pos":[4082,4207]},{"content":"For example, a Warehousing module uses an extension class to augment the ContactPerson table and uses the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WHS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> prefix in the name of all other elements.","pos":[4208,4363],"source":" For example, a Warehousing module uses an extension class to augment the ContactPerson table and uses the **WHS** prefix in the name of all other elements."},{"content":"In this case, the extension class might be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ContactPersonWHS<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4364,4445],"source":" In this case, the extension class might be named **ContactPersonWHS\\_Extension**."},{"content":"Notice that the prefix that is used to name other elements in the module is inserted as an infix in the name.","pos":[4446,4555]},{"content":"As another example, an extension class that augments the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model might be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ContactPersonApplicationSuite<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if the extension class is intended to contain all extensions to the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model.","pos":[4556,4841],"source":" As another example, an extension class that augments the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model might be named **ContactPersonApplicationSuite\\_Extension** if the extension class is intended to contain all extensions to the ContactPerson table in the ApplicationSuite model."},{"content":"Don't name the extension just <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;lt;</ph>Element that is being extended<ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph><ph id=\"ph3\">\\_</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4844,4928],"source":"Don't name the extension just **&lt;Element that is being extended&gt;\\_Extension**."},{"content":"For example, an extension class that augments the InventLocation table must not be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>InventLocation<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>Extension<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, because the risk of conflicts is too high.","pos":[4929,5091],"source":" For example, an extension class that augments the InventLocation table must not be named **InventLocation\\_Extension**, because the risk of conflicts is too high."},{"pos":[5096,5191],"content":"Naming fields, field groups, indexes, relations, and other metadata nodes in extension elements","linkify":"Naming fields, field groups, indexes, relations, and other metadata nodes in extension elements","nodes":[{"content":"Naming fields, field groups, indexes, relations, and other metadata nodes in extension elements","pos":[0,95]}]},{"content":"Fields, indexes, relations, and other metadata elements on extension elements must have a name that is unique across both the element that is being extended and other extension elements.","pos":[5193,5379]},{"content":"Therefore, these metadata nodes must include a term, abbreviation, or prefix that minimizes the risk of conflicts across models.","pos":[5380,5508]},{"content":"Include a prefix, term, or abbreviation at the beginning of the name of the metadata node.","pos":[5512,5602]},{"content":"For example, an approving worker foreign key field is added as part of a table extension, and <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WHS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is one of prefixes that are dedicated to other elements in the hosting model.","pos":[5603,5782],"source":" For example, an approving worker foreign key field is added as part of a table extension, and **WHS** is one of prefixes that are dedicated to other elements in the hosting model."},{"content":"In this case, the field might be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WHSApprovingWorker<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[5783,5845],"source":" In this case, the field might be named **WHSApprovingWorker**."},{"pos":[5850,5885],"content":"Naming members in extension classes","linkify":"Naming members in extension classes","nodes":[{"content":"Naming members in extension classes","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"Class-level variables, and methods on extension classes, must have a name that is unique across both the type that is being augmented and all other extension classes that augment the same type.","pos":[5886,6079]},{"content":"Include a prefix, term, or abbreviation at the beginning of the member name.","pos":[6083,6159]},{"content":"For example, an approving worker class-level variable might be named <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>WHSApprovingWorker<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> if <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>WHS<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> is one of the prefixes that are used by other elements in the model.","pos":[6160,6331],"source":" For example, an approving worker class-level variable might be named **WHSApprovingWorker** if **WHS** is one of the prefixes that are used by other elements in the model."},{"content":"An <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>approveWork<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> method might be named <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>WHSApproveWork<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> if <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>WHS<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> is one of the prefixes that are used by other elements in the hosting model.","pos":[6332,6479],"source":" An **approveWork** method might be named **WHSApproveWork** if **WHS** is one of the prefixes that are used by other elements in the hosting model."}]}