{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls\ndescription: This topic outlines the recommended method for implementing keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.\nauthor: robinarh\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89563\nms.assetid: C0E2E0F9-19C1-4CE0-A81C-1ACFA841F6AB\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: robinarh\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-05-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 1\n\n---\n\n# Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nKeyboard shortcuts are an important consideration when you create any extensible control. This topic provides information that will help you choose keyboard shortcuts for your extensible controls. It also outlines the recommended method for implementing keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.\n\n<h2>Overview</h2>\nFor accessibility, it's essential that keyboard-only users be able to use controls. Therefore, keyboard shortcuts are an important consideration when you create any extensible control. This topic provides information that will help you choose key combinations to use as keyboard shortcuts. It highlights the shortcuts that are currently used by Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations and supported browsers, shortcuts that are planned for implementation in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, and shortcuts that one or more browsers don't allow to be overridden. This topic also outlines the recommended way to implement keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.\n<h2>Choosing a key combination</h2>\nWhen you're trying to choose a key combination to use as a keyboard shortcut, it's important that you be aware of other existing shortcuts. In this way, you help guarantee that your shortcut won't overlap an existing shortcut. If you try to collide with an existing shortcut, one of the following outcomes might occur:\n<ul>\n    <li>The new keyboard shortcut might not work, because a browser doesn't allow that key combination to be overridden, or a framework-provided shortcut takes precedence over the new shortcut.</li>\n    <li>The new keyboard shortcut might remove expected keyboard functionality, because users expect specific key combinations to perform specific functions in a browser. Alternatively, you might override framework-provided shortcuts or other control shortcuts, so that keyboard-only users can't use them.</li>\n</ul>\nBecause of these potential issues, we recommend that you adhere to this guidance when you choose a key combination:\n<ul>\n    <li><strong>Don't</strong> choose any key combination that is currently used by Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, or that is planned for future implementation in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.</li>\n    <li><strong>Do</strong> pick key combinations that will work in all supported browsers.</li>\n    <li><strong>Do</strong> be careful when you override shortcuts that are used by a supported browser. You should not suppress shortcuts for important or frequently used browser functionality.</li>\n    <li><strong>Do</strong> use longer key combinations (three keys) for control-specific behavior. Shorter combinations should be reserved for user-defined keyboard shortcuts.</li>\n    <li><strong>Don't</strong> choose any key combination that involves Ctrl+Alt, because this combination maps to Alt+Gr for some Eastern European languages and will conflict with other shortcuts.</li>\n</ul>\n<h3>Keyboard shortcut links</h3>\nHere are links to the keyboard shortcuts that are documented for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations and supported browsers:\n<ul>\n    <li><a href=\"/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/get-started/shortcut-keys\">Keyboard shortcuts</a></li>\n    <li><a href=\"https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/13805\">Microsoft Edge</a></li>\n    <li><a href=\"https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/157179\">Google Chrome</a></li>\n    <li><a href=\"https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/15357/windows-internet-explorer-11-keyboard-shortcuts\">Internet Explorer 11</a></li>\n    <li><a href=\"https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21483\">Apple Safari</a></li>\n</ul>\n<h3>Planned keyboard shortcuts for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations</h3>\nIn addition to the keyboard shortcuts that are currently used by Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, there are several shortcuts that are planned for future implementation. To avoid conflicts with framework-provided shortcuts, you should not choose the following key combinations for extensible controls.\n<table>\n<tbody>\n<tr>\n<th>Shortcut</th>\n<th>Functionality</th>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>F3</td>\n<td>Move to the nearest QuickFilter.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+F3</td>\n<td>Add a filter that is based on the value of the current control (Filter by value).</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+Shift+F3</td>\n<td>Clear all user-defined filters.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>F6</td>\n<td>Move to the nearest toolbar.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Shift+F7</td>\n<td>Move to the toast message.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<h3>Browser/operating system keyboard shortcuts to avoid</h3>\n<h4>Keyboard shortcuts that correspond to important functionality</h4>\nThe following table provides a short, non-exhaustive list of keyboard shortcuts that correspond to important functionality in a browser or operating system. You should not choose the key combinations in this table.\n<table>\n<tbody>\n<tr>\n<th>Shortcut</th>\n<th>Functionality</th>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n<tbody>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+A</td>\n<td>Select all the text in the current field, or select all content on the page.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+C</td>\n<td>Copy.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+V</td>\n<td>Paste.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+X</td>\n<td>Cut.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>F5</td>\n<td>Refresh the page.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+F5</td>\n<td>Refresh the page, and ignore cached content.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Shift+F10</td>\n<td>Simulate a right-click.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Tab / Shift+Tab</td>\n<td>Move to the next/previous control.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+Tab / Ctrl+Shift+Tab</td>\n<td>Move to the next/previous browser tab.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+Tab / Alt+Shift+Tab</td>\n<td>Move to the next/previous application.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+Right arrow / Alt + Left arrow</td>\n<td>Go to the next/previous page in the browser history.</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<h4>Keyboard shortcuts that can't be overridden by some browsers</h4>\nSome browsers don't allow the following keyboard shortcuts to be overridden. Therefore, you should not choose the following key combinations, because the shortcut won't work in all browsers.\n<table>\n<tbody>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+A</td>\n<td>Alt+T</td>\n<td>Ctrl+F4</td>\n<td>Alt+Tab</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+C</td>\n<td>Alt+V</td>\n<td>Alt+F5</td>\n<td>Alt+Shift+Tab</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+D</td>\n<td>Ctrl+W</td>\n<td>Alt+F6</td>\n<td>Spacebar</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+Shift+D</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+W</td>\n<td>Alt+Shift+F6</td>\n<td>Alt+Shift+Backspace</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+E</td>\n<td>Alt+X</td>\n<td>F12</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Pause/Break</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+F</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+0</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Esc</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+Pause/Break</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Alt+H</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+7</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+Esc</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Page up</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+N</td>\n<td>F1</td>\n<td>Alt+Esc</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Page down</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+N</td>\n<td>Ctrl+F1</td>\n<td>Alt+Shift+Esc</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Plus sign (+)</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+Q</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+F1</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Tab</td>\n<td>Shift+Plus sign (+)</td>\n</tr>\n<tr>\n<td>Ctrl+T</td>\n<td>Shift+F1</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Shift+Tab</td>\n<td>Ctrl+Minus sign (–)</td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n<h2>Implementing keyboard shortcuts</h2>\nWe recommend that you use the registration mechanism that is described in this section to implement keyboard shortcuts. There are several benefits to registering a control's shortcuts in this manner:\n<ul>\n    <li>You specify only the modifier keys that you want. If any other modifiers are pressed, the shortcut won't run. Therefore, a keyboard shortcut that is defined for Ctrl+Down arrow won't be triggered if Ctrl+Shift+Down arrow is pressed.</li>\n    <li>You can reuse code.</li>\n    <li>If you return <strong>false</strong> from the handler function, propagation won't stop on the event. If you return <strong>true</strong> (or if you don't specify a return value), propagation will stop.</li>\n    <li>Ctrl and Meta modifiers are treated the same. Therefore, you can specify keyboard shortcuts that will work for both iOS and Microsoft Windows. For example, the shortcut Ctrl+G on Windows will be translated to Meta+G on iOS.</li>\n    <li>Built-in telemetry for the keyboard shortcuts is used.</li>\n</ul>\n<h3>Define a keyboard shortcut</h3>\n<ol>\n    <li>Define a Shortcuts object on the control's prototype. Then define the keyboard shortcuts inside the Shortcuts object. These shortcuts should have the following structure. Make sure that the key code that you're trying to use is defined in the $dyn.ui.KeyCodes object.\n<pre>Shortcuts: {\n    Name: {\n        Keys: { modifier1: true, modifier2:true, keyCode: $dyn.ui.KeyCodes.* }, \n        //Only specify the modifiers you need (between alt, ctrl/meta, shift)\n        Handler: function (evt) {\n            // Code to handle shortcut.\n        },\n        // Additional code.\n}\n</pre>\nIf more than one key code should apply to your keyboard shortcut, pass in an array of codes, as shown here.\n<pre>Keys: {modifier1:true, keyCode:[$dyn.ui.KeyCodes.*, $dyn.ui.KeyCodes.*, ... ] } \n//Note: If any of these keyCodes match then the handler is called. I.E. The keyCodes in the array are OR'd not AND'd\n</pre>\n</li>\n    <li>Add the keydown handler by using the following code.\n<pre>keydown: function (event) {\n    $dyn.util.handleShortcuts(this, event);\n},\n</pre>\n</li>\n    <li>Bind the keydown handler. The keyDown handler is automatically bound for form objects. Other controls must be manually bound to the keyDown handler, as for any regular binding.\n<pre>&lt;div data-dyn-bind=\"keyDown: $data.keydown\"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;\n</pre>\n</li>\n</ol>\n<h3>Examples</h3>\nHere is a Form example.\n<pre>Shortcuts: {\n    Save: {\n        Keys: { ctrl: true, keyCode: $dyn.ui.KeyCodes.letterS },\n        Handler: function (evt) {\n            var control = evt ? $dyn.context(evt.target) : undefined;\n            this.executeShortcuts(true, \"SaveRecord\", control);\n        },\n    },\n    New: {\n        Keys: { alt: true, keyCode: $dyn.ui.KeyCodes.letterN },\n        Handler: function (evt) {\n            var control = evt ? $dyn.context(evt.target) : undefined;\n            this.executeShortcuts(true, \"NewRecord\", control);\n        },\n    },\n    Delete: {\n        Keys: { alt: true, keyCode: $dyn.ui.KeyCodes.deleteKey },\n        Handler: function (evt) {\n            this.executeShortcuts(false, \"DeleteRecord\");\n        },\n    },\n    // Additional code\n}\n</pre>\nHere is a Dialogs example that extends the Form control.\n<pre>Shortcuts: $dyn.extendPrototype($dyn.controls.Form.prototype.Shortcuts, {\n    InvokeDefaultButton: {\n        Keys: { keyCode: $dyn.ui.KeyCodes.enter },\n        Handler: function (evt) {\n            this.executeShortcuts(false, \"InvokeDefaultButton\");\n        }\n    },\n})\n</pre>\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,723],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls\ndescription: This topic outlines the recommended method for implementing keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.\nauthor: robinarh\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations, AX Platform\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 89563\nms.assetid: C0E2E0F9-19C1-4CE0-A81C-1ACFA841F6AB\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: robinarh\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-05-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 1\n","nodes":[{"content":"Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls","nodes":[{"pos":[0,42],"content":"Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls","nodes":[{"content":"Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls","pos":[0,42]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic outlines the recommended method for implementing keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,103],"content":"This topic outlines the recommended method for implementing keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic outlines the recommended method for implementing keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.","pos":[0,103]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[731,773],"content":"Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls","linkify":"Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls","nodes":[{"content":"Keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"Keyboard shortcuts are an important consideration when you create any extensible control.","pos":[819,908]},{"content":"This topic provides information that will help you choose keyboard shortcuts for your extensible controls.","pos":[909,1015]},{"content":"It also outlines the recommended method for implementing keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.","pos":[1016,1116]},{"content":"Overview","pos":[1122,1130]},{"content":"For accessibility, it's essential that keyboard-only users be able to use controls.","pos":[1136,1219],"source":"\nFor accessibility, it's essential that keyboard-only users be able to use controls."},{"content":"Therefore, keyboard shortcuts are an important consideration when you create any extensible control.","pos":[1220,1320]},{"content":"This topic provides information that will help you choose key combinations to use as keyboard shortcuts.","pos":[1321,1425]},{"content":"It highlights the shortcuts that are currently used by Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations and supported browsers, shortcuts that are planned for implementation in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, and shortcuts that one or more browsers don't allow to be overridden.","pos":[1426,1714]},{"content":"This topic also outlines the recommended way to implement keyboard shortcuts for extensible controls.","pos":[1715,1816]},{"content":"Choosing a key combination","pos":[1821,1847]},{"content":"When you're trying to choose a key combination to use as a keyboard shortcut, it's important that you be aware of other existing shortcuts.","pos":[1853,1992],"source":"\nWhen you're trying to choose a key combination to use as a keyboard shortcut, it's important that you be aware of other existing shortcuts."},{"content":"In this way, you help guarantee that your shortcut won't overlap an existing shortcut.","pos":[1993,2079]},{"content":"If you try to collide with an existing shortcut, one of the following outcomes might occur:","pos":[2080,2171]},{"content":"The new keyboard shortcut might not work, because a browser doesn't allow that key combination to be overridden, or a framework-provided shortcut takes precedence over the new shortcut.","pos":[2185,2370]},{"content":"The new keyboard shortcut might remove expected keyboard functionality, because users expect specific key combinations to perform specific functions in a browser.","pos":[2384,2546]},{"content":"Alternatively, you might override framework-provided shortcuts or other control shortcuts, so that keyboard-only users can't use them.","pos":[2547,2681]},{"content":"Because of these potential issues, we recommend that you adhere to this guidance when you choose a key combination:","pos":[2693,2808],"source":"\nBecause of these potential issues, we recommend that you adhere to this guidance when you choose a key combination:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Don't<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> choose any key combination that is currently used by Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, or that is planned for future implementation in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[2822,3027],"source":"<strong>Don't</strong> choose any key combination that is currently used by Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, or that is planned for future implementation in Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Do<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> pick key combinations that will work in all supported browsers.","pos":[3041,3124],"source":"<strong>Do</strong> pick key combinations that will work in all supported browsers."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Do<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> be careful when you override shortcuts that are used by a supported browser.","pos":[3138,3234],"source":"<strong>Do</strong> be careful when you override shortcuts that are used by a supported browser."},{"content":"You should not suppress shortcuts for important or frequently used browser functionality.","pos":[3235,3324]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Do<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> use longer key combinations (three keys) for control-specific behavior.","pos":[3338,3429],"source":"<strong>Do</strong> use longer key combinations (three keys) for control-specific behavior."},{"content":"Shorter combinations should be reserved for user-defined keyboard shortcuts.","pos":[3430,3506]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Don't<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> choose any key combination that involves Ctrl+Alt, because this combination maps to Alt+Gr for some Eastern European languages and will conflict with other shortcuts.","pos":[3520,3709],"source":"<strong>Don't</strong> choose any key combination that involves Ctrl+Alt, because this combination maps to Alt+Gr for some Eastern European languages and will conflict with other shortcuts."},{"content":"Keyboard shortcut links","pos":[3725,3748]},{"content":"Here are links to the keyboard shortcuts that are documented for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations and supported browsers:","pos":[3754,3882],"source":"\nHere are links to the keyboard shortcuts that are documented for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations and supported browsers:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/get-started/shortcut-keys\"&gt;</bpt>Keyboard shortcuts<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>","pos":[3896,3998],"source":"<a href=\"/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/get-started/shortcut-keys\">Keyboard shortcuts</a>"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/13805\"&gt;</bpt>Microsoft Edge<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>","pos":[4012,4087],"source":"<a href=\"https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/13805\">Microsoft Edge</a>"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/157179\"&gt;</bpt>Google Chrome<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>","pos":[4101,4176],"source":"<a href=\"https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/157179\">Google Chrome</a>"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/15357/windows-internet-explorer-11-keyboard-shortcuts\"&gt;</bpt>Internet Explorer 11<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>","pos":[4190,4319],"source":"<a href=\"https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/15357/windows-internet-explorer-11-keyboard-shortcuts\">Internet Explorer 11</a>"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;a href=\"https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21483\"&gt;</bpt>Apple Safari<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/a&gt;</ept>","pos":[4333,4396],"source":"<a href=\"https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21483\">Apple Safari</a>"},{"content":"Planned keyboard shortcuts for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations","pos":[4412,4482]},{"content":"In addition to the keyboard shortcuts that are currently used by Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, there are several shortcuts that are planned for future implementation.","pos":[4488,4665],"source":"\nIn addition to the keyboard shortcuts that are currently used by Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, there are several shortcuts that are planned for future implementation."},{"content":"To avoid conflicts with framework-provided shortcuts, you should not choose the following key combinations for extensible controls.","pos":[4666,4797]},{"content":"Shortcut","pos":[4823,4831]},{"content":"Functionality","pos":[4841,4854]},{"content":"F3","pos":[4875,4877]},{"content":"Move to the nearest QuickFilter.","pos":[4887,4919]},{"content":"Alt+F3","pos":[4940,4946]},{"content":"Add a filter that is based on the value of the current control (Filter by value).","pos":[4956,5037]},{"content":"Alt+Shift+F3","pos":[5058,5070]},{"content":"Clear all user-defined filters.","pos":[5080,5111]},{"content":"F6","pos":[5132,5134]},{"content":"Move to the nearest toolbar.","pos":[5144,5172]},{"content":"Shift+F7","pos":[5193,5201]},{"content":"Move to the toast message.","pos":[5211,5237]},{"content":"Browser/operating system keyboard shortcuts to avoid","pos":[5271,5323]},{"content":"Keyboard shortcuts that correspond to important functionality","pos":[5333,5394]},{"content":"The following table provides a short, non-exhaustive list of keyboard shortcuts that correspond to important functionality in a browser or operating system.","pos":[5400,5556],"source":"\nThe following table provides a short, non-exhaustive list of keyboard shortcuts that correspond to important functionality in a browser or operating system."},{"content":"You should not choose the key combinations in this table.","pos":[5557,5614]},{"content":"Shortcut","pos":[5640,5648]},{"content":"Functionality","pos":[5658,5671]},{"content":"Alt+A","pos":[5709,5714]},{"content":"Select all the text in the current field, or select all content on the page.","pos":[5724,5800]},{"content":"Ctrl+C","pos":[5821,5827]},{"content":"Copy.","pos":[5837,5842]},{"content":"Ctrl+V","pos":[5863,5869]},{"content":"Paste.","pos":[5879,5885]},{"content":"Ctrl+X","pos":[5906,5912]},{"content":"Cut.","pos":[5922,5926]},{"content":"F5","pos":[5947,5949]},{"content":"Refresh the page.","pos":[5959,5976]},{"content":"Ctrl+F5","pos":[5997,6004]},{"content":"Refresh the page, and ignore cached content.","pos":[6014,6058]},{"content":"Shift+F10","pos":[6079,6088]},{"content":"Simulate a right-click.","pos":[6098,6121]},{"content":"Tab / Shift+Tab","pos":[6142,6157]},{"content":"Move to the next/previous control.","pos":[6167,6201]},{"content":"Ctrl+Tab / Ctrl+Shift+Tab","pos":[6222,6247]},{"content":"Move to the next/previous browser tab.","pos":[6257,6295]},{"content":"Alt+Tab / Alt+Shift+Tab","pos":[6316,6339]},{"content":"Move to the next/previous application.","pos":[6349,6387]},{"content":"Alt+Right arrow / Alt + Left arrow","pos":[6408,6442]},{"content":"Go to the next/previous page in the browser history.","pos":[6452,6504]},{"content":"Keyboard shortcuts that can't be overridden by some browsers","pos":[6538,6598]},{"content":"Some browsers don't allow the following keyboard shortcuts to be overridden.","pos":[6604,6680],"source":"\nSome browsers don't allow the following keyboard shortcuts to be overridden."},{"content":"Therefore, you should not choose the following key combinations, because the shortcut won't work in all browsers.","pos":[6681,6794]},{"content":"Alt+A","pos":[6820,6825]},{"content":"Alt+T","pos":[6835,6840]},{"content":"Ctrl+F4","pos":[6850,6857]},{"content":"Alt+Tab","pos":[6867,6874]},{"content":"Alt+C","pos":[6895,6900]},{"content":"Alt+V","pos":[6910,6915]},{"content":"Alt+F5","pos":[6925,6931]},{"content":"Alt+Shift+Tab","pos":[6941,6954]},{"content":"Alt+D","pos":[6975,6980]},{"content":"Ctrl+W","pos":[6990,6996]},{"content":"Alt+F6","pos":[7006,7012]},{"content":"Spacebar","pos":[7022,7030]},{"content":"Alt+Shift+D","pos":[7051,7062]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+W","pos":[7072,7084]},{"content":"Alt+Shift+F6","pos":[7094,7106]},{"content":"Alt+Shift+Backspace","pos":[7116,7135]},{"content":"Alt+E","pos":[7156,7161]},{"content":"Alt+X","pos":[7171,7176]},{"content":"F12","pos":[7186,7189]},{"content":"Ctrl+Pause/Break","pos":[7199,7215]},{"content":"Alt+F","pos":[7236,7241]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+0","pos":[7251,7263]},{"content":"Ctrl+Esc","pos":[7273,7281]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+Pause/Break","pos":[7291,7313]},{"content":"Alt+H","pos":[7334,7339]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+7","pos":[7349,7361]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+Esc","pos":[7371,7385]},{"content":"Ctrl+Page up","pos":[7395,7407]},{"content":"Ctrl+N","pos":[7428,7434]},{"content":"F1","pos":[7444,7446]},{"content":"Alt+Esc","pos":[7456,7463]},{"content":"Ctrl+Page down","pos":[7473,7487]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+N","pos":[7508,7520]},{"content":"Ctrl+F1","pos":[7530,7537]},{"content":"Alt+Shift+Esc","pos":[7547,7560]},{"content":"Ctrl+Plus sign (+)","pos":[7570,7588]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+Q","pos":[7609,7621]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+F1","pos":[7631,7644]},{"content":"Ctrl+Tab","pos":[7654,7662]},{"content":"Shift+Plus sign (+)","pos":[7672,7691]},{"content":"Ctrl+T","pos":[7712,7718]},{"content":"Shift+F1","pos":[7728,7736]},{"content":"Ctrl+Shift+Tab","pos":[7746,7760]},{"content":"Ctrl+Minus sign (–)","pos":[7770,7789]},{"content":"Implementing keyboard shortcuts","pos":[7823,7854]},{"content":"We recommend that you use the registration mechanism that is described in this section to implement keyboard shortcuts.","pos":[7860,7979],"source":"\nWe recommend that you use the registration mechanism that is described in this section to implement keyboard shortcuts."},{"content":"There are several benefits to registering a control's shortcuts in this manner:","pos":[7980,8059],"source":" There are several benefits to registering a control's shortcuts in this manner:\n"},{"content":"You specify only the modifier keys that you want.","pos":[8073,8122]},{"content":"If any other modifiers are pressed, the shortcut won't run.","pos":[8123,8182]},{"content":"Therefore, a keyboard shortcut that is defined for Ctrl+Down arrow won't be triggered if Ctrl+Shift+Down arrow is pressed.","pos":[8183,8305]},{"content":"You can reuse code.","pos":[8319,8338]},{"content":"If you return <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>false<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> from the handler function, propagation won't stop on the event.","pos":[8352,8452],"source":"If you return <strong>false</strong> from the handler function, propagation won't stop on the event."},{"content":"If you return <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>true<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> (or if you don't specify a return value), propagation will stop.","pos":[8453,8553],"source":" If you return <strong>true</strong> (or if you don't specify a return value), propagation will stop."},{"content":"Ctrl and Meta modifiers are treated the same.","pos":[8567,8612]},{"content":"Therefore, you can specify keyboard shortcuts that will work for both iOS and Microsoft Windows.","pos":[8613,8709]},{"content":"For example, the shortcut Ctrl+G on Windows will be translated to Meta+G on iOS.","pos":[8710,8790]},{"content":"Built-in telemetry for the keyboard shortcuts is used.","pos":[8804,8858]},{"content":"Define a keyboard shortcut","pos":[8874,8900]},{"content":"Define a Shortcuts object on the control's prototype.","pos":[8919,8972]},{"content":"Then define the keyboard shortcuts inside the Shortcuts object.","pos":[8973,9036]},{"content":"These shortcuts should have the following structure.","pos":[9037,9089]},{"content":"Make sure that the key code that you're trying to use is defined in the $dyn.ui.KeyCodes object.","pos":[9090,9186]},{"content":"If more than one key code should apply to your keyboard shortcut, pass in an array of codes, as shown here.","pos":[9498,9605],"source":"\nIf more than one key code should apply to your keyboard shortcut, pass in an array of codes, as shown here."},{"content":"Add the keydown handler by using the following code.","pos":[9830,9882]},{"content":"Bind the keydown handler.","pos":[9984,10009]},{"content":"The keyDown handler is automatically bound for form objects.","pos":[10010,10070]},{"content":"Other controls must be manually bound to the keyDown handler, as for any regular binding.","pos":[10071,10160]},{"content":"Examples","pos":[10252,10260]},{"content":"Here is a Form example.","pos":[10266,10289],"source":"\nHere is a Form example."},{"content":"Here is a Dialogs example that extends the Form control.","pos":[11053,11109],"source":"\nHere is a Dialogs example that extends the Form control."}]}