{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Electronic reporting overview\ndescription: This article provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool. It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/15/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: ERWorkspace\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 58941\nms.assetid: 5d51b6a6-ad12-4af9-a66d-a1eb820ae57f\nms.search.region: global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: nselin\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Electronic reporting overview\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool. It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.\n\nER is a tool that you can use to configure formats for both incoming and outgoing electronic documents in accordance with the legal requirements of various countries/regions. ER lets you manage these formats during their lifecycle. For example, you can adopt new regulatory requirements, and generate business documents in the required format to electronically exchange information with government bodies, banks, and other parties.\n\nThe ER engine is targeted at business users instead of developers. Because you configure formats instead of code, the processes for creating and adjusting formats for electronic documents are faster and easier.\n\nER currently supports the TEXT, XML, Microsoft Word document, and OPENXML worksheet formats. However, an extension interface provides support for additional formats.\n\n## Capabilities\nThe ER engine has the following capabilities:\n\n- It represents a single shared tool for electronic reporting in different domains and replaces more than 20 different engines that do some type of electronic reporting for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.\n- It makes a report’s format insulated from the current Finance and Operations implementation. In other words, the format is applicable for different versions of Finance and Operations.\n- It supports the creation of a custom format that is based on an original format. It also includes capabilities for automatically upgrading the customized format when the original format is changed because of localization/customization requirements.\n- It becomes the primary standard tool to support localization requirements in electronic reporting, both for Microsoft and for Microsoft partners.\n- It supports the ability to distribute formats to partners and customers through Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).\n\n## Key concepts\n### Components\n\nER supports two types of components: **Data model** and **Format**.\n\n#### Data model components\n\nA data model component is an abstract representation of a data structure. It's used to describe a specific business domain area with enough detail to satisfy the reporting requirements for that domain. A data model component consists of the following parts:\n\n- A data model, as a set of domain-specific business entities and a hierarchically structured definition of relations between those entities.\n- A model mapping that links selected Finance and Operations data sources to individual elements of a data model that specifies, at run time, the data flow and rules of business data population to a data model component.\n\nA business entity of a data model is represented as a container (record). Business entity properties are represented as data items (fields). Each data item has a unique name, label, description, and value. The value of each data item can be designed so that it's recognized as a string, integer, real, date, enumeration, Boolean, and so on. Additionally, it can be another record or records list.\n\nA single data model component can contain several hierarchies of domain-specific business entities. It can also contain model mappings that support a report-specific data flow at run time. The hierarchies are differentiated by a single record that has been selected as a root for model mapping. For example, the data model of the payment domain area might support the following mappings:\n\n- Company > Vendor > Payment transactions of the AP domain\n- Customer > Company > Payment transactions of the AR domain\n\nNote that business entities such as company and payment transactions are designed one time. Different mappings then reuse them.\n\nA model mapping that supports outgoing electronic documents has the following capabilities:\n\n- It can use different Finance and Operations data types as data sources for a data model. For example, it can use tables, data entities, methods, or enums.\n- It supports user input parameters that can be defined as data sources for a data model when some data must be specified at run time.\n- It supports the transformation of Finance and Operations data into required groups. It also lets you filter, sort, and sum data, and append logical calculated fields that are designed through formulas that resemble Microsoft Excel formulas, as shown in the following illustration. For more information, see [Formula designer in Electronic reporting](general-electronic-reporting-formula-designer.md)).\n\n[![Formula designer](./media/ER-overview-01.png)](./media/ER-overview-01.png) \n\nA model mapping that supports incoming electronic documents has the following capabilities:\n\n- It can use different updatable data elements as targets. These data elements include tables, data entities, and views. The data can be updated by using the data from incoming electronic documents. Multiple targets can be used in a single model mapping.\n- It supports user input parameters that can be defined as data sources for a data model when some data must be specified at run time.\n\nA data model component is designed for each business domain that should be used as a unified data source for reporting that isolates reporting from the physical implementation of data sources. It represents domain-specific business concepts and functionalities in a form that makes a reporting format's initial design and further maintenance more efficient.\n\n#### Format components for outgoing electronic documents\n\nA format component is the scheme of the reporting output that will be generated at run time. A scheme consists of the following elements:\n\n- A format that defines the structure and content of the outgoing electronic document that is generated at run time.\n- Data sources, as a set of user input parameters and a domain-specific data model that uses a selected model mapping.\n- A format mapping, as a set of bindings of format data sources that have individual elements of a format that specify, at run time, the data flow and rules for format output generation.\n- A format validation, as a set of configurable rules that control report generation at run time, depending on the running context. For example, there might be a rule that stops output generation of a vendor’s payments and throws an exception when specific attributes of the selected vendor are missing, such as the bank account number.\n\nA format component supports the following functions:\n\n- Creation of reporting output as individual files in various formats, such as text, XML, Microsoft Word document, or worksheet.\n- Creation of multiple files separately and encapsulation of those files into zip files.\n\nA format component lets you attach specific files that can be used in the reporting output:\n\n- Excel workbooks that contain a worksheet that can be used as a template for output in the OPENXML worksheet format\n- Word files that contain a document that can be used as a template for output in the Microsoft Word document format\n- Other files that can be incorporated into the format’s output as predefined files\n\nThe following illustration shows how the data flows for these formats.\n\n[![Data flow for outgoing format components](./media/ER-overview-02.png)](./media/ER-overview-02.png)\n\nTo run a single ER format configuration and generate an outgoing electronic document, you must identify the mapping of the format configuration.\n\n#### Format components for incoming electronic documents\nA format component is the scheme of the incoming document that is imported at run time. A scheme consists of the following elements:\n\n- A format that defines the structure and content of the incoming electronic document that contains data that is imported at run time. A format component is used to parse an incoming document in various formats, such as text and XML.\n- A format mapping that binds individual format elements to elements of a domain-specific data model. At run time, the elements in the data model specify the data flow and the rules for importing data from an incoming document, and then store the data in a data model.\n- A format validation, as a set of configurable rules that control data import at run time, depending on the running context. For example, there might be a rule that stops data import of a bank statement that has a vendor’s payments and throws an exception when a specific vendor’s attributes are missing, such as the vendor identification code.\n\nThe following illustration shows how the data flows for these formats.\n\n[![Data flow for incoming format components](./media/ER-overview-03.png)](./media/ER-overview-03.png)\n\nTo run a single ER format configuration to import data from an incoming electronic document, you must identify the desired mapping of a format configuration, and also the integration point of a model mapping. You can use the same model mapping and destinations together with different formats for different type of incoming documents.\n\n#### Component versioning\n\nVersioning is supported for ER components. The following workflow is provided to manage changes in ER components:\n\n1. The version that is originally created is marked as a **Draft** version. This version can be edited and is available for test runs.\n2. The **Draft** version can be converted to a **Completed** version. This version can be used in local reporting processes.\n3. The **Completed** version can be converted to a **Shared** version. This version is published on LCS and can be used in global reporting processes.\n4. The **Shared** version can be converted to a **Discontinued** version. This version can then be deleted.\n\nVersions that have either **Completed** or **Shared** status are available for other data interchange. The following actions can be performed on a component that has these statuses:\n\n- The component can be serialized in XML format and exported as a file in XML format.\n- The component can be reserialized from an XML file and imported into Finance and Operations as a new version of an ER component.\n\n#### Component date effectivity\n\nER component versions are date-effective. You can set the **Effective from** date for an ER component to specify the date that the component becomes effective for reporting processes. The Finance and Operations session date is used to define whether a component is valid for execution. If more than one version is valid for a particular date, the latest version is used for reporting processes.\n\n#### Component access\n\nAccess to ER format components depends on the setting for the ISO country/region code. When this setting is blank for a selected version of a format configuration, a format component can be accessed from any company at run time. When this setting contains ISO country/region codes, a format component is available only from companies that have a primary address that is defined for one of a format component's ISO country/region codes.\n\nDifferent versions of a data format component can have different settings for ISO country/region codes.\n\n#### Configuration\n\nAn ER configuration is the wrapper of a particular ER component. That component can be either a data model component or a format component. A configuration can include different versions of an ER component. Each configuration is marked as owned by a specific configuration provider. The **Draft** version of a component of a configuration can be edited when the owner of the configuration has been selected as an active provider in the ER settings in Finance and Operations.\n\nEach model configuration contains a data model component. A new format configuration can be derived from a specific data model configuration. In the configuration tree, the format configuration that is created appears as a child of the original data model configuration.\n\nThe format configuration that is created contains a format component. The data model component of the original model configuration is automatically inserted into the format component of the child format configuration as a default data source.\n\nAn ER configuration is shared for Finance and Operations companies.\n\n#### Provider\n\nThe ER provider is the party identifier that is used to indicate the author (owner) of each ER configuration. ER lets you manage the list of configuration providers. Format configurations that are released for electronic documents as part of the Finance and Operations solution are marked as owned by the **Microsoft** configuration provider.\n\nTo learn how to register a new ER provider, play the task guide, **ER Create a configuration provider and mark it as active** (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n#### Repository\n\nAn ER repository stores ER configurations. Two types of ER repositories are currently supported, **Operations resources** and **LCS project**.\n\nAn **Operations resources** repository provides access to the list of configurations that Microsoft, as an ER configuration provider, releases as part of the Finance and Operations solution. Those configurations can be imported into the current Finance and Operations instance and used for electronic reporting. They can also be used for additional localizations and customizations.\n\nAn **LCS project** repository provides access to the list of configurations of a specific LCS project (LCS project assets library) that was selected at the repository registration stage. ER lets you upload shared configurations from the current Finance and Operations instance to a specific **LCS project** repository. You can also import configurations from an **LCS project** repository into the current Finance and Operations instance.\n\nRequired **LCS project** repositories can be registered individually for each configuration provider of the current Finance and Operations instance. Each repository can be dedicated to a specific configuration provider.\n\n## Supported scenarios\n### Building a data model\n\nER provides a model designer that you can use to build a data model for a particular business domain. All domain-specific business entities, and the relations between them, can be presented in a data model as a hierarchical structure. The following illustration shows an example of this type of data model (the payment domain data model). \n\n[![Payment domain data model](./media/ER-overview-04.png)](./media/ER-overview-04.png)\n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Design domain specific data model** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Translating data model content\n\nData model content (labels and descriptions) can be translated into other languages that Finance and Operations supports. You might want to translate data model content for the following reasons:\n\n-   At design time, to make the content more intelligible for format designers who speak other languages, and who will use the data model for data mapping of format components.\n-   At run time, to make the content more user-friendly by presenting prompts and help for run-time parameters, and configured validation messages (errors and warnings), in the language that the currently signed-in user prefers.\n\nThe following illustration shows an example where data model content is translated from English to Japanese. \n\n[![Data model content in English](./media/ER-overview-05.png)](./media/ER-overview-05.png)\n\n[![Data model content translated into Japanese](./media/ER-overview-06.png)](./media/ER-overview-06.png)\n\n\n### Configuring data model mappings for outgoing documents\n\nER provides a model mapping designer that lets users map data models that they have designed to specific Finance and Operations data sources. Based on the mapping, the data will be imported at run time from selected data sources into the data model. The data model is then used as an abstract data source of ER formats that generate outgoing electronic documents. The following illustration shows an exampel of this type of data model mapping (the **SEPA Credit Transfer** model mapping of the payment domain data model). \n\n[![Example of data model mapping](./media/ER-overview-07.png)](./media/ER-overview-07.png)\n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Define model mapping and select data sources** and **ER Map data model to selected data sources** task guides (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Configuring data model mappings for incoming documents\nER provides a model mapping designer that lets users map data models that they have designed to specific destinations. For example, data models can be mapped to the Finance and Operations updatable data components (tables, data entities, and views). Based on the mapping, the Finance and Operations data will be updated at run time by using the data from the data model. As abstract storage of the ER format, the data model is filled with data that is imported from an incoming electronic document. The following illustration shows an example of this type of data model mapping. In this example, the **Import mapping for NETS** model mapping of the payment domain data model is used to support the import of bank statements in the NETS bank format for Norway.\n\n[![Import mapping for NETS data model example](./media/ER-overview-08.png)](./media/ER-overview-08.png)\n\n### Storing a designed model component as a model configuration\n\nER can store a designed data model, together with associated data mappings, as a model configuration of the current Finance and Operations instance. The following illustration shows an example of this type of data model configuration (the payment model configuration). \n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Map data model to selected data sources** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Building a format that uses a data model as a base\n\nER supports a format designer that you can use to build the format of an electronic document for a selected business domain by selecting the model component as a base. The same ER format designer lets you map a format that you create to a selected domain’s data model mapping as a data source. The following illustration shows an example of this type of format (the format configuration that supports the **BACS** payment format for the United Kingdom). \n\n[![Example of a format that has a data model as a base](./media/ER-overview-09.png)](./media/ER-overview-09.png)\n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Design domain specific format** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in OPENXML worksheet format\n\nThe ER format designer can be used to build an electronic document in OPENXML worksheet format. The following illustration shows an example of this type of format (a format configuration to generate OPENXML worksheet with details of a selected payment journal).\n\n[![Pic-ER-format-Excel](./media/ER-overview-10.png)](./media/ER-overview-10.png)\n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Create a configuration for reports in OPENXML format** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process). As part of the task guide step for importing a template, use the [Template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymWsReport.xlsx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202) Excel file as a template.\n\n### Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in a Word document format\nThe ER format designer can be used to build an electronic document in a Word document format. The following illustration shows an example of this type of format. Note that this format reuses the existing ER configuration that was originally designed to generate the report output in OPENXML format.\n\n[![Pic-ER-format-Word](./media/ER-overview-11.png)](./media/ER-overview-11.png)\n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the ER Design a configuration for generating reports in Microsoft WORD format task guide (part of the 7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677) business process). As part of the task guide step for importing a template, use the following Word files as templates for the ER format:\n\n- [Template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymDocReport.docx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)\n- [Bounded template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymDocReportBounded.docx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)\n\n### Building a configuration to import data from incoming electronic documents  \nThe ER format designer can be used to describe an electronic document that is planned for data import in either XML or text format. The designed format is used to parse an incoming document. The ER format mapping designer can be used to define the binding of the elements of the designed format to the data model. The following illustrations show an example of this type of format and format mapping. In this example, NETS bank statements that include vendor payment details in text format are imported.\n\n[![ER-format-designer](./media/ER-overview-12.png)](./media/ER-overview-12.png)\n\n[![ER-model-mapping-designer](./media/ER-overview-13.png)](./media/ER-overview-13.png)\n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the Create required ER configurations to import data from an external file task guide (part of the 7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677) business process). Use the following files to play this guide:\n\n- [ER data model configuration (1099model.xml)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)\n- [ER format configuration (1099format.xml)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)\n- [Sample of the incoming document in XML format (1099entries.xml)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)\n- [Sample of the workbook to manage data of incoming document (1099entries.xlsx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)\n\n### Storing a designed format component in a format configuration\n\nER can store a designed format together with the configured data mappings as a format configuration of the current Finance and Operations instance. The preceding illustration shows an example of this type of format configuration (**BACS (UK)**, which is a child of the **Payment model** configuration). To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Design domain specific format** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Configuring Finance and Operations to start to use a created format internally\n\nFinance and Operations can be configured to start to use a created format to generate electronic reports. The reference to the created format configuration should be defined in the settings of a specific domain. For example, to start to use an ER format configuration for electronic vendor payments in BACS format, the format configuration should be referenced in specific methods of payment, as shown in the following illustrations: \n\n[![BACS (UK) format configuration](./media/ER-overview-14.png)](./media/ER-overview-14.png)\n\n[![Referencing the BACS (UK) format in a payment method](./media/ER-overview-15.png)](./media/ER-overview-15.png)\n\nTo become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Use format to generate electronic document for payments** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n## Handling ER components\n### Publishing an ER component in LCS to offer it externally (localization)\n\nThe owner of a component (model or format) that has been created can use ER to publish the completed version of the component to LCS. A repository of the **LCS project** type for the current ER configuration provider is required. When the status of the completed version of a component is changed from **COMPLETED** to **SHARED**, that version is published in LCS. When a component has been published to LCS, the owner of that component becomes a provider of the service to support the component. For example, if the format component is designed to generate an electronic document that is legally required (for example, in accordance with a localization scenario), it's assumed that the format will be kept compliant with legislative changes, and that the provider will issue new versions of the component whenever new legislative requirements arise. To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Upload a configuration into Lifecycle Services** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Importing an ER component from LCS to use it internally\n\nER lets you import ER components from LCS to the current Finance and Operations instance. A repository of the **LCS project** type is required. When an ER component has been imported from LCS to the current Finance and Operations instance, the owner of the instance becomes a consumer of the service that is provided by the owner (author) of the imported component. For example, if a format component is designed to generate a specific electronic document from Finance and Operations in a country/region-specific format (localization scenario), it's assumed that the service consumer will be able to obtain any updates that are made to that format, to keep it compliant with legislative requirements. To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Import a configuration from Lifecycle Services** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Building a format selecting another format as a base (customization)\n\nER lets you create (derive) a new component from the current version of a component (base) that was imported from LCS. For example, a user wants to derive a new format to implement some special requirements for an electronic document (such as an additional field or an extensive description) to support a customization scenario. To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Upgrade format by adoption of new base version of it** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process).\n\n### Upgrading a format selecting a new version of base format (rebase)\n\nER lets you automatically adopt changes of the latest version of the base component in the current draft version of the derived component. This process is known as *rebasing*. For example, a new regulatory change that has been introduced in the latest version of the format that was imported from LCS can be automatically merged into the customized version of this format of the electronic document. Any changes that can’t be merged automatically are considered conflicts. These conflicts are presented for manual resolution in the designer tool for the appropriate component. To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Upgrade format by adoption of new base version of that format** task guide (part of the **7.5.5.3 Acquire/Develop changed IT service/solution component (10683)** business process).\n\n## List of ER configurations that are delivered in the Finance and Operations solution\n| Domain-specific data model configurations: Title | Domain                | Data model–dependent format configurations: Title | Description                                                        |\n|--------------------------------------------------|-----------------------|---------------------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Audit file model                                 | Financial audit       |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Audit file (NL)                                   | Audit file format for Netherlands                                  |\n| BAS model                                        | Tax reporting         |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | BAS (AU)                                          | BAS format for Australia                                           |\n| Construction industry scheme model               | Tax reporting         |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | CIS Monthly return (UK)                           | CIS monthly return format for the United Kingdom                   |\n| Collection letter model                          | Electronic invoicing  |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | OIOUBL Collection Letter (DK)                     | OIOUBL collection letter format for Denmark                        |\n| Electronic ledger accounting model (MX)          | Tax reporting         |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Auxiliary Ledger XML (MX)                         | Auxiliary ledger transactions per account report format for Mexico |\n|                                                  |                       | Chart of Account XML (MX)                         | Chart of account report format for Mexico                          |\n|                                                  |                       | Journals XML (MX)                                 | Journal transactions report format for Mexico                      |\n|                                                  |                       | Trial Balance XML (MX)                            | Trial balance report format for Mexico                             |\n| Elster model                                     | Tax reporting         |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Elster (DE)                                       | Elster format for Germany                                          |\n| EU Sales list model                              | Trade reporting       |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list (DE)                                | EU Sales list TXT format for Germany                               |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list (DK)                                | EU Sales list TXT format for Denmark                               |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list (FR)                                | EU Sales list XML format for France                                |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list (NL)                                | EU Sales list XML format for Netherlands                           |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list TXT (UK)                            | EU Sales list TXT format for the United Kingdom                    |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list XML (UK)                            | EU Sales list XML format for the United Kingdom                    |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list by columns report                   | EU Sales list by columns report                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | EU Sales list by rows report                      | EU Sales list by rows report                                       |\n| FEC accounting model (FR)                        | Tax reporting         |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | FEC Accounting data XML (FR)                      | FEC accounting data export XML format for France                   |\n| German audit file                                | Financial audit       |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | German audit file output                          | Audit file output for Germany and Austria                          |\n| Intrastat model                                  | Trade reporting       |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Intrastat (DE)                                    | Intrastat format for Germany                                       |\n|                                                  |                       | Intrastat (DK)                                    | Intrastat format for Denmark                                       |\n|                                                  |                       | Intrastat INTRACOM (FR)                           | Intrastat INTRACOM format for France                               |\n|                                                  |                       | Intrastat SAISUNIC (FR)                           | Intrastat SAISUNIC format for France                               |\n|                                                  |                       | Intrastat (NL)                                    | Intrastat format for the Netherlands                               |\n|                                                  |                       | Intrastat (UK)                                    | Intrastat format for the United Kingdom                            |\n|                                                  |                       | Intrastat report                                  | Intrastat Excel control report                                     |\n| Customer invoice model                           | Electronic invoicing  |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | OIOUBL Project credit note (DK)                   | OIOUBL Project credit note format for Denmark                      |\n|                                                  |                       | OIOUBL Project invoice (DK)                       | OIOUBL Project invoice format for Denmark                          |\n|                                                  |                       | OIOUBL Sales credit note (DK)                     | OIOUBL Sales credit note format for Denmark                        |\n|                                                  |                       | OIOUBL Sales invoice (DK)                         | OIOUBL Sales invoice format for Denmark                            |\n| OB declaration model                             | Tax reporting         |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | OB declaration (NL)                               | OB declaration format for the Netherlands                          |\n| Payment model                                    | Payments              |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Betalingsservice (DK)                             | Betalingsservice payment format for Denmark                        |\n|                                                  |                       | Bill of exchange remittance (FR)                  | Bill of exchange remittance format for France                      |\n|                                                  |                       | BTL91 (NL)                                        | BTL91 vendor payment format for the Netherlands                    |\n|                                                  |                       | CFONB Prelevements (FR)                           | CFONB direct debit payment format for France                       |\n|                                                  |                       | CFONB Virements (FR)                              | CFONB domestic vendor payment format for France                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Nordea Vendor (DK)                                | Nordea corporate netbank vendor payment format for Denmark         |\n|                                                  |                       | ANZ Direct Credit Service (AU)                    | Format for ANZ Direct Credit Service for Australia                 |\n|                                                  |                       | CBA Direct Credit Service (AU)                    | Format for CBA Direct Credit Service for Australia                 |\n|                                                  |                       | NAB Direct Credit Service (AU)                    | Format for NAB Direct Credit Service for Australia                 |\n|                                                  |                       | STG Direct Credit Service (AU)                    | Format for STG Direct Credit Service for Australia                 |\n|                                                  |                       | WBC Direct Entry System (AU)                      | Format for WBC Direct Entry System for Australia                   |\n|                                                  |                       | DirectLink (NZ)                                   | Format for DirectLink for New Zealand                              |\n|                                                  |                       | JBA Payment file (JP)                             | JBA Payment format for Japan                                       |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Credit transfer                          | SEPA Credit transfer format for Europe                             |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Credit transfer (FR)                     | SEPA Credit transfer format for France                             |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Credit transfer (DE)                     | SEPA Credit transfer format for Germany                            |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Credit transfer (NL)                     | SEPA Credit transfer format for the Netherlands                    |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Direct debit                             | SEPA Direct debit format for Europe                                |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Direct debit (FR)                        | SEPA Direct debit format for France                                |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Direct debit (DE)                        | SEPA Direct debit format for Germany                               |\n|                                                  |                       | ISO20022 Direct debit (NL)                        | SEPA Direct debit format for the Netherlands                       |\n|                                                  |                       | BACS (UK)                                         | BACS vendor payment format for the United Kingdom                  |\n| Reverse charge                                   | Tax reporting         |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Reverse charge sales list                         | Reverse charge sales list format                                   |\n| Dutch XBRL integration model                     | XBRL reporting        |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Semansys XBRL (NL)                                | Semansys XBRL export format for the Netherlands                    |\n| GAF model (MY)                                   | Financial audit       |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | GAF file (MY)                                     | Format of GAF for Malaysia                                         |\n| Vendor aging report (CN)                         | Vendors data analysis |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Vendor aging report format (CN)                   | Vendor aging report format for China                               |\n| Vendor invoice declaration model                 | Vendors data analysis |                                                   |                                                                    |\n|                                                  |                       | Vendor invoice declaration (IS)                   | Vendor invoice declaration format for Iceland                      |\n|                                                  |                       | Vendor invoice declaration report (IS)            | Vendor invoice declaration report for Iceland                      |\n\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Localization requirements – Create an Electronic reporting configuration](electronic-reporting-configuration.md)\n\n[Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle](general-electronic-reporting-manage-configuration-lifecycle.md)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,852],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Electronic reporting overview\ndescription: This article provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool. It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/15/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: ERWorkspace\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 58941\nms.assetid: 5d51b6a6-ad12-4af9-a66d-a1eb820ae57f\nms.search.region: global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: nselin\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Electronic reporting overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,29],"content":"Electronic reporting overview","nodes":[{"content":"Electronic reporting overview","pos":[0,29]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool. It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,232],"content":"This article provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool. It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool. It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.","pos":[0,232],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool.","pos":[0,72]},{"content":"It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.","pos":[73,232]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[860,889],"content":"Electronic reporting overview","linkify":"Electronic reporting overview","nodes":[{"content":"Electronic reporting overview","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"This topic provides an overview of the Electronic reporting (ER) tool.","pos":[935,1005]},{"content":"It includes information about key concepts, the scenarios that ER supports, and a list of formats that have been designed and released as part of the solution.","pos":[1006,1165]},{"content":"ER is a tool that you can use to configure formats for both incoming and outgoing electronic documents in accordance with the legal requirements of various countries/regions.","pos":[1167,1341]},{"content":"ER lets you manage these formats during their lifecycle.","pos":[1342,1398]},{"content":"For example, you can adopt new regulatory requirements, and generate business documents in the required format to electronically exchange information with government bodies, banks, and other parties.","pos":[1399,1598]},{"content":"The ER engine is targeted at business users instead of developers.","pos":[1600,1666]},{"content":"Because you configure formats instead of code, the processes for creating and adjusting formats for electronic documents are faster and easier.","pos":[1667,1810]},{"content":"ER currently supports the TEXT, XML, Microsoft Word document, and OPENXML worksheet formats.","pos":[1812,1904]},{"content":"However, an extension interface provides support for additional formats.","pos":[1905,1977]},{"pos":[1982,1994],"content":"Capabilities","linkify":"Capabilities","nodes":[{"content":"Capabilities","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"The ER engine has the following capabilities:","pos":[1995,2040]},{"content":"It represents a single shared tool for electronic reporting in different domains and replaces more than 20 different engines that do some type of electronic reporting for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[2044,2265]},{"content":"It makes a report’s format insulated from the current Finance and Operations implementation.","pos":[2268,2360]},{"content":"In other words, the format is applicable for different versions of Finance and Operations.","pos":[2361,2451]},{"content":"It supports the creation of a custom format that is based on an original format.","pos":[2454,2534]},{"content":"It also includes capabilities for automatically upgrading the customized format when the original format is changed because of localization/customization requirements.","pos":[2535,2702]},{"content":"It becomes the primary standard tool to support localization requirements in electronic reporting, both for Microsoft and for Microsoft partners.","pos":[2705,2850]},{"content":"It supports the ability to distribute formats to partners and customers through Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).","pos":[2853,2977]},{"pos":[2982,2994],"content":"Key concepts","linkify":"Key concepts","nodes":[{"content":"Key concepts","pos":[0,12]}]},{"pos":[2999,3009],"content":"Components","linkify":"Components","nodes":[{"content":"Components","pos":[0,10]}]},{"pos":[3011,3078],"content":"ER supports two types of components: <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data model<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Format<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"ER supports two types of components: **Data model** and **Format**."},{"pos":[3085,3106],"content":"Data model components","linkify":"Data model components","nodes":[{"content":"Data model components","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"A data model component is an abstract representation of a data structure.","pos":[3108,3181]},{"content":"It's used to describe a specific business domain area with enough detail to satisfy the reporting requirements for that domain.","pos":[3182,3309]},{"content":"A data model component consists of the following parts:","pos":[3310,3365]},{"content":"A data model, as a set of domain-specific business entities and a hierarchically structured definition of relations between those entities.","pos":[3369,3508]},{"content":"A model mapping that links selected Finance and Operations data sources to individual elements of a data model that specifies, at run time, the data flow and rules of business data population to a data model component.","pos":[3511,3729]},{"content":"A business entity of a data model is represented as a container (record).","pos":[3731,3804]},{"content":"Business entity properties are represented as data items (fields).","pos":[3805,3871]},{"content":"Each data item has a unique name, label, description, and value.","pos":[3872,3936]},{"content":"The value of each data item can be designed so that it's recognized as a string, integer, real, date, enumeration, Boolean, and so on.","pos":[3937,4071]},{"content":"Additionally, it can be another record or records list.","pos":[4072,4127]},{"content":"A single data model component can contain several hierarchies of domain-specific business entities.","pos":[4129,4228]},{"content":"It can also contain model mappings that support a report-specific data flow at run time.","pos":[4229,4317]},{"content":"The hierarchies are differentiated by a single record that has been selected as a root for model mapping.","pos":[4318,4423]},{"content":"For example, the data model of the payment domain area might support the following mappings:","pos":[4424,4516]},{"content":"Company &gt; Vendor &gt; Payment transactions of the AP domain","pos":[4520,4576],"source":"Company > Vendor > Payment transactions of the AP domain"},{"content":"Customer &gt; Company &gt; Payment transactions of the AR domain","pos":[4579,4637],"source":"Customer > Company > Payment transactions of the AR domain"},{"content":"Note that business entities such as company and payment transactions are designed one time.","pos":[4639,4730]},{"content":"Different mappings then reuse them.","pos":[4731,4766]},{"content":"A model mapping that supports outgoing electronic documents has the following capabilities:","pos":[4768,4859]},{"content":"It can use different Finance and Operations data types as data sources for a data model.","pos":[4863,4951]},{"content":"For example, it can use tables, data entities, methods, or enums.","pos":[4952,5017]},{"content":"It supports user input parameters that can be defined as data sources for a data model when some data must be specified at run time.","pos":[5020,5152]},{"content":"It supports the transformation of Finance and Operations data into required groups.","pos":[5155,5238]},{"content":"It also lets you filter, sort, and sum data, and append logical calculated fields that are designed through formulas that resemble Microsoft Excel formulas, as shown in the following illustration.","pos":[5239,5435]},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Formula designer in Electronic reporting<ept id=\"p1\">](general-electronic-reporting-formula-designer.md)</ept>).","pos":[5436,5556],"source":" For more information, see [Formula designer in Electronic reporting](general-electronic-reporting-formula-designer.md))."},{"pos":[5558,5635],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Formula designer<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-01.png)](./media/ER-overview-01.png)</ept>","source":"[![Formula designer](./media/ER-overview-01.png)](./media/ER-overview-01.png)"},{"content":"A model mapping that supports incoming electronic documents has the following capabilities:","pos":[5638,5729]},{"content":"It can use different updatable data elements as targets.","pos":[5733,5789]},{"content":"These data elements include tables, data entities, and views.","pos":[5790,5851]},{"content":"The data can be updated by using the data from incoming electronic documents.","pos":[5852,5929]},{"content":"Multiple targets can be used in a single model mapping.","pos":[5930,5985]},{"content":"It supports user input parameters that can be defined as data sources for a data model when some data must be specified at run time.","pos":[5988,6120]},{"content":"A data model component is designed for each business domain that should be used as a unified data source for reporting that isolates reporting from the physical implementation of data sources.","pos":[6122,6314]},{"content":"It represents domain-specific business concepts and functionalities in a form that makes a reporting format's initial design and further maintenance more efficient.","pos":[6315,6479]},{"pos":[6486,6537],"content":"Format components for outgoing electronic documents","linkify":"Format components for outgoing electronic documents","nodes":[{"content":"Format components for outgoing electronic documents","pos":[0,51]}]},{"content":"A format component is the scheme of the reporting output that will be generated at run time.","pos":[6539,6631]},{"content":"A scheme consists of the following elements:","pos":[6632,6676]},{"content":"A format that defines the structure and content of the outgoing electronic document that is generated at run time.","pos":[6680,6794]},{"content":"Data sources, as a set of user input parameters and a domain-specific data model that uses a selected model mapping.","pos":[6797,6913]},{"content":"A format mapping, as a set of bindings of format data sources that have individual elements of a format that specify, at run time, the data flow and rules for format output generation.","pos":[6916,7100]},{"content":"A format validation, as a set of configurable rules that control report generation at run time, depending on the running context.","pos":[7103,7232]},{"content":"For example, there might be a rule that stops output generation of a vendor’s payments and throws an exception when specific attributes of the selected vendor are missing, such as the bank account number.","pos":[7233,7437]},{"content":"A format component supports the following functions:","pos":[7439,7491]},{"content":"Creation of reporting output as individual files in various formats, such as text, XML, Microsoft Word document, or worksheet.","pos":[7495,7621]},{"content":"Creation of multiple files separately and encapsulation of those files into zip files.","pos":[7624,7710]},{"content":"A format component lets you attach specific files that can be used in the reporting output:","pos":[7712,7803]},{"content":"Excel workbooks that contain a worksheet that can be used as a template for output in the OPENXML worksheet format","pos":[7807,7921]},{"content":"Word files that contain a document that can be used as a template for output in the Microsoft Word document format","pos":[7924,8038]},{"content":"Other files that can be incorporated into the format’s output as predefined files","pos":[8041,8122]},{"content":"The following illustration shows how the data flows for these formats.","pos":[8124,8194]},{"pos":[8196,8297],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Data flow for outgoing format components<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-02.png)](./media/ER-overview-02.png)</ept>","source":"[![Data flow for outgoing format components](./media/ER-overview-02.png)](./media/ER-overview-02.png)"},{"content":"To run a single ER format configuration and generate an outgoing electronic document, you must identify the mapping of the format configuration.","pos":[8299,8443]},{"pos":[8450,8501],"content":"Format components for incoming electronic documents","linkify":"Format components for incoming electronic documents","nodes":[{"content":"Format components for incoming electronic documents","pos":[0,51]}]},{"content":"A format component is the scheme of the incoming document that is imported at run time.","pos":[8502,8589]},{"content":"A scheme consists of the following elements:","pos":[8590,8634]},{"content":"A format that defines the structure and content of the incoming electronic document that contains data that is imported at run time.","pos":[8638,8770]},{"content":"A format component is used to parse an incoming document in various formats, such as text and XML.","pos":[8771,8869]},{"content":"A format mapping that binds individual format elements to elements of a domain-specific data model.","pos":[8872,8971]},{"content":"At run time, the elements in the data model specify the data flow and the rules for importing data from an incoming document, and then store the data in a data model.","pos":[8972,9138]},{"content":"A format validation, as a set of configurable rules that control data import at run time, depending on the running context.","pos":[9141,9264]},{"content":"For example, there might be a rule that stops data import of a bank statement that has a vendor’s payments and throws an exception when a specific vendor’s attributes are missing, such as the vendor identification code.","pos":[9265,9484]},{"content":"The following illustration shows how the data flows for these formats.","pos":[9486,9556]},{"pos":[9558,9659],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Data flow for incoming format components<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-03.png)](./media/ER-overview-03.png)</ept>","source":"[![Data flow for incoming format components](./media/ER-overview-03.png)](./media/ER-overview-03.png)"},{"content":"To run a single ER format configuration to import data from an incoming electronic document, you must identify the desired mapping of a format configuration, and also the integration point of a model mapping.","pos":[9661,9869]},{"content":"You can use the same model mapping and destinations together with different formats for different type of incoming documents.","pos":[9870,9995]},{"pos":[10002,10022],"content":"Component versioning","linkify":"Component versioning","nodes":[{"content":"Component versioning","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Versioning is supported for ER components.","pos":[10024,10066]},{"content":"The following workflow is provided to manage changes in ER components:","pos":[10067,10137]},{"content":"The version that is originally created is marked as a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Draft<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> version.","pos":[10142,10214],"source":"The version that is originally created is marked as a **Draft** version."},{"content":"This version can be edited and is available for test runs.","pos":[10215,10273]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Draft<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> version can be converted to a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Completed<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> version.","pos":[10277,10343],"source":"The **Draft** version can be converted to a **Completed** version."},{"content":"This version can be used in local reporting processes.","pos":[10344,10398]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Completed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> version can be converted to a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Shared<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> version.","pos":[10402,10469],"source":"The **Completed** version can be converted to a **Shared** version."},{"content":"This version is published on LCS and can be used in global reporting processes.","pos":[10470,10549]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Shared<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> version can be converted to a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Discontinued<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> version.","pos":[10553,10623],"source":"The **Shared** version can be converted to a **Discontinued** version."},{"content":"This version can then be deleted.","pos":[10624,10657]},{"content":"Versions that have either <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Completed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Shared<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> status are available for other data interchange.","pos":[10659,10761],"source":"Versions that have either **Completed** or **Shared** status are available for other data interchange."},{"content":"The following actions can be performed on a component that has these statuses:","pos":[10762,10840]},{"content":"The component can be serialized in XML format and exported as a file in XML format.","pos":[10844,10927]},{"content":"The component can be reserialized from an XML file and imported into Finance and Operations as a new version of an ER component.","pos":[10930,11058]},{"pos":[11065,11091],"content":"Component date effectivity","linkify":"Component date effectivity","nodes":[{"content":"Component date effectivity","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"ER component versions are date-effective.","pos":[11093,11134]},{"content":"You can set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Effective from<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> date for an ER component to specify the date that the component becomes effective for reporting processes.","pos":[11135,11276],"source":" You can set the **Effective from** date for an ER component to specify the date that the component becomes effective for reporting processes."},{"content":"The Finance and Operations session date is used to define whether a component is valid for execution.","pos":[11277,11378]},{"content":"If more than one version is valid for a particular date, the latest version is used for reporting processes.","pos":[11379,11487]},{"pos":[11494,11510],"content":"Component access","linkify":"Component access","nodes":[{"content":"Component access","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"Access to ER format components depends on the setting for the ISO country/region code.","pos":[11512,11598]},{"content":"When this setting is blank for a selected version of a format configuration, a format component can be accessed from any company at run time.","pos":[11599,11740]},{"content":"When this setting contains ISO country/region codes, a format component is available only from companies that have a primary address that is defined for one of a format component's ISO country/region codes.","pos":[11741,11947]},{"content":"Different versions of a data format component can have different settings for ISO country/region codes.","pos":[11949,12052]},{"pos":[12059,12072],"content":"Configuration","linkify":"Configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Configuration","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"An ER configuration is the wrapper of a particular ER component.","pos":[12074,12138]},{"content":"That component can be either a data model component or a format component.","pos":[12139,12213]},{"content":"A configuration can include different versions of an ER component.","pos":[12214,12280]},{"content":"Each configuration is marked as owned by a specific configuration provider.","pos":[12281,12356]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Draft<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> version of a component of a configuration can be edited when the owner of the configuration has been selected as an active provider in the ER settings in Finance and Operations.","pos":[12357,12548],"source":" The **Draft** version of a component of a configuration can be edited when the owner of the configuration has been selected as an active provider in the ER settings in Finance and Operations."},{"content":"Each model configuration contains a data model component.","pos":[12550,12607]},{"content":"A new format configuration can be derived from a specific data model configuration.","pos":[12608,12691]},{"content":"In the configuration tree, the format configuration that is created appears as a child of the original data model configuration.","pos":[12692,12820]},{"content":"The format configuration that is created contains a format component.","pos":[12822,12891]},{"content":"The data model component of the original model configuration is automatically inserted into the format component of the child format configuration as a default data source.","pos":[12892,13064]},{"content":"An ER configuration is shared for Finance and Operations companies.","pos":[13066,13133]},{"pos":[13140,13148],"content":"Provider","linkify":"Provider","nodes":[{"content":"Provider","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"The ER provider is the party identifier that is used to indicate the author (owner) of each ER configuration.","pos":[13150,13259]},{"content":"ER lets you manage the list of configuration providers.","pos":[13260,13315]},{"content":"Format configurations that are released for electronic documents as part of the Finance and Operations solution are marked as owned by the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Microsoft<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> configuration provider.","pos":[13316,13492],"source":" Format configurations that are released for electronic documents as part of the Finance and Operations solution are marked as owned by the **Microsoft** configuration provider."},{"pos":[13494,13718],"content":"To learn how to register a new ER provider, play the task guide, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Create a configuration provider and mark it as active<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","source":"To learn how to register a new ER provider, play the task guide, **ER Create a configuration provider and mark it as active** (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[13725,13735],"content":"Repository","linkify":"Repository","nodes":[{"content":"Repository","pos":[0,10]}]},{"content":"An ER repository stores ER configurations.","pos":[13737,13779]},{"content":"Two types of ER repositories are currently supported, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operations resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>LCS project<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[13780,13879],"source":" Two types of ER repositories are currently supported, **Operations resources** and **LCS project**."},{"content":"An <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operations resources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> repository provides access to the list of configurations that Microsoft, as an ER configuration provider, releases as part of the Finance and Operations solution.","pos":[13881,14071],"source":"An **Operations resources** repository provides access to the list of configurations that Microsoft, as an ER configuration provider, releases as part of the Finance and Operations solution."},{"content":"Those configurations can be imported into the current Finance and Operations instance and used for electronic reporting.","pos":[14072,14192]},{"content":"They can also be used for additional localizations and customizations.","pos":[14193,14263]},{"content":"An <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LCS project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> repository provides access to the list of configurations of a specific LCS project (LCS project assets library) that was selected at the repository registration stage.","pos":[14265,14451],"source":"An **LCS project** repository provides access to the list of configurations of a specific LCS project (LCS project assets library) that was selected at the repository registration stage."},{"content":"ER lets you upload shared configurations from the current Finance and Operations instance to a specific <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LCS project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> repository.","pos":[14452,14583],"source":" ER lets you upload shared configurations from the current Finance and Operations instance to a specific **LCS project** repository."},{"content":"You can also import configurations from an <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LCS project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> repository into the current Finance and Operations instance.","pos":[14584,14703],"source":" You can also import configurations from an **LCS project** repository into the current Finance and Operations instance."},{"content":"Required <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LCS project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> repositories can be registered individually for each configuration provider of the current Finance and Operations instance.","pos":[14705,14853],"source":"Required **LCS project** repositories can be registered individually for each configuration provider of the current Finance and Operations instance."},{"content":"Each repository can be dedicated to a specific configuration provider.","pos":[14854,14924]},{"pos":[14929,14948],"content":"Supported scenarios","linkify":"Supported scenarios","nodes":[{"content":"Supported scenarios","pos":[0,19]}]},{"pos":[14953,14974],"content":"Building a data model","linkify":"Building a data model","nodes":[{"content":"Building a data model","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"ER provides a model designer that you can use to build a data model for a particular business domain.","pos":[14976,15077]},{"content":"All domain-specific business entities, and the relations between them, can be presented in a data model as a hierarchical structure.","pos":[15078,15210]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an example of this type of data model (the payment domain data model).","pos":[15211,15314]},{"pos":[15317,15403],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Payment domain data model<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-04.png)](./media/ER-overview-04.png)</ept>","source":"[![Payment domain data model](./media/ER-overview-04.png)](./media/ER-overview-04.png)"},{"pos":[15405,15618],"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Design domain specific data model<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","source":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Design domain specific data model** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[15624,15654],"content":"Translating data model content","linkify":"Translating data model content","nodes":[{"content":"Translating data model content","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"Data model content (labels and descriptions) can be translated into other languages that Finance and Operations supports.","pos":[15656,15777]},{"content":"You might want to translate data model content for the following reasons:","pos":[15778,15851]},{"content":"At design time, to make the content more intelligible for format designers who speak other languages, and who will use the data model for data mapping of format components.","pos":[15857,16029]},{"content":"At run time, to make the content more user-friendly by presenting prompts and help for run-time parameters, and configured validation messages (errors and warnings), in the language that the currently signed-in user prefers.","pos":[16034,16258]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an example where data model content is translated from English to Japanese.","pos":[16260,16368]},{"pos":[16371,16461],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Data model content in English<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-05.png)](./media/ER-overview-05.png)</ept>","source":"[![Data model content in English](./media/ER-overview-05.png)](./media/ER-overview-05.png)"},{"pos":[16463,16567],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Data model content translated into Japanese<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-06.png)](./media/ER-overview-06.png)</ept>","source":"[![Data model content translated into Japanese](./media/ER-overview-06.png)](./media/ER-overview-06.png)"},{"pos":[16574,16628],"content":"Configuring data model mappings for outgoing documents","linkify":"Configuring data model mappings for outgoing documents","nodes":[{"content":"Configuring data model mappings for outgoing documents","pos":[0,54]}]},{"content":"ER provides a model mapping designer that lets users map data models that they have designed to specific Finance and Operations data sources.","pos":[16630,16771]},{"content":"Based on the mapping, the data will be imported at run time from selected data sources into the data model.","pos":[16772,16879]},{"content":"The data model is then used as an abstract data source of ER formats that generate outgoing electronic documents.","pos":[16880,16993]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an exampel of this type of data model mapping (the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SEPA Credit Transfer<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> model mapping of the payment domain data model).","pos":[16994,17151],"source":" The following illustration shows an exampel of this type of data model mapping (the **SEPA Credit Transfer** model mapping of the payment domain data model)."},{"pos":[17154,17244],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Example of data model mapping<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-07.png)](./media/ER-overview-07.png)</ept>","source":"[![Example of data model mapping](./media/ER-overview-07.png)](./media/ER-overview-07.png)"},{"pos":[17246,17522],"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Define model mapping and select data sources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>ER Map data model to selected data sources<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> task guides (part of the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> business process).","source":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Define model mapping and select data sources** and **ER Map data model to selected data sources** task guides (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[17528,17582],"content":"Configuring data model mappings for incoming documents","linkify":"Configuring data model mappings for incoming documents","nodes":[{"content":"Configuring data model mappings for incoming documents","pos":[0,54]}]},{"content":"ER provides a model mapping designer that lets users map data models that they have designed to specific destinations.","pos":[17583,17701]},{"content":"For example, data models can be mapped to the Finance and Operations updatable data components (tables, data entities, and views).","pos":[17702,17832]},{"content":"Based on the mapping, the Finance and Operations data will be updated at run time by using the data from the data model.","pos":[17833,17953]},{"content":"As abstract storage of the ER format, the data model is filled with data that is imported from an incoming electronic document.","pos":[17954,18081]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an example of this type of data model mapping.","pos":[18082,18161]},{"content":"In this example, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import mapping for NETS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> model mapping of the payment domain data model is used to support the import of bank statements in the NETS bank format for Norway.","pos":[18162,18342],"source":" In this example, the **Import mapping for NETS** model mapping of the payment domain data model is used to support the import of bank statements in the NETS bank format for Norway."},{"pos":[18344,18447],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Import mapping for NETS data model example<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-08.png)](./media/ER-overview-08.png)</ept>","source":"[![Import mapping for NETS data model example](./media/ER-overview-08.png)](./media/ER-overview-08.png)"},{"pos":[18453,18512],"content":"Storing a designed model component as a model configuration","linkify":"Storing a designed model component as a model configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Storing a designed model component as a model configuration","pos":[0,59]}]},{"content":"ER can store a designed data model, together with associated data mappings, as a model configuration of the current Finance and Operations instance.","pos":[18514,18662]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an example of this type of data model configuration (the payment model configuration).","pos":[18663,18782]},{"pos":[18785,19004],"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Map data model to selected data sources<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","source":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Map data model to selected data sources** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[19010,19060],"content":"Building a format that uses a data model as a base","linkify":"Building a format that uses a data model as a base","nodes":[{"content":"Building a format that uses a data model as a base","pos":[0,50]}]},{"content":"ER supports a format designer that you can use to build the format of an electronic document for a selected business domain by selecting the model component as a base.","pos":[19062,19229]},{"content":"The same ER format designer lets you map a format that you create to a selected domain’s data model mapping as a data source.","pos":[19230,19355]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an example of this type of format (the format configuration that supports the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>BACS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> payment format for the United Kingdom).","pos":[19356,19515],"source":" The following illustration shows an example of this type of format (the format configuration that supports the **BACS** payment format for the United Kingdom)."},{"pos":[19518,19630],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Example of a format that has a data model as a base<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-09.png)](./media/ER-overview-09.png)</ept>","source":"[![Example of a format that has a data model as a base](./media/ER-overview-09.png)](./media/ER-overview-09.png)"},{"pos":[19632,19841],"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Design domain specific format<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","source":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Design domain specific format** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[19847,19932],"content":"Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in OPENXML worksheet format","linkify":"Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in OPENXML worksheet format","nodes":[{"content":"Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in OPENXML worksheet format","pos":[0,85]}]},{"content":"The ER format designer can be used to build an electronic document in OPENXML worksheet format.","pos":[19934,20029]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an example of this type of format (a format configuration to generate OPENXML worksheet with details of a selected payment journal).","pos":[20030,20195]},{"pos":[20197,20277],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Pic-ER-format-Excel<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-10.png)](./media/ER-overview-10.png)</ept>","source":"[![Pic-ER-format-Excel](./media/ER-overview-10.png)](./media/ER-overview-10.png)"},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Create a configuration for reports in OPENXML format<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","pos":[20279,20511],"source":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Create a configuration for reports in OPENXML format** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"content":"As part of the task guide step for importing a template, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymWsReport.xlsx)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)</ept> Excel file as a template.","pos":[20512,20709],"source":" As part of the task guide step for importing a template, use the [Template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymWsReport.xlsx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202) Excel file as a template."},{"pos":[20715,20798],"content":"Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in a Word document format","linkify":"Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in a Word document format","nodes":[{"content":"Building a configuration to generate electronic documents in a Word document format","pos":[0,83]}]},{"content":"The ER format designer can be used to build an electronic document in a Word document format.","pos":[20799,20892]},{"content":"The following illustration shows an example of this type of format.","pos":[20893,20960]},{"content":"Note that this format reuses the existing ER configuration that was originally designed to generate the report output in OPENXML format.","pos":[20961,21097]},{"pos":[21099,21178],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Pic-ER-format-Word<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-11.png)](./media/ER-overview-11.png)</ept>","source":"[![Pic-ER-format-Word](./media/ER-overview-11.png)](./media/ER-overview-11.png)"},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the ER Design a configuration for generating reports in Microsoft WORD format task guide (part of the 7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677) business process).","pos":[21180,21422]},{"content":"As part of the task guide step for importing a template, use the following Word files as templates for the ER format:","pos":[21423,21540]},{"pos":[21544,21651],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymDocReport.docx)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)</ept>","source":"[Template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymDocReport.docx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)"},{"pos":[21654,21776],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Bounded template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymDocReportBounded.docx)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)</ept>","source":"[Bounded template of Payment Report (SampleVendPaymDocReportBounded.docx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)"},{"pos":[21782,21856],"content":"Building a configuration to import data from incoming electronic documents","linkify":"Building a configuration to import data from incoming electronic documents","nodes":[{"content":"Building a configuration to import data from incoming electronic documents","pos":[0,74]}]},{"content":"The ER format designer can be used to describe an electronic document that is planned for data import in either XML or text format.","pos":[21859,21990]},{"content":"The designed format is used to parse an incoming document.","pos":[21991,22049]},{"content":"The ER format mapping designer can be used to define the binding of the elements of the designed format to the data model.","pos":[22050,22172]},{"content":"The following illustrations show an example of this type of format and format mapping.","pos":[22173,22259]},{"content":"In this example, NETS bank statements that include vendor payment details in text format are imported.","pos":[22260,22362]},{"pos":[22364,22443],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>ER-format-designer<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-12.png)](./media/ER-overview-12.png)</ept>","source":"[![ER-format-designer](./media/ER-overview-12.png)](./media/ER-overview-12.png)"},{"pos":[22445,22531],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>ER-model-mapping-designer<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-13.png)](./media/ER-overview-13.png)</ept>","source":"[![ER-model-mapping-designer](./media/ER-overview-13.png)](./media/ER-overview-13.png)"},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the Create required ER configurations to import data from an external file task guide (part of the 7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677) business process).","pos":[22533,22772]},{"content":"Use the following files to play this guide:","pos":[22773,22816]},{"pos":[22820,22913],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ER data model configuration (1099model.xml)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)</ept>","source":"[ER data model configuration (1099model.xml)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)"},{"pos":[22916,23006],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>ER format configuration (1099format.xml)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)</ept>","source":"[ER format configuration (1099format.xml)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)"},{"pos":[23009,23122],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sample of the incoming document in XML format (1099entries.xml)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)</ept>","source":"[Sample of the incoming document in XML format (1099entries.xml)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)"},{"pos":[23125,23252],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Sample of the workbook to manage data of incoming document (1099entries.xlsx)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)</ept>","source":"[Sample of the workbook to manage data of incoming document (1099entries.xlsx)](https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=845202)"},{"pos":[23258,23319],"content":"Storing a designed format component in a format configuration","linkify":"Storing a designed format component in a format configuration","nodes":[{"content":"Storing a designed format component in a format configuration","pos":[0,61]}]},{"content":"ER can store a designed format together with the configured data mappings as a format configuration of the current Finance and Operations instance.","pos":[23321,23468]},{"content":"The preceding illustration shows an example of this type of format configuration (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>BACS (UK)<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, which is a child of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Payment model<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> configuration).","pos":[23469,23623],"source":" The preceding illustration shows an example of this type of format configuration (**BACS (UK)**, which is a child of the **Payment model** configuration)."},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Design domain specific format<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","pos":[23624,23833],"source":" To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Design domain specific format** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[23839,23917],"content":"Configuring Finance and Operations to start to use a created format internally","linkify":"Configuring Finance and Operations to start to use a created format internally","nodes":[{"content":"Configuring Finance and Operations to start to use a created format internally","pos":[0,78]}]},{"content":"Finance and Operations can be configured to start to use a created format to generate electronic reports.","pos":[23919,24024]},{"content":"The reference to the created format configuration should be defined in the settings of a specific domain.","pos":[24025,24130]},{"content":"For example, to start to use an ER format configuration for electronic vendor payments in BACS format, the format configuration should be referenced in specific methods of payment, as shown in the following illustrations:","pos":[24131,24352]},{"pos":[24355,24446],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>BACS (UK) format configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-14.png)](./media/ER-overview-14.png)</ept>","source":"[![BACS (UK) format configuration](./media/ER-overview-14.png)](./media/ER-overview-14.png)"},{"pos":[24448,24561],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Referencing the BACS (UK) format in a payment method<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/ER-overview-15.png)](./media/ER-overview-15.png)</ept>","source":"[![Referencing the BACS (UK) format in a payment method](./media/ER-overview-15.png)](./media/ER-overview-15.png)"},{"pos":[24563,24798],"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Use format to generate electronic document for payments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","source":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Use format to generate electronic document for payments** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[24803,24825],"content":"Handling ER components","linkify":"Handling ER components","nodes":[{"content":"Handling ER components","pos":[0,22]}]},{"pos":[24830,24901],"content":"Publishing an ER component in LCS to offer it externally (localization)","linkify":"Publishing an ER component in LCS to offer it externally (localization)","nodes":[{"content":"Publishing an ER component in LCS to offer it externally (localization)","pos":[0,71]}]},{"content":"The owner of a component (model or format) that has been created can use ER to publish the completed version of the component to LCS.","pos":[24903,25036]},{"content":"A repository of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LCS project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> type for the current ER configuration provider is required.","pos":[25037,25132],"source":" A repository of the **LCS project** type for the current ER configuration provider is required."},{"content":"When the status of the completed version of a component is changed from <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>COMPLETED<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SHARED<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, that version is published in LCS.","pos":[25133,25267],"source":" When the status of the completed version of a component is changed from **COMPLETED** to **SHARED**, that version is published in LCS."},{"content":"When a component has been published to LCS, the owner of that component becomes a provider of the service to support the component.","pos":[25268,25399]},{"content":"For example, if the format component is designed to generate an electronic document that is legally required (for example, in accordance with a localization scenario), it's assumed that the format will be kept compliant with legislative changes, and that the provider will issue new versions of the component whenever new legislative requirements arise.","pos":[25400,25753]},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Upload a configuration into Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","pos":[25754,25980],"source":" To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Upload a configuration into Lifecycle Services** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[25986,26041],"content":"Importing an ER component from LCS to use it internally","linkify":"Importing an ER component from LCS to use it internally","nodes":[{"content":"Importing an ER component from LCS to use it internally","pos":[0,55]}]},{"content":"ER lets you import ER components from LCS to the current Finance and Operations instance.","pos":[26043,26132]},{"content":"A repository of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>LCS project<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> type is required.","pos":[26133,26186],"source":" A repository of the **LCS project** type is required."},{"content":"When an ER component has been imported from LCS to the current Finance and Operations instance, the owner of the instance becomes a consumer of the service that is provided by the owner (author) of the imported component.","pos":[26187,26408]},{"content":"For example, if a format component is designed to generate a specific electronic document from Finance and Operations in a country/region-specific format (localization scenario), it's assumed that the service consumer will be able to obtain any updates that are made to that format, to keep it compliant with legislative requirements.","pos":[26409,26743]},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Import a configuration from Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","pos":[26744,26970],"source":" To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Import a configuration from Lifecycle Services** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[26976,27044],"content":"Building a format selecting another format as a base (customization)","linkify":"Building a format selecting another format as a base (customization)","nodes":[{"content":"Building a format selecting another format as a base (customization)","pos":[0,68]}]},{"content":"ER lets you create (derive) a new component from the current version of a component (base) that was imported from LCS.","pos":[27046,27164]},{"content":"For example, a user wants to derive a new format to implement some special requirements for an electronic document (such as an additional field or an extensive description) to support a customization scenario.","pos":[27165,27374]},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Upgrade format by adoption of new base version of it<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","pos":[27375,27607],"source":" To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Upgrade format by adoption of new base version of it** task guide (part of the **7.5.4.3 Acquire/Develop IT service/solution components (10677)** business process)."},{"pos":[27613,27679],"content":"Upgrading a format selecting a new version of base format (rebase)","linkify":"Upgrading a format selecting a new version of base format (rebase)","nodes":[{"content":"Upgrading a format selecting a new version of base format (rebase)","pos":[0,66]}]},{"content":"ER lets you automatically adopt changes of the latest version of the base component in the current draft version of the derived component.","pos":[27681,27819]},{"content":"This process is known as <bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>rebasing<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>.","pos":[27820,27856],"source":" This process is known as *rebasing*."},{"content":"For example, a new regulatory change that has been introduced in the latest version of the format that was imported from LCS can be automatically merged into the customized version of this format of the electronic document.","pos":[27857,28080]},{"content":"Any changes that can’t be merged automatically are considered conflicts.","pos":[28081,28153]},{"content":"These conflicts are presented for manual resolution in the designer tool for the appropriate component.","pos":[28154,28257]},{"content":"To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>ER Upgrade format by adoption of new base version of that format<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> task guide (part of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>7.5.5.3 Acquire/Develop changed IT service/solution component (10683)<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> business process).","pos":[28258,28506],"source":" To become familiar with the details of this scenario, play the **ER Upgrade format by adoption of new base version of that format** task guide (part of the **7.5.5.3 Acquire/Develop changed IT service/solution component (10683)** business process)."},{"pos":[28511,28594],"content":"List of ER configurations that are delivered in the Finance and Operations solution","linkify":"List of ER configurations that are delivered in the Finance and Operations solution","nodes":[{"content":"List of ER configurations that are delivered in the Finance and Operations solution","pos":[0,83]}]},{"content":"Domain-specific data model configurations: Title","pos":[28597,28645]},{"content":"Domain","pos":[28648,28654]},{"content":"Data model–dependent format configurations: Title","pos":[28672,28721]},{"content":"Description","pos":[28724,28735]},{"content":"Audit file model","pos":[28993,29009]},{"content":"Financial audit","pos":[29044,29059]},{"content":"Audit file (NL)","pos":[29266,29281]},{"content":"Audit file format for Netherlands","pos":[29318,29351]},{"content":"BAS model","pos":[29389,29398]},{"content":"Tax reporting","pos":[29440,29453]},{"content":"BAS (AU)","pos":[29662,29670]},{"content":"BAS format for Australia","pos":[29714,29738]},{"content":"Construction industry scheme model","pos":[29785,29819]},{"content":"Tax reporting","pos":[29836,29849]},{"content":"CIS Monthly return (UK)","pos":[30058,30081]},{"content":"CIS monthly return format for the United Kingdom","pos":[30110,30158]},{"content":"Collection letter model","pos":[30181,30204]},{"content":"Electronic invoicing","pos":[30232,30252]},{"content":"OIOUBL Collection Letter (DK)","pos":[30454,30483]},{"content":"OIOUBL collection letter format for Denmark","pos":[30506,30549]},{"content":"Electronic ledger accounting model (MX)","pos":[30577,30616]},{"content":"Tax reporting","pos":[30628,30641]},{"content":"Auxiliary Ledger XML (MX)","pos":[30850,30875]},{"content":"Auxiliary ledger transactions per account report format for Mexico","pos":[30902,30968]},{"content":"Chart of Account XML (MX)","pos":[31048,31073]},{"content":"Chart of account report format for Mexico","pos":[31100,31141]},{"content":"Journals XML (MX)","pos":[31246,31263]},{"content":"Journal transactions report format for Mexico","pos":[31298,31343]},{"content":"Trial Balance XML (MX)","pos":[31444,31466]},{"content":"Trial balance report format for Mexico","pos":[31496,31534]},{"content":"Elster model","pos":[31567,31579]},{"content":"Tax reporting","pos":[31618,31631]},{"content":"Elster (DE)","pos":[31840,31851]},{"content":"Elster format for Germany","pos":[31892,31917]},{"content":"EU Sales list model","pos":[31963,31982]},{"content":"Trade reporting","pos":[32014,32029]},{"content":"EU Sales list (DE)","pos":[32236,32254]},{"content":"EU Sales list TXT format for Germany","pos":[32288,32324]},{"content":"EU Sales list (DK)","pos":[32434,32452]},{"content":"EU Sales list TXT format for Denmark","pos":[32486,32522]},{"content":"EU Sales list (FR)","pos":[32632,32650]},{"content":"EU Sales list XML format for France","pos":[32684,32719]},{"content":"EU Sales list (NL)","pos":[32830,32848]},{"content":"EU Sales list XML format for Netherlands","pos":[32882,32922]},{"content":"EU Sales list TXT (UK)","pos":[33028,33050]},{"content":"EU Sales list TXT format for the United Kingdom","pos":[33080,33127]},{"content":"EU Sales list XML (UK)","pos":[33226,33248]},{"content":"EU Sales list XML format for the United Kingdom","pos":[33278,33325]},{"content":"EU Sales list by columns report","pos":[33424,33455]},{"content":"EU Sales list by columns report","pos":[33476,33507]},{"content":"EU Sales list by rows report","pos":[33622,33650]},{"content":"EU Sales list by rows report","pos":[33674,33702]},{"content":"FEC accounting model (FR)","pos":[33745,33770]},{"content":"Tax reporting","pos":[33796,33809]},{"content":"FEC Accounting data XML (FR)","pos":[34018,34046]},{"content":"FEC accounting data export XML format for France","pos":[34070,34118]},{"content":"German audit file","pos":[34141,34158]},{"content":"Financial audit","pos":[34192,34207]},{"content":"German audit file output","pos":[34414,34438]},{"content":"Audit file output for Germany and Austria","pos":[34466,34507]},{"content":"Intrastat model","pos":[34537,34552]},{"content":"Trade reporting","pos":[34588,34603]},{"content":"Intrastat (DE)","pos":[34810,34824]},{"content":"Intrastat format for Germany","pos":[34862,34890]},{"content":"Intrastat (DK)","pos":[35008,35022]},{"content":"Intrastat format for Denmark","pos":[35060,35088]},{"content":"Intrastat INTRACOM (FR)","pos":[35206,35229]},{"content":"Intrastat INTRACOM format for France","pos":[35258,35294]},{"content":"Intrastat SAISUNIC (FR)","pos":[35404,35427]},{"content":"Intrastat SAISUNIC format for France","pos":[35456,35492]},{"content":"Intrastat (NL)","pos":[35602,35616]},{"content":"Intrastat format for the Netherlands","pos":[35654,35690]},{"content":"Intrastat (UK)","pos":[35800,35814]},{"content":"Intrastat format for the United Kingdom","pos":[35852,35891]},{"content":"Intrastat report","pos":[35998,36014]},{"content":"Intrastat Excel control report","pos":[36050,36080]},{"content":"Customer invoice model","pos":[36121,36143]},{"content":"Electronic invoicing","pos":[36172,36192]},{"content":"OIOUBL Project credit note (DK)","pos":[36394,36425]},{"content":"OIOUBL Project credit note format for Denmark","pos":[36446,36491]},{"content":"OIOUBL Project invoice (DK)","pos":[36592,36619]},{"content":"OIOUBL Project invoice format for Denmark","pos":[36644,36685]},{"content":"OIOUBL Sales credit note (DK)","pos":[36790,36819]},{"content":"OIOUBL Sales credit note format for Denmark","pos":[36842,36885]},{"content":"OIOUBL Sales invoice (DK)","pos":[36988,37013]},{"content":"OIOUBL Sales invoice format for Denmark","pos":[37040,37079]},{"content":"OB declaration model","pos":[37111,37131]},{"content":"Tax reporting","pos":[37162,37175]},{"content":"OB declaration (NL)","pos":[37384,37403]},{"content":"OB declaration format for the Netherlands","pos":[37436,37477]},{"content":"Payment model","pos":[37507,37520]},{"content":"Payments","pos":[37558,37566]},{"content":"Betalingsservice (DK)","pos":[37780,37801]},{"content":"Betalingsservice payment format for Denmark","pos":[37832,37875]},{"content":"Bill of exchange remittance (FR)","pos":[37978,38010]},{"content":"Bill of exchange remittance format for France","pos":[38030,38075]},{"content":"BTL91 (NL)","pos":[38176,38186]},{"content":"BTL91 vendor payment format for the Netherlands","pos":[38228,38275]},{"content":"CFONB Prelevements (FR)","pos":[38374,38397]},{"content":"CFONB direct debit payment format for France","pos":[38426,38470]},{"content":"CFONB Virements (FR)","pos":[38572,38592]},{"content":"CFONB domestic vendor payment format for France","pos":[38624,38671]},{"content":"Nordea Vendor (DK)","pos":[38770,38788]},{"content":"Nordea corporate netbank vendor payment format for Denmark","pos":[38822,38880]},{"content":"ANZ Direct Credit Service (AU)","pos":[38968,38998]},{"content":"Format for ANZ Direct Credit Service for Australia","pos":[39020,39070]},{"content":"CBA Direct Credit Service (AU)","pos":[39166,39196]},{"content":"Format for CBA Direct Credit Service for Australia","pos":[39218,39268]},{"content":"NAB Direct Credit Service (AU)","pos":[39364,39394]},{"content":"Format for NAB Direct Credit Service for Australia","pos":[39416,39466]},{"content":"STG Direct Credit Service (AU)","pos":[39562,39592]},{"content":"Format for STG Direct Credit Service for Australia","pos":[39614,39664]},{"content":"WBC Direct Entry System (AU)","pos":[39760,39788]},{"content":"Format for WBC Direct Entry System for Australia","pos":[39812,39860]},{"content":"DirectLink (NZ)","pos":[39958,39973]},{"content":"Format for DirectLink for New Zealand","pos":[40010,40047]},{"content":"JBA Payment file (JP)","pos":[40156,40177]},{"content":"JBA Payment format for Japan","pos":[40208,40236]},{"content":"ISO20022 Credit transfer","pos":[40354,40378]},{"content":"SEPA Credit transfer format for Europe","pos":[40406,40444]},{"content":"ISO20022 Credit transfer (FR)","pos":[40552,40581]},{"content":"SEPA Credit transfer format for France","pos":[40604,40642]},{"content":"ISO20022 Credit transfer (DE)","pos":[40750,40779]},{"content":"SEPA Credit transfer format for Germany","pos":[40802,40841]},{"content":"ISO20022 Credit transfer (NL)","pos":[40948,40977]},{"content":"SEPA Credit transfer format for the Netherlands","pos":[41000,41047]},{"content":"ISO20022 Direct debit","pos":[41146,41167]},{"content":"SEPA Direct debit format for Europe","pos":[41198,41233]},{"content":"ISO20022 Direct debit (FR)","pos":[41344,41370]},{"content":"SEPA Direct debit format for France","pos":[41396,41431]},{"content":"ISO20022 Direct debit (DE)","pos":[41542,41568]},{"content":"SEPA Direct debit format for Germany","pos":[41594,41630]},{"content":"ISO20022 Direct debit (NL)","pos":[41740,41766]},{"content":"SEPA Direct debit format for the Netherlands","pos":[41792,41836]},{"content":"BACS (UK)","pos":[41938,41947]},{"content":"BACS vendor payment format for the United Kingdom","pos":[41990,42039]},{"content":"Reverse charge","pos":[42061,42075]},{"content":"Tax reporting","pos":[42112,42125]},{"content":"Reverse charge sales list","pos":[42334,42359]},{"content":"Reverse charge sales list format","pos":[42386,42418]},{"content":"Dutch XBRL integration model","pos":[42457,42485]},{"content":"XBRL reporting","pos":[42508,42522]},{"content":"Semansys XBRL (NL)","pos":[42730,42748]},{"content":"Semansys XBRL export format for the Netherlands","pos":[42782,42829]},{"content":"GAF model (MY)","pos":[42853,42867]},{"content":"Financial audit","pos":[42904,42919]},{"content":"GAF file (MY)","pos":[43126,43139]},{"content":"Format of GAF for Malaysia","pos":[43178,43204]},{"content":"Vendor aging report (CN)","pos":[43249,43273]},{"content":"Vendors data analysis","pos":[43300,43321]},{"content":"Vendor aging report format (CN)","pos":[43522,43553]},{"content":"Vendor aging report format for China","pos":[43574,43610]},{"content":"Vendor invoice declaration model","pos":[43645,43677]},{"content":"Vendors data analysis","pos":[43696,43717]},{"content":"Vendor invoice declaration (IS)","pos":[43918,43949]},{"content":"Vendor invoice declaration format for Iceland","pos":[43970,44015]},{"content":"Vendor invoice declaration report (IS)","pos":[44116,44154]},{"content":"Vendor invoice declaration report for Iceland","pos":[44168,44213]},{"pos":[44240,44248],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[44259,44372],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Localization requirements – Create an Electronic reporting configuration<ept id=\"p1\">](electronic-reporting-configuration.md)</ept>","source":"[Localization requirements – Create an Electronic reporting configuration](electronic-reporting-configuration.md)"},{"pos":[44374,44495],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle<ept id=\"p1\">](general-electronic-reporting-manage-configuration-lifecycle.md)</ept>","source":"[Manage the Electronic reporting configuration lifecycle](general-electronic-reporting-manage-configuration-lifecycle.md)"}]}