{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail \ndescription: This topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores. \nauthor: jashanno\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics-365-retail\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: margoc\nms.search.scope: Operations, UnifiedOperations, Retail\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 44351\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: jashanno\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-07-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Retail July 2017 update\n\n---\n\n# Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail\n\nThis topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX (previously **N-1**) in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores. Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX consists of two separate installers. One installer is for the Retail Async Server Connector service, and the other installer is for the Real-time service for AX 2012 R3. When the installation is completed, a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail environment will be used as the back-end infrastructure for currently installed and working stores that contain Enterprise POS and Retail Modern POS from AX 2012 R3. This topic also explains how to uninstall and troubleshoot these installations.\n\n## Before you begin\n\n> [!IMPORTANT]\n> To help maintain a high level of security across the company, we strongly recommend that you create a new client ID and secret for this installation. This step requires a new Web App.\n\n1. Generate a Microsoft Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret. For instructions, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in [Create an Azure Active Directory Application](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application).\n2. After you've created a client ID and secret for Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX, the client ID must be accepted in Retail. Go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Azure Active Directory applications**. Enter the client ID in the **Client ID** column, enter descriptive text in the **Name** column, and enter **RetailServiceAccount** in the **User ID** column.\n\n## Configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX\nTo configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX, complete the procedures in all sections of this topic through the \"Running the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers\" section.\n\n1. Use Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials to sign in to the Retail headquarters or Retail trial.\n2. On the **Welcome** page, use the menu in the upper left to go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Retail scheduler** &gt; **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX**.\n3. On the Action Pane, select **New**.\n4. In the **Profile** field, enter a unique value.\n5. Under **Real-Time Service location**, in the **Server** field, enter the server URL where the Real-time service for 2012 R3 will be installed.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > Use can either use the same location where the current Real-time service was originally installed, or you can specify a new location.\n\n6. In the **Port** field, enter the port that the new Real-time service for AX 2012 R3 should use.\n7. In the **Web application name** field, enter the web application name that should be used in Internet Information Services (IIS). By default, **RetailCDXRealTimeService** is selected.\n8. In the **Protocol** field, select the protocol that the original Real-time service currently uses.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > Although we recommend that you use HTTPS, **net.tcp** is listed for better support of previous installation scenarios. \n\n9. Under **Connection information**, in the **Common name** field, enter the friendly name of the certificate that the Real-time service for AX 2012 R3 should use. Together, this value and the value of the **Passphrase** field enable connections to the original Real-time service and the new Real-time service for AX 2012 R3.\n10. In the **Language** field, select the language that the associated stores should use.\n11. On the Action Pane, select **Save**.\n12. On the Action Pane, select **Retail scheduler parameters**. You can now enter the details for the Async Server Connector service.\n13. Under **HQ Message Database**, in the **SQL Server instance name** field, enter the instance name of the Microsoft SQL Server that should be used.\n14. In the **Server name** field, enter the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) of the computer where SQL Server is used.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > If the database will be on the same computer as the Async Server Connector service, enter **localhost**.\n\n15. On the **Database name** field, enter the name of the HQ Message Database.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > In AX 2012 R3, the default value was **HQMessageDB**.\n\n16. On the Action Pane, select **Save**.\n17. Go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Retail scheduler** &gt; **Channel data group**.\n18. Select the **Default** data group or the data group that is associated with the channels in your previous installation set (N-1 channels that used Enterprise POS and Modern POS from AX 2012 R3).\n19. On the Action Pane, select **Full data sync**. In the **Select a distribution schedule** field, select job **9999**, and then select **OK**. In the dialog box that appears, select **OK** to confirm the full synchronization. All the data in the channel database is prepared for download.\n\n### Download the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers\n\n1. Use Azure AD credentials to sign in to the Microsoft Dynamics Retail headquarters or Retail trial.\n2. On the **Welcome** page, use the menu in the upper left to go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Retail scheduler** &gt; **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX**.\n3. In the list of connectors on the left, select the connector that you created earlier for this installation.\n4. On the Action Pane, select **Download**.\n5. On the drop-down menu, under **Async Server Connector service**, select **Configuration file**.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > To help guarantee that the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers correctly use the configuration file (XML file), you must save the configuration file to the same location as the installers.\n\n6. On the Notification bar that appears at the bottom of the Internet Explorer window, select **Save**. (The Notification bar might appear in a different place in other browsers.)\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > Browsers might block the download pop-up that is generated. Select either **Allow once** or **Options for this site** &gt; **Always allow**. Then select **Download** again.\n\n7. On the Action Pane, select **Download**.\n8. On the drop-down menu, select **Async Server Connector service**.\n9. On the Notification bar that appears at the bottom of the Internet Explorer window, select **Save**. (The Notification bar might appear in a different place in other browsers.)\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > The correct installation package is automatically selected for download, based on the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX package on the selected channel database.\n\n10. After the setup installer has been saved, on the Notification bar, select **Run**. (This step might differ, depending on the type of browser.)\n11. Repeat steps 4 through 10 for **Real-time service for Dynamics AX 2012 R3**.\n\n### Running the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> Before you run the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers, make sure that the following requirements are met:\n> - The installer requires that the Microsoft .NET Framework version 4.5.1 be installed on the system.\n> - The installers install the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications only on the following operating systems. Before you install any component, you must update the operating system with all service packs and updates that are available for it.\n>     - Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, or Ultimate edition (both x86 and x64 architectures). Home edition and Embedded edition aren’t supported.\n>     - Windows 8.1 Update 1 Pro or Enterprise edition (both x86 and x64 architectures). Standard edition isn’t supported.\n>     - Windows 10 Pro or Enterprise edition (both x86 and x64 architectures). Home edition isn’t supported.\n>     - Windows Server 2012 R2 or Windows Server 2016.\n\nThe Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers first extract the associated files and then begin the installation.\n\n#### Async Server Connector service\n\n1. The installer validates that all prerequisites are met. These prerequisites include SQL prerequisites, such as a local installation of SQL Server, or the alternative prerequisites, such as SQL Command Line Utilities and other required SQL connectivity installations.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > - To meet prerequisites, the SQL Server that is connected to must have Full-text search and, at a minimum, support for Transport Layer Security (TLS) 1.2. For Microsoft SQL Server 2012, Service Pack 3 must be installed, at a minimum. For Microsoft SQL Server 2014, Service Pack 2 must be installed.\n    > - If a system restart is required, the installer shows this requirement. Although the restart is recommended, the installer can continue without it.\n\n2. Verify the Application Object Server (AOS) URL (the URL that is used to access Retail headquarters), and then select **Next**.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > This URL is automatically entered from the configuration file.\n\n3. Select a valid Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificate to use for HTTPS communication. Select **Next** to continue.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > The certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property. Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired. It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.\n\n4. If a specific user is required, enter the user name and password that the service should run as. By default, the installer automatically generates a service account to use. This approach is more secure and is recommended, but it can't be used when the database is located on a separate computer. Select **Next** to continue.\n5. Verify the HTTPS port that should be used, and verify that the host name of the computer is correct. Select **Next** to continue.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > - The HTTPS port is listed in the Store system profile. To access the Store system profile, on the **Retail store details** page, on the **Store systems** FastTab, select the profile ID of the selected Store system.\n    > - The installer automatically enters the host name. If, for any reason, the host name must be changed for the installation, change it here. The host name must be the FQDN of the system, and it must match the value that you entered on the **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX** page in the previous section of this topic.\n\n6. Enter the application ID (client ID) and secret that are associated with this Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installation. Additionally, verify the channel database ID, which is automatically entered from the configuration file. Then select **Install**.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > - For information about how to correctly generate an Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in [Create an Azure Active Directory Application](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application).\n    > - When you create the Web App, the initial URI and URL don't have to be any specific value. Only the application ID (client ID) and secret that are created are important.\n\n7. After the installation is completed, the final health page appears. This page shows whether the installation was successful. It also shows the health of each component, based on basic connection tests, and the location of this topic. If the installation wasn't successful, the page shows the location of the log files.\n8. After an application ID (client ID) and secret are created, the application ID must be accepted in Retail. Go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Azure Active Directory applications**. Enter the client ID in the **Client ID** column, enter descriptive text in the **Name** column, and enter **RetailServiceAccount** in the **User ID** column.\n9. Add the client ID to the **Retail shared parameters** page in Retail.\n\n    1. In Retail, go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Parameters** &gt; **Retail shared parameters**.\n    2. Select **Identity providers**.\n    3. On the **Identity providers** FastTab, select the provider that begins with **HTTPS://sts.windows.net/**. The values on the **Relying parties** FastTab are set, based on your selection.\n    4. On the **Relying parties** FastTab, select **+Add**. Enter the client ID that was created for this installation. Set the **Type** field to **Public** and the **UserType** field to **Worker**. Then, on the Action Pane, select **Save**.\n    5. On the Action Pane, select **Save**.\n\n10. When you've finished, return to the application installer, and select **Finish**.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > If the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud. Then check again. If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.\n\n#### Real-time service for AX 2012 R3\n\n1. The installer validates that all prerequisites are met.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > If a system restart is required, the installer shows this requirement. Although the restart is recommended, the installer can continue without it.\n\n2. Verify the AOS URL (the URL that is used to access Retail headquarters), and then select **Next**.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > This URL is automatically entered from the configuration file.\n\n3. Select a valid SSL certificate to use for HTTPS communication. Select **Next** to continue.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > The certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property. Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired. It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.\n\n4. If a specific user is required, enter the user name and password that the application pool should run as. By default, the installer automatically generates a service account to use. This approach is more secure and is recommended, but it can't be used when the database is located on a separate computer. Select **Next** to continue.\n5. Verify the HTTPS port that should be used, and verify that the host name of the computer is correct. Select **Next** to continue.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > - The HTTPS port is listed in the Store system profile. To access the Store system profile, on the **Retail store details** page, on the **Store systems** FastTab, select the profile ID of the selected Store system.\n    > - The installer automatically enters the host name. If, for any reason, the host name must be changed for the installation, change it here. The host name must be the FQDN of the system, and it must match the value that you entered on the **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX** page earlier in this topic.\n\n6. Enter the application ID (client ID) and secret that are associated with this Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installation. Then select **Install**.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > - This application ID and secret can be the same application ID and secret that you used in the Async Server Connector service installation. For information about how to correctly generate an Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in [Create an Azure Active Directory Application](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application).\n    > - When you create the Web App, the initial URI and URL don't have to be any specific value. Only the application ID (client ID) and secret that are created are important.\n\n7. After the installation is completed, the final health page appears. This page shows whether the installation was successful. It also shows the health of the component, based on basic connection tests, and the location of this topic. If the installation wasn't successful, the page shows the location of the log files.\n8. If the application ID and secret aren't the same as the application ID and secret that you used for the Async Server Connector service, the application ID must be accepted in Retail. Go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Azure Active Directory applications**. Enter the client ID in the **Client ID** column, enter descriptive text in the **Name** column, and enter **RetailServiceAccount** in the **User ID** column.\n9. If the application ID and secret aren't the same as the application ID and secret that you used for the Async Server Connector service, you must add the application ID (client ID) that was created for this installation to the **Retail shared parameters** page in Retail.\n\n    1. In Retail, go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Parameters** &gt; **Retail shared parameters**.\n    2. Select **Identity providers**.\n    3. On the **Identity providers** FastTab, select the provider that begins with **HTTPS://sts.windows.net/**. The values on the **Relying parties** FastTab are set, based on your selection.\n    4. On the **Relying parties** FastTab, select **+Add**. Enter the client ID that was created for this installation. Set the **Type** field to **Public** and the **UserType** field to **Worker**. Then, on the Action Pane, select **Save**.\n    5. On the Action Pane, select **Save**.\n\n10. When you've finished, return to the application installer, and select **Finish**.\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > If the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes, so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud. Then check again. If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.\n\n### Help secure the Connector for Dynamics AX applications\n\nAccording to current Payment Card Industry (PCI) security standards, the following options should be set in a production environment:\n\n- You should completely disable SSL (v2 and v3) on the computer.\n- You should enable and use only TLS version 1.2 (or the current highest version).\n\n    > [!NOTE]\n    > - By default, the installers don't change these settings. (In this respect, these installers differ from other Self-service installers). To edit or enable these settings, follow these steps:\n    >     1. Press the Windows logo key+R to open a **Run** window.\n    >     2. In the **Open** field, enter **Regedit**, and then select **OK**.\n    >     3. In the **User Account Control** window, select **Yes** (if this step is required), and then, in the new **Registry Editor** window, go to **HKEY\\_LOCAL\\_MACHINE\\\\System\\\\CurrentControlSet\\\\SecurityProviders\\\\SCHANNEL\\\\Protocols**.\n    >         The following keys have been automatically entered to enabled only TLS 1.2:\n    >         - TLS 1.2\\\\Server:Enabled=1\n    >         - TLS 1.2\\\\Server:DisabledByDefault=0\n    >         - TLS 1.2\\\\Client:Enabled=1\n    >         - TLS 1.2\\\\Client:DisabledByDefault=0\n    >         - TLS 1.1\\\\Server:Enabled=0\n    >         - TLS 1.1\\\\Client:Enabled=0\n    >         - TLS 1.0\\\\Server:Enabled=0\n    >         - TLS 1.0\\\\Client:Enabled=0\n    >         - SSL 3.0\\\\Server:Enabled=0\n    >         - SSL 3.0\\\\Client:Enabled=0\n    >         - SSL 2.0\\\\Server:Enabled=0\n    >         - SSL 2.0\\\\Client:Enabled=0\n    > - This configuration will have a major impact on communication between AX 2012 R3 stores (Enterprise POS and Modern POS) and the headquarters components that are installed in this topic. Therefore, you should carefully review how communication currently works.\n\n- No additional network ports should be open, unless they are required for known, specified reasons.\n- You must disable cross-origin resource sharing, and you must specify the allowed origins that are accepted.\n- You should use only trusted certificate authorities to obtain certificates that will be used on computers where the applications are installed.\n\n> [!IMPORTANT]\n> It's critical that you review security guidelines for IIS and PCI requirements.\n\n### Troubleshoot the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications\n\nThis section will be more thorough in the future. For now, here is a checklist of things to verify:\n\n1. In Retail, on the **Retail shared parameters** page, verify that the correct client ID has been added on the **Relying Parties** FastTab. \n2. In Retail, verify that every client ID that was created exists on the **Azure Active Directory applications** page.\n\n### Uninstall the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications\n\nUse Control Panel in Microsoft Windows to uninstall Retail Store system.\n\n1. Press the Windows logo key, and then enter **Control Panel** in the search box. In the search results, select **Control Panel**.\n2. In Control Panel, select **Programs** &gt; **Uninstall a program**.\n3. In the **Programs and Features** window, select **Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail Store system**, and then, above the list of programs, select **Uninstall**.\n4. Wait for the uninstaller to finish removing the program.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,901],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail \ndescription: This topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores. \nauthor: jashanno\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: Dynamics-365-retail\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: margoc\nms.search.scope: Operations, UnifiedOperations, Retail\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 44351\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: jashanno\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-07-31\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Retail July 2017 update\n","nodes":[{"content":"Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"pos":[0,69],"content":"Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"content":"Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","pos":[0,69]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,314],"content":"This topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores.","pos":[0,314]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[909,978],"content":"Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","linkify":"Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"content":"Install N-1 components for use with Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","pos":[0,69]}]},{"content":"This topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX (previously <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>N-1<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>) in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores.","pos":[980,1315],"source":"This topic explains how you can use self-service to configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX (previously **N-1**) in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail headquarters, download it, and install it on the domain computers of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 R3 environment, so that it can be used by previously deployed and running stores."},{"content":"Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX consists of two separate installers.","pos":[1316,1388]},{"content":"One installer is for the Retail Async Server Connector service, and the other installer is for the Real-time service for AX 2012 R3.","pos":[1389,1521]},{"content":"When the installation is completed, a Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail environment will be used as the back-end infrastructure for currently installed and working stores that contain Enterprise POS and Retail Modern POS from AX 2012 R3.","pos":[1522,1759]},{"content":"This topic also explains how to uninstall and troubleshoot these installations.","pos":[1760,1839]},{"pos":[1844,1860],"content":"Before you begin","linkify":"Before you begin","nodes":[{"content":"Before you begin","pos":[0,16]}]},{"pos":[1864,2062],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\nTo help maintain a high level of security across the company, we strongly recommend that you create a new client ID and secret for this installation. This step requires a new Web App.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"To help maintain a high level of security across the company, we strongly recommend that you create a new client ID and secret for this installation. This step requires a new Web App.","pos":[13,196],"nodes":[{"content":"To help maintain a high level of security across the company, we strongly recommend that you create a new client ID and secret for this installation.","pos":[0,149]},{"content":"This step requires a new Web App.","pos":[150,183]}]}]},{"content":"Generate a Microsoft Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret.","pos":[2067,2135]},{"content":"For instructions, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create an Azure Active Directory Application<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application)</ept>.","pos":[2136,2426],"source":" For instructions, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in [Create an Azure Active Directory Application](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application)."},{"content":"After you've created a client ID and secret for Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX, the client ID must be accepted in Retail.","pos":[2430,2556]},{"content":"Go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System administration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Azure Active Directory applications<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[2557,2649],"source":" Go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Azure Active Directory applications**."},{"content":"Enter the client ID in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Client ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column, enter descriptive text in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> column, and enter <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>RetailServiceAccount<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>User ID<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> column.","pos":[2650,2807],"source":" Enter the client ID in the **Client ID** column, enter descriptive text in the **Name** column, and enter **RetailServiceAccount** in the **User ID** column."},{"pos":[2812,2857],"content":"Configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX","linkify":"Configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX","nodes":[{"content":"Configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX","pos":[0,45]}]},{"content":"To configure Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX, complete the procedures in all sections of this topic through the \"Running the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers\" section.","pos":[2858,3043]},{"content":"Use Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) credentials to sign in to the Retail headquarters or Retail trial.","pos":[3048,3152]},{"pos":[3156,3331],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Welcome<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, use the menu in the upper left to go to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Headquarters setup<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Retail scheduler<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Welcome** page, use the menu in the upper left to go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Retail scheduler** &gt; **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX**."},{"pos":[3335,3370],"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, select **New**."},{"pos":[3374,3421],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Profile<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter a unique value.","source":"In the **Profile** field, enter a unique value."},{"pos":[3425,3567],"content":"Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Real-Time Service location<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Server<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field, enter the server URL where the Real-time service for 2012 R3 will be installed.","source":"Under **Real-Time Service location**, in the **Server** field, enter the server URL where the Real-time service for 2012 R3 will be installed."},{"pos":[3575,3722],"content":"[!NOTE]\nUse can either use the same location where the current Real-time service was originally installed, or you can specify a new location.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"Use can either use the same location where the current Real-time service was originally installed, or you can specify a new location.","pos":[8,141]}]},{"pos":[3727,3822],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Port<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter the port that the new Real-time service for AX 2012 R3 should use.","source":"In the **Port** field, enter the port that the new Real-time service for AX 2012 R3 should use."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Web application name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter the web application name that should be used in Internet Information Services (IIS).","pos":[3826,3955],"source":"In the **Web application name** field, enter the web application name that should be used in Internet Information Services (IIS)."},{"content":"By default, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>RetailCDXRealTimeService<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is selected.","pos":[3956,4009],"source":" By default, **RetailCDXRealTimeService** is selected."},{"pos":[4013,4111],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Protocol<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select the protocol that the original Real-time service currently uses.","source":"In the **Protocol** field, select the protocol that the original Real-time service currently uses."},{"pos":[4119,4251],"content":"[!NOTE]\nAlthough we recommend that you use HTTPS, **net.tcp** is listed for better support of previous installation scenarios.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"Although we recommend that you use HTTPS, <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>net.tcp<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is listed for better support of previous installation scenarios.","pos":[8,126],"source":"Although we recommend that you use HTTPS, **net.tcp** is listed for better support of previous installation scenarios."}]},{"content":"Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connection information<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Common name<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field, enter the friendly name of the certificate that the Real-time service for AX 2012 R3 should use.","pos":[4257,4417],"source":"Under **Connection information**, in the **Common name** field, enter the friendly name of the certificate that the Real-time service for AX 2012 R3 should use."},{"content":"Together, this value and the value of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Passphrase<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field enable connections to the original Real-time service and the new Real-time service for AX 2012 R3.","pos":[4418,4579],"source":" Together, this value and the value of the **Passphrase** field enable connections to the original Real-time service and the new Real-time service for AX 2012 R3."},{"pos":[4584,4669],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Language<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select the language that the associated stores should use.","source":"In the **Language** field, select the language that the associated stores should use."},{"pos":[4674,4710],"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, select **Save**."},{"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail scheduler parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4715,4774],"source":"On the Action Pane, select **Retail scheduler parameters**."},{"content":"You can now enter the details for the Async Server Connector service.","pos":[4775,4844]},{"pos":[4849,4995],"content":"Under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>HQ Message Database<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>SQL Server instance name<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field, enter the instance name of the Microsoft SQL Server that should be used.","source":"Under **HQ Message Database**, in the **SQL Server instance name** field, enter the instance name of the Microsoft SQL Server that should be used."},{"pos":[5000,5116],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Server name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) of the computer where SQL Server is used.","source":"In the **Server name** field, enter the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) of the computer where SQL Server is used."},{"pos":[5124,5242],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf the database will be on the same computer as the Async Server Connector service, enter **localhost**.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"If the database will be on the same computer as the Async Server Connector service, enter <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>localhost<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[8,112],"source":"If the database will be on the same computer as the Async Server Connector service, enter **localhost**."}]},{"pos":[5248,5322],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Database name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter the name of the HQ Message Database.","source":"On the **Database name** field, enter the name of the HQ Message Database."},{"pos":[5330,5397],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIn AX 2012 R3, the default value was **HQMessageDB**.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"In AX 2012 R3, the default value was <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>HQMessageDB<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[8,61],"source":"In AX 2012 R3, the default value was **HQMessageDB**."}]},{"pos":[5403,5439],"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, select **Save**."},{"pos":[5444,5543],"content":"Go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Headquarters setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Retail scheduler<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Channel data group<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","source":"Go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Retail scheduler** &gt; **Channel data group**."},{"pos":[5548,5742],"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Default<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> data group or the data group that is associated with the channels in your previous installation set (N-1 channels that used Enterprise POS and Modern POS from AX 2012 R3).","source":"Select the **Default** data group or the data group that is associated with the channels in your previous installation set (N-1 channels that used Enterprise POS and Modern POS from AX 2012 R3)."},{"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Full data sync<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[5747,5793],"source":"On the Action Pane, select **Full data sync**."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select a distribution schedule<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select job <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>9999<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then select <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[5794,5887],"source":" In the **Select a distribution schedule** field, select job **9999**, and then select **OK**."},{"content":"In the dialog box that appears, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to confirm the full synchronization.","pos":[5888,5970],"source":" In the dialog box that appears, select **OK** to confirm the full synchronization."},{"content":"All the data in the channel database is prepared for download.","pos":[5971,6033]},{"pos":[6039,6098],"content":"Download the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers","linkify":"Download the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers","nodes":[{"content":"Download the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers","pos":[0,59]}]},{"content":"Use Azure AD credentials to sign in to the Microsoft Dynamics Retail headquarters or Retail trial.","pos":[6103,6201]},{"pos":[6205,6380],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Welcome<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, use the menu in the upper left to go to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Headquarters setup<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Retail scheduler<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p5\">**</bpt>Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX<ept id=\"p5\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Welcome** page, use the menu in the upper left to go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Retail scheduler** &gt; **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX**."},{"content":"In the list of connectors on the left, select the connector that you created earlier for this installation.","pos":[6384,6491]},{"pos":[6495,6535],"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, select **Download**."},{"pos":[6539,6634],"content":"On the drop-down menu, under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Async Server Connector service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Configuration file<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"On the drop-down menu, under **Async Server Connector service**, select **Configuration file**."},{"pos":[6642,6855],"content":"[!NOTE]\nTo help guarantee that the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers correctly use the configuration file (XML file), you must save the configuration file to the same location as the installers.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"To help guarantee that the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers correctly use the configuration file (XML file), you must save the configuration file to the same location as the installers.","pos":[8,207]}]},{"content":"On the Notification bar that appears at the bottom of the Internet Explorer window, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[6860,6960],"source":"On the Notification bar that appears at the bottom of the Internet Explorer window, select **Save**."},{"content":"(The Notification bar might appear in a different place in other browsers.)","pos":[6961,7036]},{"pos":[7044,7230],"content":"[!NOTE]\nBrowsers might block the download pop-up that is generated. Select either **Allow once** or **Options for this site** &gt; **Always allow**. Then select **Download** again.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"Browsers might block the download pop-up that is generated. Select either **Allow once** or **Options for this site** &gt; **Always allow**. Then select **Download** again.","pos":[8,180],"nodes":[{"content":"Browsers might block the download pop-up that is generated.","pos":[0,59]},{"content":"Select either <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Allow once<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Options for this site<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Always allow<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[60,140],"source":" Select either **Allow once** or **Options for this site** &gt; **Always allow**."},{"content":"Then select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> again.","pos":[141,172],"source":" Then select **Download** again."}]}]},{"pos":[7235,7275],"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, select **Download**."},{"pos":[7279,7344],"content":"On the drop-down menu, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Async Server Connector service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the drop-down menu, select **Async Server Connector service**."},{"content":"On the Notification bar that appears at the bottom of the Internet Explorer window, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[7348,7448],"source":"On the Notification bar that appears at the bottom of the Internet Explorer window, select **Save**."},{"content":"(The Notification bar might appear in a different place in other browsers.)","pos":[7449,7524]},{"pos":[7532,7709],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThe correct installation package is automatically selected for download, based on the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX package on the selected channel database.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"The correct installation package is automatically selected for download, based on the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX package on the selected channel database.","pos":[8,171]}]},{"content":"After the setup installer has been saved, on the Notification bar, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[7715,7797],"source":"After the setup installer has been saved, on the Notification bar, select **Run**."},{"content":"(This step might differ, depending on the type of browser.)","pos":[7798,7857]},{"pos":[7862,7938],"content":"Repeat steps 4 through 10 for <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Real-time service for Dynamics AX 2012 R3<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Repeat steps 4 through 10 for **Real-time service for Dynamics AX 2012 R3**."},{"pos":[7944,8002],"content":"Running the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers","linkify":"Running the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers","nodes":[{"content":"Running the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers","pos":[0,58]}]},{"pos":[8006,8133],"content":"[!NOTE]\nBefore you run the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers, make sure that the following requirements are met:","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Before you run the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers, make sure that the following requirements are met:","pos":[8,125]}]},{"content":"The installer requires that the Microsoft .NET Framework version 4.5.1 be installed on the system.","pos":[8138,8236]},{"content":"The installers install the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications only on the following operating systems.","pos":[8241,8357]},{"content":"Before you install any component, you must update the operating system with all service packs and updates that are available for it.","pos":[8358,8490]},{"content":"Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, or Ultimate edition (both x86 and x64 architectures).","pos":[8499,8588]},{"content":"Home edition and Embedded edition aren’t supported.","pos":[8589,8640]},{"content":"Windows 8.1 Update 1 Pro or Enterprise edition (both x86 and x64 architectures).","pos":[8649,8729]},{"content":"Standard edition isn’t supported.","pos":[8730,8763]},{"content":"Windows 10 Pro or Enterprise edition (both x86 and x64 architectures).","pos":[8772,8842]},{"content":"Home edition isn’t supported.","pos":[8843,8872]},{"content":"Windows Server 2012 R2 or Windows Server 2016.","pos":[8881,8927]},{"content":"The Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installers first extract the associated files and then begin the installation.","pos":[8929,9047]},{"pos":[9054,9084],"content":"Async Server Connector service","linkify":"Async Server Connector service","nodes":[{"content":"Async Server Connector service","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"The installer validates that all prerequisites are met.","pos":[9089,9144]},{"content":"These prerequisites include SQL prerequisites, such as a local installation of SQL Server, or the alternative prerequisites, such as SQL Command Line Utilities and other required SQL connectivity installations.","pos":[9145,9355]},{"content":"To meet prerequisites, the SQL Server that is connected to must have Full-text search and, at a minimum, support for Transport Layer Security (TLS) 1.2.","pos":[9379,9531]},{"content":"For Microsoft SQL Server 2012, Service Pack 3 must be installed, at a minimum.","pos":[9532,9610]},{"content":"For Microsoft SQL Server 2014, Service Pack 2 must be installed.","pos":[9611,9675]},{"content":"If a system restart is required, the installer shows this requirement.","pos":[9684,9754]},{"content":"Although the restart is recommended, the installer can continue without it.","pos":[9755,9830]},{"pos":[9835,9961],"content":"Verify the Application Object Server (AOS) URL (the URL that is used to access Retail headquarters), and then select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Verify the Application Object Server (AOS) URL (the URL that is used to access Retail headquarters), and then select **Next**."},{"pos":[9969,10045],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThis URL is automatically entered from the configuration file.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"This URL is automatically entered from the configuration file.","pos":[8,70]}]},{"content":"Select a valid Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) certificate to use for HTTPS communication.","pos":[10050,10135]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue.","pos":[10136,10164],"source":" Select **Next** to continue."},{"pos":[10172,10472],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThe certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property. Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired. It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"The certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property. Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired. It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.","pos":[8,294],"nodes":[{"content":"The certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property.","pos":[0,122]},{"content":"Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired.","pos":[123,202]},{"content":"It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.","pos":[203,286]}]}]},{"content":"If a specific user is required, enter the user name and password that the service should run as.","pos":[10477,10573]},{"content":"By default, the installer automatically generates a service account to use.","pos":[10574,10649]},{"content":"This approach is more secure and is recommended, but it can't be used when the database is located on a separate computer.","pos":[10650,10772]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue.","pos":[10773,10801],"source":" Select **Next** to continue."},{"content":"Verify the HTTPS port that should be used, and verify that the host name of the computer is correct.","pos":[10805,10905]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue.","pos":[10906,10934],"source":" Select **Next** to continue."},{"content":"The HTTPS port is listed in the Store system profile.","pos":[10958,11011]},{"content":"To access the Store system profile, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail store details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Store systems<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> FastTab, select the profile ID of the selected Store system.","pos":[11012,11171],"source":" To access the Store system profile, on the **Retail store details** page, on the **Store systems** FastTab, select the profile ID of the selected Store system."},{"content":"The installer automatically enters the host name.","pos":[11180,11229]},{"content":"If, for any reason, the host name must be changed for the installation, change it here.","pos":[11230,11317]},{"content":"The host name must be the FQDN of the system, and it must match the value that you entered on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in the previous section of this topic.","pos":[11318,11499],"source":" The host name must be the FQDN of the system, and it must match the value that you entered on the **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX** page in the previous section of this topic."},{"content":"Enter the application ID (client ID) and secret that are associated with this Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installation.","pos":[11504,11631]},{"content":"Additionally, verify the channel database ID, which is automatically entered from the configuration file.","pos":[11632,11737]},{"content":"Then select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[11738,11762],"source":" Then select **Install**."},{"pos":[11786,12157],"content":"For information about how to correctly generate an Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create an Azure Active Directory Application<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application)</ept>.","source":"For information about how to correctly generate an Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in [Create an Azure Active Directory Application](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application)."},{"content":"When you create the Web App, the initial URI and URL don't have to be any specific value.","pos":[12166,12255]},{"content":"Only the application ID (client ID) and secret that are created are important.","pos":[12256,12334]},{"content":"After the installation is completed, the final health page appears.","pos":[12339,12406]},{"content":"This page shows whether the installation was successful.","pos":[12407,12463]},{"content":"It also shows the health of each component, based on basic connection tests, and the location of this topic.","pos":[12464,12572]},{"content":"If the installation wasn't successful, the page shows the location of the log files.","pos":[12573,12657]},{"content":"After an application ID (client ID) and secret are created, the application ID must be accepted in Retail.","pos":[12661,12767]},{"content":"Go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System administration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Azure Active Directory applications<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[12768,12860],"source":" Go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Azure Active Directory applications**."},{"content":"Enter the client ID in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Client ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column, enter descriptive text in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> column, and enter <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>RetailServiceAccount<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>User ID<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> column.","pos":[12861,13018],"source":" Enter the client ID in the **Client ID** column, enter descriptive text in the **Name** column, and enter **RetailServiceAccount** in the **User ID** column."},{"pos":[13022,13091],"content":"Add the client ID to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail shared parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in Retail.","source":"Add the client ID to the **Retail shared parameters** page in Retail."},{"pos":[13100,13210],"content":"In Retail, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Headquarters setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Retail shared parameters<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","source":"In Retail, go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Parameters** &gt; **Retail shared parameters**."},{"pos":[13218,13248],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity providers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Select **Identity providers**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity providers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, select the provider that begins with <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>HTTPS://sts.windows.net/<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[13256,13361],"source":"On the **Identity providers** FastTab, select the provider that begins with **HTTPS://sts.windows.net/**."},{"content":"The values on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Relying parties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab are set, based on your selection.","pos":[13362,13441],"source":" The values on the **Relying parties** FastTab are set, based on your selection."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Relying parties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>+Add<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[13449,13501],"source":"On the **Relying parties** FastTab, select **+Add**."},{"content":"Enter the client ID that was created for this installation.","pos":[13502,13561]},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Public<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>UserType<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> field to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Worker<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[13562,13640],"source":" Set the **Type** field to **Public** and the **UserType** field to **Worker**."},{"content":"Then, on the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[13641,13683],"source":" Then, on the Action Pane, select **Save**."},{"pos":[13691,13727],"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, select **Save**."},{"pos":[13733,13814],"content":"When you've finished, return to the application installer, and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Finish<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"When you've finished, return to the application installer, and select **Finish**."},{"pos":[13822,14118],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud. Then check again. If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"If the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud. Then check again. If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.","pos":[8,290],"nodes":[{"content":"If the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud.","pos":[0,132]},{"content":"Then check again.","pos":[133,150]},{"content":"If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.","pos":[151,282]}]}]},{"pos":[14125,14157],"content":"Real-time service for AX 2012 R3","linkify":"Real-time service for AX 2012 R3","nodes":[{"content":"Real-time service for AX 2012 R3","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"The installer validates that all prerequisites are met.","pos":[14162,14217]},{"pos":[14225,14385],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf a system restart is required, the installer shows this requirement. Although the restart is recommended, the installer can continue without it.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"If a system restart is required, the installer shows this requirement. Although the restart is recommended, the installer can continue without it.","pos":[8,154],"nodes":[{"content":"If a system restart is required, the installer shows this requirement.","pos":[0,70]},{"content":"Although the restart is recommended, the installer can continue without it.","pos":[71,146]}]}]},{"pos":[14390,14488],"content":"Verify the AOS URL (the URL that is used to access Retail headquarters), and then select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Verify the AOS URL (the URL that is used to access Retail headquarters), and then select **Next**."},{"pos":[14496,14572],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThis URL is automatically entered from the configuration file.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"This URL is automatically entered from the configuration file.","pos":[8,70]}]},{"content":"Select a valid SSL certificate to use for HTTPS communication.","pos":[14577,14639]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue.","pos":[14640,14668],"source":" Select **Next** to continue."},{"pos":[14676,14976],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThe certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property. Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired. It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"The certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property. Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired. It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.","pos":[8,294],"nodes":[{"content":"The certificate must use private key storage, and server authentication must be listed in the enhanced key usage property.","pos":[0,122]},{"content":"Additionally, the certificate must be trusted locally, and it can’t be expired.","pos":[123,202]},{"content":"It must be stored in the personal certificate store location on the local computer.","pos":[203,286]}]}]},{"content":"If a specific user is required, enter the user name and password that the application pool should run as.","pos":[14981,15086]},{"content":"By default, the installer automatically generates a service account to use.","pos":[15087,15162]},{"content":"This approach is more secure and is recommended, but it can't be used when the database is located on a separate computer.","pos":[15163,15285]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue.","pos":[15286,15314],"source":" Select **Next** to continue."},{"content":"Verify the HTTPS port that should be used, and verify that the host name of the computer is correct.","pos":[15318,15418]},{"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Next<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to continue.","pos":[15419,15447],"source":" Select **Next** to continue."},{"content":"The HTTPS port is listed in the Store system profile.","pos":[15471,15524]},{"content":"To access the Store system profile, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail store details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Store systems<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> FastTab, select the profile ID of the selected Store system.","pos":[15525,15684],"source":" To access the Store system profile, on the **Retail store details** page, on the **Store systems** FastTab, select the profile ID of the selected Store system."},{"content":"The installer automatically enters the host name.","pos":[15693,15742]},{"content":"If, for any reason, the host name must be changed for the installation, change it here.","pos":[15743,15830]},{"content":"The host name must be the FQDN of the system, and it must match the value that you entered on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page earlier in this topic.","pos":[15831,15996],"source":" The host name must be the FQDN of the system, and it must match the value that you entered on the **Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX** page earlier in this topic."},{"content":"Enter the application ID (client ID) and secret that are associated with this Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX installation.","pos":[16001,16128]},{"content":"Then select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Install<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[16129,16153],"source":" Then select **Install**."},{"content":"This application ID and secret can be the same application ID and secret that you used in the Async Server Connector service installation.","pos":[16177,16315]},{"content":"For information about how to correctly generate an Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create an Azure Active Directory Application<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application)</ept>.","pos":[16316,16687],"source":" For information about how to correctly generate an Azure Web App to create a client ID and secret, see the \"Basics of Registering an Application in Azure AD\" section in [Create an Azure Active Directory Application](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-create-service-principal-portal#create-an-azure-active-directory-application)."},{"content":"When you create the Web App, the initial URI and URL don't have to be any specific value.","pos":[16696,16785]},{"content":"Only the application ID (client ID) and secret that are created are important.","pos":[16786,16864]},{"content":"After the installation is completed, the final health page appears.","pos":[16869,16936]},{"content":"This page shows whether the installation was successful.","pos":[16937,16993]},{"content":"It also shows the health of the component, based on basic connection tests, and the location of this topic.","pos":[16994,17101]},{"content":"If the installation wasn't successful, the page shows the location of the log files.","pos":[17102,17186]},{"content":"If the application ID and secret aren't the same as the application ID and secret that you used for the Async Server Connector service, the application ID must be accepted in Retail.","pos":[17190,17372]},{"content":"Go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System administration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Azure Active Directory applications<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[17373,17465],"source":" Go to **System administration** &gt; **Setup** &gt; **Azure Active Directory applications**."},{"content":"Enter the client ID in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Client ID<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column, enter descriptive text in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> column, and enter <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>RetailServiceAccount<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>User ID<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> column.","pos":[17466,17623],"source":" Enter the client ID in the **Client ID** column, enter descriptive text in the **Name** column, and enter **RetailServiceAccount** in the **User ID** column."},{"pos":[17627,17897],"content":"If the application ID and secret aren't the same as the application ID and secret that you used for the Async Server Connector service, you must add the application ID (client ID) that was created for this installation to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail shared parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in Retail.","source":"If the application ID and secret aren't the same as the application ID and secret that you used for the Async Server Connector service, you must add the application ID (client ID) that was created for this installation to the **Retail shared parameters** page in Retail."},{"pos":[17906,18016],"content":"In Retail, go to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Headquarters setup<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Parameters<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph3\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Retail shared parameters<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","source":"In Retail, go to **Retail** &gt; **Headquarters setup** &gt; **Parameters** &gt; **Retail shared parameters**."},{"pos":[18024,18054],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity providers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Select **Identity providers**."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Identity providers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, select the provider that begins with <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>HTTPS://sts.windows.net/<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[18062,18167],"source":"On the **Identity providers** FastTab, select the provider that begins with **HTTPS://sts.windows.net/**."},{"content":"The values on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Relying parties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab are set, based on your selection.","pos":[18168,18247],"source":" The values on the **Relying parties** FastTab are set, based on your selection."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Relying parties<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> FastTab, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>+Add<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[18255,18307],"source":"On the **Relying parties** FastTab, select **+Add**."},{"content":"Enter the client ID that was created for this installation.","pos":[18308,18367]},{"content":"Set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Public<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>UserType<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> field to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Worker<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[18368,18446],"source":" Set the **Type** field to **Public** and the **UserType** field to **Worker**."},{"content":"Then, on the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[18447,18489],"source":" Then, on the Action Pane, select **Save**."},{"pos":[18497,18533],"content":"On the Action Pane, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, select **Save**."},{"pos":[18539,18620],"content":"When you've finished, return to the application installer, and select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Finish<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"When you've finished, return to the application installer, and select **Finish**."},{"pos":[18628,18925],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes, so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud. Then check again. If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"If the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes, so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud. Then check again. If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.","pos":[8,291],"nodes":[{"content":"If the installer doesn't show a check mark for the component, wait 10 minutes, so that any cached values can be updated in the cloud.","pos":[0,133]},{"content":"Then check again.","pos":[134,151]},{"content":"If the installer still isn't fully successful, run a full synchronization on the distribution schedule that this installation uses.","pos":[152,283]}]}]},{"pos":[18931,18985],"content":"Help secure the Connector for Dynamics AX applications","linkify":"Help secure the Connector for Dynamics AX applications","nodes":[{"content":"Help secure the Connector for Dynamics AX applications","pos":[0,54]}]},{"content":"According to current Payment Card Industry (PCI) security standards, the following options should be set in a production environment:","pos":[18987,19120]},{"content":"You should completely disable SSL (v2 and v3) on the computer.","pos":[19124,19186]},{"content":"You should enable and use only TLS version 1.2 (or the current highest version).","pos":[19189,19269]},{"content":"By default, the installers don't change these settings.","pos":[19293,19348]},{"content":"(In this respect, these installers differ from other Self-service installers).","pos":[19349,19427]},{"content":"To edit or enable these settings, follow these steps:","pos":[19428,19481]},{"pos":[19495,19549],"content":"Press the Windows logo key+R to open a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window.","source":"Press the Windows logo key+R to open a **Run** window."},{"pos":[19563,19628],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Regedit<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then select <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"In the **Open** field, enter **Regedit**, and then select **OK**."},{"pos":[19642,19962],"content":"In the **User Account Control** window, select **Yes** (if this step is required), and then, in the new **Registry Editor** window, go to **HKEY\\_LOCAL\\_MACHINE\\\\System\\\\CurrentControlSet\\\\SecurityProviders\\\\SCHANNEL\\\\Protocols**.\n The following keys have been automatically entered to enabled only TLS 1.2:","leadings":["","    >        "],"nodes":[{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>User Account Control<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> (if this step is required), and then, in the new <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Registry Editor<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> window, go to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>HKEY<ph id=\"ph1\">\\_</ph>LOCAL<ph id=\"ph2\">\\_</ph>MACHINE<ph id=\"ph3\">\\\\</ph>System<ph id=\"ph4\">\\\\</ph>CurrentControlSet<ph id=\"ph5\">\\\\</ph>SecurityProviders<ph id=\"ph6\">\\\\</ph>SCHANNEL<ph id=\"ph7\">\\\\</ph>Protocols<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[0,230],"source":"In the **User Account Control** window, select **Yes** (if this step is required), and then, in the new **Registry Editor** window, go to **HKEY\\_LOCAL\\_MACHINE\\\\System\\\\CurrentControlSet\\\\SecurityProviders\\\\SCHANNEL\\\\Protocols**."},{"content":"The following keys have been automatically entered to enabled only TLS 1.2:","pos":[232,307]}]},{"content":"TLS 1.2<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Server:Enabled=1","pos":[19979,20004],"source":"TLS 1.2\\\\Server:Enabled=1"},{"content":"TLS 1.2<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Server:DisabledByDefault=0","pos":[20021,20056],"source":"TLS 1.2\\\\Server:DisabledByDefault=0"},{"content":"TLS 1.2<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Client:Enabled=1","pos":[20073,20098],"source":"TLS 1.2\\\\Client:Enabled=1"},{"content":"TLS 1.2<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Client:DisabledByDefault=0","pos":[20115,20150],"source":"TLS 1.2\\\\Client:DisabledByDefault=0"},{"content":"TLS 1.1<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Server:Enabled=0","pos":[20167,20192],"source":"TLS 1.1\\\\Server:Enabled=0"},{"content":"TLS 1.1<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Client:Enabled=0","pos":[20209,20234],"source":"TLS 1.1\\\\Client:Enabled=0"},{"content":"TLS 1.0<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Server:Enabled=0","pos":[20251,20276],"source":"TLS 1.0\\\\Server:Enabled=0"},{"content":"TLS 1.0<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Client:Enabled=0","pos":[20293,20318],"source":"TLS 1.0\\\\Client:Enabled=0"},{"content":"SSL 3.0<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Server:Enabled=0","pos":[20335,20360],"source":"SSL 3.0\\\\Server:Enabled=0"},{"content":"SSL 3.0<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Client:Enabled=0","pos":[20377,20402],"source":"SSL 3.0\\\\Client:Enabled=0"},{"content":"SSL 2.0<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Server:Enabled=0","pos":[20419,20444],"source":"SSL 2.0\\\\Server:Enabled=0"},{"content":"SSL 2.0<ph id=\"ph1\">\\\\</ph>Client:Enabled=0","pos":[20461,20486],"source":"SSL 2.0\\\\Client:Enabled=0"},{"content":"This configuration will have a major impact on communication between AX 2012 R3 stores (Enterprise POS and Modern POS) and the headquarters components that are installed in this topic.","pos":[20495,20679]},{"content":"Therefore, you should carefully review how communication currently works.","pos":[20680,20753]},{"content":"No additional network ports should be open, unless they are required for known, specified reasons.","pos":[20757,20855]},{"content":"You must disable cross-origin resource sharing, and you must specify the allowed origins that are accepted.","pos":[20858,20965]},{"content":"You should use only trusted certificate authorities to obtain certificates that will be used on computers where the applications are installed.","pos":[20968,21111]},{"pos":[21115,21209],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\nIt's critical that you review security guidelines for IIS and PCI requirements.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"It's critical that you review security guidelines for IIS and PCI requirements.","pos":[13,92]}]},{"pos":[21215,21280],"content":"Troubleshoot the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications","linkify":"Troubleshoot the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications","nodes":[{"content":"Troubleshoot the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications","pos":[0,65]}]},{"content":"This section will be more thorough in the future.","pos":[21282,21331]},{"content":"For now, here is a checklist of things to verify:","pos":[21332,21381]},{"pos":[21386,21523],"content":"In Retail, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Retail shared parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, verify that the correct client ID has been added on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Relying Parties<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> FastTab.","source":"In Retail, on the **Retail shared parameters** page, verify that the correct client ID has been added on the **Relying Parties** FastTab."},{"pos":[21528,21643],"content":"In Retail, verify that every client ID that was created exists on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Azure Active Directory applications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","source":"In Retail, verify that every client ID that was created exists on the **Azure Active Directory applications** page."},{"pos":[21649,21711],"content":"Uninstall the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications","linkify":"Uninstall the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications","nodes":[{"content":"Uninstall the Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX applications","pos":[0,62]}]},{"content":"Use Control Panel in Microsoft Windows to uninstall Retail Store system.","pos":[21713,21785]},{"content":"Press the Windows logo key, and then enter <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Control Panel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the search box.","pos":[21790,21869],"source":"Press the Windows logo key, and then enter **Control Panel** in the search box."},{"content":"In the search results, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Control Panel<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[21870,21918],"source":" In the search results, select **Control Panel**."},{"pos":[21922,21989],"content":"In Control Panel, select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Programs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Uninstall a program<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"In Control Panel, select **Programs** &gt; **Uninstall a program**."},{"pos":[21993,22152],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Programs and Features<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> window, select <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail Store system<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and then, above the list of programs, select <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Uninstall<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"In the **Programs and Features** window, select **Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail Store system**, and then, above the list of programs, select **Uninstall**."},{"content":"Wait for the uninstaller to finish removing the program.","pos":[22156,22212]}]}