{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Power BI Embedded integration\ndescription: Power BI content that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application. This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Power BI Embedded integration.\nauthor: TJVass\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 07/26/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 270754\nms.assetid: ca4b2ccf-d68d-4344-833e-1c45d966246c\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tjvass\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 4\n\n---\n\n# Power BI Embedded integration\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\nMicrosoft Power BI content that partners and independent software vendors (ISVs) developed can be embedded directly into the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Microsoft Power BI Embedded integration.\n\n## Overview\nThe integration of Finance and Operations and [Power BI](http://www.powerbi.com/) enables data mash-up scenarios that require access to external data sources that are supported through Microsoft Power Query for Excel. Users can personalize workspaces by embedding tiles that are hosted on PowerBI.com. Users can also add direct links to reports that are hosted on PowerBI.com. In this way, users can access and interact with the reports without leaving the application. Power BI content (PBIX files) that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application. PBIX files that are associated with a model file are automatically published in Power BI Embedded as part of the application deployment process. Additionally, you can add X++ extensions for embedded reporting scenarios that require the following functionality:\n\n- Drill-down navigation into detailed pages in response to user interactions\n- Report filters that are based on user and session context information, such as company or date range\n- The ability to navigate directly to a specific tab on a Power BI report via menu items\n\nFor more information about customizations that use extensions, see [Customization: Overlayering and extensions](..\\extensibility\\customization-overlayering-extensions.md).\n\n## Why might I want to use Power BI Embedded?\nAlthough both Power BI services are available, it's important that you know which service is best suited to target application scenarios. The following illustration shows a comparison of features across services.\n\n![Comparison of features across services](media/Power-BI-Embedded-integration.png) \n\nFor more information about the Power BI Embedded service, see the [Power BI Embedded FAQ](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/powerbi-frequently-asked-questions/).\n\n## Advantages of Power BI Embedded\n- **Deliver Power BI workspaces and reports in the application.** If you're a power user or a business analyst, you can tweak ready-made reports or create new reports by using Power BI tools. As a developer, you can use the reports that your users create to provide rich navigation experiences in the product through workspaces. If you're in the partner and ISV community, you can build rich workspaces that include Power BI experiences, and then release those workspaces as part of your solution.\n- **The Power BI Embedded service license is bundled with Finance and Operations.** If you're an ISV or a systems integrator, you can package workspaces that are enabled for Power BI (and navigational experiences that those workspaces provide) as part of a Microsoft Dynamics Lifecyle Services (LCS) solution. Your customers get the same experience without having to have a PowerBI.com subscription. The workspaces just work with Finance and Operations.\n- **Enable drill-down into detailed pages from Power BI.** The visuals are the starting point for action. Your users can drill down to business processes and pages to act immediately on issues that they uncover. The visuals let users filter data and uncover trends. Action pages reflect just the set of data that requires attention.\n- **Help secure access to Power BI reports by using menu items.** As a developer, you can use familiar programming concepts that are available in Finance and Operations, because we have extended the same concepts to workspaces that are based on Power BI. You can create new workspaces or extend existing workspaces by adding an overview page that is driven by Power BI. Developers can associate menu items with Power BI reports and include them as links in workspaces. The role-based and task-based security in Finance and Operations can be used to help secure these menu items.\n- **Filter reports based on application context.** You can build navigation experiences by passing one or more filters to Power BI reports. For example, depending on a user’s actions or context, you can filter the Power BI report to reflect data from one business unit or a specific product. The user doesn't have to filter the data. You can define drill-through links to Finance and Operations pages, so that users can go directly to the transactional details pages.\n\n## Service availability\n**The Power BI Embedded service is automatically deployed and configured for all cloud-hosted, multi-box deployments.**  Because the service relies on Microsoft Azure services, application analytical workspaces and reports are unavailable in one-box environments. The Power BI Embedded service is already available in most Azure datacenters. You can check the latest availability on the [Azure status](https://azure.microsoft.com/status/) page.  \n \n> [!NOTE]\n> The Microsoft Dynamics 365 team is working on a solution that will enable analytical workspaces in one-box environments without requiring that customers host their own instance of the Power BI Embedded service. Watch for announcements on the [Dynamics 365 Roadmap](http://roadmap.dynamics.com) site.\n \n## Frequently asked questions\n\n### Can I customize the Power BI embedded reports?\nYes. To customize the Power BI embedded reports, just install Power BI Desktop in a one-box environment, and follow the steps in [Author and distribute Power BI reports with Entity store](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/analytics/author-distribute-power-bi-reports?toc=dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/toc.json).\n \n### Do customers have to purchase a separate Power BI license to use the new embedded analytics?\nNo, customers don't have to purchase a separate Power BI license to use the new embedded analytics. However, a Power BI Pro license is required in order to connect to Entity Store from PowerBI.com by using DirectQuery.\n \n### Can I do data mash-ups by using external data in the embedded reports?\nNo, you can't currently do data mash-ups by using external data in the embedded reports.\n \n### Can I help secure data to only those companies that I have access to?\nYes, the single company view prevents users from accessing data from companies that they don’t have access to. For more information about how to help secure custom solutions, see [Help secure analytical workspaces and reports by using Power BI Embedded](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/analytics/secure-analytical-workspaces?toc=dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/toc.json).\n \n### How is currency shown across multiple companies?\nCurrency is shown as a system currency. The system currency is defined on the **System parameters** page in Finance and Operations.\n \n### Can I drill from summary balances back into Finance and Operations?\nYes, you can drill into the details on a Power BI report. However, there is limited support for drill-down into Finance and Operations.\n \n### What languages are currently supported?\nCurrently, only English is supported. However, the Power BI team plans to add support for other languages.\n \n### Can I access analytical workspaces and reports in the on-premises version of Finance and Operations?\nNo, you can't currently access analytical workspaces and reports in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition (on-premises). Systems of Intelligence functions rely on cloud-hosted solutions.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,784],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Power BI Embedded integration\ndescription: Power BI content that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application. This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Power BI Embedded integration.\nauthor: TJVass\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 07/26/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: sericks\nms.search.scope: Operations, Platform, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 270754\nms.assetid: ca4b2ccf-d68d-4344-833e-1c45d966246c\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: tjvass\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 4\n","nodes":[{"content":"Power BI Embedded integration","nodes":[{"pos":[0,29],"content":"Power BI Embedded integration","nodes":[{"content":"Power BI Embedded integration","pos":[0,29]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"Power BI content that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application. This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Power BI Embedded integration.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,184],"content":"Power BI content that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application. This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Power BI Embedded integration.","nodes":[{"content":"Power BI content that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application. This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Power BI Embedded integration.","pos":[0,184],"nodes":[{"content":"Power BI content that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application.","pos":[0,94]},{"content":"This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Power BI Embedded integration.","pos":[95,184]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[792,821],"content":"Power BI Embedded integration","linkify":"Power BI Embedded integration","nodes":[{"content":"Power BI Embedded integration","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"Microsoft Power BI content that partners and independent software vendors (ISVs) developed can be embedded directly into the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[866,1061]},{"content":"This topic describes some of the ways that you can use the Microsoft Power BI Embedded integration.","pos":[1062,1161]},{"pos":[1166,1174],"content":"Overview","linkify":"Overview","nodes":[{"content":"Overview","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"The integration of Finance and Operations and <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Power BI<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.powerbi.com/)</ept> enables data mash-up scenarios that require access to external data sources that are supported through Microsoft Power Query for Excel.","pos":[1175,1392],"source":"The integration of Finance and Operations and [Power BI](http://www.powerbi.com/) enables data mash-up scenarios that require access to external data sources that are supported through Microsoft Power Query for Excel."},{"content":"Users can personalize workspaces by embedding tiles that are hosted on PowerBI.com.","pos":[1393,1476]},{"content":"Users can also add direct links to reports that are hosted on PowerBI.com.","pos":[1477,1551]},{"content":"In this way, users can access and interact with the reports without leaving the application.","pos":[1552,1644]},{"content":"Power BI content (PBIX files) that partners and ISVs develop can be embedded directly into the application.","pos":[1645,1752]},{"content":"PBIX files that are associated with a model file are automatically published in Power BI Embedded as part of the application deployment process.","pos":[1753,1897]},{"content":"Additionally, you can add X++ extensions for embedded reporting scenarios that require the following functionality:","pos":[1898,2013]},{"content":"Drill-down navigation into detailed pages in response to user interactions","pos":[2017,2091]},{"content":"Report filters that are based on user and session context information, such as company or date range","pos":[2094,2194]},{"content":"The ability to navigate directly to a specific tab on a Power BI report via menu items","pos":[2197,2283]},{"pos":[2285,2456],"content":"For more information about customizations that use extensions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Customization: Overlayering and extensions<ept id=\"p1\">](..\\extensibility\\customization-overlayering-extensions.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information about customizations that use extensions, see [Customization: Overlayering and extensions](..\\extensibility\\customization-overlayering-extensions.md)."},{"pos":[2461,2503],"content":"Why might I want to use Power BI Embedded?","linkify":"Why might I want to use Power BI Embedded?","nodes":[{"content":"Why might I want to use Power BI Embedded?","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"Although both Power BI services are available, it's important that you know which service is best suited to target application scenarios.","pos":[2504,2641]},{"content":"The following illustration shows a comparison of features across services.","pos":[2642,2716]},{"content":"Comparison of features across services","pos":[2720,2758]},{"pos":[2803,2980],"content":"For more information about the Power BI Embedded service, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Power BI Embedded FAQ<ept id=\"p1\">](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/powerbi-frequently-asked-questions/)</ept>.","source":"For more information about the Power BI Embedded service, see the [Power BI Embedded FAQ](https://powerbi.microsoft.com/en-us/documentation/powerbi-frequently-asked-questions/)."},{"pos":[2985,3016],"content":"Advantages of Power BI Embedded","linkify":"Advantages of Power BI Embedded","nodes":[{"content":"Advantages of Power BI Embedded","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Deliver Power BI workspaces and reports in the application.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[3019,3082],"source":"**Deliver Power BI workspaces and reports in the application.**"},{"content":"If you're a power user or a business analyst, you can tweak ready-made reports or create new reports by using Power BI tools.","pos":[3083,3208]},{"content":"As a developer, you can use the reports that your users create to provide rich navigation experiences in the product through workspaces.","pos":[3209,3345]},{"content":"If you're in the partner and ISV community, you can build rich workspaces that include Power BI experiences, and then release those workspaces as part of your solution.","pos":[3346,3514]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>The Power BI Embedded service license is bundled with Finance and Operations.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[3517,3598],"source":"**The Power BI Embedded service license is bundled with Finance and Operations.**"},{"content":"If you're an ISV or a systems integrator, you can package workspaces that are enabled for Power BI (and navigational experiences that those workspaces provide) as part of a Microsoft Dynamics Lifecyle Services (LCS) solution.","pos":[3599,3824]},{"content":"Your customers get the same experience without having to have a PowerBI.com subscription.","pos":[3825,3914]},{"content":"The workspaces just work with Finance and Operations.","pos":[3915,3968]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Enable drill-down into detailed pages from Power BI.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[3971,4027],"source":"**Enable drill-down into detailed pages from Power BI.**"},{"content":"The visuals are the starting point for action.","pos":[4028,4074]},{"content":"Your users can drill down to business processes and pages to act immediately on issues that they uncover.","pos":[4075,4180]},{"content":"The visuals let users filter data and uncover trends.","pos":[4181,4234]},{"content":"Action pages reflect just the set of data that requires attention.","pos":[4235,4301]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Help secure access to Power BI reports by using menu items.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[4304,4367],"source":"**Help secure access to Power BI reports by using menu items.**"},{"content":"As a developer, you can use familiar programming concepts that are available in Finance and Operations, because we have extended the same concepts to workspaces that are based on Power BI.","pos":[4368,4556]},{"content":"You can create new workspaces or extend existing workspaces by adding an overview page that is driven by Power BI.","pos":[4557,4671]},{"content":"Developers can associate menu items with Power BI reports and include them as links in workspaces.","pos":[4672,4770]},{"content":"The role-based and task-based security in Finance and Operations can be used to help secure these menu items.","pos":[4771,4880]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Filter reports based on application context.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[4883,4931],"source":"**Filter reports based on application context.**"},{"content":"You can build navigation experiences by passing one or more filters to Power BI reports.","pos":[4932,5020]},{"content":"For example, depending on a user’s actions or context, you can filter the Power BI report to reflect data from one business unit or a specific product.","pos":[5021,5172]},{"content":"The user doesn't have to filter the data.","pos":[5173,5214]},{"content":"You can define drill-through links to Finance and Operations pages, so that users can go directly to the transactional details pages.","pos":[5215,5348]},{"pos":[5353,5373],"content":"Service availability","linkify":"Service availability","nodes":[{"content":"Service availability","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>The Power BI Embedded service is automatically deployed and configured for all cloud-hosted, multi-box deployments.<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","pos":[5374,5493],"source":"**The Power BI Embedded service is automatically deployed and configured for all cloud-hosted, multi-box deployments.**"},{"content":"Because the service relies on Microsoft Azure services, application analytical workspaces and reports are unavailable in one-box environments.","pos":[5495,5637]},{"content":"The Power BI Embedded service is already available in most Azure datacenters.","pos":[5638,5715]},{"content":"You can check the latest availability on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Azure status<ept id=\"p1\">](https://azure.microsoft.com/status/)</ept> page.","pos":[5716,5818],"source":" You can check the latest availability on the [Azure status](https://azure.microsoft.com/status/) page."},{"pos":[5825,6134],"content":"[!NOTE]\nThe Microsoft Dynamics 365 team is working on a solution that will enable analytical workspaces in one-box environments without requiring that customers host their own instance of the Power BI Embedded service. Watch for announcements on the [Dynamics 365 Roadmap](http://roadmap.dynamics.com) site.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics 365 team is working on a solution that will enable analytical workspaces in one-box environments without requiring that customers host their own instance of the Power BI Embedded service. Watch for announcements on the [Dynamics 365 Roadmap](http://roadmap.dynamics.com) site.","pos":[8,307],"nodes":[{"content":"The Microsoft Dynamics 365 team is working on a solution that will enable analytical workspaces in one-box environments without requiring that customers host their own instance of the Power BI Embedded service.","pos":[0,210]},{"content":"Watch for announcements on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dynamics 365 Roadmap<ept id=\"p1\">](http://roadmap.dynamics.com)</ept> site.","pos":[211,299],"source":" Watch for announcements on the [Dynamics 365 Roadmap](http://roadmap.dynamics.com) site."}]}]},{"pos":[6140,6166],"content":"Frequently asked questions","linkify":"Frequently asked questions","nodes":[{"content":"Frequently asked questions","pos":[0,26]}]},{"pos":[6172,6218],"content":"Can I customize the Power BI embedded reports?","linkify":"Can I customize the Power BI embedded reports?","nodes":[{"content":"Can I customize the Power BI embedded reports?","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"Yes.","pos":[6219,6223]},{"content":"To customize the Power BI embedded reports, just install Power BI Desktop in a one-box environment, and follow the steps in <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Author and distribute Power BI reports with Entity store<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/analytics/author-distribute-power-bi-reports?toc=dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/toc.json)</ept>.","pos":[6224,6583],"source":" To customize the Power BI embedded reports, just install Power BI Desktop in a one-box environment, and follow the steps in [Author and distribute Power BI reports with Entity store](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/analytics/author-distribute-power-bi-reports?toc=dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/toc.json)."},{"pos":[6590,6682],"content":"Do customers have to purchase a separate Power BI license to use the new embedded analytics?","linkify":"Do customers have to purchase a separate Power BI license to use the new embedded analytics?","nodes":[{"content":"Do customers have to purchase a separate Power BI license to use the new embedded analytics?","pos":[0,92]}]},{"content":"No, customers don't have to purchase a separate Power BI license to use the new embedded analytics.","pos":[6683,6782]},{"content":"However, a Power BI Pro license is required in order to connect to Entity Store from PowerBI.com by using DirectQuery.","pos":[6783,6901]},{"pos":[6908,6978],"content":"Can I do data mash-ups by using external data in the embedded reports?","linkify":"Can I do data mash-ups by using external data in the embedded reports?","nodes":[{"content":"Can I do data mash-ups by using external data in the embedded reports?","pos":[0,70]}]},{"content":"No, you can't currently do data mash-ups by using external data in the embedded reports.","pos":[6979,7067]},{"pos":[7074,7143],"content":"Can I help secure data to only those companies that I have access to?","linkify":"Can I help secure data to only those companies that I have access to?","nodes":[{"content":"Can I help secure data to only those companies that I have access to?","pos":[0,69]}]},{"content":"Yes, the single company view prevents users from accessing data from companies that they don’t have access to.","pos":[7144,7254]},{"content":"For more information about how to help secure custom solutions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Help secure analytical workspaces and reports by using Power BI Embedded<ept id=\"p1\">](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/analytics/secure-analytical-workspaces?toc=dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/toc.json)</ept>.","pos":[7255,7568],"source":" For more information about how to help secure custom solutions, see [Help secure analytical workspaces and reports by using Power BI Embedded](https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/analytics/secure-analytical-workspaces?toc=dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/toc.json)."},{"pos":[7575,7623],"content":"How is currency shown across multiple companies?","linkify":"How is currency shown across multiple companies?","nodes":[{"content":"How is currency shown across multiple companies?","pos":[0,48]}]},{"content":"Currency is shown as a system currency.","pos":[7624,7663]},{"content":"The system currency is defined on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in Finance and Operations.","pos":[7664,7755],"source":" The system currency is defined on the **System parameters** page in Finance and Operations."},{"pos":[7762,7829],"content":"Can I drill from summary balances back into Finance and Operations?","linkify":"Can I drill from summary balances back into Finance and Operations?","nodes":[{"content":"Can I drill from summary balances back into Finance and Operations?","pos":[0,67]}]},{"content":"Yes, you can drill into the details on a Power BI report.","pos":[7830,7887]},{"content":"However, there is limited support for drill-down into Finance and Operations.","pos":[7888,7965]},{"pos":[7972,8011],"content":"What languages are currently supported?","linkify":"What languages are currently supported?","nodes":[{"content":"What languages are currently supported?","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"Currently, only English is supported.","pos":[8012,8049]},{"content":"However, the Power BI team plans to add support for other languages.","pos":[8050,8118]},{"pos":[8125,8225],"content":"Can I access analytical workspaces and reports in the on-premises version of Finance and Operations?","linkify":"Can I access analytical workspaces and reports in the on-premises version of Finance and Operations?","nodes":[{"content":"Can I access analytical workspaces and reports in the on-premises version of Finance and Operations?","pos":[0,100]}]},{"content":"No, you can't currently access analytical workspaces and reports in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition (on-premises).","pos":[8226,8378]},{"content":"Systems of Intelligence functions rely on cloud-hosted solutions.","pos":[8379,8444]}]}