{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution\ndescription: A Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities. A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function. For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package. The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: kfend\nms.search.scope: Lifecycle Services\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 197113\nms.assetid: ff06961e-2d11-4e4c-addf-5e4b9528a924\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: omarc\n\n\n---\n\n# Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nA Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities. A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function. For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package. The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.\n\nBefore you create your data package, make a plan for what it should include. In this way, you make sure that the correct entities, entity sequence, and fields are included. You create a data package by using the **Data management** workspace in Finance and Operations. Follow these steps to create a data package.\n\n1.  In Finance and Operations, click **System administration** &gt; **Workspaces** &gt; **Data Management IT**.\n2.  Click the **Export** tile, and then, in the **Name** field, enter **Data project**.\n3.  In the **Target data format** field, select the format for the export. The data formats that are available include comma separated value (CSV) format and Microsoft Excel format.\n4.  In the **Entity name** field, enter or select an entity. You can add multiple entities, but you must add each entity separately.\n5.  In the **Select fields** field, select a field setting, and then click **Add entity** to add the entity to the project.\n6.  Repeat steps 4 and 5 to add more entities to the project. **Note:** As you add each entity to the project, a tile appears that contains the entity's name and two buttons: **View map** and **Filter**. To automatically create a data package when you export the data project, set the **Generate data package** option to **Yes**. If you don't set this option, you can create a data package at the time of export.\n7.  On the Action Pane, click **Export**.\n8.  Click **Download**. The package is saved to the **Downloads** folder of the computer where the browser session is running. When you work with data packages, you must plan for and consider any prerequisites for the entities that will be included in the packages. For example, the customer groups are required in order to create customers. Therefore, you should either import the customer groups into a package before you import customers, or sequence customer groups within a data package that will be completed before customers are imported. For example, in the following illustration, sequencing is set within the data package. As you can see, the Customer groups entity and Customers entity are part of the Customers data project. [![Customers data project containing Customer groups and Customers entities](./media/pdp_03.png)](./media/pdp_03.png)\n\n9.  On the Action Pane, click **Entity sequence** to open the **Definition group entity sequence** page. Based on the current setup, the Customer groups entity and Customers entity are run at the same level. However, this sequence might not be ideal. [![Customer groups and Customers entities at the same execution level](./media/pdp_04.png)](./media/pdp_04.png)\n\n10. To create a better sequence, select the **Customers** entity, and then update the value of the **Execution unit** field from **1** to **2**. This change helps guarantee that customer groups are imported before the Customers entity is run. \n\n[![New sequence for the Customers and Customer groups entities](./media/pdp_05.png)](./media/pdp_05.png)\n\nMicrosoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS) contains multiple base data packages that you can use to reduce implementation time. These packages contain the elements that are required in each module/area in order to meet the minimum requirements. For advanced business processes, you might have to add more entities to the list of packages. The data packages that Microsoft publishes on LCS use a numbering sequence that is based on the module, data type, and sequence. Here is an example:\n\n-   Module/area number \n\n[![Module/area number](./media/pdp_06.png)](./media/pdp_06.png)\n\n-   Data type numbering \n\n[![Data type numbering](./media/pdp_07.png)](./media/pdp_07.png)\n\n-   Numbering format \n\n[![Numbering format](./media/pdp_08.png)](./media/pdp_08.png)\n\nThe names of data packages include the numbering format, which is followed by the module abbreviation and then a description. For example, the following illustration shows the General ledger data packages. \n\n[![General ledger data packages](./media/pdp_09.png)](./media/pdp_09.png)\n\n## Process data packages\nA process data package (PDP) consolidates Data import/export framework (DIXF) data packages into a unified bundle. The PDP is then used to configure a business process or a group of business processes in one business process library. Together, DIXF data packages, dependencies between those packages, and business processes that require the packages for their configuration make up a PDP. This section describes how to create a PDP for your LCS solution package. To create a PDP, you must have the following items and knowledge:\n\n-   An implementation business process library for the solution in your working LCS project.\n-   DIXF data packages that have configurations that follow best practices. These packages should include master and reference data for the whole solution.\n-   An understanding of the dependencies among the data in the packages.\n-   An understanding of the data dependencies between the data packages.\n\nFollow these steps to create a PDP.\n\n1.  In LCS, click the **Asset library** tile.\n2.  Select **Data package** as the asset type, and then click the plus sign (**+**) to add a data package.\n\nFollow these steps to consolidate the data packages that you uploaded to LCS into a single PDP.\n\n1.  In LCS, click the **Asset library** tile.\n2.  Select **Process data package** as the asset type, and then click the plus sign (**+**) to add a PDP.\n3.  Enter a name and description for the PDP, and then click **Confirm**.\n4.  For step 1, \"Add business process library,\" select the implementation business process library that your solution is built for, and then click **Continue**.\n5.  For step 2, \"Add data packages,\" click **Edit**, and add the data packages that are required in order to configure the system and enable the business process library transactions to be run. When you've finished adding data packages, click **Select**. The order in which data packages in the PDP are loaded into the system might be important. For example, before a chart of accounts (COA) can be loaded, the legal entity setup and currencies are required. Those data entities are in 01.1.002 System Setup. Therefore, 03.1.1001 COA Setup depends on 01.1.002 System Setup. In the next step, you must make a note of this dependency.\n6.  For step 3, \"Add data package dependencies,\" select a data package, and then click **Edit**. Select the dependent data packages that must be loaded into your target environment before the data package that you selected, and then click **Select**.\n7.  For step 4, \"Associate business process to data packages,\" select the business process that will be used to configure the process nodes.\n\n## Consume a PDP\nThe Consume flow lets you review a business process and apply the required configuration and data for implementing the business process to your Finance and Operations environment. To consume PDPs, you must have the following items:\n\n-   An implementation business process library for the solution in your working LCS project\n-   PDPs\n-   A target environment that includes an existing legal entity\n\nFollow these steps to consume the PDP.\n\n1.  In LCS, click the **Asset library** tile.\n2.  Select **Process data** **packages** as the asset type, and then click **Consume**.\n3.  The **Consume process data package** page shows a list of the existing PDP assets. Click the plus sign (**+**) to create a new Consume PDP.\n4.  Enter a name for the Consume PDP, select the PDP that you created and saved in the Asset library, select a target environment, and then click **Create**.\n5.  The Consume PDP that you created appears in the list of PDP assets. Click the package. **Note:** The asset that you created can be consumed only in the target environment that was linked to it.\n\n### Review and approve BPMs\n\n-   For step 1, \"Review business process,\" review the business process models (BPMs), and then click **Mark as reviewed**. The review status is updated for all dependent processes, and a green bar appears to the right of them. The **Reviewed by** and **Completed on** fields are also updated for each business process.[![Reviewed business processes with a green bar and updated Reviewed by and Completed on values](./media/pdplcssolutions_04.jpg)](./media/pdplcssolutions_04.jpg)\n\n### Review and approve data packages that are associated with a BPM\n\n1.  In the BPM library that you just reviewed, click **2 Approve the data packages** in the left pane.\n2.  Select the business process that is associated with the data packages. The data packages appear in the right pane, under **Process details**. Click **Review and Approve** in the right pane.\n3.  On the **Consume process data package** page, select a package, and then click **Download** to download the data package. Save the package locally. You can then update the data files in the data package with data that is specific to your target environment. When you've finished updating the data files, click **Upload data package** to upload your changes.\n4.  After the data package has been updated and completed, click **Approve**. The status is changed to **Approved**. You can approve as many data packages as necessary.\n5.  Click the **Back** button, click **2 Approve the data packages** again, and then select the business process. You should see the **Approved** status in the right pane, under **Process details** &gt; **Dependent packages**.\n\n### Apply a process data package\n\n1.  In the BPM library, click **3 Apply process data package** in the left pane.\n2.  Select the business process, and then, in the right pane, click **Apply Data Packages**.\n3.  On the **Consume process data package** page, select a package, and then click **Apply**.\n4.  Select the destination company in the target environment that is linked to the PDP, and then click **Apply**.\n\n### View the data package history\n\n-   On the **Consume process data package** page, select a package, and then click **History**. You can review the status of the data package. The available information includes the target environment, company, package name, start and end times, status by data entity, and the overall status of the data package. To see the details of any errors that occurred, you can sign in to the target environment.\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[LCS Solutions for AppSource home page](lcs-solutions-app-source.md)\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,1007],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution\ndescription: A Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities. A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function. For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package. The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.\nauthor: kfend\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: kfend\nms.search.scope: Lifecycle Services\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 197113\nms.assetid: ff06961e-2d11-4e4c-addf-5e4b9528a924\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: omarc\n\n","nodes":[{"content":"Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution","nodes":[{"pos":[0,52],"content":"Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution","nodes":[{"content":"Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution","pos":[0,52]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"A Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities. A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function. For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package. The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,481],"content":"A Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities. A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function. For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package. The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.","nodes":[{"content":"A Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities. A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function. For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package. The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.","pos":[0,481],"nodes":[{"content":"A Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities.","pos":[0,106]},{"content":"A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function.","pos":[107,206]},{"content":"For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package.","pos":[207,315]},{"content":"The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.","pos":[316,481]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[1015,1067],"content":"Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution","linkify":"Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution","nodes":[{"content":"Process and consume data packages in an LCS solution","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"A Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations data package can consist of one to many data entities.","pos":[1113,1219]},{"content":"A typical data package consists of a group of entities for a particular task, process, or function.","pos":[1220,1319]},{"content":"For example, the data entities that are required for General ledger setup might be part of one data package.","pos":[1320,1428]},{"content":"The format of a data package is a compressed file that contains a package manifest, package header, and any additional files for the data entities that are included.","pos":[1429,1594]},{"content":"Before you create your data package, make a plan for what it should include.","pos":[1596,1672]},{"content":"In this way, you make sure that the correct entities, entity sequence, and fields are included.","pos":[1673,1768]},{"content":"You create a data package by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data management<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> workspace in Finance and Operations.","pos":[1769,1864],"source":" You create a data package by using the **Data management** workspace in Finance and Operations."},{"content":"Follow these steps to create a data package.","pos":[1865,1909]},{"pos":[1915,2022],"content":"In Finance and Operations, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System administration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Workspaces<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph2\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Data Management IT<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"In Finance and Operations, click **System administration** &gt; **Workspaces** &gt; **Data Management IT**."},{"pos":[2027,2110],"content":"Click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Export<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tile, and then, in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Name<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field, enter <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Data project<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"Click the **Export** tile, and then, in the **Name** field, enter **Data project**."},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Target data format<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select the format for the export.","pos":[2115,2185],"source":"In the **Target data format** field, select the format for the export."},{"content":"The data formats that are available include comma separated value (CSV) format and Microsoft Excel format.","pos":[2186,2292]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Entity name<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, enter or select an entity.","pos":[2297,2353],"source":"In the **Entity name** field, enter or select an entity."},{"content":"You can add multiple entities, but you must add each entity separately.","pos":[2354,2425]},{"pos":[2430,2549],"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select fields<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field, select a field setting, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Add entity<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to add the entity to the project.","source":"In the **Select fields** field, select a field setting, and then click **Add entity** to add the entity to the project."},{"content":"Repeat steps 4 and 5 to add more entities to the project.","pos":[2554,2611]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> As you add each entity to the project, a tile appears that contains the entity's name and two buttons: <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>View map<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Filter<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[2612,2753],"source":"**Note:** As you add each entity to the project, a tile appears that contains the entity's name and two buttons: **View map** and **Filter**."},{"content":"To automatically create a data package when you export the data project, set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Generate data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2754,2879],"source":" To automatically create a data package when you export the data project, set the **Generate data package** option to **Yes**."},{"content":"If you don't set this option, you can create a data package at the time of export.","pos":[2880,2962]},{"pos":[2967,3004],"content":"On the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Export<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"On the Action Pane, click **Export**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Download<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[3009,3028],"source":"Click **Download**."},{"content":"The package is saved to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Downloads<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> folder of the computer where the browser session is running.","pos":[3029,3131],"source":" The package is saved to the **Downloads** folder of the computer where the browser session is running."},{"content":"When you work with data packages, you must plan for and consider any prerequisites for the entities that will be included in the packages.","pos":[3132,3270]},{"content":"For example, the customer groups are required in order to create customers.","pos":[3271,3346]},{"content":"Therefore, you should either import the customer groups into a package before you import customers, or sequence customer groups within a data package that will be completed before customers are imported.","pos":[3347,3550]},{"content":"For example, in the following illustration, sequencing is set within the data package.","pos":[3551,3637]},{"content":"As you can see, the Customer groups entity and Customers entity are part of the Customers data project.","pos":[3638,3741]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Customers data project containing Customer groups and Customers entities<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/pdp_03.png)](./media/pdp_03.png)</ept>","pos":[3742,3859],"source":"[![Customers data project containing Customer groups and Customers entities](./media/pdp_03.png)](./media/pdp_03.png)"},{"content":"On the Action Pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Entity sequence<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Definition group entity sequence<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3865,3965],"source":"On the Action Pane, click **Entity sequence** to open the **Definition group entity sequence** page."},{"content":"Based on the current setup, the Customer groups entity and Customers entity are run at the same level.","pos":[3966,4068]},{"content":"However, this sequence might not be ideal.","pos":[4069,4111]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Customer groups and Customers entities at the same execution level<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/pdp_04.png)](./media/pdp_04.png)</ept>","pos":[4112,4223],"source":"[![Customer groups and Customers entities at the same execution level](./media/pdp_04.png)](./media/pdp_04.png)"},{"content":"To create a better sequence, select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Customers<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> entity, and then update the value of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Execution unit<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field from <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>1<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> to <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>2<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept>.","pos":[4229,4369],"source":"To create a better sequence, select the **Customers** entity, and then update the value of the **Execution unit** field from **1** to **2**."},{"content":"This change helps guarantee that customer groups are imported before the Customers entity is run.","pos":[4370,4467]},{"pos":[4470,4574],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>New sequence for the Customers and Customer groups entities<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/pdp_05.png)](./media/pdp_05.png)</ept>","source":"[![New sequence for the Customers and Customer groups entities](./media/pdp_05.png)](./media/pdp_05.png)"},{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS) contains multiple base data packages that you can use to reduce implementation time.","pos":[4576,4704]},{"content":"These packages contain the elements that are required in each module/area in order to meet the minimum requirements.","pos":[4705,4821]},{"content":"For advanced business processes, you might have to add more entities to the list of packages.","pos":[4822,4915]},{"content":"The data packages that Microsoft publishes on LCS use a numbering sequence that is based on the module, data type, and sequence.","pos":[4916,5044]},{"content":"Here is an example:","pos":[5045,5064]},{"content":"Module/area number","pos":[5070,5088]},{"pos":[5091,5154],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Module/area number<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/pdp_06.png)](./media/pdp_06.png)</ept>","source":"[![Module/area number](./media/pdp_06.png)](./media/pdp_06.png)"},{"content":"Data type numbering","pos":[5160,5179]},{"pos":[5182,5246],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Data type numbering<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/pdp_07.png)](./media/pdp_07.png)</ept>","source":"[![Data type numbering](./media/pdp_07.png)](./media/pdp_07.png)"},{"content":"Numbering format","pos":[5252,5268]},{"pos":[5271,5332],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Numbering format<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/pdp_08.png)](./media/pdp_08.png)</ept>","source":"[![Numbering format](./media/pdp_08.png)](./media/pdp_08.png)"},{"content":"The names of data packages include the numbering format, which is followed by the module abbreviation and then a description.","pos":[5334,5459]},{"content":"For example, the following illustration shows the General ledger data packages.","pos":[5460,5539]},{"pos":[5542,5615],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>General ledger data packages<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/pdp_09.png)](./media/pdp_09.png)</ept>","source":"[![General ledger data packages](./media/pdp_09.png)](./media/pdp_09.png)"},{"pos":[5620,5641],"content":"Process data packages","linkify":"Process data packages","nodes":[{"content":"Process data packages","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"A process data package (PDP) consolidates Data import/export framework (DIXF) data packages into a unified bundle.","pos":[5642,5756]},{"content":"The PDP is then used to configure a business process or a group of business processes in one business process library.","pos":[5757,5875]},{"content":"Together, DIXF data packages, dependencies between those packages, and business processes that require the packages for their configuration make up a PDP.","pos":[5876,6030]},{"content":"This section describes how to create a PDP for your LCS solution package.","pos":[6031,6104]},{"content":"To create a PDP, you must have the following items and knowledge:","pos":[6105,6170]},{"content":"An implementation business process library for the solution in your working LCS project.","pos":[6176,6264]},{"content":"DIXF data packages that have configurations that follow best practices.","pos":[6269,6340]},{"content":"These packages should include master and reference data for the whole solution.","pos":[6341,6420]},{"content":"An understanding of the dependencies among the data in the packages.","pos":[6425,6493]},{"content":"An understanding of the data dependencies between the data packages.","pos":[6498,6566]},{"content":"Follow these steps to create a PDP.","pos":[6568,6603]},{"pos":[6609,6650],"content":"In LCS, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Asset library<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tile.","source":"In LCS, click the **Asset library** tile."},{"pos":[6655,6757],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the asset type, and then click the plus sign (<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">+</ph><ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>) to add a data package.","source":"Select **Data package** as the asset type, and then click the plus sign (**+**) to add a data package."},{"content":"Follow these steps to consolidate the data packages that you uploaded to LCS into a single PDP.","pos":[6759,6854]},{"pos":[6860,6901],"content":"In LCS, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Asset library<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tile.","source":"In LCS, click the **Asset library** tile."},{"pos":[6906,7007],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Process data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> as the asset type, and then click the plus sign (<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">+</ph><ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>) to add a PDP.","source":"Select **Process data package** as the asset type, and then click the plus sign (**+**) to add a PDP."},{"pos":[7012,7081],"content":"Enter a name and description for the PDP, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Confirm<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Enter a name and description for the PDP, and then click **Confirm**."},{"pos":[7086,7242],"content":"For step 1, \"Add business process library,\" select the implementation business process library that your solution is built for, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Continue<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"For step 1, \"Add business process library,\" select the implementation business process library that your solution is built for, and then click **Continue**."},{"content":"For step 2, \"Add data packages,\" click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and add the data packages that are required in order to configure the system and enable the business process library transactions to be run.","pos":[7247,7436],"source":"For step 2, \"Add data packages,\" click **Edit**, and add the data packages that are required in order to configure the system and enable the business process library transactions to be run."},{"content":"When you've finished adding data packages, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[7437,7497],"source":" When you've finished adding data packages, click **Select**."},{"content":"The order in which data packages in the PDP are loaded into the system might be important.","pos":[7498,7588]},{"content":"For example, before a chart of accounts (COA) can be loaded, the legal entity setup and currencies are required.","pos":[7589,7701]},{"content":"Those data entities are in 01.1.002 System Setup.","pos":[7702,7751]},{"content":"Therefore, 03.1.1001 COA Setup depends on 01.1.002 System Setup.","pos":[7752,7816]},{"content":"In the next step, you must make a note of this dependency.","pos":[7817,7875]},{"content":"For step 3, \"Add data package dependencies,\" select a data package, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Edit<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[7880,7972],"source":"For step 3, \"Add data package dependencies,\" select a data package, and then click **Edit**."},{"content":"Select the dependent data packages that must be loaded into your target environment before the data package that you selected, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Select<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[7973,8126],"source":" Select the dependent data packages that must be loaded into your target environment before the data package that you selected, and then click **Select**."},{"content":"For step 4, \"Associate business process to data packages,\" select the business process that will be used to configure the process nodes.","pos":[8131,8267]},{"pos":[8272,8285],"content":"Consume a PDP","linkify":"Consume a PDP","nodes":[{"content":"Consume a PDP","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"The Consume flow lets you review a business process and apply the required configuration and data for implementing the business process to your Finance and Operations environment.","pos":[8286,8465]},{"content":"To consume PDPs, you must have the following items:","pos":[8466,8517]},{"content":"An implementation business process library for the solution in your working LCS project","pos":[8523,8610]},{"content":"PDPs","pos":[8615,8619]},{"content":"A target environment that includes an existing legal entity","pos":[8624,8683]},{"content":"Follow these steps to consume the PDP.","pos":[8685,8723]},{"pos":[8729,8770],"content":"In LCS, click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Asset library<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tile.","source":"In LCS, click the **Asset library** tile."},{"pos":[8775,8858],"content":"Select <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Process data<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>packages<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> as the asset type, and then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Consume<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","source":"Select **Process data** **packages** as the asset type, and then click **Consume**."},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Consume process data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page shows a list of the existing PDP assets.","pos":[8863,8945],"source":"The **Consume process data package** page shows a list of the existing PDP assets."},{"content":"Click the plus sign (<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">+</ph><ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>) to create a new Consume PDP.","pos":[8946,9002],"source":" Click the plus sign (**+**) to create a new Consume PDP."},{"pos":[9007,9160],"content":"Enter a name for the Consume PDP, select the PDP that you created and saved in the Asset library, select a target environment, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Create<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Enter a name for the Consume PDP, select the PDP that you created and saved in the Asset library, select a target environment, and then click **Create**."},{"content":"The Consume PDP that you created appears in the list of PDP assets.","pos":[9165,9232]},{"content":"Click the package.","pos":[9233,9251]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The asset that you created can be consumed only in the target environment that was linked to it.","pos":[9252,9358],"source":"**Note:** The asset that you created can be consumed only in the target environment that was linked to it."},{"pos":[9364,9387],"content":"Review and approve BPMs","linkify":"Review and approve BPMs","nodes":[{"content":"Review and approve BPMs","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"For step 1, \"Review business process,\" review the business process models (BPMs), and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Mark as reviewed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[9393,9511],"source":"For step 1, \"Review business process,\" review the business process models (BPMs), and then click **Mark as reviewed**."},{"content":"The review status is updated for all dependent processes, and a green bar appears to the right of them.","pos":[9512,9615]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reviewed by<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Completed on<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> fields are also updated for each business process.<bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Reviewed business processes with a green bar and updated Reviewed by and Completed on values<ept id=\"p3\">](./media/pdplcssolutions_04.jpg)](./media/pdplcssolutions_04.jpg)</ept>","pos":[9616,9868],"source":" The **Reviewed by** and **Completed on** fields are also updated for each business process.[![Reviewed business processes with a green bar and updated Reviewed by and Completed on values](./media/pdplcssolutions_04.jpg)](./media/pdplcssolutions_04.jpg)"},{"pos":[9874,9937],"content":"Review and approve data packages that are associated with a BPM","linkify":"Review and approve data packages that are associated with a BPM","nodes":[{"content":"Review and approve data packages that are associated with a BPM","pos":[0,63]}]},{"pos":[9943,10041],"content":"In the BPM library that you just reviewed, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>2 Approve the data packages<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the left pane.","source":"In the BPM library that you just reviewed, click **2 Approve the data packages** in the left pane."},{"content":"Select the business process that is associated with the data packages.","pos":[10046,10116]},{"content":"The data packages appear in the right pane, under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Process details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[10117,10187],"source":" The data packages appear in the right pane, under **Process details**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Review and Approve<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the right pane.","pos":[10188,10235],"source":" Click **Review and Approve** in the right pane."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Consume process data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select a package, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Download<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to download the data package.","pos":[10240,10361],"source":"On the **Consume process data package** page, select a package, and then click **Download** to download the data package."},{"content":"Save the package locally.","pos":[10362,10387]},{"content":"You can then update the data files in the data package with data that is specific to your target environment.","pos":[10388,10497]},{"content":"When you've finished updating the data files, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Upload data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to upload your changes.","pos":[10498,10597],"source":" When you've finished updating the data files, click **Upload data package** to upload your changes."},{"content":"After the data package has been updated and completed, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approve<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[10602,10675],"source":"After the data package has been updated and completed, click **Approve**."},{"content":"The status is changed to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[10676,10714],"source":" The status is changed to **Approved**."},{"content":"You can approve as many data packages as necessary.","pos":[10715,10766]},{"content":"Click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Back<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>2 Approve the data packages<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> again, and then select the business process.","pos":[10771,10880],"source":"Click the **Back** button, click **2 Approve the data packages** again, and then select the business process."},{"content":"You should see the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Approved<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> status in the right pane, under <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Process details<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Dependent packages<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[10881,10993],"source":" You should see the **Approved** status in the right pane, under **Process details** &gt; **Dependent packages**."},{"pos":[10999,11027],"content":"Apply a process data package","linkify":"Apply a process data package","nodes":[{"content":"Apply a process data package","pos":[0,28]}]},{"pos":[11033,11109],"content":"In the BPM library, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>3 Apply process data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the left pane.","source":"In the BPM library, click **3 Apply process data package** in the left pane."},{"pos":[11114,11202],"content":"Select the business process, and then, in the right pane, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply Data Packages<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Select the business process, and then, in the right pane, click **Apply Data Packages**."},{"pos":[11207,11296],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Consume process data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select a package, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Apply<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"On the **Consume process data package** page, select a package, and then click **Apply**."},{"pos":[11301,11410],"content":"Select the destination company in the target environment that is linked to the PDP, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Apply<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"Select the destination company in the target environment that is linked to the PDP, and then click **Apply**."},{"pos":[11416,11445],"content":"View the data package history","linkify":"View the data package history","nodes":[{"content":"View the data package history","pos":[0,29]}]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Consume process data package<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select a package, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>History<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[11451,11542],"source":"On the **Consume process data package** page, select a package, and then click **History**."},{"content":"You can review the status of the data package.","pos":[11543,11589]},{"content":"The available information includes the target environment, company, package name, start and end times, status by data entity, and the overall status of the data package.","pos":[11590,11759]},{"content":"To see the details of any errors that occurred, you can sign in to the target environment.","pos":[11760,11850]},{"pos":[11853,11861],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[11872,11940],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>LCS Solutions for AppSource home page<ept id=\"p1\">](lcs-solutions-app-source.md)</ept>","source":"[LCS Solutions for AppSource home page](lcs-solutions-app-source.md)"}]}