{"content":"--- \n# required metadata \n \ntitle: Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan\ndescription: The compensation and benefits manager can assign employees to fixed compensation plans to manage their base pay. \nauthor: kherr75\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 11/14/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kherr\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 \n---\n# Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan\n\n[!include[task guide banner](../../includes/task-guide-banner.md)]\n\nThe compensation and benefits manager can assign employees to fixed compensation plans to manage their base pay. This procedure assumes that a fixed plan has been created and is active, and that eligibility rules have been set for the plan. The demo data company used to create this procedure is USMF. To begin the procedure, go to Human resources > Workers > Employees > Compensation > Fixed plan\n\n1. Click New.\n2. In the Action field, select a Fixed compensation action of type Hire/Rehire to describe the change in the employee's compensation.\n3. In the list, click the link in the selected row.\n4. In the Position field, click the drop-down button to open the lookup.\n5. In the list, click the link in the selected row.\n    * The level that's displayed is from the Compensation Level of the Job on the Position. The level must be set on the Job before compensation can be assigned to the employee.  \n6. In the Plan field, select the fixed compensation plan for the employee. The Plan lookup is filtered to show only the plans that the employee is eligible for based on the Eligibility rules.\n7. In the list, find and select the desired record.\n    * The Effective and Expiration dates for the compensation default from the start and end dates for the worker's position assignment. You can adjust these dates as needed.  \n    * If the Fixed compensation plan is a step plan, select the step containing the correct pay rate for the employee. If the fixed compensation plan is a grade or a band plan, enter the pay rate for the employee. The pay rate will be validated against the tolerance settings for the plan, and the minimum and maximum reference points for the job's compensation level.  \n8. Click OK.\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[5,666],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata \n \ntitle: Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan\ndescription: The compensation and benefits manager can assign employees to fixed compensation plans to manage their base pay. \nauthor: kherr75\nmanager: AnnBe \nms.date: 11/14/2016\nms.topic: business-process \nms.prod:  \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications \nms.technology:  \n \n# optional metadata \n \n# ms.search.form:   \naudience: Application User \n# ms.devlang:  \nms.reviewer: rschloma\nms.search.scope: Operations \n# ms.tgt_pltfrm:  \n# ms.custom:  \nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: kherr\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-06-30 \nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 7.0.0 ","nodes":[{"content":"Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan","nodes":[{"pos":[0,47],"content":"Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan","nodes":[{"content":"Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan","pos":[0,47]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"The compensation and benefits manager can assign employees to fixed compensation plans to manage their base pay.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,112],"content":"The compensation and benefits manager can assign employees to fixed compensation plans to manage their base pay.","nodes":[{"content":"The compensation and benefits manager can assign employees to fixed compensation plans to manage their base pay.","pos":[0,112]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata \n","yml":true},{"pos":[673,720],"content":"Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan","linkify":"Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan","nodes":[{"content":"Enroll an employee in a fixed compensation plan","pos":[0,47]}]},{"content":"The compensation and benefits manager can assign employees to fixed compensation plans to manage their base pay.","pos":[790,902]},{"content":"This procedure assumes that a fixed plan has been created and is active, and that eligibility rules have been set for the plan.","pos":[903,1030]},{"content":"The demo data company used to create this procedure is USMF.","pos":[1031,1091]},{"content":"To begin the procedure, go to Human resources &gt; Workers &gt; Employees &gt; Compensation &gt; Fixed plan","pos":[1092,1187],"source":" To begin the procedure, go to Human resources > Workers > Employees > Compensation > Fixed plan"},{"content":"Click New.","pos":[1192,1202]},{"content":"In the Action field, select a Fixed compensation action of type Hire/Rehire to describe the change in the employee's compensation.","pos":[1206,1336]},{"content":"In the list, click the link in the selected row.","pos":[1340,1388]},{"content":"In the Position field, click the drop-down button to open the lookup.","pos":[1392,1461]},{"content":"In the list, click the link in the selected row.","pos":[1465,1513]},{"content":"The level that's displayed is from the Compensation Level of the Job on the Position.","pos":[1520,1605]},{"content":"The level must be set on the Job before compensation can be assigned to the employee.","pos":[1606,1691]},{"content":"In the Plan field, select the fixed compensation plan for the employee.","pos":[1697,1768]},{"content":"The Plan lookup is filtered to show only the plans that the employee is eligible for based on the Eligibility rules.","pos":[1769,1885]},{"content":"In the list, find and select the desired record.","pos":[1889,1937]},{"content":"The Effective and Expiration dates for the compensation default from the start and end dates for the worker's position assignment.","pos":[1944,2074]},{"content":"You can adjust these dates as needed.","pos":[2075,2112]},{"content":"If the Fixed compensation plan is a step plan, select the step containing the correct pay rate for the employee.","pos":[2121,2233]},{"content":"If the fixed compensation plan is a grade or a band plan, enter the pay rate for the employee.","pos":[2234,2328]},{"content":"The pay rate will be validated against the tolerance settings for the plan, and the minimum and maximum reference points for the job's compensation level.","pos":[2329,2483]},{"content":"Click OK.","pos":[2489,2498]}]}