{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Registration for manufacturing execution\ndescription: This topic describes key concepts and terms that you need to understand to configure and use manufacturing execution. \nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: JmgRegistration\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 70103\nms.assetid: 52ba1cdd-767f-4edd-896f-61adce8479d3\nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Manufacturing\nms.author: johanho\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Registration for manufacturing execution\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic describes key concepts and terms that you need to understand to configure and use manufacturing execution. \n\nManufacturing execution is intended to be used primarily by manufacturing companies. Workers can register time and item consumption on production jobs by using the **Job registration** page. All registrations are approved and are later transferred to the relevant modules. Continuous approval and transfer of registrations lets managers easily track actual costs on production orders.\n\n## Manufacturing execution and registration terminology\nThe following table contains terms that pertain to manufacturing execution and related registration tasks.\n\n| Term                          | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n|-------------------------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Manufacturing execution       | A function that is used to register time, material consumption, costs on production jobs, projects, and indirect activities. Registration is done in a manufacturing execution registration client.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |\n| Job list                      | On the **Job registration** page, workers are shown the list of jobs that they must perform on a specific resource, such as a machine. A worker can register time and item consumption on each job or task in the job list.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n| Job bundling                  | If a worker starts more than one job at the same time on the **Job registration** page, this is called job bundling. The time that is spent on bundled jobs can be allocated to the individual jobs in various ways by using allocation keys.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         |\n| Pilot/assistant registrations | A worker can register as an assistant to a resource, and can create a small team where several workers work on the same production jobs. Resources that workers are connected to as assistants are called pilots. Only the pilot resource must make registrations. All assistants automatically get the same registrations. For example, if a machine acts as the pilot, workers who have registered as assistants to that machine can make registrations on the **Job registration** page, and both the machine and the workers who are connected as assistants will receive the same registrations. |\n| Indirect activity             | An activity or task that isn't directly related to a production job or a project, such as a department meeting, a cleaning job, or a maintenance job on the shop floor. Workers can make registrations on indirect activities, in the same way that they can register on production jobs and projects.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n\n## Registrations in manufacturing execution\nWorkers can make various types of registrations in manufacturing execution for work that is performed on production jobs. Depending on the system setup, workers might also be able to make registrations on project activities and nonproductive tasks, such as breaks, absences, and indirect activities. Here are the registration types:\n\n-   **Clock-in/clock-out** (available with time and attendance) – Workers clock in when they arrive at work and clock out when they leave to go home.\n-   **Register on production jobs** – Workers can make registrations, such as starting a job and reporting feedback for a job, on the production jobs that appear in their job list. Workers can start several jobs at the same time. This is referred to as job bundling.\n-   **Register on inventory** – Workers can make registrations on materials that are used on the shop floor, but that aren't directly related to production jobs. Examples include grease, lubricants, or other materials that are used to keep machinery running. Registration is performed in an inventory journal.\n-   **Register on projects** (available with time and attendance) – Workers can make registrations, such as starting and finishing work on the projects or project activities that appear in their job list.\n-   **Register project fees and project items** (available with time and attendance) – Workers can register fees (expenses) that are associated with a project in a project fee journal, such as mileage and bridge toll. Workers can also register item consumption on projects. This is done in a project item journal.\n-   **Register as assistant to another worker** – If two or more workers will work together on a production job or a project, a worker can register as an assistant to a machine, or to another worker, who will then act as the pilot. The pilot can select another worker as the pilot, as required.\n-   **Register absence** (available with time and attendance) – Workers can register time on various absence codes that are set up. Absence can be indicated if a worker arrives late, requires absence during the work day, or leaves earlier than expected according to the standard work time profile.\n-   **Register breaks** (available with time and attendance) – During the work day, workers can register that they are leaving their workstation to take a break. Several break types can be set up. When a worker returns and logs on again, the system registers that the worker is back, and the break registration stops.\n-   **Register indirect activities** (available with time and attendance) – Indirect activities are nonproductive activities that workers might engage in during a workday, such as a department meeting, a team meeting, or a maintenance job that is performed on the shop floor. Workers can make registrations on the indirect activities that are set up.\n-   **Register overtime** (available with time and attendance) – Workers who have been asked to work longer hours can select whether the extra hours should be registered as flextime or overtime.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,757],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Registration for manufacturing execution\ndescription: This topic describes key concepts and terms that you need to understand to configure and use manufacturing execution. \nauthor: YuyuScheller\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: JmgRegistration\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 70103\nms.assetid: 52ba1cdd-767f-4edd-896f-61adce8479d3\nms.search.region: Global\nms.search.industry: Manufacturing\nms.author: johanho\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Registration for manufacturing execution","nodes":[{"pos":[0,40],"content":"Registration for manufacturing execution","nodes":[{"content":"Registration for manufacturing execution","pos":[0,40]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic describes key concepts and terms that you need to understand to configure and use manufacturing execution.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,117],"content":"This topic describes key concepts and terms that you need to understand to configure and use manufacturing execution.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic describes key concepts and terms that you need to understand to configure and use manufacturing execution.","pos":[0,117]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[765,805],"content":"Registration for manufacturing execution","linkify":"Registration for manufacturing execution","nodes":[{"content":"Registration for manufacturing execution","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"This topic describes key concepts and terms that you need to understand to configure and use manufacturing execution.","pos":[851,968]},{"content":"Manufacturing execution is intended to be used primarily by manufacturing companies.","pos":[971,1055]},{"content":"Workers can register time and item consumption on production jobs by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[1056,1161],"source":" Workers can register time and item consumption on production jobs by using the **Job registration** page."},{"content":"All registrations are approved and are later transferred to the relevant modules.","pos":[1162,1243]},{"content":"Continuous approval and transfer of registrations lets managers easily track actual costs on production orders.","pos":[1244,1355]},{"pos":[1360,1412],"content":"Manufacturing execution and registration terminology","linkify":"Manufacturing execution and registration terminology","nodes":[{"content":"Manufacturing execution and registration terminology","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"The following table contains terms that pertain to manufacturing execution and related registration tasks.","pos":[1413,1519]},{"content":"Term","pos":[1523,1527]},{"content":"Description","pos":[1555,1566]},{"content":"Manufacturing execution","pos":[2759,2782]},{"content":"A function that is used to register time, material consumption, costs on production jobs, projects, and indirect activities.","pos":[2791,2915]},{"content":"Registration is done in a manufacturing execution registration client.","pos":[2916,2986]},{"content":"Job list","pos":[3377,3385]},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, workers are shown the list of jobs that they must perform on a specific resource, such as a machine.","pos":[3409,3543],"source":"On the **Job registration** page, workers are shown the list of jobs that they must perform on a specific resource, such as a machine."},{"content":"A worker can register time and item consumption on each job or task in the job list.","pos":[3544,3628]},{"content":"Job bundling","pos":[3995,4007]},{"content":"If a worker starts more than one job at the same time on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, this is called job bundling.","pos":[4027,4143],"source":"If a worker starts more than one job at the same time on the **Job registration** page, this is called job bundling."},{"content":"The time that is spent on bundled jobs can be allocated to the individual jobs in various ways by using allocation keys.","pos":[4144,4264]},{"content":"Pilot/assistant registrations","pos":[4613,4642]},{"content":"A worker can register as an assistant to a resource, and can create a small team where several workers work on the same production jobs.","pos":[4645,4781]},{"content":"Resources that workers are connected to as assistants are called pilots.","pos":[4782,4854]},{"content":"Only the pilot resource must make registrations.","pos":[4855,4903]},{"content":"All assistants automatically get the same registrations.","pos":[4904,4960]},{"content":"For example, if a machine acts as the pilot, workers who have registered as assistants to that machine can make registrations on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job registration<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, and both the machine and the workers who are connected as assistants will receive the same registrations.","pos":[4961,5226],"source":" For example, if a machine acts as the pilot, workers who have registered as assistants to that machine can make registrations on the **Job registration** page, and both the machine and the workers who are connected as assistants will receive the same registrations."},{"content":"Indirect activity","pos":[5231,5248]},{"content":"An activity or task that isn't directly related to a production job or a project, such as a department meeting, a cleaning job, or a maintenance job on the shop floor.","pos":[5263,5430]},{"content":"Workers can make registrations on indirect activities, in the same way that they can register on production jobs and projects.","pos":[5431,5557]},{"pos":[5851,5891],"content":"Registrations in manufacturing execution","linkify":"Registrations in manufacturing execution","nodes":[{"content":"Registrations in manufacturing execution","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"Workers can make various types of registrations in manufacturing execution for work that is performed on production jobs.","pos":[5892,6013]},{"content":"Depending on the system setup, workers might also be able to make registrations on project activities and nonproductive tasks, such as breaks, absences, and indirect activities.","pos":[6014,6191]},{"content":"Here are the registration types:","pos":[6192,6224]},{"pos":[6230,6375],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Clock-in/clock-out<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (available with time and attendance) – Workers clock in when they arrive at work and clock out when they leave to go home.","source":"**Clock-in/clock-out** (available with time and attendance) – Workers clock in when they arrive at work and clock out when they leave to go home."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register on production jobs<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Workers can make registrations, such as starting a job and reporting feedback for a job, on the production jobs that appear in their job list.","pos":[6380,6556],"source":"**Register on production jobs** – Workers can make registrations, such as starting a job and reporting feedback for a job, on the production jobs that appear in their job list."},{"content":"Workers can start several jobs at the same time.","pos":[6557,6605]},{"content":"This is referred to as job bundling.","pos":[6606,6642]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register on inventory<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Workers can make registrations on materials that are used on the shop floor, but that aren't directly related to production jobs.","pos":[6647,6804],"source":"**Register on inventory** – Workers can make registrations on materials that are used on the shop floor, but that aren't directly related to production jobs."},{"content":"Examples include grease, lubricants, or other materials that are used to keep machinery running.","pos":[6805,6901]},{"content":"Registration is performed in an inventory journal.","pos":[6902,6952]},{"pos":[6957,7157],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register on projects<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (available with time and attendance) – Workers can make registrations, such as starting and finishing work on the projects or project activities that appear in their job list.","source":"**Register on projects** (available with time and attendance) – Workers can make registrations, such as starting and finishing work on the projects or project activities that appear in their job list."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register project fees and project items<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (available with time and attendance) – Workers can register fees (expenses) that are associated with a project in a project fee journal, such as mileage and bridge toll.","pos":[7162,7375],"source":"**Register project fees and project items** (available with time and attendance) – Workers can register fees (expenses) that are associated with a project in a project fee journal, such as mileage and bridge toll."},{"content":"Workers can also register item consumption on projects.","pos":[7376,7431]},{"content":"This is done in a project item journal.","pos":[7432,7471]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register as assistant to another worker<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – If two or more workers will work together on a production job or a project, a worker can register as an assistant to a machine, or to another worker, who will then act as the pilot.","pos":[7476,7703],"source":"**Register as assistant to another worker** – If two or more workers will work together on a production job or a project, a worker can register as an assistant to a machine, or to another worker, who will then act as the pilot."},{"content":"The pilot can select another worker as the pilot, as required.","pos":[7704,7766]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register absence<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (available with time and attendance) – Workers can register time on various absence codes that are set up.","pos":[7771,7898],"source":"**Register absence** (available with time and attendance) – Workers can register time on various absence codes that are set up."},{"content":"Absence can be indicated if a worker arrives late, requires absence during the work day, or leaves earlier than expected according to the standard work time profile.","pos":[7899,8064]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register breaks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (available with time and attendance) – During the work day, workers can register that they are leaving their workstation to take a break.","pos":[8069,8226],"source":"**Register breaks** (available with time and attendance) – During the work day, workers can register that they are leaving their workstation to take a break."},{"content":"Several break types can be set up.","pos":[8227,8261]},{"content":"When a worker returns and logs on again, the system registers that the worker is back, and the break registration stops.","pos":[8262,8382]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register indirect activities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (available with time and attendance) – Indirect activities are nonproductive activities that workers might engage in during a workday, such as a department meeting, a team meeting, or a maintenance job that is performed on the shop floor.","pos":[8387,8658],"source":"**Register indirect activities** (available with time and attendance) – Indirect activities are nonproductive activities that workers might engage in during a workday, such as a department meeting, a team meeting, or a maintenance job that is performed on the shop floor."},{"content":"Workers can make registrations on the indirect activities that are set up.","pos":[8659,8733]},{"pos":[8738,8928],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Register overtime<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (available with time and attendance) – Workers who have been asked to work longer hours can select whether the extra hours should be registered as flextime or overtime.","source":"**Register overtime** (available with time and attendance) – Workers who have been asked to work longer hours can select whether the extra hours should be registered as flextime or overtime."}]}