{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail \ndescription: Home page for Dynamics 365 for Retail\nauthor: josaw1\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: index-page\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-365-retail\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: josaw\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations, Retail\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: \nms.assetid: ed0f77f7-3609-4330-bebd-ca3134575216\nms.search.region: global\nms.search.industry: Retail\nms.author: josaw\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-6-19\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611, Retail Version\n\n---\n\n# Welcome to Dynamics 365 for Retail\n\nMicrosoft Dynamics 365 for Retail is an end-to-end retail solution that delivers unified commerce across all channels. It encompasses sales, mobility, intelligence, and productivity to help retailers and workers achieve more in a cloud-first, mobile-first manner. Retail offers comprehensive support to operate a wide range of business processes, such as merchandising, inventory, and channel management capabilities. It also provides immersive customer experiences across all touchpoints.\n\n> [!NOTE] \n> Dynamics 365 for Retail is closely related to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition, and Dynamics 365 for Talent. The same functionality may appear in all three products. As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to the core product (Finance and Operations), the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; in topics that are primarily related to human resources, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent. \n\nIn the left pane, select a feature area to learn more about it.\n\n## Channel management\nAs you set up your Retail experience, you will decide how to define and configure your stores. They can be brick-and-mortar stores, online stores, or call centers.\n\nEach retail store can have its own payment methods, delivery methods, price groups, income and expense accounts, registers, and staff. After you create your retail store, you create an assortment of products that you want the store to carry. You can also define store-specific prices and discounts that apply to products that are available in the store.\n\n## Clienteling and loyalty\nCustomer needs constantly change. You must be able to quickly and effectively keep up with changes in buying habits and trends, so that you can target and attract new customers, but also keep your existing customer base happy.\n\nFurthermore, customers have many options for getting what they want, when they want it, and at the price they want. To maintain customer loyalty, you can use personalized notifications and offers that make shopping easier.\n\n## Hardware and peripherals\nRetail Modern point of sale (MPOS) and Cloud POS can use a wide range of hardware peripherals. Both MPOS and Cloud POS offer multiple interfaces and deployment options to help you with your various business scenarios.\n\nThe Peripheral simulator for Retail includes a virtual peripheral simulator and a POS simulator. The virtual peripheral simulator primarily supports testing of scenarios that usually require physical POS peripheral devices. The POS simulator lets you test the compatibility of physical peripheral devices with Retail without having to deploy the POS client.\n\n## Intelligence\nAdvanced analytics bring the power of machine learning to retail challenges, and enable predictive, optimized, and personalized insights that help lead to growth and profitability. Retail lets you deliver visual reports on any device, whether it's online or offline. Additionally, you can help customers identify products and services that meet their needs before the time of purchase.\n\n## Monitoring and diagnosis\nRetail lets you monitor sales and margin performance in real time across various levels of the organization hierarchy.\n\n## Merchandising\nBefore you can offer products for sale in your retail channels, you must create and configure the products in Retail. You can create the products, define the product properties and attributes, and assign the products to retail category hierarchies. To make the products available to your retail channels and add them to an active assortment, you must release the products to the legal entities where they are available.\n\nYou can make price adjustments to products, and can also set up discounts that are applied to a line item or a transaction at the POS, in a call center sales order, or in an online order.\n\n## Store operations and POS\nMPOS is a POS app for PCs, tablets, and phones. Sales staff can process sales transactions and customer orders, perform clienteling activities, and perform daily operations and inventory management on mobile devices anywhere in the store, and also at PC-based registers. Cloud POS is a browser-based POS that can be started in any standard browser.\n\nYou will set up several components to define the relationships among a store, the POS registers in the store, and the retail peripherals that those registers use to process transactions. You will also define the characteristics of a specific instance of the POS. These characteristics include the hardware profile or setup for retail peripherals that will be used at the register, the store that the register is mapped to, the visual experience for the user who signs in to that register, and the functionalities that are enabled in the register. You will also define whether the register can operate in a disconnected or offline state.\n\n## Workforce management\nTo be profitable in an environment where margins are decreasing, retailers constantly try to reduce their operational cost. For most retailers, the cost of retail staff is a significant part of the operational cost. Therefore, by controlling this cost, retailers can have a significant impact on their bottom line. Additionally, an empowered and productive workforce lends itself to improved customer experience.\n\nRetail lets store managers create and publish shifts and schedules for workers in stores, annotate shifts via instructions, copy schedules from a previous week to the current week. Additionally, managers gain visibility into absence requests that retail workers submit, and can approve or reject those requests. They also gain visibility into \"shift swap\" and \"shift offer\" requests, and can approve or reject those requests.\n\nStore associates gain visibility into shifts and assigned schedules, together with instructions for the shifts, and gain visibility into the co-workers who are assigned to shifts. They can also submit absence requests, requests for shift swaps with co-workers, and shift offer requests.\n\n## Customize and administer Retail environments\nIf you've been asked to customize your environment, or if you're responsible for deploying and maintaining your system, be sure to see the developer and system administrator content that is specific to Retail, in addition to the more general content.\n\n- [Dynamics 365 for Retail for IT Pros and Developers](dev-itpro/dev-retail-home-page.md)\n- [Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail for Developers and IT Pros](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/developer-home-page)\n\n## Additional resources\n### What's new and in development\nGo to the [Microsoft Dynamics 365 Roadmap](https://roadmap.dynamics.com/) to see what new features have been released and what new features are in development.\n\n### Blogs\nYou can find opinions, news, and other information about Retail and other solutions on the [Microsoft Dynamics 365 blog](https://community.dynamics.com/b/msftdynamicsblog).\n\nThere are many posts about Retail on the [Microsoft Dynamics AX product team blog](https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dax/). Although some of these posts were written for the previous version of Retail, the same concepts still apply. and the procedures are also similar in the current version.\n\nThe [Microsoft Dynamics Operations Partner Community Blog](https://community.dynamics.com/partner/b/operationspartnercommunityblog) gives Microsoft Dynamics Partners a single resource where they can learn what is new and trending in MBS Operations.\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,652],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail \ndescription: Home page for Dynamics 365 for Retail\nauthor: josaw1\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: index-page\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-365-retail\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: josaw\nms.search.scope: Core, Operations, UnifiedOperations, Retail\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: \nms.assetid: ed0f77f7-3609-4330-bebd-ca3134575216\nms.search.region: global\nms.search.industry: Retail\nms.author: josaw\nms.search.validFrom: 2017-6-19\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Version 1611, Retail Version\n","nodes":[{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"pos":[0,33],"content":"Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail","pos":[0,33]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"Home page for Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"pos":[0,37],"content":"Home page for Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"content":"Home page for Dynamics 365 for Retail","pos":[0,37]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[660,694],"content":"Welcome to Dynamics 365 for Retail","linkify":"Welcome to Dynamics 365 for Retail","nodes":[{"content":"Welcome to Dynamics 365 for Retail","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail is an end-to-end retail solution that delivers unified commerce across all channels.","pos":[696,814]},{"content":"It encompasses sales, mobility, intelligence, and productivity to help retailers and workers achieve more in a cloud-first, mobile-first manner.","pos":[815,959]},{"content":"Retail offers comprehensive support to operate a wide range of business processes, such as merchandising, inventory, and channel management capabilities.","pos":[960,1113]},{"content":"It also provides immersive customer experiences across all touchpoints.","pos":[1114,1185]},{"pos":[1189,1799],"content":"[!NOTE] \nDynamics 365 for Retail is closely related to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition, and Dynamics 365 for Talent. The same functionality may appear in all three products. As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to the core product (Finance and Operations), the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; in topics that are primarily related to human resources, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Retail is closely related to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition, and Dynamics 365 for Talent. The same functionality may appear in all three products. As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to the core product (Finance and Operations), the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; in topics that are primarily related to human resources, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent.","pos":[9,608],"nodes":[{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Retail is closely related to Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition, and Dynamics 365 for Talent.","pos":[0,135]},{"content":"The same functionality may appear in all three products.","pos":[136,192]},{"content":"As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to the core product (Finance and Operations), the product name will be Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; in topics that are primarily related to human resources, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent.","pos":[193,599]}]}]},{"content":"In the left pane, select a feature area to learn more about it.","pos":[1802,1865]},{"pos":[1870,1888],"content":"Channel management","linkify":"Channel management","nodes":[{"content":"Channel management","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"As you set up your Retail experience, you will decide how to define and configure your stores.","pos":[1889,1983]},{"content":"They can be brick-and-mortar stores, online stores, or call centers.","pos":[1984,2052]},{"content":"Each retail store can have its own payment methods, delivery methods, price groups, income and expense accounts, registers, and staff.","pos":[2054,2188]},{"content":"After you create your retail store, you create an assortment of products that you want the store to carry.","pos":[2189,2295]},{"content":"You can also define store-specific prices and discounts that apply to products that are available in the store.","pos":[2296,2407]},{"pos":[2412,2435],"content":"Clienteling and loyalty","linkify":"Clienteling and loyalty","nodes":[{"content":"Clienteling and loyalty","pos":[0,23]}]},{"content":"Customer needs constantly change.","pos":[2436,2469]},{"content":"You must be able to quickly and effectively keep up with changes in buying habits and trends, so that you can target and attract new customers, but also keep your existing customer base happy.","pos":[2470,2662]},{"content":"Furthermore, customers have many options for getting what they want, when they want it, and at the price they want.","pos":[2664,2779]},{"content":"To maintain customer loyalty, you can use personalized notifications and offers that make shopping easier.","pos":[2780,2886]},{"pos":[2891,2915],"content":"Hardware and peripherals","linkify":"Hardware and peripherals","nodes":[{"content":"Hardware and peripherals","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"Retail Modern point of sale (MPOS) and Cloud POS can use a wide range of hardware peripherals.","pos":[2916,3010]},{"content":"Both MPOS and Cloud POS offer multiple interfaces and deployment options to help you with your various business scenarios.","pos":[3011,3133]},{"content":"The Peripheral simulator for Retail includes a virtual peripheral simulator and a POS simulator.","pos":[3135,3231]},{"content":"The virtual peripheral simulator primarily supports testing of scenarios that usually require physical POS peripheral devices.","pos":[3232,3358]},{"content":"The POS simulator lets you test the compatibility of physical peripheral devices with Retail without having to deploy the POS client.","pos":[3359,3492]},{"pos":[3497,3509],"content":"Intelligence","linkify":"Intelligence","nodes":[{"content":"Intelligence","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"Advanced analytics bring the power of machine learning to retail challenges, and enable predictive, optimized, and personalized insights that help lead to growth and profitability.","pos":[3510,3690]},{"content":"Retail lets you deliver visual reports on any device, whether it's online or offline.","pos":[3691,3776]},{"content":"Additionally, you can help customers identify products and services that meet their needs before the time of purchase.","pos":[3777,3895]},{"pos":[3900,3924],"content":"Monitoring and diagnosis","linkify":"Monitoring and diagnosis","nodes":[{"content":"Monitoring and diagnosis","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"Retail lets you monitor sales and margin performance in real time across various levels of the organization hierarchy.","pos":[3925,4043]},{"pos":[4048,4061],"content":"Merchandising","linkify":"Merchandising","nodes":[{"content":"Merchandising","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"Before you can offer products for sale in your retail channels, you must create and configure the products in Retail.","pos":[4062,4179]},{"content":"You can create the products, define the product properties and attributes, and assign the products to retail category hierarchies.","pos":[4180,4310]},{"content":"To make the products available to your retail channels and add them to an active assortment, you must release the products to the legal entities where they are available.","pos":[4311,4481]},{"content":"You can make price adjustments to products, and can also set up discounts that are applied to a line item or a transaction at the POS, in a call center sales order, or in an online order.","pos":[4483,4670]},{"pos":[4675,4699],"content":"Store operations and POS","linkify":"Store operations and POS","nodes":[{"content":"Store operations and POS","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"MPOS is a POS app for PCs, tablets, and phones.","pos":[4700,4747]},{"content":"Sales staff can process sales transactions and customer orders, perform clienteling activities, and perform daily operations and inventory management on mobile devices anywhere in the store, and also at PC-based registers.","pos":[4748,4970]},{"content":"Cloud POS is a browser-based POS that can be started in any standard browser.","pos":[4971,5048]},{"content":"You will set up several components to define the relationships among a store, the POS registers in the store, and the retail peripherals that those registers use to process transactions.","pos":[5050,5236]},{"content":"You will also define the characteristics of a specific instance of the POS.","pos":[5237,5312]},{"content":"These characteristics include the hardware profile or setup for retail peripherals that will be used at the register, the store that the register is mapped to, the visual experience for the user who signs in to that register, and the functionalities that are enabled in the register.","pos":[5313,5596]},{"content":"You will also define whether the register can operate in a disconnected or offline state.","pos":[5597,5686]},{"pos":[5691,5711],"content":"Workforce management","linkify":"Workforce management","nodes":[{"content":"Workforce management","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"To be profitable in an environment where margins are decreasing, retailers constantly try to reduce their operational cost.","pos":[5712,5835]},{"content":"For most retailers, the cost of retail staff is a significant part of the operational cost.","pos":[5836,5927]},{"content":"Therefore, by controlling this cost, retailers can have a significant impact on their bottom line.","pos":[5928,6026]},{"content":"Additionally, an empowered and productive workforce lends itself to improved customer experience.","pos":[6027,6124]},{"content":"Retail lets store managers create and publish shifts and schedules for workers in stores, annotate shifts via instructions, copy schedules from a previous week to the current week.","pos":[6126,6306]},{"content":"Additionally, managers gain visibility into absence requests that retail workers submit, and can approve or reject those requests.","pos":[6307,6437]},{"content":"They also gain visibility into \"shift swap\" and \"shift offer\" requests, and can approve or reject those requests.","pos":[6438,6551]},{"content":"Store associates gain visibility into shifts and assigned schedules, together with instructions for the shifts, and gain visibility into the co-workers who are assigned to shifts.","pos":[6553,6732]},{"content":"They can also submit absence requests, requests for shift swaps with co-workers, and shift offer requests.","pos":[6733,6839]},{"pos":[6844,6888],"content":"Customize and administer Retail environments","linkify":"Customize and administer Retail environments","nodes":[{"content":"Customize and administer Retail environments","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":"If you've been asked to customize your environment, or if you're responsible for deploying and maintaining your system, be sure to see the developer and system administrator content that is specific to Retail, in addition to the more general content.","pos":[6889,7139]},{"pos":[7143,7230],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dynamics 365 for Retail for IT Pros and Developers<ept id=\"p1\">](dev-itpro/dev-retail-home-page.md)</ept>","source":"[Dynamics 365 for Retail for IT Pros and Developers](dev-itpro/dev-retail-home-page.md)"},{"pos":[7233,7368],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail for Developers and IT Pros<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/developer-home-page)</ept>","source":"[Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail for Developers and IT Pros](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/developer-home-page)"},{"pos":[7373,7393],"content":"Additional resources","linkify":"Additional resources","nodes":[{"content":"Additional resources","pos":[0,20]}]},{"pos":[7398,7427],"content":"What's new and in development","linkify":"What's new and in development","nodes":[{"content":"What's new and in development","pos":[0,29]}]},{"pos":[7428,7587],"content":"Go to the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics 365 Roadmap<ept id=\"p1\">](https://roadmap.dynamics.com/)</ept> to see what new features have been released and what new features are in development.","source":"Go to the [Microsoft Dynamics 365 Roadmap](https://roadmap.dynamics.com/) to see what new features have been released and what new features are in development."},{"pos":[7593,7598],"content":"Blogs","linkify":"Blogs","nodes":[{"content":"Blogs","pos":[0,5]}]},{"pos":[7599,7771],"content":"You can find opinions, news, and other information about Retail and other solutions on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics 365 blog<ept id=\"p1\">](https://community.dynamics.com/b/msftdynamicsblog)</ept>.","source":"You can find opinions, news, and other information about Retail and other solutions on the [Microsoft Dynamics 365 blog](https://community.dynamics.com/b/msftdynamicsblog)."},{"content":"There are many posts about Retail on the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics AX product team blog<ept id=\"p1\">](https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dax/)</ept>.","pos":[7773,7895],"source":"There are many posts about Retail on the [Microsoft Dynamics AX product team blog](https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/dax/)."},{"content":"Although some of these posts were written for the previous version of Retail, the same concepts still apply.","pos":[7896,8004]},{"content":"and the procedures are also similar in the current version.","pos":[8005,8064]},{"pos":[8066,8314],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft Dynamics Operations Partner Community Blog<ept id=\"p1\">](https://community.dynamics.com/partner/b/operationspartnercommunityblog)</ept> gives Microsoft Dynamics Partners a single resource where they can learn what is new and trending in MBS Operations.","source":"The [Microsoft Dynamics Operations Partner Community Blog](https://community.dynamics.com/partner/b/operationspartnercommunityblog) gives Microsoft Dynamics Partners a single resource where they can learn what is new and trending in MBS Operations."}]}