{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: System requirements\ndescription: This topic lists the system requirements for the current version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition for cloud and on-premises deployments.\nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 07/14/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 55651\nms.assetid: e564d51d-42d3-47c5-b388-93b8219c692a\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sericks\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-08-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 2\n\n---\n\n# System requirements\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic lists the system requirements for the current version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition, for cloud and on-premises deployments. Before you install Finance and Operations, when appropriate, verify that the system that you're working with meets or exceeds the minimum network, hardware, and software requirements.\n\n\n## Supported Microsoft Office applications\nThe following Office applications are supported in the cloud and on-premises deployments of Finance and Operations.\n-   To run the Microsoft Excel and Word add-ins, you must have Microsoft Office 2016 for Windows or Mac installed. For more details about version requirements, see [Office integration troubleshooting](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/office-integration/office-integration-troubleshooting).\n-   To view documents that are generated by the Export to Excel or Export to Word functionality, you must have Microsoft Office 2007 or later installed.\n\n# System requirements specific to cloud deployments\n## Network requirements\n-   Finance and Operations is designed for networks with latency of 250-300 milliseconds (ms) or less. This is the latency from a browser client to the Microsoft Azure data center that hosts Finance and Operations. We recommend that you test network latency at <http://www.azurespeed.com>.\n-   Bandwidth requirements for Finance and Operations depend on your scenario. Most typical scenarios require a bandwidth of more than 50 kilobytes per second (KBps). However, for scenarios that have high payload requirements, such as workspaces or scenarios that involve extensive customization, more bandwidth is recommended.\n\nIn general, Finance and Operations is optimized for the Internet. The number of round trips from a browser client to the Azure data center is very small, and the whole payload is compressed. \n\n> [!WARNING]\n> Don't compute bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements. The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate. For customers who are concerned about bandwidth requirements, use a preview version of Finance and Operations.\n\n## .NET Framework requirements\nFinance and Operations requires .NET Framework version 4.6.2 for all click-once applications, such as the document routing agent. For installation instructions, see [Installing the .NET Framework](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/5a4x27ek(v=vs.110).aspx).\n\n## Supported web browsers\nThe web application can run in any of the following web browsers that run on the specified operating systems:\n\n\n-   Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10\n-   Internet Explorer 11 on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7\n-   Google Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, Windows 8, Windows 7, or Google Nexus 10 tablet\n-   Apple Safari (latest publicly available version) on Mac OS X 10.10 (Yosemite), 10.11 (El Capitan) or 10.12 (Sierra), or Apple iPad\n\nTo find the latest release for each web browser, go to the software manufacturer’s website. \n\n> [!NOTE]\n> -   A pre-release Chrome extension must be installed to allow screenshot images to be captured by Task Recorder and included in generated Microsoft Word documents. <!---For instructions about how to install the extension, see [Screenshot Extension setup](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/user-interface/task-recorder).-->\n> -   The Workflow Editor is started as a ClickOnce application. Only Microsoft Edge and Internet Explorer (on a supported version of Microsoft Windows) support ClickOnce applications. The Workflow Editor ClickOnce application requires a 64-bit compatible operating system.\n> -   The Report Designer for Financial reporting is started as a ClickOnce application. It requires a 64-bit compatible operating system. If you’re using Chrome, you must install a ClickOnce extension to download the report designer client. If you’re using Chrome with the incognito mode, make sure that the ClickOnce extension is also enabled for incognito mode.\n> -   To preview PDF files, we recommend that you use browsers such as Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10,  or Google Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, Windows 8, Windows 7, or Google Nexus 10 tablet.\n\n\n### Supported web browsers for Retail Cloud POS\n\nRetail Cloud POS can run in any of the following web browsers that run on the specified operating systems:\n\n-   Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10\n-   Internet Explorer 11 on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7\n-   Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7\n\n## Retail Modern POS requirements\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> If Retail Modern POS will utilize an offline database, then the computer must meet all system requirements for Microsoft SQL Server. Retail Modern POS offline database will function on SQL Server 2012 with Service Pack 3 or later, SQL 2014 with Service Pack 2 or later, and SQL Server 2016.  It is always recommended to use the newest version available with the latest service pack installed.\n\n### Supported operating systems\n\n-   Retail Modern POS is a 32-bit application, but it will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.\n-   Retail Modern POS is supported only on Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise Long Term Servicing Branch (LTSB) editions.\n\n### Minimum system requirements\n\n-   The minimum supported resolution is 1280 × 1024.\n-   The computer that Retail Modern POS runs on must meet these requirements:\n    -   It must have, at a minimum, a dual-core processor that runs at no less than 2 gigahertz (GHz).\n    -   It must have, at a minimum, 3 gigabytes (GB) of RAM.\n    -   It must have Internet access.\n\n## Retail hardware station requirements\n### Supported operating systems\n\n-   Retail hardware station is a 32-bit application, but it will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.\n-   Retail hardware station is supported on the following operating systems:\n    -   Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, and Ultimate editions \n    \n    > [!NOTE]\n    > Windows 7 is supported only if Internet Explorer 11 is manually installed on the system.\n\n    -   Windows 8.1 Update 1 Professional, Enterprise, and Embedded editions\n    -   Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise LTSB editions\n\n### Minimum system requirements\n\nThe computer must meet all system requirements for installing and using the following items:\n\n-   Internet Information Services (IIS)\n-   Third-party hardware\n\n## Retail Store Scale Unit requirements\n### Supported operating systems\n\n-   Retail Store Scale Unit is a 32-bit application, but it will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.\n-   Retail Store Scale Unit is supported on the following operating systems:\n    -   Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, and Ultimate editions\n    -   Windows 8.1 Update 1 Professional, Enterprise, and Embedded editions\n    -   Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise LTSB editions\n\n### Minimum system requirements\n\n-   4 GB of RAM\n-   1.6 GHz peak CPU speed per core (Two cores are the minimum.)\n-   At least 10 GB of free space (The channel database can require a large amount of space.)\n\n### Recommended system requirements\n\n-   6 GB of RAM\n-   2.4 GHz i7 (or equivalent) peak CPU speed per core (Four cores are recommended.)\n-   At least 10 GB of free space (The channel database can require a large amount of space.)\n\n## Connector requirements\n### Supported operating systems\n\n-   The Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX has two separate installers, the **Async Server Connector service** and the **Real-time service for Dynamics AX 2012 R3**.\n-   Both components are 32-bit applications, but will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.\n-   Both components are supported on the following operating systems:\n    -   Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, and Ultimate editions\n    -   Windows 8.1 Update 1 Professional, Enterprise, and Embedded editions\n    -   Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise LTSB editions\n    -   Windows Server 2012 R2, Windows Server 2016\n\n### Minimum system requirements\n\n-   2 GB of RAM, 4 GB of RAM recommended\n-   1.6 GHz peak CPU speed per core (Two cores are the minimum.)\n-   At least 10 GB of free space (The channel database can require a large amount of space.)\n\n## Requirements for development on local VMs\nFor information about the requirements for development on local virtual machines (VMs), see [VM running on-premises](../dev-tools/access-instances.md).\n\n# System requirements for on-premises deployments\n\n## Network requirements\nFinance and Operations (on-premises) can work on networks that use Internet Protocol Version 4 (IPv4) or Internet Protocol Version 6 (IPv6). Consider the network environment when you plan your system and use the following guidelines.\n\n### Network response time\nThe following table lists the minimum network requirements for the connection between the web browser and Application Object Server (AOS), and for the connection between AOS and the database in an on-premises system.\n\n| Value     | Web browser to AOS | AOS to database                                            |\n|-----------|--------------------|------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Bandwidth | 50 KBps per user   | 100 MBps                                                   |\n| Latency   | < 250-300 ms       | < 1 ms (LAN only). AOS and database need to be co-located. |\n\n- Finance and Operations (on-premises) is designed for networks that have a latency of 250–300 milliseconds (ms) or less. This latency is the latency from a browser client to the data center that hosts Finance and Operations.\n- Bandwidth requirements for Finance and Operations (on-premises) depend on your scenario. Typical scenarios require a bandwidth of more than 50 kilobytes per second (KBps) between the browser and the Finance and Operations server. However, for scenarios that have high payload requirements, such as workspaces or scenarios that involve extensive customization, higher bandwidth is recommended and depends on use.\nDeployments where the AOS and the SQL Server Database are in different data centers are not supported. The AOS and the SQL Server database need to be co-located. \nIn general, Finance and Operations is optimized to reduce browser-to-server round trips. The number of round trips from a browser client to the data center is either zero or one for each user interaction, and the payload is compressed.\n\n> [!WARNING]\n> Do not calculate bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements. The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate. We suggest using a real-life simulation against a non-production environment of Finance and Operations as the best gauge of performance for your specific case. \n\n### LAN environments\nIn local area network (LAN) environments, Microsoft Remote Desktop in Microsoft Windows Server is not required to connect to Finance and Operations. However, it might be required for servicing operations on the VMs that make up the server deployments.\n\n### WAN environments\nIn wide area network (WAN) environments, Remote Desktop in Windows Server is not required to connect to Finance and Operations.\n\n### Internet connectivity requirements\nFinance and Operations (on-premises) does not require Internet connectivity from end user work stations. However, some features will not be available without Internet connectivity.\n\n| Browser client | An intranet scenario without Internet connectivity is a design point for the on-premises deployment option. Some features that require cloud services will not be available, such as Help and Task guide libraries in LCS. |\n|----------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Server         | The AOS or Service Fabric tier must be able to communicate with LCS. The on-premises browser-based client does not require Internet access.                                                                                |\n| Telemetry      | Telemetry data might be lost if there are long interruptions in connectivity. Interruptions in connectivity to LCS do not affect the on-premises application functionality.                                                |\n| LCS            | Connectivity to LCS is required for deployment, code deployment, and servicing operations.                                                                                                                                 |\n## Telemetry data transfer to the cloud\nMost telemetry is stored locally and can be accessed by using Event Viewer in Microsoft Windows. A small subset of telemetry events is transferred to the Microsoft telemetry pipeline in the cloud for diagnostics. Customer data and end user identifiable data are not part of the telemetry sent to Microsoft. VM names are sent to Microsoft to aid in environment management and diagnostics from the LCS portal.\n\n## Domain requirements\nConsider the following domain requirements when you install Finance and Operations (on-premises):\n\n- Virtual machines that host Finance and Operations (on-premises) components must belong to an Active Directory Domain. Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) must be configured in native mode.\n- Virtual Machines that run Finance and Operations (on-premises) components must have access to each other configured in Active Directory Domain Services. \n- The domain controller must be Windows Server 2012 R2 or later with a domain functional level of 2012 R2 or greater.\n\n## Hardware requirements\nThis section describes the hardware that is required to run Finance and Operations (on-premises).\nBased on the system configuration, data composition, and the applications and features that you decide to use, the actual hardware requirements will vary. Here are some of the factors that could affect the choice of appropriate hardware for Finance and Operations (on-premises):\n\n- The number of transactions per hour.\n- The number of concurrent users.\n\n## Minimum infrastructure requirements\nFinance and Operations (on-premises) uses Microsoft Azure Service Fabric to host the AOS, Batch, Data management, Management reporter, and Environment orchestrator services. Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) are not hosted in the Service Fabric cluster.\nSQL Server must be set up in a high-availability HADRON setup that has at least two nodes for production use.\nThe following figure shows the minimum recommended number of nodes in your Service Fabric cluster.\n\n[![recommended number of nodes for service fabric cluster](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-01.png)](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-01.png) \n\n## Processor and RAM requirements\nThe following table lists the number of processors and the amount of random-access memory (RAM) that are required for each of the roles required to run this deployment option. For more information, read the minimum requirements recommendation for Service Fabric standalone cluster, [Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation).\n\n> [!NOTE]\n> If other Microsoft software is installed on the same computer, the system must also comply with the hardware requirements for that software. We recommend that you limit other server applications on the same computer as AOS to 1 gigabyte (GB) of RAM.\n\n**Sizing by role and topology type**\n\n| Topology   | Role (node type)              | Recommended processor cores | Recommended memory (GB) |\n|------------|-------------------------------|-----------------------------|-------------------------|\n| Production | AOS, Data management, Batch   | 8                           | 24                      |\n|            | Management Reporter           | 4                           | 16                      |\n|            | SQL Server Reporting Services | 4                           | 16                      |\n|            | Orchestrator                  | 4                           | 16                      |\n| Sandbox    | AOS, Data management, Batch   | 4                           | 24                      |\n|            | Management Reporter           | 4                           | 16                      |\n|            | SQL Server Reporting Services | 4                           | 16                      |\n|            | Orchestrator                  | 4                           | 16                      |\n\n**Minimum sizing estimates for production and sandbox deployments**\\*\n\n| Topology                                  | Role                          | Number of instances |\n|-------------------------------------------|-------------------------------|---------------------|\n| Production                                | AOS (Data management, Batch)  | 3                   |\n|                                           | Management Reporter           | 2                   |\n|                                           | SQL Server Reporting Services | 1                   |\n|                                           | Orchestrator\\*\\*                | 3                   |\n| Sandbox                                   | AOS, Data management, Batch   | 2                   |\n|                                           | Management Reporter           | 1                   |\n|                                           | SQL Server Reporting Services | 1                   |\n|                                           | Orchestrator                  | 3                   |\n| *Summary Production and Sandbox topologies* |                               | 16                  |\n\n\\*These numbers are being validated by our preview customers and may be adjusted as needed based on that feedback.\n\n\\*\\*Orchestrator is designated as the primary node type and will be used to run the Service Fabric services as well.\n\n**Backend SQL Server and AD initial estimates**\n\n[![Back end SQL server and AD initial estimates](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-02.PNG)](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-02.PNG) \n\n\\*SQL Server sizes are highly dependent on workloads. For more information, see the topic [Hardware sizing for on-premises environments](hardware-sizing-on-premises-environments.md).\n\n## Storage\n\n- **AOS** - Finance and Operations (on-premises) will use a Server Message Block (SMB) 3.0 share to store unstructured data. For more information, see [Storage Spaces Direct in Windows Server 2016](/windows-server/storage/storage-spaces/storage-spaces-direct-overview).\n- **SQL** – Viable options:\n    - A highly available solid-state drive (SSD) setup.\n    - A storage area network (SAN) optimized for OLTP throughputs.\n    - High performance Direct-attached storage (DAS) \n- **SQL and data management IOPS** – The storage for both data management and SQL Server should have at least 2,000 input/output operations per second (IOPS). Production IOPS depends on many factors. For more information, see the topic [Hardware sizing for on-premises environments](hardware-sizing-on-premises-environments.md).\n- **Virtual machine IOPS** – Each virtual machine should have at least 100 write IOPS.\n\n## Virtual host requirements\nWhen you set up the virtual hosts for a Finance and Operations (on-premises) environment, refer to the following guidelines: [Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation) and [Describing a service fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-resource-manager-cluster-description). Each virtual host should have enough cores for the infrastructure that is being sized. Multiple advanced configurations are possible, where SQL Server resides on physical hardware but everything else is virtualized. If SQL Server is virtualized, the disk subsystem should be a fast SAN or the equivalent. In all cases, make sure that the basic setup of the virtual host is highly available and redundant. In all cases, when virtualization is used, no VM snapshots should be taken.\n\n## Software requirements for all server computers\nThe following software must be present on a computer before any Finance and Operations (on-premises) components can be installed:\n\n- Microsoft .NET Framework 4.5.1 or higher\n- Service Fabric\nFor more information, see [Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation).\n\n## Supported server operating systems\nThe following table lists the server operating systems that are supported for Finance and Operations components.\n\n| Operating system                                     | Notes                                                                                  |\n|------------------------------------------------------|----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Microsoft Windows Server 2016 Datacenter or Standard | These requirements are for the database and the Service Fabric cluster that hosts AOS. |\n\n## Software requirements for database servers\n\n- Only 64-bit versions of SQL Server 2016 are supported.\n- In a production environment, we recommend that you install the latest cumulative update (CU) for the version of SQL Server that you’re using.\n- Finance and Operations (on-premises) supports Unicode collations that are case-insensitive, accent-sensitive, kana-sensitive, and width-insensitive. The collation must match the Windows locale of the computers that are running AOS instances. If you’re setting up a new installation, we recommend that you select a Windows collation instead of a SQL Server collation. For more information about how to select a collation for a SQL Server database, see the [SQL Server documentation](/sql/sql-server/sql-server-technical-documentation).\nThe following table lists the SQL Server versions that are supported for the Finance and Operations databases. For more information, see the minimum hardware requirements for [SQL Server](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/sql-server/sql-server-2016).\n\n| Requirement                                                      | Notes                                                                                                                     |\n|------------------------------------------------------------------|---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Microsoft SQL Server 2016 Standard Edition or Enterprise Edition | For the hardware requirements for SQL Server 2016, see [Hardware and Software Requirements for Installing SQL Server 2016](/sql/sql-server/install/hardware-and-software-requirements-for-installing-sql-server). |\n\n## Software requirements for client computers\nThe Finance and Operations web application can run on any device with an HTML5.0 compliant web browser. Specific device/browser combinations that Microsoft has confirmed include:\n\n- Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10\n- Internet Explorer 11 on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7\n- Google Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, Windows 8, Windows 7, or Google Nexus 10 tablet\n- Apple Safari (latest publicly available version) on Mac OS X 10.10 (Yosemite), 10.11 (El Capitan) or 10.12 (Sierra), or Apple iPad\n\n## Software requirements for Active Directory Federation Services \nActive Directory Federation Services (AD FS) on Windows Server 2016\n\nThe domain controller must be Windows Server 2012 R2 or later with a domain functional level of 2012 R2 or greater\n\nFor more information about domain functional levels, see: \n- [What Are Active Directory Functional Levels](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc787290(v=ws.10).aspx)\n- [Understanding Active Directory Domain Services Functional Levels](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/understanding-active-directory-functional-levels(v=ws.10).aspx)\n \n## Hardware and software requirements for Retail components\nFinance and Operations (on-premises) does not include the Retail components at this time.\n\nSee also\n--------\n\n[Get an evaluation copy of Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/get-evaluation-copy)\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,748],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: System requirements\ndescription: This topic lists the system requirements for the current version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition for cloud and on-premises deployments.\nauthor: sericks007\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 07/14/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: robinr\nms.search.scope: Core\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 55651\nms.assetid: e564d51d-42d3-47c5-b388-93b8219c692a\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: sericks\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-08-30\nms.dyn365.ops.version: Platform update 2\n","nodes":[{"content":"System requirements","nodes":[{"pos":[0,19],"content":"System requirements","nodes":[{"content":"System requirements","pos":[0,19]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This topic lists the system requirements for the current version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition for cloud and on-premises deployments.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,172],"content":"This topic lists the system requirements for the current version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition for cloud and on-premises deployments.","nodes":[{"content":"This topic lists the system requirements for the current version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition for cloud and on-premises deployments.","pos":[0,172]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[756,775],"content":"System requirements","linkify":"System requirements","nodes":[{"content":"System requirements","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"This topic lists the system requirements for the current version of Microsoft Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition, for cloud and on-premises deployments.","pos":[821,994]},{"content":"Before you install Finance and Operations, when appropriate, verify that the system that you're working with meets or exceeds the minimum network, hardware, and software requirements.","pos":[995,1178]},{"pos":[1184,1223],"content":"Supported Microsoft Office applications","linkify":"Supported Microsoft Office applications","nodes":[{"content":"Supported Microsoft Office applications","pos":[0,39]}]},{"content":"The following Office applications are supported in the cloud and on-premises deployments of Finance and Operations.","pos":[1224,1339]},{"content":"To run the Microsoft Excel and Word add-ins, you must have Microsoft Office 2016 for Windows or Mac installed.","pos":[1344,1454]},{"content":"For more details about version requirements, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Office integration troubleshooting<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/office-integration/office-integration-troubleshooting)</ept>.","pos":[1455,1638],"source":" For more details about version requirements, see [Office integration troubleshooting](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/office-integration/office-integration-troubleshooting)."},{"content":"To view documents that are generated by the Export to Excel or Export to Word functionality, you must have Microsoft Office 2007 or later installed.","pos":[1643,1791]},{"pos":[1795,1844],"content":"System requirements specific to cloud deployments","linkify":"System requirements specific to cloud deployments","nodes":[{"content":"System requirements specific to cloud deployments","pos":[0,49]}]},{"pos":[1848,1868],"content":"Network requirements","linkify":"Network requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Network requirements","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Finance and Operations is designed for networks with latency of 250-300 milliseconds (ms) or less.","pos":[1873,1971]},{"content":"This is the latency from a browser client to the Microsoft Azure data center that hosts Finance and Operations.","pos":[1972,2083]},{"content":"We recommend that you test network latency at <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;</bpt>http://www.azurespeed.com<ept id=\"p1\">&gt;</ept>.","pos":[2084,2158],"source":" We recommend that you test network latency at <http://www.azurespeed.com>."},{"content":"Bandwidth requirements for Finance and Operations depend on your scenario.","pos":[2163,2237]},{"content":"Most typical scenarios require a bandwidth of more than 50 kilobytes per second (KBps).","pos":[2238,2325]},{"content":"However, for scenarios that have high payload requirements, such as workspaces or scenarios that involve extensive customization, more bandwidth is recommended.","pos":[2326,2486]},{"content":"In general, Finance and Operations is optimized for the Internet.","pos":[2488,2553]},{"content":"The number of round trips from a browser client to the Azure data center is very small, and the whole payload is compressed.","pos":[2554,2678]},{"pos":[2683,3013],"content":"[!WARNING]\nDon't compute bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements. The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate. For customers who are concerned about bandwidth requirements, use a preview version of Finance and Operations.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Don't compute bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements. The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate. For customers who are concerned about bandwidth requirements, use a preview version of Finance and Operations.","pos":[11,328],"nodes":[{"content":"Don't compute bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements.","pos":[0,133]},{"content":"The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate.","pos":[134,206]},{"content":"For customers who are concerned about bandwidth requirements, use a preview version of Finance and Operations.","pos":[207,317]}]}]},{"pos":[3018,3045],"content":".NET Framework requirements","linkify":".NET Framework requirements","nodes":[{"content":".NET Framework requirements","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Finance and Operations requires .NET Framework version 4.6.2 for all click-once applications, such as the document routing agent.","pos":[3046,3175]},{"content":"For installation instructions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Installing the .NET Framework<ept id=\"p1\">](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/5a4x27ek(v=vs.110).aspx)</ept>.","pos":[3176,3309],"source":" For installation instructions, see [Installing the .NET Framework](https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/5a4x27ek(v=vs.110).aspx)."},{"pos":[3314,3336],"content":"Supported web browsers","linkify":"Supported web browsers","nodes":[{"content":"Supported web browsers","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"The web application can run in any of the following web browsers that run on the specified operating systems:","pos":[3337,3446]},{"content":"Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10","pos":[3453,3517]},{"content":"Internet Explorer 11 on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7","pos":[3522,3583]},{"content":"Google Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, Windows 8, Windows 7, or Google Nexus 10 tablet","pos":[3588,3713]},{"content":"Apple Safari (latest publicly available version) on Mac OS X 10.10 (Yosemite), 10.11 (El Capitan) or 10.12 (Sierra), or Apple iPad","pos":[3718,3848]},{"content":"To find the latest release for each web browser, go to the software manufacturer’s website.","pos":[3850,3941]},{"content":"A pre-release Chrome extension must be installed to allow screenshot images to be captured by Task Recorder and included in generated Microsoft Word documents.","pos":[3960,4119]},{"content":"The Workflow Editor is started as a ClickOnce application.","pos":[4293,4351]},{"content":"Only Microsoft Edge and Internet Explorer (on a supported version of Microsoft Windows) support ClickOnce applications.","pos":[4352,4471]},{"content":"The Workflow Editor ClickOnce application requires a 64-bit compatible operating system.","pos":[4472,4560]},{"content":"The Report Designer for Financial reporting is started as a ClickOnce application.","pos":[4567,4649]},{"content":"It requires a 64-bit compatible operating system.","pos":[4650,4699]},{"content":"If you’re using Chrome, you must install a ClickOnce extension to download the report designer client.","pos":[4700,4802]},{"content":"If you’re using Chrome with the incognito mode, make sure that the ClickOnce extension is also enabled for incognito mode.","pos":[4803,4925]},{"content":"To preview PDF files, we recommend that you use browsers such as Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10,  or Google Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, Windows 8, Windows 7, or Google Nexus 10 tablet.","pos":[4932,5193]},{"pos":[5200,5243],"content":"Supported web browsers for Retail Cloud POS","linkify":"Supported web browsers for Retail Cloud POS","nodes":[{"content":"Supported web browsers for Retail Cloud POS","pos":[0,43]}]},{"content":"Retail Cloud POS can run in any of the following web browsers that run on the specified operating systems:","pos":[5245,5351]},{"content":"Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10","pos":[5357,5421]},{"content":"Internet Explorer 11 on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7","pos":[5426,5487]},{"content":"Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7","pos":[5492,5575]},{"pos":[5580,5610],"content":"Retail Modern POS requirements","linkify":"Retail Modern POS requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Retail Modern POS requirements","pos":[0,30]}]},{"pos":[5614,6016],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf Retail Modern POS will utilize an offline database, then the computer must meet all system requirements for Microsoft SQL Server. Retail Modern POS offline database will function on SQL Server 2012 with Service Pack 3 or later, SQL 2014 with Service Pack 2 or later, and SQL Server 2016.  It is always recommended to use the newest version available with the latest service pack installed.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"If Retail Modern POS will utilize an offline database, then the computer must meet all system requirements for Microsoft SQL Server. Retail Modern POS offline database will function on SQL Server 2012 with Service Pack 3 or later, SQL 2014 with Service Pack 2 or later, and SQL Server 2016.  It is always recommended to use the newest version available with the latest service pack installed.","pos":[8,400],"nodes":[{"content":"If Retail Modern POS will utilize an offline database, then the computer must meet all system requirements for Microsoft SQL Server.","pos":[0,132]},{"content":"Retail Modern POS offline database will function on SQL Server 2012 with Service Pack 3 or later, SQL 2014 with Service Pack 2 or later, and SQL Server 2016.","pos":[133,290]},{"content":"It is always recommended to use the newest version available with the latest service pack installed.","pos":[292,392]}]}]},{"pos":[6022,6049],"content":"Supported operating systems","linkify":"Supported operating systems","nodes":[{"content":"Supported operating systems","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Retail Modern POS is a 32-bit application, but it will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.","pos":[6055,6148]},{"content":"Retail Modern POS is supported only on Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise Long Term Servicing Branch (LTSB) editions.","pos":[6153,6278]},{"pos":[6284,6311],"content":"Minimum system requirements","linkify":"Minimum system requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Minimum system requirements","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"The minimum supported resolution is 1280 × 1024.","pos":[6317,6365]},{"content":"The computer that Retail Modern POS runs on must meet these requirements:","pos":[6370,6443]},{"content":"It must have, at a minimum, a dual-core processor that runs at no less than 2 gigahertz (GHz).","pos":[6452,6546]},{"content":"It must have, at a minimum, 3 gigabytes (GB) of RAM.","pos":[6555,6607]},{"content":"It must have Internet access.","pos":[6616,6645]},{"pos":[6650,6686],"content":"Retail hardware station requirements","linkify":"Retail hardware station requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Retail hardware station requirements","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[6691,6718],"content":"Supported operating systems","linkify":"Supported operating systems","nodes":[{"content":"Supported operating systems","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Retail hardware station is a 32-bit application, but it will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.","pos":[6724,6823]},{"content":"Retail hardware station is supported on the following operating systems:","pos":[6828,6900]},{"content":"Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, and Ultimate editions","pos":[6909,6966]},{"pos":[6979,7081],"content":"[!NOTE]\nWindows 7 is supported only if Internet Explorer 11 is manually installed on the system.","leadings":["","    > "],"nodes":[{"content":"Windows 7 is supported only if Internet Explorer 11 is manually installed on the system.","pos":[8,96]}]},{"content":"Windows 8.1 Update 1 Professional, Enterprise, and Embedded editions","pos":[7091,7159]},{"content":"Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise LTSB editions","pos":[7168,7224]},{"pos":[7230,7257],"content":"Minimum system requirements","linkify":"Minimum system requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Minimum system requirements","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"The computer must meet all system requirements for installing and using the following items:","pos":[7259,7351]},{"content":"Internet Information Services (IIS)","pos":[7357,7392]},{"content":"Third-party hardware","pos":[7397,7417]},{"pos":[7422,7458],"content":"Retail Store Scale Unit requirements","linkify":"Retail Store Scale Unit requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Retail Store Scale Unit requirements","pos":[0,36]}]},{"pos":[7463,7490],"content":"Supported operating systems","linkify":"Supported operating systems","nodes":[{"content":"Supported operating systems","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"Retail Store Scale Unit is a 32-bit application, but it will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.","pos":[7496,7595]},{"content":"Retail Store Scale Unit is supported on the following operating systems:","pos":[7600,7672]},{"content":"Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, and Ultimate editions","pos":[7681,7738]},{"content":"Windows 8.1 Update 1 Professional, Enterprise, and Embedded editions","pos":[7747,7815]},{"content":"Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise LTSB editions","pos":[7824,7880]},{"pos":[7886,7913],"content":"Minimum system requirements","linkify":"Minimum system requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Minimum system requirements","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"4 GB of RAM","pos":[7919,7930]},{"content":"1.6 GHz peak CPU speed per core (Two cores are the minimum.)","pos":[7935,7995]},{"content":"At least 10 GB of free space (The channel database can require a large amount of space.)","pos":[8000,8088]},{"pos":[8094,8125],"content":"Recommended system requirements","linkify":"Recommended system requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Recommended system requirements","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"6 GB of RAM","pos":[8131,8142]},{"content":"2.4 GHz i7 (or equivalent) peak CPU speed per core (Four cores are recommended.)","pos":[8147,8227]},{"content":"At least 10 GB of free space (The channel database can require a large amount of space.)","pos":[8232,8320]},{"pos":[8325,8347],"content":"Connector requirements","linkify":"Connector requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Connector requirements","pos":[0,22]}]},{"pos":[8352,8379],"content":"Supported operating systems","linkify":"Supported operating systems","nodes":[{"content":"Supported operating systems","pos":[0,27]}]},{"pos":[8385,8547],"content":"The Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX has two separate installers, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Async Server Connector service<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Real-time service for Dynamics AX 2012 R3<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"The Connector for Microsoft Dynamics AX has two separate installers, the **Async Server Connector service** and the **Real-time service for Dynamics AX 2012 R3**."},{"content":"Both components are 32-bit applications, but will run on both x86 and x64 architectures.","pos":[8552,8640]},{"content":"Both components are supported on the following operating systems:","pos":[8645,8710]},{"content":"Windows 7 Professional, Enterprise, and Ultimate editions","pos":[8719,8776]},{"content":"Windows 8.1 Update 1 Professional, Enterprise, and Embedded editions","pos":[8785,8853]},{"content":"Windows 10 Pro, Enterprise, and Enterprise LTSB editions","pos":[8862,8918]},{"content":"Windows Server 2012 R2, Windows Server 2016","pos":[8927,8970]},{"pos":[8976,9003],"content":"Minimum system requirements","linkify":"Minimum system requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Minimum system requirements","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"2 GB of RAM, 4 GB of RAM recommended","pos":[9009,9045]},{"content":"1.6 GHz peak CPU speed per core (Two cores are the minimum.)","pos":[9050,9110]},{"content":"At least 10 GB of free space (The channel database can require a large amount of space.)","pos":[9115,9203]},{"pos":[9208,9249],"content":"Requirements for development on local VMs","linkify":"Requirements for development on local VMs","nodes":[{"content":"Requirements for development on local VMs","pos":[0,41]}]},{"pos":[9250,9401],"content":"For information about the requirements for development on local virtual machines (VMs), see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>VM running on-premises<ept id=\"p1\">](../dev-tools/access-instances.md)</ept>.","source":"For information about the requirements for development on local virtual machines (VMs), see [VM running on-premises](../dev-tools/access-instances.md)."},{"pos":[9405,9452],"content":"System requirements for on-premises deployments","linkify":"System requirements for on-premises deployments","nodes":[{"content":"System requirements for on-premises deployments","pos":[0,47]}]},{"pos":[9457,9477],"content":"Network requirements","linkify":"Network requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Network requirements","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Finance and Operations (on-premises) can work on networks that use Internet Protocol Version 4 (IPv4) or Internet Protocol Version 6 (IPv6).","pos":[9478,9618]},{"content":"Consider the network environment when you plan your system and use the following guidelines.","pos":[9619,9711]},{"pos":[9717,9738],"content":"Network response time","linkify":"Network response time","nodes":[{"content":"Network response time","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"The following table lists the minimum network requirements for the connection between the web browser and Application Object Server (AOS), and for the connection between AOS and the database in an on-premises system.","pos":[9739,9955]},{"content":"Value","pos":[9959,9964]},{"content":"Web browser to AOS","pos":[9971,9989]},{"content":"AOS to database","pos":[9992,10007]},{"content":"Bandwidth","pos":[10151,10160]},{"content":"50 KBps per user","pos":[10163,10179]},{"content":"100 MBps","pos":[10184,10192]},{"content":"Latency","pos":[10247,10254]},{"content":"&lt; 250-300 ms","pos":[10259,10271],"source":"< 250-300 ms"},{"content":"&lt; 1 ms (LAN only).","pos":[10280,10298],"source":"< 1 ms (LAN only)."},{"content":"AOS and database need to be co-located.","pos":[10299,10338]},{"content":"Finance and Operations (on-premises) is designed for networks that have a latency of 250–300 milliseconds (ms) or less.","pos":[10344,10463]},{"content":"This latency is the latency from a browser client to the data center that hosts Finance and Operations.","pos":[10464,10567]},{"content":"Bandwidth requirements for Finance and Operations (on-premises) depend on your scenario.","pos":[10570,10658]},{"content":"Typical scenarios require a bandwidth of more than 50 kilobytes per second (KBps) between the browser and the Finance and Operations server.","pos":[10659,10799]},{"content":"However, for scenarios that have high payload requirements, such as workspaces or scenarios that involve extensive customization, higher bandwidth is recommended and depends on use.","pos":[10800,10981]},{"content":"Deployments where the AOS and the SQL Server Database are in different data centers are not supported.","pos":[10982,11084],"source":"\nDeployments where the AOS and the SQL Server Database are in different data centers are not supported."},{"content":"The AOS and the SQL Server database need to be co-located.","pos":[11085,11143]},{"content":"In general, Finance and Operations is optimized to reduce browser-to-server round trips.","pos":[11144,11233],"source":" \nIn general, Finance and Operations is optimized to reduce browser-to-server round trips."},{"content":"The number of round trips from a browser client to the data center is either zero or one for each user interaction, and the payload is compressed.","pos":[11234,11380]},{"pos":[11384,11766],"content":"[!WARNING]\nDo not calculate bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements. The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate. We suggest using a real-life simulation against a non-production environment of Finance and Operations as the best gauge of performance for your specific case.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"Do not calculate bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements. The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate. We suggest using a real-life simulation against a non-production environment of Finance and Operations as the best gauge of performance for your specific case.","pos":[11,380],"nodes":[{"content":"Do not calculate bandwidth requirements from a client location by multiplying the number of users by the minimum bandwidth requirements.","pos":[0,136]},{"content":"The concurrent usage of a given location is very difficult to calculate.","pos":[137,209]},{"content":"We suggest using a real-life simulation against a non-production environment of Finance and Operations as the best gauge of performance for your specific case.","pos":[210,369]}]}]},{"pos":[11773,11789],"content":"LAN environments","linkify":"LAN environments","nodes":[{"content":"LAN environments","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"In local area network (LAN) environments, Microsoft Remote Desktop in Microsoft Windows Server is not required to connect to Finance and Operations.","pos":[11790,11938]},{"content":"However, it might be required for servicing operations on the VMs that make up the server deployments.","pos":[11939,12041]},{"pos":[12047,12063],"content":"WAN environments","linkify":"WAN environments","nodes":[{"content":"WAN environments","pos":[0,16]}]},{"content":"In wide area network (WAN) environments, Remote Desktop in Windows Server is not required to connect to Finance and Operations.","pos":[12064,12191]},{"pos":[12197,12231],"content":"Internet connectivity requirements","linkify":"Internet connectivity requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Internet connectivity requirements","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"Finance and Operations (on-premises) does not require Internet connectivity from end user work stations.","pos":[12232,12336]},{"content":"However, some features will not be available without Internet connectivity.","pos":[12337,12412]},{"content":"Browser client","pos":[12416,12430]},{"content":"An intranet scenario without Internet connectivity is a design point for the on-premises deployment option.","pos":[12433,12540]},{"content":"Some features that require cloud services will not be available, such as Help and Task guide libraries in LCS.","pos":[12541,12651]},{"content":"Server","pos":[12896,12902]},{"content":"The AOS or Service Fabric tier must be able to communicate with LCS.","pos":[12913,12981]},{"content":"The on-premises browser-based client does not require Internet access.","pos":[12982,13052]},{"content":"Telemetry","pos":[13136,13145]},{"content":"Telemetry data might be lost if there are long interruptions in connectivity.","pos":[13153,13230]},{"content":"Interruptions in connectivity to LCS do not affect the on-premises application functionality.","pos":[13231,13324]},{"content":"LCS","pos":[13376,13379]},{"content":"Connectivity to LCS is required for deployment, code deployment, and servicing operations.","pos":[13393,13483]},{"pos":[13617,13653],"content":"Telemetry data transfer to the cloud","linkify":"Telemetry data transfer to the cloud","nodes":[{"content":"Telemetry data transfer to the cloud","pos":[0,36]}]},{"content":"Most telemetry is stored locally and can be accessed by using Event Viewer in Microsoft Windows.","pos":[13654,13750]},{"content":"A small subset of telemetry events is transferred to the Microsoft telemetry pipeline in the cloud for diagnostics.","pos":[13751,13866]},{"content":"Customer data and end user identifiable data are not part of the telemetry sent to Microsoft.","pos":[13867,13960]},{"content":"VM names are sent to Microsoft to aid in environment management and diagnostics from the LCS portal.","pos":[13961,14061]},{"pos":[14066,14085],"content":"Domain requirements","linkify":"Domain requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Domain requirements","pos":[0,19]}]},{"content":"Consider the following domain requirements when you install Finance and Operations (on-premises):","pos":[14086,14183]},{"content":"Virtual machines that host Finance and Operations (on-premises) components must belong to an Active Directory Domain.","pos":[14187,14304]},{"content":"Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) must be configured in native mode.","pos":[14305,14380]},{"content":"Virtual Machines that run Finance and Operations (on-premises) components must have access to each other configured in Active Directory Domain Services.","pos":[14383,14535]},{"content":"The domain controller must be Windows Server 2012 R2 or later with a domain functional level of 2012 R2 or greater.","pos":[14539,14654]},{"pos":[14659,14680],"content":"Hardware requirements","linkify":"Hardware requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Hardware requirements","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"This section describes the hardware that is required to run Finance and Operations (on-premises).","pos":[14681,14778]},{"content":"Based on the system configuration, data composition, and the applications and features that you decide to use, the actual hardware requirements will vary.","pos":[14779,14933],"source":"\nBased on the system configuration, data composition, and the applications and features that you decide to use, the actual hardware requirements will vary."},{"content":"Here are some of the factors that could affect the choice of appropriate hardware for Finance and Operations (on-premises):","pos":[14934,15057]},{"content":"The number of transactions per hour.","pos":[15061,15097]},{"content":"The number of concurrent users.","pos":[15100,15131]},{"pos":[15136,15171],"content":"Minimum infrastructure requirements","linkify":"Minimum infrastructure requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Minimum infrastructure requirements","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"Finance and Operations (on-premises) uses Microsoft Azure Service Fabric to host the AOS, Batch, Data management, Management reporter, and Environment orchestrator services.","pos":[15172,15345]},{"content":"Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) are not hosted in the Service Fabric cluster.","pos":[15346,15438]},{"content":"SQL Server must be set up in a high-availability HADRON setup that has at least two nodes for production use.","pos":[15439,15548],"source":"\nSQL Server must be set up in a high-availability HADRON setup that has at least two nodes for production use."},{"content":"The following figure shows the minimum recommended number of nodes in your Service Fabric cluster.","pos":[15549,15647],"source":"\nThe following figure shows the minimum recommended number of nodes in your Service Fabric cluster."},{"pos":[15649,15788],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>recommended number of nodes for service fabric cluster<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-01.png)](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-01.png)</ept>","source":"[![recommended number of nodes for service fabric cluster](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-01.png)](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-01.png)"},{"pos":[15794,15824],"content":"Processor and RAM requirements","linkify":"Processor and RAM requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Processor and RAM requirements","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"The following table lists the number of processors and the amount of random-access memory (RAM) that are required for each of the roles required to run this deployment option.","pos":[15825,16000]},{"content":"For more information, read the minimum requirements recommendation for Service Fabric standalone cluster, <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster<ept id=\"p1\">](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation)</ept>.","pos":[16001,16234],"source":" For more information, read the minimum requirements recommendation for Service Fabric standalone cluster, [Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation)."},{"pos":[16238,16497],"content":"[!NOTE]\nIf other Microsoft software is installed on the same computer, the system must also comply with the hardware requirements for that software. We recommend that you limit other server applications on the same computer as AOS to 1 gigabyte (GB) of RAM.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"If other Microsoft software is installed on the same computer, the system must also comply with the hardware requirements for that software. We recommend that you limit other server applications on the same computer as AOS to 1 gigabyte (GB) of RAM.","pos":[8,257],"nodes":[{"content":"If other Microsoft software is installed on the same computer, the system must also comply with the hardware requirements for that software.","pos":[0,140]},{"content":"We recommend that you limit other server applications on the same computer as AOS to 1 gigabyte (GB) of RAM.","pos":[141,249]}]}]},{"pos":[16499,16535],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sizing by role and topology type<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Sizing by role and topology type**"},{"content":"Topology","pos":[16539,16547]},{"content":"Role (node type)","pos":[16552,16568]},{"content":"Recommended processor cores","pos":[16584,16611]},{"content":"Recommended memory (GB)","pos":[16614,16637]},{"content":"Production","pos":[16745,16755]},{"content":"AOS, Data management, Batch","pos":[16758,16785]},{"content":"8","pos":[16790,16791]},{"content":"24","pos":[16820,16822]},{"content":"Management Reporter","pos":[16861,16880]},{"content":"4","pos":[16893,16894]},{"content":"16","pos":[16923,16925]},{"content":"SQL Server Reporting Services","pos":[16964,16993]},{"content":"4","pos":[16996,16997]},{"content":"16","pos":[17026,17028]},{"content":"Orchestrator","pos":[17067,17079]},{"content":"4","pos":[17099,17100]},{"content":"16","pos":[17129,17131]},{"content":"Sandbox","pos":[17157,17164]},{"content":"AOS, Data management, Batch","pos":[17170,17197]},{"content":"4","pos":[17202,17203]},{"content":"24","pos":[17232,17234]},{"content":"Management Reporter","pos":[17273,17292]},{"content":"4","pos":[17305,17306]},{"content":"16","pos":[17335,17337]},{"content":"SQL Server Reporting Services","pos":[17376,17405]},{"content":"4","pos":[17408,17409]},{"content":"16","pos":[17438,17440]},{"content":"Orchestrator","pos":[17479,17491]},{"content":"4","pos":[17511,17512]},{"content":"16","pos":[17541,17543]},{"pos":[17568,17637],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Minimum sizing estimates for production and sandbox deployments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph>","source":"**Minimum sizing estimates for production and sandbox deployments**\\*"},{"content":"Topology","pos":[17641,17649]},{"content":"Role","pos":[17685,17689]},{"content":"Number of instances","pos":[17717,17736]},{"content":"Production","pos":[17841,17851]},{"content":"AOS (Data management, Batch)","pos":[17885,17913]},{"content":"3","pos":[17917,17918]},{"content":"Management Reporter","pos":[17985,18004]},{"content":"2","pos":[18017,18018]},{"content":"SQL Server Reporting Services","pos":[18085,18114]},{"content":"1","pos":[18117,18118]},{"content":"Orchestrator<ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">\\*</ph>","pos":[18185,18201],"source":"Orchestrator\\*\\*"},{"content":"3","pos":[18219,18220]},{"content":"Sandbox","pos":[18243,18250]},{"content":"AOS, Data management, Batch","pos":[18287,18314]},{"content":"2","pos":[18319,18320]},{"content":"Management Reporter","pos":[18387,18406]},{"content":"1","pos":[18419,18420]},{"content":"SQL Server Reporting Services","pos":[18487,18516]},{"content":"1","pos":[18519,18520]},{"content":"Orchestrator","pos":[18587,18599]},{"content":"3","pos":[18619,18620]},{"pos":[18643,18686],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">*</bpt>Summary Production and Sandbox topologies<ept id=\"p1\">*</ept>","source":"*Summary Production and Sandbox topologies*"},{"content":"16","pos":[18721,18723]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph>These numbers are being validated by our preview customers and may be adjusted as needed based on that feedback.","pos":[18744,18858],"source":"\\*These numbers are being validated by our preview customers and may be adjusted as needed based on that feedback."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph><ph id=\"ph2\">\\*</ph>Orchestrator is designated as the primary node type and will be used to run the Service Fabric services as well.","pos":[18860,18976],"source":"\\*\\*Orchestrator is designated as the primary node type and will be used to run the Service Fabric services as well."},{"pos":[18978,19025],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Backend SQL Server and AD initial estimates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Backend SQL Server and AD initial estimates**"},{"pos":[19027,19156],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt><ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Back end SQL server and AD initial estimates<ept id=\"p1\">](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-02.PNG)](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-02.PNG)</ept>","source":"[![Back end SQL server and AD initial estimates](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-02.PNG)](./media/system-reqs-on-premises-02.PNG)"},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph>SQL Server sizes are highly dependent on workloads.","pos":[19159,19212],"source":"\\*SQL Server sizes are highly dependent on workloads."},{"content":"For more information, see the topic <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Hardware sizing for on-premises environments<ept id=\"p1\">](hardware-sizing-on-premises-environments.md)</ept>.","pos":[19213,19341],"source":" For more information, see the topic [Hardware sizing for on-premises environments](hardware-sizing-on-premises-environments.md)."},{"pos":[19346,19353],"content":"Storage","linkify":"Storage","nodes":[{"content":"Storage","pos":[0,7]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>AOS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> - Finance and Operations (on-premises) will use a Server Message Block (SMB) 3.0 share to store unstructured data.","pos":[19357,19479],"source":"**AOS** - Finance and Operations (on-premises) will use a Server Message Block (SMB) 3.0 share to store unstructured data."},{"content":"For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Storage Spaces Direct in Windows Server 2016<ept id=\"p1\">](/windows-server/storage/storage-spaces/storage-spaces-direct-overview)</ept>.","pos":[19480,19624],"source":" For more information, see [Storage Spaces Direct in Windows Server 2016](/windows-server/storage/storage-spaces/storage-spaces-direct-overview)."},{"pos":[19627,19652],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SQL<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Viable options:","source":"**SQL** – Viable options:"},{"content":"A highly available solid-state drive (SSD) setup.","pos":[19659,19708]},{"content":"A storage area network (SAN) optimized for OLTP throughputs.","pos":[19715,19775]},{"content":"High performance Direct-attached storage (DAS)","pos":[19782,19828]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>SQL and data management IOPS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The storage for both data management and SQL Server should have at least 2,000 input/output operations per second (IOPS).","pos":[19832,19988],"source":"**SQL and data management IOPS** – The storage for both data management and SQL Server should have at least 2,000 input/output operations per second (IOPS)."},{"content":"Production IOPS depends on many factors.","pos":[19989,20029]},{"content":"For more information, see the topic <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Hardware sizing for on-premises environments<ept id=\"p1\">](hardware-sizing-on-premises-environments.md)</ept>.","pos":[20030,20158],"source":" For more information, see the topic [Hardware sizing for on-premises environments](hardware-sizing-on-premises-environments.md)."},{"pos":[20161,20245],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Virtual machine IOPS<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Each virtual machine should have at least 100 write IOPS.","source":"**Virtual machine IOPS** – Each virtual machine should have at least 100 write IOPS."},{"pos":[20250,20275],"content":"Virtual host requirements","linkify":"Virtual host requirements","nodes":[{"content":"Virtual host requirements","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"When you set up the virtual hosts for a Finance and Operations (on-premises) environment, refer to the following guidelines: <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster<ept id=\"p1\">](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation)</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>Describing a service fabric cluster<ept id=\"p2\">](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-resource-manager-cluster-description)</ept>.","pos":[20276,20653],"source":"When you set up the virtual hosts for a Finance and Operations (on-premises) environment, refer to the following guidelines: [Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation) and [Describing a service fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-resource-manager-cluster-description)."},{"content":"Each virtual host should have enough cores for the infrastructure that is being sized.","pos":[20654,20740]},{"content":"Multiple advanced configurations are possible, where SQL Server resides on physical hardware but everything else is virtualized.","pos":[20741,20869]},{"content":"If SQL Server is virtualized, the disk subsystem should be a fast SAN or the equivalent.","pos":[20870,20958]},{"content":"In all cases, make sure that the basic setup of the virtual host is highly available and redundant.","pos":[20959,21058]},{"content":"In all cases, when virtualization is used, no VM snapshots should be taken.","pos":[21059,21134]},{"pos":[21139,21185],"content":"Software requirements for all server computers","linkify":"Software requirements for all server computers","nodes":[{"content":"Software requirements for all server computers","pos":[0,46]}]},{"content":"The following software must be present on a computer before any Finance and Operations (on-premises) components can be installed:","pos":[21186,21315]},{"content":"Microsoft .NET Framework 4.5.1 or higher","pos":[21319,21359]},{"pos":[21362,21530],"content":"Service Fabric For more information, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster<ept id=\"p1\">](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation)</ept>.","source":"Service Fabric\nFor more information, see [Plan and prepare your Service Fabric cluster](/azure/service-fabric/service-fabric-cluster-standalone-deployment-preparation)."},{"pos":[21535,21569],"content":"Supported server operating systems","linkify":"Supported server operating systems","nodes":[{"content":"Supported server operating systems","pos":[0,34]}]},{"content":"The following table lists the server operating systems that are supported for Finance and Operations components.","pos":[21570,21682]},{"content":"Operating system","pos":[21686,21702]},{"content":"Notes","pos":[21741,21746]},{"content":"Microsoft Windows Server 2016 Datacenter or Standard","pos":[21978,22030]},{"content":"These requirements are for the database and the Service Fabric cluster that hosts AOS.","pos":[22033,22119]},{"pos":[22126,22168],"content":"Software requirements for database servers","linkify":"Software requirements for database servers","nodes":[{"content":"Software requirements for database servers","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"Only 64-bit versions of SQL Server 2016 are supported.","pos":[22172,22226]},{"content":"In a production environment, we recommend that you install the latest cumulative update (CU) for the version of SQL Server that you’re using.","pos":[22229,22370]},{"content":"Finance and Operations (on-premises) supports Unicode collations that are case-insensitive, accent-sensitive, kana-sensitive, and width-insensitive.","pos":[22373,22521]},{"content":"The collation must match the Windows locale of the computers that are running AOS instances.","pos":[22522,22614]},{"content":"If you’re setting up a new installation, we recommend that you select a Windows collation instead of a SQL Server collation.","pos":[22615,22739]},{"content":"For more information about how to select a collation for a SQL Server database, see the <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SQL Server documentation<ept id=\"p1\">](/sql/sql-server/sql-server-technical-documentation)</ept>.","pos":[22740,22907],"source":" For more information about how to select a collation for a SQL Server database, see the [SQL Server documentation](/sql/sql-server/sql-server-technical-documentation)."},{"content":"The following table lists the SQL Server versions that are supported for the Finance and Operations databases.","pos":[22908,23018],"source":"\nThe following table lists the SQL Server versions that are supported for the Finance and Operations databases."},{"content":"For more information, see the minimum hardware requirements for <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>SQL Server<ept id=\"p1\">](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/sql-server/sql-server-2016)</ept>.","pos":[23019,23156],"source":" For more information, see the minimum hardware requirements for [SQL Server](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/sql-server/sql-server-2016)."},{"content":"Requirement","pos":[23160,23171]},{"content":"Notes","pos":[23227,23232]},{"content":"Microsoft SQL Server 2016 Standard Edition or Enterprise Edition","pos":[23546,23610]},{"pos":[23613,23822],"content":"For the hardware requirements for SQL Server 2016, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Hardware and Software Requirements for Installing SQL Server 2016<ept id=\"p1\">](/sql/sql-server/install/hardware-and-software-requirements-for-installing-sql-server)</ept>.","source":"For the hardware requirements for SQL Server 2016, see [Hardware and Software Requirements for Installing SQL Server 2016](/sql/sql-server/install/hardware-and-software-requirements-for-installing-sql-server)."},{"pos":[23829,23871],"content":"Software requirements for client computers","linkify":"Software requirements for client computers","nodes":[{"content":"Software requirements for client computers","pos":[0,42]}]},{"content":"The Finance and Operations web application can run on any device with an HTML5.0 compliant web browser.","pos":[23872,23975]},{"content":"Specific device/browser combinations that Microsoft has confirmed include:","pos":[23976,24050]},{"content":"Microsoft Edge (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10","pos":[24054,24118]},{"content":"Internet Explorer 11 on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, or Windows 7","pos":[24121,24182]},{"content":"Google Chrome (latest publicly available version) on Windows 10, Windows 8.1, Windows 8, Windows 7, or Google Nexus 10 tablet","pos":[24185,24310]},{"content":"Apple Safari (latest publicly available version) on Mac OS X 10.10 (Yosemite), 10.11 (El Capitan) or 10.12 (Sierra), or Apple iPad","pos":[24313,24443]},{"pos":[24448,24510],"content":"Software requirements for Active Directory Federation Services","linkify":"Software requirements for Active Directory Federation Services","nodes":[{"content":"Software requirements for Active Directory Federation Services","pos":[0,62]}]},{"content":"Active Directory Federation Services (AD FS) on Windows Server 2016","pos":[24512,24579]},{"content":"The domain controller must be Windows Server 2012 R2 or later with a domain functional level of 2012 R2 or greater","pos":[24581,24695]},{"content":"For more information about domain functional levels, see:","pos":[24697,24754]},{"pos":[24758,24871],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>What Are Active Directory Functional Levels<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc787290(v=ws.10).aspx)</ept>","source":"[What Are Active Directory Functional Levels](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc787290(v=ws.10).aspx)"},{"pos":[24874,25048],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Understanding Active Directory Domain Services Functional Levels<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/understanding-active-directory-functional-levels(v=ws.10).aspx)</ept>","source":"[Understanding Active Directory Domain Services Functional Levels](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/understanding-active-directory-functional-levels(v=ws.10).aspx)"},{"pos":[25054,25110],"content":"Hardware and software requirements for Retail components","linkify":"Hardware and software requirements for Retail components","nodes":[{"content":"Hardware and software requirements for Retail components","pos":[0,56]}]},{"content":"Finance and Operations (on-premises) does not include the Retail components at this time.","pos":[25111,25200]},{"pos":[25202,25210],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[25221,25381],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get an evaluation copy of Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/get-evaluation-copy)</ept>","source":"[Get an evaluation copy of Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition](/dynamics365/unified-operations/dev-itpro/dev-tools/get-evaluation-copy)"}]}