{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Help overview\n\ndescription: This article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system. It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization. \nauthor: margoc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 16381\nms.assetid: 018c148c-9cbd-41e0-8186-d75dbf66288f\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: margoc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Help overview\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\nThis article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system. It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization. \n\n> [!NOTE] \n> The following products are closely related: Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; Dynamics 365 for Retail; and Dynamics 365 for Talent. The same functionality may appear in all 3 products. As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to Talent, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent; and in topics that are related to the core product, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations. Topics that are written for one product may apply to the same functionality in a related product.\n\nThe Help system is shared by all Unified Operations products:\n- Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition\n- Dynamics 365 for Retail\n- Dynamics 365 for Talent\n\nFinance and Operations includes a Help system that is based on two main components:\n\n-   A documentation site\n-   Task guides\n\nYou can access both help topics and task guides from the Help pane in whichever product you are using. The following screenshot shows Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations\n\n![Help pane](./media/help-pane-ops-task-guides.png)\n\nThis topic describes the Help system, and explains how you can create custom documentation and training resources for your organization.\n\n> [!IMPORTANT]\n> The **Task guides** tab is currently not available in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Talent and Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail. We are currently working to enable this functionality in a future release. The Task guides in the Getting Started experience in Talent remain available to cover basic functionality. Procedural help is also available on the docs.microsoft.com site ([docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index) for both Retail and Talent.\n\n## Help on docs.microsoft.com\n\nThe docs.microsoft.com site ([docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index)) is the primary source of product documentation for Finance and Operations. The site offers the following features:\n\n-   **Access to the most up-to-date content** – The site gives us a faster and more flexible way to create, deliver, and update product documentation. Therefore, it helps to ensure that you have access to the latest technical information.\n-   **Content that is written by experts** – The site provides a richer set of product documentation that can be enhanced by community members both inside and outside Microsoft.\n-   **Access to different types of content** – The site lets you quickly access different types of content about Finance and Operations, such as Microsoft Office Mix presentations, task guides, videos, and topics.\n-   **Content that supports your business processes** – The site includes business process–focused content that takes advantage of the Business Process Modeler (BPM) in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).\n\n### Searching on docs.microsoft.com\nWe get a lot of questions about how to search for our content. On our site, if you start from a page about Finance and Operations, we scope your search to just be for Finance and Operations content. You can remove the scoping by clicking the X next to Operations in the search box. \n\n![Search](./media/search-scope-2.png)\n\nYou can also find our content with any search engine. We recommend that for best results, you use a site search, such as \nsite:docs.microsoft.com dynamics 365 \"search term\".  \n\n![Site search](./media/site-search-1.png)\n\n![Site search results](./media/site-search-results-2.png)\n\n### The docs.microsoft.com table of contents for Unified Operations\nAll products share a single table of contents on the docs site, which enables customers to see the context of the topic they are in. It also enables you to use the Filter control to find topics that you are looking for.\n\n### How can I contribute? \n\nLeave us a comment! \n\n1 Click **Comments** to get to the comments at the bottom of the page.\n\n![Comments](./media/comments.png)\n\n2 Start typing your comments, and then click **Post comment**.\n\n![Post comment](./media/before-signin.png)\n\n3 Select the type of account that you want to sign in with:  \nClick one of the icons on the left to associate this site with an existing account, such as a Twitter, Facebook, or Microsoft account. \n\nOr \n\nOn the right, enter an email address, and a new password to create a new account for the site. \n\n![Sign in options](./media/signin-options.png)\n\n\n## Task guides\nA Task guide is a controlled, guided, interactive experience that leads you through the steps of a task, or business process. You can open (play) a Task guide from the Help pane. When you first click a Task guide, the Help pane will show the step-by-step instructions for the task. Localized Task guides are now available. \n\nWe will provide different sets of task guides for each Unified Operations product. The section Accessing Task guides from the Help pane describes how to find the correct task guides for your product. \n\n![Task guide reading view](./media/task-guide-ops.png)\n\nTo begin the guided, interactive experience, click **Start task guide** at the bottom of the Help pane. A black pointer opens and indicates the action that you must perform. Follow the directions that appear in the UI, and enter data as directed. \n![Task guide step instruction](./media/task-guide-step-1-ops.png)\n\n> [!IMPORTANT] \n> The data that you enter when you play a Task guide is real. If you're in a production environment, the data will be entered in the company that you’re currently using.\n\n### It all begins with Task Recorder\n\nTask guides are created by using Task Recorder. When you use Task Recorder, all the actions that you perform in the Finance and Operations UI (such as clicking menus, changing settings, and entering data) are recorded. The steps that you record are collectively called a task recording. As we explained in the previous section, task recordings can be displayed in the Help pane and played as task guides. However, there are other ways that you can use task recordings:\n\n-   **Save task recordings to BPM** – You can save a task recording to a line of a hierarchy in a BPM library in LCS. When you save a task recording to BPM, a flowchart diagram is generated and displayed, together with the steps of the recording. **Note:** To display a task recording in the Finance and Operations Help pane and play it as a task guide, you'll have to save the recording to a BPM library.\n-   **Save task recordings as Word documents** – By saving a task recording as a Microsoft Word document, you can easily produce printable training guides for your organization.\n\nFor more information about Task Recorder, see [Task recorder in Finance and Operations](../user-interface/task-recorder.md).\n\n### Creating customized task recordings\n\nYou can create your own task recordings, or you can download and customize task recording that Microsoft provides. Therefore, you can create customized Help for your organization that reflects your specific Finance and Operations implementation. To display a task recording in the Finance and Operations Help pane and play it as a Task guide, you'll have to save the recording to a BPM library in LCS. If you're a partner, and you promote a library to a corporate library and include it in a solution, it will be available to your customers. For complete instructions, see [Using task recordings to create documentation or training](../user-interface/task-recorder.md).\n\n## In-product Help\nTo access Help content within Finance and Operations, either click the **Help** (**?**) icon and then choose Help or press Ctrl+Shift+?. In both cases, the Help pane opens. From the Help pane, you can access articles or task guides. \n\n![Help pane](./media/help-pane-wiki.png)\n\n### Accessing help topics from the Help pane\n\nFrom the Help pane, you can access articles that apply to the Finance and Operations client. When you first open the Help pane and click the **Wiki** tab, you’ll see the articles that apply to the page that you’re currently on in Finance and Operations. If no articles are found, you can enter keywords to refine your search. When you click an article in the Help pane, a new tab opens in your browser and displays the article. \n\n> [!IMPORTANT]\n> This section does not apply to Dynamics 365 for Talent. The Help system for Talent is automatically connected to Task guides for the product. Also, you cannot create custom Task guides for Talent. \n\n### Accessing Task guides from the Help pane\n\nBefore you can access Task guides from the Help pane, a System administrator has to go to the **System parameters** page in Finance and Operations and configure some settings. \n\n> [!NOTE]\n> -   In order to configure help, you must be signed in with an account in the same tenant as the tenant in which Finance and Operations is deployed.\n> -   It is not possible to connect to an LCS library from an instance of Finance and Operations running in a local virtual hard drive (VHD).\n\n![System Parameters form with Help settings](./media/system-parameters_ops-1024x437.png)\n\nOn the **System parameters** page, follow these steps:\n\n1.  **Important:** The first time that you open the Help tab, you must connect to Lifecycle Services. Be sure to click the link in the middle of the form, wait for the connection, close the dialog box, and then click **OK** to get to the parameters form.\n![Connect to LCS](./media/connect-to-lcs-crop-1024x365.png)\n2.  Select the Lifecycle Services project to connect to.\n3.  Select BPM libraries (within the selected project) to retrieve task recordings from.\n    - For Finance and Operations, for Microsoft content, select the February 2017 QPC Unified Library for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations. \n    - For Retail, we will be releasing a library in July. \n    - You do not need to select a library for Talent—the connection to the correct library is established for you. \n\n4.  Set the display order of the BPM libraries. This determines the order in which task recordings from the libraries will appear in the Help pane.\n\nAfter a System administrator has completed these steps, you can open the Help pane and click the **Task guides** tab. You'll now see the Task guides that apply to the page that you’re currently on in Finance and Operations. If no Task guides are found, you can enter keywords to refine your search. After you click a Task guide in the Help pane, the Help pane shows the step-by-step instructions, and you can play the task guide. \n\n![Task guide reading view](./media/task-guide-ops.png)\n\n### Where are the translated Task guides?\n\nTranslated Task guides are released in libraries with \"All languages\" in the title. In Finance and Operations, to see localized Task guide help, make sure that you are connected to an apppropriate library. The language that a Task guide appears in is controlled for each user by the Language settings under **Options** &gt; **Preferences**. \n-   If a Task guide has been translated, when you open that Task guide all the text of the Task guide will appear in your selected language.\n-   If a Task guide has not yet been translated, when you open it, only some of the text (the text of the controls) will appear in your selected language.\n\n## Additional resources\nThe following table lists websites that provide Unified Operations content. Our content websites are organized to support the customer life cycle. Each phase is supported by a different set of sites. Sites that have an asterisk (\\*) next to the name require that you sign in by using an account that is associated with a service plan.\n\n| Site                                                                     | Description                                                                                                                                                                                                                                |\n|--------------------------------------------------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| [Docs.microsoft.com](/dynamics365/) | Hosts or links to all product documentation for Dynamics 365.                                                                                                                                                               |\n| [Lifecycle Services](http://lcs.dynamics.com/en/)\\*                      | Provides a cloud-based collaborative workspace that customers and partners can use to manage Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations projects from pre-sales to implementation and operations. This site is useful in all phases of an implementation. |\n| [CustomerSource](http://www.customersource.com/)\\*                       | Hosts extensive training resources and is the primary support site for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations. Sign in may be required to access specific resources on the site.                                                                      |\n| [Support blog](http://aka.ms/AXSupportBlog)                              | Provides tips and tricks that are posted by the Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Support team.                                                                                                                                                  |\n| [MSDN](http://aka.ms/AXMSDN)                                             | Hosts content from previous releases that is written for developers.                                                                                                                                                                       |\n| [TechNet](http://aka.ms/TechNet)                                         | Hosts content from previous releases that is written for IT professionals and application users.                                                                                                                                           |\n| [Dynamics Community](http://community.dynamics.com/)                  | Hosts blogs, forums, and videos.                                                                                                                                                                                                           |\n| [Microsoft.com/Dynamics/](http://www.microsoft.com/dynamics/)                 | Provides evaluation and sales information.                                                                                                                                                                                                 |\n\n\n\nSee also\n--------\n[Finance and Operations help system (downloadable fact sheet)](https://mbs.microsoft.com/files/public/CS/AX2012R3/DynamicsAXHelpSystemFactSheet.pdf)\n\n[Task Recorder](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)\n\n[Create documentation or training using Task recordings](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)\n\n[New or updated Task guides (November 2016)](new-task-guides-november-2016.md)\n[New or updated task guides (August 2016)](new-updated-task-guides-available-august-2016.md)\n[New or updated task guides (May 2016)](new-updated-task-guides-available-may-2016.md)\n[New task guides (February 2016)](new-task-guides-available-february-2016.md)\n\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,812],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Help overview\n\ndescription: This article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system. It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization. \nauthor: margoc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/16/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-platform\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User, Developer, IT Pro\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: annbe\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 16381\nms.assetid: 018c148c-9cbd-41e0-8186-d75dbf66288f\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: margoc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Help overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,13],"content":"Help overview","nodes":[{"content":"Help overview","pos":[0,13]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system. It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,214],"content":"This article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system. It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system. It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization.","pos":[0,214],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system.","pos":[0,121]},{"content":"It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization.","pos":[122,214]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[820,833],"content":"Help overview","linkify":"Help overview","nodes":[{"content":"Help overview","pos":[0,13]}]},{"content":"This article provides an overview of the components of the Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Help system.","pos":[878,999]},{"content":"It also explains how you can provide custom documentation and training to your organization.","pos":[1000,1092]},{"pos":[1097,1744],"content":"[!NOTE] \nThe following products are closely related: Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; Dynamics 365 for Retail; and Dynamics 365 for Talent. The same functionality may appear in all 3 products. As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to Talent, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent; and in topics that are related to the core product, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations. Topics that are written for one product may apply to the same functionality in a related product.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The following products are closely related: Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; Dynamics 365 for Retail; and Dynamics 365 for Talent. The same functionality may appear in all 3 products. As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to Talent, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent; and in topics that are related to the core product, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations. Topics that are written for one product may apply to the same functionality in a related product.","pos":[9,645],"nodes":[{"content":"The following products are closely related: Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition; Dynamics 365 for Retail; and Dynamics 365 for Talent.","pos":[0,158]},{"content":"The same functionality may appear in all 3 products.","pos":[159,211]},{"content":"As a result, in topics that are primarily related to Retail, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Retail; in topics that are primarily related to Talent, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Talent; and in topics that are related to the core product, the product name will be Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[212,538]},{"content":"Topics that are written for one product may apply to the same functionality in a related product.","pos":[539,636]}]}]},{"content":"The Help system is shared by all Unified Operations products:","pos":[1746,1807]},{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition","pos":[1810,1869]},{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Retail","pos":[1872,1895]},{"content":"Dynamics 365 for Talent","pos":[1898,1921]},{"content":"Finance and Operations includes a Help system that is based on two main components:","pos":[1923,2006]},{"content":"A documentation site","pos":[2012,2032]},{"content":"Task guides","pos":[2037,2048]},{"content":"You can access both help topics and task guides from the Help pane in whichever product you are using.","pos":[2050,2152]},{"content":"The following screenshot shows Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations","pos":[2153,2223]},{"content":"Help pane","pos":[2227,2236]},{"content":"This topic describes the Help system, and explains how you can create custom documentation and training resources for your organization.","pos":[2278,2414]},{"pos":[2418,2930],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\nThe **Task guides** tab is currently not available in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Talent and Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail. We are currently working to enable this functionality in a future release. The Task guides in the Getting Started experience in Talent remain available to cover basic functionality. Procedural help is also available on the docs.microsoft.com site ([docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index) for both Retail and Talent.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The **Task guides** tab is currently not available in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Talent and Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail. We are currently working to enable this functionality in a future release. The Task guides in the Getting Started experience in Talent remain available to cover basic functionality. Procedural help is also available on the docs.microsoft.com site ([docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index) for both Retail and Talent.","pos":[13,510],"nodes":[{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Task guides<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab is currently not available in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Talent and Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail.","pos":[0,126],"source":"The **Task guides** tab is currently not available in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Talent and Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Retail."},{"content":"We are currently working to enable this functionality in a future release.","pos":[127,201]},{"content":"The Task guides in the Getting Started experience in Talent remain available to cover basic functionality.","pos":[202,308]},{"content":"Procedural help is also available on the docs.microsoft.com site (<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index)</ept> for both Retail and Talent.","pos":[309,497],"source":" Procedural help is also available on the docs.microsoft.com site ([docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index) for both Retail and Talent."}]}]},{"pos":[2935,2961],"content":"Help on docs.microsoft.com","linkify":"Help on docs.microsoft.com","nodes":[{"content":"Help on docs.microsoft.com","pos":[0,26]}]},{"content":"The docs.microsoft.com site (<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index)</ept>) is the primary source of product documentation for Finance and Operations.","pos":[2963,3162],"source":"The docs.microsoft.com site ([docs.microsoft.com/dynamics365/operations](/dynamics365/unified-operations/fin-and-ops/index)) is the primary source of product documentation for Finance and Operations."},{"content":"The site offers the following features:","pos":[3163,3202]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Access to the most up-to-date content<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The site gives us a faster and more flexible way to create, deliver, and update product documentation.","pos":[3208,3354],"source":"**Access to the most up-to-date content** – The site gives us a faster and more flexible way to create, deliver, and update product documentation."},{"content":"Therefore, it helps to ensure that you have access to the latest technical information.","pos":[3355,3442]},{"pos":[3447,3620],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Content that is written by experts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The site provides a richer set of product documentation that can be enhanced by community members both inside and outside Microsoft.","source":"**Content that is written by experts** – The site provides a richer set of product documentation that can be enhanced by community members both inside and outside Microsoft."},{"pos":[3625,3834],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Access to different types of content<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The site lets you quickly access different types of content about Finance and Operations, such as Microsoft Office Mix presentations, task guides, videos, and topics.","source":"**Access to different types of content** – The site lets you quickly access different types of content about Finance and Operations, such as Microsoft Office Mix presentations, task guides, videos, and topics."},{"pos":[3839,4048],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Content that supports your business processes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – The site includes business process–focused content that takes advantage of the Business Process Modeler (BPM) in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS).","source":"**Content that supports your business processes** – The site includes business process–focused content that takes advantage of the Business Process Modeler (BPM) in Microsoft Dynamics Lifecycle Services (LCS)."},{"pos":[4054,4085],"content":"Searching on docs.microsoft.com","linkify":"Searching on docs.microsoft.com","nodes":[{"content":"Searching on docs.microsoft.com","pos":[0,31]}]},{"content":"We get a lot of questions about how to search for our content.","pos":[4086,4148]},{"content":"On our site, if you start from a page about Finance and Operations, we scope your search to just be for Finance and Operations content.","pos":[4149,4284]},{"content":"You can remove the scoping by clicking the X next to Operations in the search box.","pos":[4285,4367]},{"content":"Search","pos":[4372,4378]},{"content":"You can also find our content with any search engine.","pos":[4409,4462]},{"content":"We recommend that for best results, you use a site search, such as site:docs.microsoft.com dynamics 365 \"search term\".","pos":[4463,4582],"source":" We recommend that for best results, you use a site search, such as \nsite:docs.microsoft.com dynamics 365 \"search term\"."},{"content":"Site search","pos":[4588,4599]},{"content":"Site search results","pos":[4631,4650]},{"pos":[4692,4755],"content":"The docs.microsoft.com table of contents for Unified Operations","linkify":"The docs.microsoft.com table of contents for Unified Operations","nodes":[{"content":"The docs.microsoft.com table of contents for Unified Operations","pos":[0,63]}]},{"content":"All products share a single table of contents on the docs site, which enables customers to see the context of the topic they are in.","pos":[4756,4888]},{"content":"It also enables you to use the Filter control to find topics that you are looking for.","pos":[4889,4975]},{"pos":[4981,5002],"content":"How can I contribute?","linkify":"How can I contribute?","nodes":[{"content":"How can I contribute?","pos":[0,21]}]},{"content":"Leave us a comment!","pos":[5005,5024]},{"pos":[5027,5097],"content":"1 Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Comments<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to get to the comments at the bottom of the page.","source":"1 Click **Comments** to get to the comments at the bottom of the page."},{"content":"Comments","pos":[5101,5109]},{"pos":[5134,5196],"content":"2 Start typing your comments, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post comment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","source":"2 Start typing your comments, and then click **Post comment**."},{"content":"Post comment","pos":[5200,5212]},{"content":"3 Select the type of account that you want to sign in with:","pos":[5242,5301]},{"content":"Click one of the icons on the left to associate this site with an existing account, such as a Twitter, Facebook, or Microsoft account.","pos":[5304,5438]},{"content":"Or","pos":[5441,5443]},{"content":"On the right, enter an email address, and a new password to create a new account for the site.","pos":[5446,5540]},{"content":"Sign in options","pos":[5545,5560]},{"pos":[5595,5606],"content":"Task guides","linkify":"Task guides","nodes":[{"content":"Task guides","pos":[0,11]}]},{"content":"A Task guide is a controlled, guided, interactive experience that leads you through the steps of a task, or business process.","pos":[5607,5732]},{"content":"You can open (play) a Task guide from the Help pane.","pos":[5733,5785]},{"content":"When you first click a Task guide, the Help pane will show the step-by-step instructions for the task.","pos":[5786,5888]},{"content":"Localized Task guides are now available.","pos":[5889,5929]},{"content":"We will provide different sets of task guides for each Unified Operations product.","pos":[5932,6014]},{"content":"The section Accessing Task guides from the Help pane describes how to find the correct task guides for your product.","pos":[6015,6131]},{"content":"Task guide reading view","pos":[6136,6159]},{"content":"To begin the guided, interactive experience, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Start task guide<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> at the bottom of the Help pane.","pos":[6190,6293],"source":"To begin the guided, interactive experience, click **Start task guide** at the bottom of the Help pane."},{"content":"A black pointer opens and indicates the action that you must perform.","pos":[6294,6363]},{"content":"Follow the directions that appear in the UI, and enter data as directed.","pos":[6364,6436]},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Task guide step instruction<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/task-guide-step-1-ops.png)</ph>","pos":[6438,6503],"source":"![Task guide step instruction](./media/task-guide-step-1-ops.png)"},{"pos":[6507,6690],"content":"[!IMPORTANT] \nThe data that you enter when you play a Task guide is real. If you're in a production environment, the data will be entered in the company that you’re currently using.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"The data that you enter when you play a Task guide is real. If you're in a production environment, the data will be entered in the company that you’re currently using.","pos":[14,181],"nodes":[{"content":"The data that you enter when you play a Task guide is real.","pos":[0,59]},{"content":"If you're in a production environment, the data will be entered in the company that you’re currently using.","pos":[60,167]}]}]},{"pos":[6696,6728],"content":"It all begins with Task Recorder","linkify":"It all begins with Task Recorder","nodes":[{"content":"It all begins with Task Recorder","pos":[0,32]}]},{"content":"Task guides are created by using Task Recorder.","pos":[6730,6777]},{"content":"When you use Task Recorder, all the actions that you perform in the Finance and Operations UI (such as clicking menus, changing settings, and entering data) are recorded.","pos":[6778,6948]},{"content":"The steps that you record are collectively called a task recording.","pos":[6949,7016]},{"content":"As we explained in the previous section, task recordings can be displayed in the Help pane and played as task guides.","pos":[7017,7134]},{"content":"However, there are other ways that you can use task recordings:","pos":[7135,7198]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save task recordings to BPM<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – You can save a task recording to a line of a hierarchy in a BPM library in LCS.","pos":[7204,7317],"source":"**Save task recordings to BPM** – You can save a task recording to a line of a hierarchy in a BPM library in LCS."},{"content":"When you save a task recording to BPM, a flowchart diagram is generated and displayed, together with the steps of the recording.","pos":[7318,7446]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> To display a task recording in the Finance and Operations Help pane and play it as a task guide, you'll have to save the recording to a BPM library.","pos":[7447,7605],"source":"**Note:** To display a task recording in the Finance and Operations Help pane and play it as a task guide, you'll have to save the recording to a BPM library."},{"pos":[7610,7783],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Save task recordings as Word documents<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – By saving a task recording as a Microsoft Word document, you can easily produce printable training guides for your organization.","source":"**Save task recordings as Word documents** – By saving a task recording as a Microsoft Word document, you can easily produce printable training guides for your organization."},{"pos":[7785,7909],"content":"For more information about Task Recorder, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Task recorder in Finance and Operations<ept id=\"p1\">](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)</ept>.","source":"For more information about Task Recorder, see [Task recorder in Finance and Operations](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)."},{"pos":[7915,7950],"content":"Creating customized task recordings","linkify":"Creating customized task recordings","nodes":[{"content":"Creating customized task recordings","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"You can create your own task recordings, or you can download and customize task recording that Microsoft provides.","pos":[7952,8066]},{"content":"Therefore, you can create customized Help for your organization that reflects your specific Finance and Operations implementation.","pos":[8067,8197]},{"content":"To display a task recording in the Finance and Operations Help pane and play it as a Task guide, you'll have to save the recording to a BPM library in LCS.","pos":[8198,8353]},{"content":"If you're a partner, and you promote a library to a corporate library and include it in a solution, it will be available to your customers.","pos":[8354,8493]},{"content":"For complete instructions, see <bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Using task recordings to create documentation or training<ept id=\"p1\">](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)</ept>.","pos":[8494,8621],"source":" For complete instructions, see [Using task recordings to create documentation or training](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)."},{"pos":[8626,8641],"content":"In-product Help","linkify":"In-product Help","nodes":[{"content":"In-product Help","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"To access Help content within Finance and Operations, either click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Help<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> (<bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>?<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>) icon and then choose Help or press Ctrl+Shift+?.","pos":[8642,8778],"source":"To access Help content within Finance and Operations, either click the **Help** (**?**) icon and then choose Help or press Ctrl+Shift+?."},{"content":"In both cases, the Help pane opens.","pos":[8779,8814]},{"content":"From the Help pane, you can access articles or task guides.","pos":[8815,8874]},{"content":"Help pane","pos":[8879,8888]},{"pos":[8923,8963],"content":"Accessing help topics from the Help pane","linkify":"Accessing help topics from the Help pane","nodes":[{"content":"Accessing help topics from the Help pane","pos":[0,40]}]},{"content":"From the Help pane, you can access articles that apply to the Finance and Operations client.","pos":[8965,9057]},{"content":"When you first open the Help pane and click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Wiki<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab, you’ll see the articles that apply to the page that you’re currently on in Finance and Operations.","pos":[9058,9218],"source":" When you first open the Help pane and click the **Wiki** tab, you’ll see the articles that apply to the page that you’re currently on in Finance and Operations."},{"content":"If no articles are found, you can enter keywords to refine your search.","pos":[9219,9290]},{"content":"When you click an article in the Help pane, a new tab opens in your browser and displays the article.","pos":[9291,9392]},{"pos":[9397,9608],"content":"[!IMPORTANT]\nThis section does not apply to Dynamics 365 for Talent. The Help system for Talent is automatically connected to Task guides for the product. Also, you cannot create custom Task guides for Talent.","leadings":["","> "],"nodes":[{"content":"This section does not apply to Dynamics 365 for Talent. The Help system for Talent is automatically connected to Task guides for the product. Also, you cannot create custom Task guides for Talent.","pos":[13,209],"nodes":[{"content":"This section does not apply to Dynamics 365 for Talent.","pos":[0,55]},{"content":"The Help system for Talent is automatically connected to Task guides for the product.","pos":[56,141]},{"content":"Also, you cannot create custom Task guides for Talent.","pos":[142,196]}]}]},{"pos":[9615,9655],"content":"Accessing Task guides from the Help pane","linkify":"Accessing Task guides from the Help pane","nodes":[{"content":"Accessing Task guides from the Help pane","pos":[0,40]}]},{"pos":[9657,9832],"content":"Before you can access Task guides from the Help pane, a System administrator has to go to the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page in Finance and Operations and configure some settings.","source":"Before you can access Task guides from the Help pane, a System administrator has to go to the **System parameters** page in Finance and Operations and configure some settings."},{"content":"In order to configure help, you must be signed in with an account in the same tenant as the tenant in which Finance and Operations is deployed.","pos":[9851,9994]},{"content":"It is not possible to connect to an LCS library from an instance of Finance and Operations running in a local virtual hard drive (VHD).","pos":[10001,10136]},{"content":"System Parameters form with Help settings","pos":[10140,10181]},{"pos":[10228,10282],"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>System parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, follow these steps:","source":"On the **System parameters** page, follow these steps:"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Important:<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> The first time that you open the Help tab, you must connect to Lifecycle Services.","pos":[10288,10385],"source":"**Important:** The first time that you open the Help tab, you must connect to Lifecycle Services."},{"content":"Be sure to click the link in the middle of the form, wait for the connection, close the dialog box, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>OK<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to get to the parameters form.","pos":[10386,10538],"source":" Be sure to click the link in the middle of the form, wait for the connection, close the dialog box, and then click **OK** to get to the parameters form."},{"content":"<ph id=\"ph1\">![</ph>Connect to LCS<ph id=\"ph2\">](./media/connect-to-lcs-crop-1024x365.png)</ph>","pos":[10539,10598],"source":"![Connect to LCS](./media/connect-to-lcs-crop-1024x365.png)"},{"content":"Select the Lifecycle Services project to connect to.","pos":[10603,10655]},{"content":"Select BPM libraries (within the selected project) to retrieve task recordings from.","pos":[10660,10744]},{"content":"For Finance and Operations, for Microsoft content, select the February 2017 QPC Unified Library for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[10751,10901]},{"content":"For Retail, we will be releasing a library in July.","pos":[10909,10960]},{"content":"You do not need to select a library for Talent—the connection to the correct library is established for you.","pos":[10968,11076]},{"content":"Set the display order of the BPM libraries.","pos":[11083,11126]},{"content":"This determines the order in which task recordings from the libraries will appear in the Help pane.","pos":[11127,11226]},{"content":"After a System administrator has completed these steps, you can open the Help pane and click the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Task guides<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab.","pos":[11228,11345],"source":"After a System administrator has completed these steps, you can open the Help pane and click the **Task guides** tab."},{"content":"You'll now see the Task guides that apply to the page that you’re currently on in Finance and Operations.","pos":[11346,11451]},{"content":"If no Task guides are found, you can enter keywords to refine your search.","pos":[11452,11526]},{"content":"After you click a Task guide in the Help pane, the Help pane shows the step-by-step instructions, and you can play the task guide.","pos":[11527,11657]},{"content":"Task guide reading view","pos":[11662,11685]},{"pos":[11720,11757],"content":"Where are the translated Task guides?","linkify":"Where are the translated Task guides?","nodes":[{"content":"Where are the translated Task guides?","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"Translated Task guides are released in libraries with \"All languages\" in the title.","pos":[11759,11842]},{"content":"In Finance and Operations, to see localized Task guide help, make sure that you are connected to an apppropriate library.","pos":[11843,11964]},{"content":"The language that a Task guide appears in is controlled for each user by the Language settings under <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Options<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> <ph id=\"ph1\">&amp;gt;</ph> <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Preferences<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[11965,12099],"source":" The language that a Task guide appears in is controlled for each user by the Language settings under **Options** &gt; **Preferences**."},{"content":"If a Task guide has been translated, when you open that Task guide all the text of the Task guide will appear in your selected language.","pos":[12105,12241]},{"content":"If a Task guide has not yet been translated, when you open it, only some of the text (the text of the controls) will appear in your selected language.","pos":[12246,12396]},{"pos":[12401,12421],"content":"Additional resources","linkify":"Additional resources","nodes":[{"content":"Additional resources","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"The following table lists websites that provide Unified Operations content.","pos":[12422,12497]},{"content":"Our content websites are organized to support the customer life cycle.","pos":[12498,12568]},{"content":"Each phase is supported by a different set of sites.","pos":[12569,12621]},{"content":"Sites that have an asterisk (<ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph>) next to the name require that you sign in by using an account that is associated with a service plan.","pos":[12622,12756],"source":" Sites that have an asterisk (\\*) next to the name require that you sign in by using an account that is associated with a service plan."},{"content":"Site","pos":[12760,12764]},{"content":"Description","pos":[12835,12846]},{"pos":[13388,13423],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Docs.microsoft.com<ept id=\"p1\">](/dynamics365/)</ept>","source":"[Docs.microsoft.com](/dynamics365/)"},{"content":"Hosts or links to all product documentation for Dynamics 365.","pos":[13426,13487]},{"pos":[13650,13701],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Lifecycle Services<ept id=\"p1\">](http://lcs.dynamics.com/en/)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph>","source":"[Lifecycle Services](http://lcs.dynamics.com/en/)\\*"},{"content":"Provides a cloud-based collaborative workspace that customers and partners can use to manage Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations projects from pre-sales to implementation and operations.","pos":[13725,13915]},{"content":"This site is useful in all phases of an implementation.","pos":[13916,13971]},{"pos":[13976,14026],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>CustomerSource<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.customersource.com/)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">\\*</ph>","source":"[CustomerSource](http://www.customersource.com/)\\*"},{"content":"Hosts extensive training resources and is the primary support site for Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations.","pos":[14051,14162]},{"content":"Sign in may be required to access specific resources on the site.","pos":[14163,14228]},{"pos":[14302,14345],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Support blog<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/AXSupportBlog)</ept>","source":"[Support blog](http://aka.ms/AXSupportBlog)"},{"content":"Provides tips and tricks that are posted by the Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations Support team.","pos":[14377,14478]},{"pos":[14628,14656],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>MSDN<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/AXMSDN)</ept>","source":"[MSDN](http://aka.ms/AXMSDN)"},{"content":"Hosts content from previous releases that is written for developers.","pos":[14703,14771]},{"pos":[14942,14974],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>TechNet<ept id=\"p1\">](http://aka.ms/TechNet)</ept>","source":"[TechNet](http://aka.ms/TechNet)"},{"content":"Hosts content from previous releases that is written for IT professionals and application users.","pos":[15017,15113]},{"pos":[15256,15308],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Dynamics Community<ept id=\"p1\">](http://community.dynamics.com/)</ept>","source":"[Dynamics Community](http://community.dynamics.com/)"},{"content":"Hosts blogs, forums, and videos.","pos":[15328,15360]},{"pos":[15567,15628],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Microsoft.com/Dynamics/<ept id=\"p1\">](http://www.microsoft.com/dynamics/)</ept>","source":"[Microsoft.com/Dynamics/](http://www.microsoft.com/dynamics/)"},{"content":"Provides evaluation and sales information.","pos":[15647,15689]},{"pos":[15887,15895],"content":"See also","linkify":"See also","nodes":[{"content":"See also","pos":[0,8]}]},{"pos":[15905,16053],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Finance and Operations help system (downloadable fact sheet)<ept id=\"p1\">](https://mbs.microsoft.com/files/public/CS/AX2012R3/DynamicsAXHelpSystemFactSheet.pdf)</ept>","source":"[Finance and Operations help system (downloadable fact sheet)](https://mbs.microsoft.com/files/public/CS/AX2012R3/DynamicsAXHelpSystemFactSheet.pdf)"},{"pos":[16055,16106],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Task Recorder<ept id=\"p1\">](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)</ept>","source":"[Task Recorder](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)"},{"pos":[16108,16200],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Create documentation or training using Task recordings<ept id=\"p1\">](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)</ept>","source":"[Create documentation or training using Task recordings](../user-interface/task-recorder.md)"},{"pos":[16202,16538],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>New or updated Task guides (November 2016)<ept id=\"p1\">](new-task-guides-november-2016.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph1\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p2\">[</bpt>New or updated task guides (August 2016)<ept id=\"p2\">](new-updated-task-guides-available-august-2016.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph2\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p3\">[</bpt>New or updated task guides (May 2016)<ept id=\"p3\">](new-updated-task-guides-available-may-2016.md)</ept><ph id=\"ph3\">\n</ph><bpt id=\"p4\">[</bpt>New task guides (February 2016)<ept id=\"p4\">](new-task-guides-available-february-2016.md)</ept>","source":"[New or updated Task guides (November 2016)](new-task-guides-november-2016.md)\n[New or updated task guides (August 2016)](new-updated-task-guides-available-august-2016.md)\n[New or updated task guides (May 2016)](new-updated-task-guides-available-may-2016.md)\n[New task guides (February 2016)](new-task-guides-available-february-2016.md)"}]}