{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation\ndescription: The Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. This topic explains the reconciliation process.  \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 98243\nms.assetid: 9df13adf-aa9d-4f6b-bde6-25a214611692\nms.search.region: global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: saraschi\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThe Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. This topic explains the reconciliation process.  \n\nImport an electronic bank statement\n-----------------------------------\n\nYou import your bank statements by using the **Import statement** action on the **Bank statements** page. On the bank statement, the bank account is identified through a combination of values that are set on the bank account details. These values include the bank name, bank account number, routing number, Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication (SWIFT) code, and International Bank Account Number (IBAN). \n\nYou can upload a bank statement that contains information for either a single account or multiple accounts. If there are multiple accounts, the accounts can be in different legal entities.\n\n-   To import a single bank statement file for a single account, set the **Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities** option to **No**, and select the bank account that is associated with the statement. Click **Browse** to select the associated bank statement file, and then click **Upload**.\n-   To import a single bank statement file for multiple accounts, set the **Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities** option to **Yes**. Click **Browse** to select the associated bank statement file, and then click **Upload**.\n\nIf any statements in the electronic file can't be associated with a bank account by using the identifying fields, they won't be imported. However, other statements in the file can still be imported. The user then receives a message that states that the import of bank statements was unsuccessful for specific bank accounts. Note that the user who is importing the bank statement file must have access to a legal entity to import statements for that legal entity's bank accounts. \n\nYou can use a zip file to upload multiple statement files to Finance and Operations in a single process. To import multiple bank statement files for multiple accounts, combine all the bank statement files into one zip file. In the **Import bank statements** dialog box, set the **Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities** option to **Yes**. Click **Browse** to select the zip file that contains the bank statement files, and then click **Upload**. The import process will recognize the zip file and upload each statement that is included in it, regardless of the legal entity of the bank account. \n\nA **Reconcile after import** option is available. When you set this option to **Yes**, the system automatically validates the bank statement, creates a new bank reconciliation and worksheet, and runs the Default matching rule set when the bank statement is uploaded. This functionality automates the process up to the point where transactions must be manually matched.\n\n## Validate the bank statement\nTo validate a statement, on the **Bank statements** page, click **Validate**. Bank statements must be validated before they can be reconciled. This step is automatically completed if you set the **Reconcile after import** option to **Yes** at the time of import. \n\nBank statement validation verifies the following details:\n\n-   The bank statement matches the selected bank account.\n-   The bank statement currency matches the bank account currency.\n-   The opening balance of the statement equals the closing balance of the previous statement for the bank account.\n-   The date doesn’t overlap the date for another bank statement for the same bank account.\n-   There are no gaps in the dates for statements for the bank account.\n-   Dates on the statement lines are between the from-date and to-date of the bank statement.\n-   The opening balance and summarized line amounts equal the ending balance.\n\nWhen the validation is completed, the status of the bank statement is updated to **Validated**. A bank statement must be validated before it can be reconciled.\n\n## Reconcile the bank statement\nAfter you’ve imported an electronic bank statement and validated the statement on the **Bank statements** page, you can reconcile the bank statement by using the **Bank reconciliation** and **Bank reconciliation worksheet** pages. \n\nOn the **Bank reconciliation** page, click **New** to create a new reconciliation, and then select the bank account of the statement that was imported. A bank account can have only one open bank reconciliation. The cut-off date determines the bank statement transactions and Operations bank transactions that are included on the reconciliation worksheet. By default, the current system date is used as the cut-off date, but you can change the date for the reconciliation. The remaining header information is automatically taken from the statement. This step is automatically completed if you set the **Reconcile after import** option to **Yes** at the time of import. \n\nOn the **Bank reconciliation** page, click **Worksheet** to open the **Bank reconciliation worksheet** page. If you set the **Reconcile after import** option to **Yes**, the Default matching rule set is automatically run for the reconciliation. To manually run matching rules, click **Run matching rules** to select the matching rule sets or matching rules to run against the bank transactions. If you have many transactions to process, you can complete this step as a batch process. \n\nThe **Bank reconciliation worksheet** page has four grids that contain transactions. The two upper grids show transactions from the bank statement and Operations that haven’t yet been matched. The two lower grids show matched transactions. The **Bank statement transaction details** tab shows details for the unmatched bank statement transaction that is selected in the upper grid. \n\nThere are three ways to match or reconcile bank statement transactions:\n\n-   Match the transactions with Operations bank transactions.\n-   Match the transactions with a reversal bank statement transaction.\n-   Mark the transactions as **New**, so that they can be posted later as a bank transaction in Finance and Operations.\n\nTo manually match transactions, select the transactions in the **Bank statement transactions** grid, select the corresponding transactions in the **Operations bank transactions** grid, and then click **Match**. The selected transactions are moved from the upper grids for unmatched transactions to the lower grids for matched transactions. Additionally, the matched and unmatched total amounts are updated. You can have one-to-one, many-to-one, and many-to-many transaction matches. Matches must follow the rules for allowed date differences and transaction type mapping. These rules are set on the **Cash and bank management parameters** page.\n\nPenny differences might occur in your reconciliation. You can match a single bank statement transaction and a single Operations bank transaction that have penny differences if the penny differences are within the tolerance amount that is defined by the **Allowed penny difference** field on the bank account. The amount is shown in the **Correction amount** field on the matched Operations bank transaction. When the bank reconciliation is marked as reconciled, corrections are automatically posted by using the main account that is defined on the associated bank transaction type. Corrections aren't supported for the **Check** and **Deposit** document types. \n\nBank statement transaction reversals are matched by using the reconciliation worksheet. Two statement lines can be matched if the amounts are opposite, and if one of the transactions is marked as a reversal. You can also set up a matching rule for the **Clear reversal statement lines** action.\n\nReversed Operations bank transactions must be reconciled by using the **Operations bank transactions** page. You can reconcile two Operations bank transactions together if the documents have the same bank account, document type, and payment reference, and if they have opposite amounts. You can also reconcile a single canceled check to prevent those transactions from appearing on the reconciliation worksheet. \n\nIf there are new bank-initiated transactions, such as interest, fees, and charges, that aren’t yet in Finance and Operations, you can add them to a journal that is associated with the selected bank statement reconciliation. Select a bank statement transaction in the **Bank statement transactions** grid for unmatched transactions, and then click **Mark as new**. The status of the transaction is set to **New**, and the transaction is moved to the **Bank statement transactions** grid for matched transactions. You will post transactions that are marked as **New** later, from the **Bank statement** page. \n\nYou can unmatch transactions that were incorrectly matched. Select the matched bank statement transaction, and then click **Unmatch**. All associated transactions are moved back to the upper grids for unmatched transactions, and the matched and unmatched total amounts are updated. \n\nAfter all statement lines have been processed, you should mark the Bank reconciliation worksheet as reconciled.\n\n## Post new transactions that are associated with the reconciliation\nBank statement transactions that you marked as **New** on the reconciliation worksheet are posted on the **Bank statement** page. On the **Bank statement** page, select the statement ID to view the statement details. On the **Accounting** menu, you can use the **View distributions** and **View accounting** options to view details behind the new transactions and the associated ledger entries. Select the **Post** option to post the bank statement lines that are marked as **New** to the general ledger. Note that posting can be completed only one time per bank statement.\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,901],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation\ndescription: The Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. This topic explains the reconciliation process.  \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 98243\nms.assetid: 9df13adf-aa9d-4f6b-bde6-25a214611692\nms.search.region: global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: saraschi\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation","nodes":[{"pos":[0,63],"content":"Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation","nodes":[{"content":"Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation","pos":[0,63]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"The Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. This topic explains the reconciliation process.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,261],"content":"The Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. This topic explains the reconciliation process.","nodes":[{"content":"The Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition. This topic explains the reconciliation process.","pos":[0,261],"nodes":[{"content":"The Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[0,213]},{"content":"This topic explains the reconciliation process.","pos":[214,261]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[909,972],"content":"Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation","linkify":"Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation","nodes":[{"content":"Reconcile bank statements by using advanced bank reconciliation","pos":[0,63]}]},{"content":"The Advanced bank reconciliation feature lets you import electronic bank statements and automatically reconcile them with bank transactions in Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations, Enterprise edition.","pos":[1018,1231]},{"content":"This topic explains the reconciliation process.","pos":[1232,1279]},{"pos":[1283,1318],"content":"Import an electronic bank statement","linkify":"Import an electronic bank statement","nodes":[{"content":"Import an electronic bank statement","pos":[0,35]}]},{"content":"You import your bank statements by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import statement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> action on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank statements<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[1356,1461],"source":"You import your bank statements by using the **Import statement** action on the **Bank statements** page."},{"content":"On the bank statement, the bank account is identified through a combination of values that are set on the bank account details.","pos":[1462,1589]},{"content":"These values include the bank name, bank account number, routing number, Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication (SWIFT) code, and International Bank Account Number (IBAN).","pos":[1590,1782]},{"content":"You can upload a bank statement that contains information for either a single account or multiple accounts.","pos":[1785,1892]},{"content":"If there are multiple accounts, the accounts can be in different legal entities.","pos":[1893,1973]},{"content":"To import a single bank statement file for a single account, set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>No<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, and select the bank account that is associated with the statement.","pos":[1979,2202],"source":"To import a single bank statement file for a single account, set the **Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities** option to **No**, and select the bank account that is associated with the statement."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Browse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to select the associated bank statement file, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Upload<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2203,2292],"source":" Click **Browse** to select the associated bank statement file, and then click **Upload**."},{"content":"To import a single bank statement file for multiple accounts, set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2297,2455],"source":"To import a single bank statement file for multiple accounts, set the **Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities** option to **Yes**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Browse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to select the associated bank statement file, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Upload<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[2456,2545],"source":" Click **Browse** to select the associated bank statement file, and then click **Upload**."},{"content":"If any statements in the electronic file can't be associated with a bank account by using the identifying fields, they won't be imported.","pos":[2547,2684]},{"content":"However, other statements in the file can still be imported.","pos":[2685,2745]},{"content":"The user then receives a message that states that the import of bank statements was unsuccessful for specific bank accounts.","pos":[2746,2870]},{"content":"Note that the user who is importing the bank statement file must have access to a legal entity to import statements for that legal entity's bank accounts.","pos":[2871,3025]},{"content":"You can use a zip file to upload multiple statement files to Finance and Operations in a single process.","pos":[3028,3132]},{"content":"To import multiple bank statement files for multiple accounts, combine all the bank statement files into one zip file.","pos":[3133,3251]},{"content":"In the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Import bank statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> dialog box, set the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[3252,3394],"source":" In the **Import bank statements** dialog box, set the **Import statement for multiple bank accounts in all legal entities** option to **Yes**."},{"content":"Click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Browse<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to select the zip file that contains the bank statement files, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Upload<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[3395,3501],"source":" Click **Browse** to select the zip file that contains the bank statement files, and then click **Upload**."},{"content":"The import process will recognize the zip file and upload each statement that is included in it, regardless of the legal entity of the bank account.","pos":[3502,3650]},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reconcile after import<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option is available.","pos":[3653,3702],"source":"A **Reconcile after import** option is available."},{"content":"When you set this option to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, the system automatically validates the bank statement, creates a new bank reconciliation and worksheet, and runs the Default matching rule set when the bank statement is uploaded.","pos":[3703,3919],"source":" When you set this option to **Yes**, the system automatically validates the bank statement, creates a new bank reconciliation and worksheet, and runs the Default matching rule set when the bank statement is uploaded."},{"content":"This functionality automates the process up to the point where transactions must be manually matched.","pos":[3920,4021]},{"pos":[4026,4053],"content":"Validate the bank statement","linkify":"Validate the bank statement","nodes":[{"content":"Validate the bank statement","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"To validate a statement, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Validate<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[4054,4131],"source":"To validate a statement, on the **Bank statements** page, click **Validate**."},{"content":"Bank statements must be validated before they can be reconciled.","pos":[4132,4196]},{"content":"This step is automatically completed if you set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reconcile after import<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> at the time of import.","pos":[4197,4316],"source":" This step is automatically completed if you set the **Reconcile after import** option to **Yes** at the time of import."},{"content":"Bank statement validation verifies the following details:","pos":[4319,4376]},{"content":"The bank statement matches the selected bank account.","pos":[4382,4435]},{"content":"The bank statement currency matches the bank account currency.","pos":[4440,4502]},{"content":"The opening balance of the statement equals the closing balance of the previous statement for the bank account.","pos":[4507,4618]},{"content":"The date doesn’t overlap the date for another bank statement for the same bank account.","pos":[4623,4710]},{"content":"There are no gaps in the dates for statements for the bank account.","pos":[4715,4782]},{"content":"Dates on the statement lines are between the from-date and to-date of the bank statement.","pos":[4787,4876]},{"content":"The opening balance and summarized line amounts equal the ending balance.","pos":[4881,4954]},{"content":"When the validation is completed, the status of the bank statement is updated to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Validated<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[4956,5051],"source":"When the validation is completed, the status of the bank statement is updated to **Validated**."},{"content":"A bank statement must be validated before it can be reconciled.","pos":[5052,5115]},{"pos":[5120,5148],"content":"Reconcile the bank statement","linkify":"Reconcile the bank statement","nodes":[{"content":"Reconcile the bank statement","pos":[0,28]}]},{"pos":[5149,5379],"content":"After you’ve imported an electronic bank statement and validated the statement on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank statements<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can reconcile the bank statement by using the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank reconciliation<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Bank reconciliation worksheet<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> pages.","source":"After you’ve imported an electronic bank statement and validated the statement on the **Bank statements** page, you can reconcile the bank statement by using the **Bank reconciliation** and **Bank reconciliation worksheet** pages."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank reconciliation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to create a new reconciliation, and then select the bank account of the statement that was imported.","pos":[5382,5533],"source":"On the **Bank reconciliation** page, click **New** to create a new reconciliation, and then select the bank account of the statement that was imported."},{"content":"A bank account can have only one open bank reconciliation.","pos":[5534,5592]},{"content":"The cut-off date determines the bank statement transactions and Operations bank transactions that are included on the reconciliation worksheet.","pos":[5593,5736]},{"content":"By default, the current system date is used as the cut-off date, but you can change the date for the reconciliation.","pos":[5737,5853]},{"content":"The remaining header information is automatically taken from the statement.","pos":[5854,5929]},{"content":"This step is automatically completed if you set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reconcile after import<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> at the time of import.","pos":[5930,6049],"source":" This step is automatically completed if you set the **Reconcile after import** option to **Yes** at the time of import."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank reconciliation<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Worksheet<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to open the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Bank reconciliation worksheet<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> page.","pos":[6052,6160],"source":"On the **Bank reconciliation** page, click **Worksheet** to open the **Bank reconciliation worksheet** page."},{"content":"If you set the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Reconcile after import<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Yes<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>, the Default matching rule set is automatically run for the reconciliation.","pos":[6161,6296],"source":" If you set the **Reconcile after import** option to **Yes**, the Default matching rule set is automatically run for the reconciliation."},{"content":"To manually run matching rules, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Run matching rules<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> to select the matching rule sets or matching rules to run against the bank transactions.","pos":[6297,6446],"source":" To manually run matching rules, click **Run matching rules** to select the matching rule sets or matching rules to run against the bank transactions."},{"content":"If you have many transactions to process, you can complete this step as a batch process.","pos":[6447,6535]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank reconciliation worksheet<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page has four grids that contain transactions.","pos":[6538,6622],"source":"The **Bank reconciliation worksheet** page has four grids that contain transactions."},{"content":"The two upper grids show transactions from the bank statement and Operations that haven’t yet been matched.","pos":[6623,6730]},{"content":"The two lower grids show matched transactions.","pos":[6731,6777]},{"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank statement transaction details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> tab shows details for the unmatched bank statement transaction that is selected in the upper grid.","pos":[6778,6919],"source":" The **Bank statement transaction details** tab shows details for the unmatched bank statement transaction that is selected in the upper grid."},{"content":"There are three ways to match or reconcile bank statement transactions:","pos":[6922,6993]},{"content":"Match the transactions with Operations bank transactions.","pos":[6999,7056]},{"content":"Match the transactions with a reversal bank statement transaction.","pos":[7061,7127]},{"pos":[7132,7247],"content":"Mark the transactions as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, so that they can be posted later as a bank transaction in Finance and Operations.","source":"Mark the transactions as **New**, so that they can be posted later as a bank transaction in Finance and Operations."},{"content":"To manually match transactions, select the transactions in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank statement transactions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> grid, select the corresponding transactions in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Operations bank transactions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> grid, and then click <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Match<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[7249,7459],"source":"To manually match transactions, select the transactions in the **Bank statement transactions** grid, select the corresponding transactions in the **Operations bank transactions** grid, and then click **Match**."},{"content":"The selected transactions are moved from the upper grids for unmatched transactions to the lower grids for matched transactions.","pos":[7460,7588]},{"content":"Additionally, the matched and unmatched total amounts are updated.","pos":[7589,7655]},{"content":"You can have one-to-one, many-to-one, and many-to-many transaction matches.","pos":[7656,7731]},{"content":"Matches must follow the rules for allowed date differences and transaction type mapping.","pos":[7732,7820]},{"content":"These rules are set on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Cash and bank management parameters<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[7821,7893],"source":" These rules are set on the **Cash and bank management parameters** page."},{"content":"Penny differences might occur in your reconciliation.","pos":[7895,7948]},{"content":"You can match a single bank statement transaction and a single Operations bank transaction that have penny differences if the penny differences are within the tolerance amount that is defined by the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Allowed penny difference<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field on the bank account.","pos":[7949,8203],"source":" You can match a single bank statement transaction and a single Operations bank transaction that have penny differences if the penny differences are within the tolerance amount that is defined by the **Allowed penny difference** field on the bank account."},{"content":"The amount is shown in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Correction amount<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field on the matched Operations bank transaction.","pos":[8204,8302],"source":" The amount is shown in the **Correction amount** field on the matched Operations bank transaction."},{"content":"When the bank reconciliation is marked as reconciled, corrections are automatically posted by using the main account that is defined on the associated bank transaction type.","pos":[8303,8476]},{"content":"Corrections aren't supported for the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Check<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Deposit<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> document types.","pos":[8477,8555],"source":" Corrections aren't supported for the **Check** and **Deposit** document types."},{"content":"Bank statement transaction reversals are matched by using the reconciliation worksheet.","pos":[8558,8645]},{"content":"Two statement lines can be matched if the amounts are opposite, and if one of the transactions is marked as a reversal.","pos":[8646,8765]},{"content":"You can also set up a matching rule for the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Clear reversal statement lines<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> action.","pos":[8766,8852],"source":" You can also set up a matching rule for the **Clear reversal statement lines** action."},{"content":"Reversed Operations bank transactions must be reconciled by using the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Operations bank transactions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[8854,8962],"source":"Reversed Operations bank transactions must be reconciled by using the **Operations bank transactions** page."},{"content":"You can reconcile two Operations bank transactions together if the documents have the same bank account, document type, and payment reference, and if they have opposite amounts.","pos":[8963,9140]},{"content":"You can also reconcile a single canceled check to prevent those transactions from appearing on the reconciliation worksheet.","pos":[9141,9265]},{"content":"If there are new bank-initiated transactions, such as interest, fees, and charges, that aren’t yet in Finance and Operations, you can add them to a journal that is associated with the selected bank statement reconciliation.","pos":[9268,9491]},{"content":"Select a bank statement transaction in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank statement transactions<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> grid for unmatched transactions, and then click <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Mark as new<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","pos":[9492,9631],"source":" Select a bank statement transaction in the **Bank statement transactions** grid for unmatched transactions, and then click **Mark as new**."},{"content":"The status of the transaction is set to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, and the transaction is moved to the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank statement transactions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> grid for matched transactions.","pos":[9632,9779],"source":" The status of the transaction is set to **New**, and the transaction is moved to the **Bank statement transactions** grid for matched transactions."},{"content":"You will post transactions that are marked as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> later, from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[9780,9874],"source":" You will post transactions that are marked as **New** later, from the **Bank statement** page."},{"content":"You can unmatch transactions that were incorrectly matched.","pos":[9877,9936]},{"content":"Select the matched bank statement transaction, and then click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Unmatch<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>.","pos":[9937,10011],"source":" Select the matched bank statement transaction, and then click **Unmatch**."},{"content":"All associated transactions are moved back to the upper grids for unmatched transactions, and the matched and unmatched total amounts are updated.","pos":[10012,10158]},{"content":"After all statement lines have been processed, you should mark the Bank reconciliation worksheet as reconciled.","pos":[10161,10272]},{"pos":[10277,10342],"content":"Post new transactions that are associated with the reconciliation","linkify":"Post new transactions that are associated with the reconciliation","nodes":[{"content":"Post new transactions that are associated with the reconciliation","pos":[0,65]}]},{"content":"Bank statement transactions that you marked as <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the reconciliation worksheet are posted on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Bank statement<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[10343,10472],"source":"Bank statement transactions that you marked as **New** on the reconciliation worksheet are posted on the **Bank statement** page."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Bank statement<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, select the statement ID to view the statement details.","pos":[10473,10559],"source":" On the **Bank statement** page, select the statement ID to view the statement details."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Accounting<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu, you can use the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>View distributions<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>View accounting<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> options to view details behind the new transactions and the associated ledger entries.","pos":[10560,10737],"source":" On the **Accounting** menu, you can use the **View distributions** and **View accounting** options to view details behind the new transactions and the associated ledger entries."},{"content":"Select the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> option to post the bank statement lines that are marked as <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>New<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to the general ledger.","pos":[10738,10847],"source":" Select the **Post** option to post the bank statement lines that are marked as **New** to the general ledger."},{"content":"Note that posting can be completed only one time per bank statement.","pos":[10848,10916]}]}