{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Create a customer invoice\ndescription: \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 77772\nms.assetid: 00b4b40c-1576-4098-9aed-ac376fdeb8c5\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mfalkner\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Create a customer invoice\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\n\n\nA **customer invoice for a sales order** is a bill that is related to a sale, and that an organization gives to a customer. This type of customer invoice is created based on a sales order, which includes order lines and item numbers. Item numbers are specified and posted in the ledger. Subledger journal entries aren't available for a customer invoice for a sales order. \n\nA **free text invoice** isn't related to a sales order. It contains order lines that include ledger accounts, free-text descriptions, and a sales amount that you enter. You can't enter an item number on this kind of invoice. You must enter the appropriate sales tax information. A main account for the sale is indicated on each invoice line, which you can distribute to multiple ledger accounts by clicking **Distribute amounts** on the **Free text invoice** page. Additionally, the customer balance is posted to the summary account from the posting profile that is used for the free text invoice.\n\nA **pro forma invoice** is an invoice that is prepared as an estimate of the actual invoice amounts before the invoice is posted. You can print a pro forma invoice either for a customer invoice for a sales order or for a free text invoice.\n\n## Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on sales orders\nUse this process to create an invoice that is based on a sales order. You might do this if you decide to invoice the customer before you deliver the goods or services. \n\nWhen you post an invoice, the **Invoice remainder** quantity for each item is updated with the total of the invoiced quantities from the selected sales order. If both the **Invoice remainder** quantity and the **Deliver remainder** quantity for all items on the sales order are 0 (zero), the status of the sales order is changed to **Invoiced**. If the **Invoice remainder** quantity isn't 0 (zero), the status of the sales order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it.\n\nYou can view the status of the sales orders on the **All sales orders** list page. Use the **Open customer invoices** list page to view the invoices that you posted.\n\n## Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on packing slips and the date\nUse this process when one or more packing slips have been posted for the sales order. The customer invoice is based on these packing slips and reflects the quantities from them. The financial information for the invoice is based on the information that is entered when you post the invoice. \n\nYou can create a customer invoice that is based on the packing slip line items that have been shipped to date, even if all the items for a particular sales order haven't yet been shipped. You might do this if, for example, your legal entity issues one invoice per customer per month that covers all the deliveries that you ship during that month. Each packing slip represents a partial or complete delivery of the items on the sales order. \n\nWhen you post the invoice, the **Invoice remainder** quantity for each item is updated with the total of the delivered quantities from the selected packing slips. If both the **Invoice remainder** quantity and the **Deliver remainder** quantity for all items on the sales order are 0 (zero), the status of the sales order is changed to **Invoiced**. If the **Invoice remainder** quantity isn't 0 (zero), the status of the sales order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it. \n\nInventory transactions are updated with the invoice number, and the status in the **Line status** field on the sales order is changed to **Invoiced**. \n\nView the status of the sales orders in the **All sales orders** list page.\n\n## Consolidate sales orders or packing slips for posting\nUse this process when one or more sales orders are ready to be invoiced, and you want to consolidate them into a single invoice. \n\nYou can select multiple invoices on the **Sales order** list page and then use **Generate invoices** to consolidate them. On the **Posting invoice** page, you can change the **Summary order** setting to summarize by order number (where there are multiple packing slips for a single sales order) or by invoice account (where there are multiple sales orders for a single invoice account). Use the **Arrange** button to consolidate sales orders into single invoices, based on the **Summary order** settings.\n\n## Additional settings that change the posting behavior\nThe following fields change the behavior of the posting process.\n\n<table>\n<colgroup>\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n<col width=\"50%\" />\n</colgroup>\n<thead>\n<tr class=\"header\">\n<th>Field</th>\n<th>Description</th>\n</tr>\n</thead>\n<tbody>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Quantity</td>\n<td>Select the quantities to base the posting of the document on. The options that are available vary, depending on the type of document that you are posting, such as a packing slip or an invoice.\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Deliver now</strong> – Select all quantities that are entered in the <strong>Deliver now</strong> field. Use this option to confirm or deliver a partial order.</li>\n<li><strong>Picked</strong> – Select all quantities that have been picked.</li>\n<li><strong>All</strong> – Select all quantities on the sales order that haven't yet been updated by the current document type.</li>\n<li><strong>Packing slip</strong> – Select all quantities that have been updated by a packing slip.</li>\n<li><strong>Picked quantity and not stocked products</strong> – Select all quantities that have been picked and all product quantities that aren't stocked.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Posting</td>\n<td><ul>\n<li>Select this option to journalize the sales order.</li>\n<li>Clear this option to print a pro forma sales order. <strong>Note:</strong> If you made an agreement for a payment schedule, the payment schedule isn't shown on the pro forma sales order. Payment schedules are shown only on actual sales orders.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Late selection</td>\n<td>Select this option to apply the selected query later. This option is used for batch jobs. The query is run when the batch job is run.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Reduce quantity</td>\n<td>Select this option to automatically reduce the delivered quantity when the document is posted, so that the delivered quantity equals the available inventory.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Print</td>\n<td>Select when to print documents:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Current</strong> – Print documents after each invoice has been updated.</li>\n<li><strong>After</strong> – Print documents after all the invoices have been updated.</li>\n</ul>\n<strong>Note:</strong> The <strong>Print</strong> field is available only if you select the <strong>Print invoice</strong>, <strong>Print confirmation</strong>, <strong>Print picking list</strong>, or <strong>Print packing slip</strong> option. For example, on the <strong>Form sorting</strong> page, you have set up the system to sort the information by invoice account. You can then select <strong>After</strong> to print the documents in a batch that is sorted by invoice account. Otherwise, the documents are printed before processing is completed, and the documents aren't sorted in the order that is specified on the <strong>Form sorting</strong> page.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Print invoice</td>\n<td>Select this option to print the invoice. If this option is turned off, you can post an invoice without printing it.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Send e-mail</td>\n<td>Select this option to send the invoice for a sales order to the customer as an email attachment after the invoice is posted. Attachments are sent as PDF and XML files. This option is available only if you select the <strong>Enable CFD (electronic invoices)</strong> option on the <strong>Electronic invoice parameters</strong> page. <strong>Note:</strong> (MEX) This control is available only to legal entities whose primary address is in Mexico.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Use print management destination</td>\n<td>Select this option to use the print settings that are specified for the transaction, document, or module on the <strong>Print management setup</strong> page.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Check credit limit</td>\n<td>Select the information that should be analyzed when a credit limit check is performed.\n<ul>\n<li><strong>None</strong> – There is no requirement for the credit limit check.</li>\n<li><strong>Balance</strong> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance.</li>\n<li><strong>Balance + packing slip or product receipt</strong> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance and deliveries.</li>\n<li><strong>Balance+All</strong> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance, deliveries, and open orders.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Credit correction</td>\n<td>Select this option to display the credit note as a debit in the voucher transactions.</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"odd\">\n<td>Credit remaining quantity</td>\n<td>If you're posting a credit note, select this option to keep the remaining quantity on order. If this option is cleared, the remaining quantity is set to 0 (zero).</td>\n</tr>\n<tr class=\"even\">\n<td>Summary update for</td>\n<td>Select how multiple sales orders should be summarized:\n<ul>\n<li><strong>None</strong> – Don't summarize sales orders. For example, a separate invoice will be created for each sales order.</li>\n<li><strong>Invoice account</strong> – Summarize all selected orders, based on the criteria that are set up on the <strong>Summary update parameters</strong> page.</li>\n<li><strong>Order</strong> – Summarize a selected range of orders into one order that you specify. The orders are summarized based on the criteria that are set up on the <strong>Summary update parameters</strong> page. If you select this option, you must select a value in the <strong>Sales order</strong> field.</li>\n<li><strong>Automatic summary</strong> – If summary updates have been specified on the <strong>Summary update</strong> page, summarize all selected orders, based on the criteria that are set up on the <strong>Summary update parameters</strong> page. If summary updates haven't been specified, the order is posted separately.</li>\n<li><strong>Packing slip</strong> – Summarize a selected range of orders into one invoice for each packing slip. This option is available only if <strong>Packing slip</strong> is selected in the <strong>Quantity</strong> field.</li>\n</ul></td>\n</tr>\n</tbody>\n</table>\n\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,600],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Create a customer invoice\ndescription: \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 77772\nms.assetid: 00b4b40c-1576-4098-9aed-ac376fdeb8c5\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mfalkner\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Create a customer invoice","nodes":[{"pos":[0,25],"content":"Create a customer invoice","nodes":[{"content":"Create a customer invoice","pos":[0,25]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[608,633],"content":"Create a customer invoice","linkify":"Create a customer invoice","nodes":[{"content":"Create a customer invoice","pos":[0,25]}]},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>customer invoice for a sales order<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is a bill that is related to a sale, and that an organization gives to a customer.","pos":[681,804],"source":"A **customer invoice for a sales order** is a bill that is related to a sale, and that an organization gives to a customer."},{"content":"This type of customer invoice is created based on a sales order, which includes order lines and item numbers.","pos":[805,914]},{"content":"Item numbers are specified and posted in the ledger.","pos":[915,967]},{"content":"Subledger journal entries aren't available for a customer invoice for a sales order.","pos":[968,1052]},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>free text invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> isn't related to a sales order.","pos":[1055,1110],"source":"A **free text invoice** isn't related to a sales order."},{"content":"It contains order lines that include ledger accounts, free-text descriptions, and a sales amount that you enter.","pos":[1111,1223]},{"content":"You can't enter an item number on this kind of invoice.","pos":[1224,1279]},{"content":"You must enter the appropriate sales tax information.","pos":[1280,1333]},{"content":"A main account for the sale is indicated on each invoice line, which you can distribute to multiple ledger accounts by clicking <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Distribute amounts<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Free text invoice<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[1334,1519],"source":" A main account for the sale is indicated on each invoice line, which you can distribute to multiple ledger accounts by clicking **Distribute amounts** on the **Free text invoice** page."},{"content":"Additionally, the customer balance is posted to the summary account from the posting profile that is used for the free text invoice.","pos":[1520,1652]},{"content":"A <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>pro forma invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> is an invoice that is prepared as an estimate of the actual invoice amounts before the invoice is posted.","pos":[1654,1783],"source":"A **pro forma invoice** is an invoice that is prepared as an estimate of the actual invoice amounts before the invoice is posted."},{"content":"You can print a pro forma invoice either for a customer invoice for a sales order or for a free text invoice.","pos":[1784,1893]},{"pos":[1898,1972],"content":"Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on sales orders","linkify":"Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on sales orders","nodes":[{"content":"Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on sales orders","pos":[0,74]}]},{"content":"Use this process to create an invoice that is based on a sales order.","pos":[1973,2042]},{"content":"You might do this if you decide to invoice the customer before you deliver the goods or services.","pos":[2043,2140]},{"content":"When you post an invoice, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity for each item is updated with the total of the invoiced quantities from the selected sales order.","pos":[2143,2301],"source":"When you post an invoice, the **Invoice remainder** quantity for each item is updated with the total of the invoiced quantities from the selected sales order."},{"content":"If both the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Deliver remainder<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> quantity for all items on the sales order are 0 (zero), the status of the sales order is changed to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Invoiced<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[2302,2488],"source":" If both the **Invoice remainder** quantity and the **Deliver remainder** quantity for all items on the sales order are 0 (zero), the status of the sales order is changed to **Invoiced**."},{"content":"If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity isn't 0 (zero), the status of the sales order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it.","pos":[2489,2638],"source":" If the **Invoice remainder** quantity isn't 0 (zero), the status of the sales order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it."},{"content":"You can view the status of the sales orders on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All sales orders<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list page.","pos":[2640,2722],"source":"You can view the status of the sales orders on the **All sales orders** list page."},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open customer invoices<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list page to view the invoices that you posted.","pos":[2723,2805],"source":" Use the **Open customer invoices** list page to view the invoices that you posted."},{"pos":[2810,2898],"content":"Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on packing slips and the date","linkify":"Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on packing slips and the date","nodes":[{"content":"Post and print individual customer invoices that are based on packing slips and the date","pos":[0,88]}]},{"content":"Use this process when one or more packing slips have been posted for the sales order.","pos":[2899,2984]},{"content":"The customer invoice is based on these packing slips and reflects the quantities from them.","pos":[2985,3076]},{"content":"The financial information for the invoice is based on the information that is entered when you post the invoice.","pos":[3077,3189]},{"content":"You can create a customer invoice that is based on the packing slip line items that have been shipped to date, even if all the items for a particular sales order haven't yet been shipped.","pos":[3192,3379]},{"content":"You might do this if, for example, your legal entity issues one invoice per customer per month that covers all the deliveries that you ship during that month.","pos":[3380,3538]},{"content":"Each packing slip represents a partial or complete delivery of the items on the sales order.","pos":[3539,3631]},{"content":"When you post the invoice, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity for each item is updated with the total of the delivered quantities from the selected packing slips.","pos":[3634,3796],"source":"When you post the invoice, the **Invoice remainder** quantity for each item is updated with the total of the delivered quantities from the selected packing slips."},{"content":"If both the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Deliver remainder<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> quantity for all items on the sales order are 0 (zero), the status of the sales order is changed to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Invoiced<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[3797,3983],"source":" If both the **Invoice remainder** quantity and the **Deliver remainder** quantity for all items on the sales order are 0 (zero), the status of the sales order is changed to **Invoiced**."},{"content":"If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity isn't 0 (zero), the status of the sales order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it.","pos":[3984,4133],"source":" If the **Invoice remainder** quantity isn't 0 (zero), the status of the sales order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it."},{"pos":[4136,4286],"content":"Inventory transactions are updated with the invoice number, and the status in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Line status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field on the sales order is changed to <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Invoiced<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept>.","source":"Inventory transactions are updated with the invoice number, and the status in the **Line status** field on the sales order is changed to **Invoiced**."},{"pos":[4289,4363],"content":"View the status of the sales orders in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>All sales orders<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list page.","source":"View the status of the sales orders in the **All sales orders** list page."},{"pos":[4368,4421],"content":"Consolidate sales orders or packing slips for posting","linkify":"Consolidate sales orders or packing slips for posting","nodes":[{"content":"Consolidate sales orders or packing slips for posting","pos":[0,53]}]},{"content":"Use this process when one or more sales orders are ready to be invoiced, and you want to consolidate them into a single invoice.","pos":[4422,4550]},{"content":"You can select multiple invoices on the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Sales order<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> list page and then use <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Generate invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to consolidate them.","pos":[4553,4674],"source":"You can select multiple invoices on the **Sales order** list page and then use **Generate invoices** to consolidate them."},{"content":"On the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Posting invoice<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page, you can change the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Summary order<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> setting to summarize by order number (where there are multiple packing slips for a single sales order) or by invoice account (where there are multiple sales orders for a single invoice account).","pos":[4675,4939],"source":" On the **Posting invoice** page, you can change the **Summary order** setting to summarize by order number (where there are multiple packing slips for a single sales order) or by invoice account (where there are multiple sales orders for a single invoice account)."},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Arrange<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button to consolidate sales orders into single invoices, based on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Summary order<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> settings.","pos":[4940,5057],"source":" Use the **Arrange** button to consolidate sales orders into single invoices, based on the **Summary order** settings."},{"pos":[5062,5114],"content":"Additional settings that change the posting behavior","linkify":"Additional settings that change the posting behavior","nodes":[{"content":"Additional settings that change the posting behavior","pos":[0,52]}]},{"content":"The following fields change the behavior of the posting process.","pos":[5115,5179]},{"content":"Field","pos":[5284,5289]},{"content":"Description","pos":[5299,5310]},{"content":"Quantity","pos":[5360,5368]},{"content":"Select the quantities to base the posting of the document on.","pos":[5378,5439]},{"content":"The options that are available vary, depending on the type of document that you are posting, such as a packing slip or an invoice.","pos":[5440,5570]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Deliver now<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select all quantities that are entered in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Deliver now<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[5580,5692],"source":"<strong>Deliver now</strong> – Select all quantities that are entered in the <strong>Deliver now</strong> field."},{"content":"Use this option to confirm or deliver a partial order.","pos":[5693,5747]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Picked<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select all quantities that have been picked.","pos":[5757,5827],"source":"<strong>Picked</strong> – Select all quantities that have been picked."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>All<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select all quantities on the sales order that haven't yet been updated by the current document type.","pos":[5837,5960],"source":"<strong>All</strong> – Select all quantities on the sales order that haven't yet been updated by the current document type."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Packing slip<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select all quantities that have been updated by a packing slip.","pos":[5970,6065],"source":"<strong>Packing slip</strong> – Select all quantities that have been updated by a packing slip."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Picked quantity and not stocked products<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Select all quantities that have been picked and all product quantities that aren't stocked.","pos":[6075,6226],"source":"<strong>Picked quantity and not stocked products</strong> – Select all quantities that have been picked and all product quantities that aren't stocked."},{"content":"Posting","pos":[6271,6278]},{"content":"Select this option to journalize the sales order.","pos":[6297,6346]},{"content":"Clear this option to print a pro forma sales order.","pos":[6356,6407]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> If you made an agreement for a payment schedule, the payment schedule isn't shown on the pro forma sales order.","pos":[6408,6542],"source":"<strong>Note:</strong> If you made an agreement for a payment schedule, the payment schedule isn't shown on the pro forma sales order."},{"content":"Payment schedules are shown only on actual sales orders.","pos":[6543,6599]},{"content":"Late selection","pos":[6643,6657]},{"content":"Select this option to apply the selected query later.","pos":[6667,6720]},{"content":"This option is used for batch jobs.","pos":[6721,6756]},{"content":"The query is run when the batch job is run.","pos":[6757,6800]},{"content":"Reduce quantity","pos":[6834,6849]},{"content":"Select this option to automatically reduce the delivered quantity when the document is posted, so that the delivered quantity equals the available inventory.","pos":[6859,7016]},{"content":"Print","pos":[7049,7054]},{"content":"Select when to print documents:","pos":[7064,7095],"source":"Select when to print documents:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Current<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Print documents after each invoice has been updated.","pos":[7105,7184],"source":"<strong>Current</strong> – Print documents after each invoice has been updated."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>After<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Print documents after all the invoices have been updated.","pos":[7194,7276],"source":"<strong>After</strong> – Print documents after all the invoices have been updated."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">\n&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> The <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Print<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field is available only if you select the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Print invoice<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p4\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Print confirmation<ept id=\"p4\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, <bpt id=\"p5\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Print picking list<ept id=\"p5\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept>, or <bpt id=\"p6\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Print packing slip<ept id=\"p6\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> option.","pos":[7287,7532],"source":"\n<strong>Note:</strong> The <strong>Print</strong> field is available only if you select the <strong>Print invoice</strong>, <strong>Print confirmation</strong>, <strong>Print picking list</strong>, or <strong>Print packing slip</strong> option."},{"content":"For example, on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Form sorting<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page, you have set up the system to sort the information by invoice account.","pos":[7533,7659],"source":" For example, on the <strong>Form sorting</strong> page, you have set up the system to sort the information by invoice account."},{"content":"You can then select <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>After<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> to print the documents in a batch that is sorted by invoice account.","pos":[7660,7771],"source":" You can then select <strong>After</strong> to print the documents in a batch that is sorted by invoice account."},{"content":"Otherwise, the documents are printed before processing is completed, and the documents aren't sorted in the order that is specified on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Form sorting<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[7772,7946],"source":" Otherwise, the documents are printed before processing is completed, and the documents aren't sorted in the order that is specified on the <strong>Form sorting</strong> page."},{"content":"Print invoice","pos":[7980,7993]},{"content":"Select this option to print the invoice.","pos":[8003,8043]},{"content":"If this option is turned off, you can post an invoice without printing it.","pos":[8044,8118]},{"content":"Send e-mail","pos":[8151,8162]},{"content":"Select this option to send the invoice for a sales order to the customer as an email attachment after the invoice is posted.","pos":[8172,8296]},{"content":"Attachments are sent as PDF and XML files.","pos":[8297,8339]},{"content":"This option is available only if you select the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Enable CFD (electronic invoices)<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> option on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Electronic invoice parameters<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[8340,8504],"source":" This option is available only if you select the <strong>Enable CFD (electronic invoices)</strong> option on the <strong>Electronic invoice parameters</strong> page."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Note:<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> (MEX) This control is available only to legal entities whose primary address is in Mexico.","pos":[8505,8618],"source":"<strong>Note:</strong> (MEX) This control is available only to legal entities whose primary address is in Mexico."},{"content":"Use print management destination","pos":[8652,8684]},{"content":"Select this option to use the print settings that are specified for the transaction, document, or module on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Print management setup<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[8694,8851],"source":"Select this option to use the print settings that are specified for the transaction, document, or module on the <strong>Print management setup</strong> page."},{"content":"Check credit limit","pos":[8884,8902]},{"content":"Select the information that should be analyzed when a credit limit check is performed.","pos":[8912,8998]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>None<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – There is no requirement for the credit limit check.","pos":[9008,9083],"source":"<strong>None</strong> – There is no requirement for the credit limit check."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Balance<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance.","pos":[9093,9177],"source":"<strong>Balance</strong> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Balance + packing slip or product receipt<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance and deliveries.","pos":[9187,9320],"source":"<strong>Balance + packing slip or product receipt</strong> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance and deliveries."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Balance+All<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance, deliveries, and open orders.","pos":[9330,9447],"source":"<strong>Balance+All</strong> – The credit limit is checked against the customer balance, deliveries, and open orders."},{"content":"Credit correction","pos":[9492,9509]},{"content":"Select this option to display the credit note as a debit in the voucher transactions.","pos":[9519,9604]},{"content":"Credit remaining quantity","pos":[9637,9662]},{"content":"If you're posting a credit note, select this option to keep the remaining quantity on order.","pos":[9672,9764]},{"content":"If this option is cleared, the remaining quantity is set to 0 (zero).","pos":[9765,9834]},{"content":"Summary update for","pos":[9868,9886]},{"content":"Select how multiple sales orders should be summarized:","pos":[9896,9950],"source":"Select how multiple sales orders should be summarized:\n"},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>None<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Don't summarize sales orders.","pos":[9960,10013],"source":"<strong>None</strong> – Don't summarize sales orders."},{"content":"For example, a separate invoice will be created for each sales order.","pos":[10014,10083]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Invoice account<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Summarize all selected orders, based on the criteria that are set up on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Summary update parameters<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[10093,10252],"source":"<strong>Invoice account</strong> – Summarize all selected orders, based on the criteria that are set up on the <strong>Summary update parameters</strong> page."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Order<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Summarize a selected range of orders into one order that you specify.","pos":[10262,10356],"source":"<strong>Order</strong> – Summarize a selected range of orders into one order that you specify."},{"content":"The orders are summarized based on the criteria that are set up on the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Summary update parameters<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[10357,10476],"source":" The orders are summarized based on the criteria that are set up on the <strong>Summary update parameters</strong> page."},{"content":"If you select this option, you must select a value in the <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Sales order<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[10477,10570],"source":" If you select this option, you must select a value in the <strong>Sales order</strong> field."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Automatic summary<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – If summary updates have been specified on the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Summary update<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page, summarize all selected orders, based on the criteria that are set up on the <bpt id=\"p3\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Summary update parameters<ept id=\"p3\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> page.","pos":[10580,10825],"source":"<strong>Automatic summary</strong> – If summary updates have been specified on the <strong>Summary update</strong> page, summarize all selected orders, based on the criteria that are set up on the <strong>Summary update parameters</strong> page."},{"content":"If summary updates haven't been specified, the order is posted separately.","pos":[10826,10900]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Packing slip<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> – Summarize a selected range of orders into one invoice for each packing slip.","pos":[10910,11018],"source":"<strong>Packing slip</strong> – Summarize a selected range of orders into one invoice for each packing slip."},{"content":"This option is available only if <bpt id=\"p1\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Packing slip<ept id=\"p1\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> is selected in the <bpt id=\"p2\">&lt;strong&gt;</bpt>Quantity<ept id=\"p2\">&lt;/strong&gt;</ept> field.","pos":[11019,11133],"source":" This option is available only if <strong>Packing slip</strong> is selected in the <strong>Quantity</strong> field."}]}