{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Vendor invoices overview\ndescription: This article provides general information about vendor invoices. Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received. Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services. \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 13971\nms.assetid: 0ec4dbc0-2eeb-423b-8592-4b5d37e559d3\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mfalkner\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Vendor invoices overview\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis article provides general information about vendor invoices. Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received. Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services. \n\nVendor invoices\n---------------\n\nA vendor invoice from a purchase order is an invoice that is produced when products or services are received according to a purchase order that was placed with a vendor. The vendor invoice contains a header, and one or more lines for items or services. A vendor invoice completes the cycle from purchase order to product receipt to vendor invoice. \n\nAlthough some vendor invoices are connected to a purchase order, vendor invoices can also contain lines that don't correspond to purchase order lines. You can also create vendor invoices that aren't associated with any purchase order. These vendor invoices might represent ongoing services, such as a utility bill, and you don't have to reference a purchase order when you add them. \n\nThere are several ways to enter a vendor invoice:\n\n-   The vendor invoice register lets you quickly enter invoices that don't reference a purchase order, so that you can accrue the expense. By using the vendor invoice approval journal, you can select those invoices and post them to the vendor balance to reverse the accrual.\n-   The vendor invoice journal lets you quickly enter invoices that don't reference a purchase order, in a single step.\n-   Together with the vendor invoice pool, the vendor invoice register lets you quickly enter invoices to accrue the expense. You can open the associated purchase orders later to post the invoice against the expense account.\n-   The **Open vendor invoices** and **Pending vendor invoices** pages let you create vendor invoices from confirmed purchase orders.\n\nThe following discussion provide more information about how to use the **Open vendor invoices** or **Pending vendor invoices** page to create a vendor invoice from a purchase order.\n\n## Understanding invoice line quantities\nWhen you open a vendor invoice from a related purchase order, invoice lines are created from the purchase order. By default, the quantities are taken from the product receipt quantity. However, you can use any of the following default behaviors:\n\n-   **Receive now quantity** – Use this option for partial shipments. The default value in the **Quantity** field is taken from the **Receive now** quantity field on the purchase order.\n-   **Ordered quantity** – Use this option for complete shipments. The default value in the **Quantity** field is taken from the **Ordered** quantity field on the purchase order.\n-   **Registered quantity** – Use this option if the item requires registration, as specified on the **Item model groups** page. The default value in the **Quantity** field is the physical update quantity that has been registered.\n-   **Product receipt quantity** – Use this option if a product receipt has already been received for the order. The default value in the **Quantity** field is taken from the total quantity of available product receipts.\n-   **Registered quantity and services** – Use this option if quantities have been registered in arrival journals for stocked items or items that aren't stocked. This option also includes services, regardless of whether they are registered.\n\nIf your legal entity uses invoice matching, you can view the results of the quantity matching in the **Product receipt quantity match** column. You can also use the **Matching details** menu command on the **Review** tab to view the results of the quantity matching.\n\n## Adding a line that wasn't on the purchase order\nYou can add a new line that wasn't on the purchase order to the vendor invoice. You must select an item number or procurement category. You can then add quantities, prices, and amounts to the line. The line will be included only in matching policies for invoice totals.\n\n## Submitting a vendor invoice for review\nYour organization might use workflows to manage the review process for vendor invoices. Workflow review can be required for the invoice header, the invoice line, or both. The workflow controls apply to the header or the line, depending on where the focus is when you click the control. Instead of the **Post** button, you will see a **Submit** button that you can use to send the vendor invoice through the review process.\n\n## Matching vendor invoices to product receipts\nYou can enter and save information for vendor invoices, and you can match invoice lines to product receipt lines. You can also match partial quantities for a line. \n\nYou can create a vendor invoice that is based on the product receipt line items that have been received to date, even if all the items for a particular purchase order haven't yet been received. For example, you might use this option if a vendor sends one invoice per month that covers all the deliveries that the vendor shipped during that month. Each product receipt represents a partial or complete delivery of the items on the purchase order. \n\nWhen you post the invoice, the **Invoice remainder** quantity for each item is updated with the total of the received quantities from the selected product receipts. If both the **Invoice remainder** quantity and the **Deliver remainder** quantity for all items on the purchase order are 0 (zero), the status of the purchase order is changed to **Invoiced**. If the **Invoice remainder** quantity isn't 0, the status of the purchase order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it.\n\nThis option assumes that at least one product receipt has been posted for the purchase order. The vendor invoice is based on these product receipts and reflects the quantities from them. The financial information for the invoice is based on the information that is entered when you post the invoice.\n\n## Working with multiple invoices\n\nYou can work with multiple invoices at the same time and post them all at the same time. If you must create multiple invoices, use the **Pending vendor invoices** page. If you must post and print multiple vendor invoices, use the invoice approval journal page. If you're using the invoice approval journal, at least one product receipt must be posted for the purchase order, and an invoice for the purchase order must be posted in an invoice register. The financial information for the invoice comes from the invoice that was posted in the register.\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,883],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Vendor invoices overview\ndescription: This article provides general information about vendor invoices. Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received. Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services. \nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\n# ms.search.form: \n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 13971\nms.assetid: 0ec4dbc0-2eeb-423b-8592-4b5d37e559d3\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: mfalkner\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Vendor invoices overview","nodes":[{"pos":[0,24],"content":"Vendor invoices overview","nodes":[{"content":"Vendor invoices overview","pos":[0,24]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article provides general information about vendor invoices. Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received. Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,283],"content":"This article provides general information about vendor invoices. Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received. Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services.","nodes":[{"content":"This article provides general information about vendor invoices. Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received. Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services.","pos":[0,283],"nodes":[{"content":"This article provides general information about vendor invoices.","pos":[0,64]},{"content":"Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received.","pos":[65,151]},{"content":"Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services.","pos":[152,283]}]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[891,915],"content":"Vendor invoices overview","linkify":"Vendor invoices overview","nodes":[{"content":"Vendor invoices overview","pos":[0,24]}]},{"content":"This article provides general information about vendor invoices.","pos":[961,1025]},{"content":"Vendor invoices are requests for payment for products and services that were received.","pos":[1026,1112]},{"content":"Vendor invoices can represent a bill for ongoing services, or they can be based on purchase orders for specific items and services.","pos":[1113,1244]},{"pos":[1247,1262],"content":"Vendor invoices","linkify":"Vendor invoices","nodes":[{"content":"Vendor invoices","pos":[0,15]}]},{"content":"A vendor invoice from a purchase order is an invoice that is produced when products or services are received according to a purchase order that was placed with a vendor.","pos":[1280,1449]},{"content":"The vendor invoice contains a header, and one or more lines for items or services.","pos":[1450,1532]},{"content":"A vendor invoice completes the cycle from purchase order to product receipt to vendor invoice.","pos":[1533,1627]},{"content":"Although some vendor invoices are connected to a purchase order, vendor invoices can also contain lines that don't correspond to purchase order lines.","pos":[1630,1780]},{"content":"You can also create vendor invoices that aren't associated with any purchase order.","pos":[1781,1864]},{"content":"These vendor invoices might represent ongoing services, such as a utility bill, and you don't have to reference a purchase order when you add them.","pos":[1865,2012]},{"content":"There are several ways to enter a vendor invoice:","pos":[2015,2064]},{"content":"The vendor invoice register lets you quickly enter invoices that don't reference a purchase order, so that you can accrue the expense.","pos":[2070,2204]},{"content":"By using the vendor invoice approval journal, you can select those invoices and post them to the vendor balance to reverse the accrual.","pos":[2205,2340]},{"content":"The vendor invoice journal lets you quickly enter invoices that don't reference a purchase order, in a single step.","pos":[2345,2460]},{"content":"Together with the vendor invoice pool, the vendor invoice register lets you quickly enter invoices to accrue the expense.","pos":[2465,2586]},{"content":"You can open the associated purchase orders later to post the invoice against the expense account.","pos":[2587,2685]},{"pos":[2690,2819],"content":"The <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open vendor invoices<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pending vendor invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> pages let you create vendor invoices from confirmed purchase orders.","source":"The **Open vendor invoices** and **Pending vendor invoices** pages let you create vendor invoices from confirmed purchase orders."},{"pos":[2821,3002],"content":"The following discussion provide more information about how to use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Open vendor invoices<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> or <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Pending vendor invoices<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page to create a vendor invoice from a purchase order.","source":"The following discussion provide more information about how to use the **Open vendor invoices** or **Pending vendor invoices** page to create a vendor invoice from a purchase order."},{"pos":[3007,3044],"content":"Understanding invoice line quantities","linkify":"Understanding invoice line quantities","nodes":[{"content":"Understanding invoice line quantities","pos":[0,37]}]},{"content":"When you open a vendor invoice from a related purchase order, invoice lines are created from the purchase order.","pos":[3045,3157]},{"content":"By default, the quantities are taken from the product receipt quantity.","pos":[3158,3229]},{"content":"However, you can use any of the following default behaviors:","pos":[3230,3290]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Receive now quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Use this option for partial shipments.","pos":[3296,3361],"source":"**Receive now quantity** – Use this option for partial shipments."},{"content":"The default value in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is taken from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Receive now<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> quantity field on the purchase order.","pos":[3362,3477],"source":" The default value in the **Quantity** field is taken from the **Receive now** quantity field on the purchase order."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Ordered quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Use this option for complete shipments.","pos":[3482,3544],"source":"**Ordered quantity** – Use this option for complete shipments."},{"content":"The default value in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is taken from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Ordered<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> quantity field on the purchase order.","pos":[3545,3656],"source":" The default value in the **Quantity** field is taken from the **Ordered** quantity field on the purchase order."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Registered quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Use this option if the item requires registration, as specified on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Item model groups<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[3661,3785],"source":"**Registered quantity** – Use this option if the item requires registration, as specified on the **Item model groups** page."},{"content":"The default value in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is the physical update quantity that has been registered.","pos":[3786,3887],"source":" The default value in the **Quantity** field is the physical update quantity that has been registered."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product receipt quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Use this option if a product receipt has already been received for the order.","pos":[3892,4000],"source":"**Product receipt quantity** – Use this option if a product receipt has already been received for the order."},{"content":"The default value in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Quantity<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> field is taken from the total quantity of available product receipts.","pos":[4001,4108],"source":" The default value in the **Quantity** field is taken from the total quantity of available product receipts."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Registered quantity and services<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> – Use this option if quantities have been registered in arrival journals for stocked items or items that aren't stocked.","pos":[4113,4270],"source":"**Registered quantity and services** – Use this option if quantities have been registered in arrival journals for stocked items or items that aren't stocked."},{"content":"This option also includes services, regardless of whether they are registered.","pos":[4271,4349]},{"content":"If your legal entity uses invoice matching, you can view the results of the quantity matching in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Product receipt quantity match<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> column.","pos":[4351,4494],"source":"If your legal entity uses invoice matching, you can view the results of the quantity matching in the **Product receipt quantity match** column."},{"content":"You can also use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Matching details<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> menu command on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Review<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> tab to view the results of the quantity matching.","pos":[4495,4617],"source":" You can also use the **Matching details** menu command on the **Review** tab to view the results of the quantity matching."},{"pos":[4622,4669],"content":"Adding a line that wasn't on the purchase order","linkify":"Adding a line that wasn't on the purchase order","nodes":[{"content":"Adding a line that wasn't on the purchase order","pos":[0,47]}]},{"content":"You can add a new line that wasn't on the purchase order to the vendor invoice.","pos":[4670,4749]},{"content":"You must select an item number or procurement category.","pos":[4750,4805]},{"content":"You can then add quantities, prices, and amounts to the line.","pos":[4806,4867]},{"content":"The line will be included only in matching policies for invoice totals.","pos":[4868,4939]},{"pos":[4944,4982],"content":"Submitting a vendor invoice for review","linkify":"Submitting a vendor invoice for review","nodes":[{"content":"Submitting a vendor invoice for review","pos":[0,38]}]},{"content":"Your organization might use workflows to manage the review process for vendor invoices.","pos":[4983,5070]},{"content":"Workflow review can be required for the invoice header, the invoice line, or both.","pos":[5071,5153]},{"content":"The workflow controls apply to the header or the line, depending on where the focus is when you click the control.","pos":[5154,5268]},{"content":"Instead of the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Post<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button, you will see a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Submit<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> button that you can use to send the vendor invoice through the review process.","pos":[5269,5405],"source":" Instead of the **Post** button, you will see a **Submit** button that you can use to send the vendor invoice through the review process."},{"pos":[5410,5454],"content":"Matching vendor invoices to product receipts","linkify":"Matching vendor invoices to product receipts","nodes":[{"content":"Matching vendor invoices to product receipts","pos":[0,44]}]},{"content":"You can enter and save information for vendor invoices, and you can match invoice lines to product receipt lines.","pos":[5455,5568]},{"content":"You can also match partial quantities for a line.","pos":[5569,5618]},{"content":"You can create a vendor invoice that is based on the product receipt line items that have been received to date, even if all the items for a particular purchase order haven't yet been received.","pos":[5621,5814]},{"content":"For example, you might use this option if a vendor sends one invoice per month that covers all the deliveries that the vendor shipped during that month.","pos":[5815,5967]},{"content":"Each product receipt represents a partial or complete delivery of the items on the purchase order.","pos":[5968,6066]},{"content":"When you post the invoice, the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity for each item is updated with the total of the received quantities from the selected product receipts.","pos":[6069,6233],"source":"When you post the invoice, the **Invoice remainder** quantity for each item is updated with the total of the received quantities from the selected product receipts."},{"content":"If both the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity and the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Deliver remainder<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> quantity for all items on the purchase order are 0 (zero), the status of the purchase order is changed to <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Invoiced<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept>.","pos":[6234,6426],"source":" If both the **Invoice remainder** quantity and the **Deliver remainder** quantity for all items on the purchase order are 0 (zero), the status of the purchase order is changed to **Invoiced**."},{"content":"If the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Invoice remainder<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> quantity isn't 0, the status of the purchase order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it.","pos":[6427,6572],"source":" If the **Invoice remainder** quantity isn't 0, the status of the purchase order remains unchanged, and additional invoices can be entered for it."},{"content":"This option assumes that at least one product receipt has been posted for the purchase order.","pos":[6574,6667]},{"content":"The vendor invoice is based on these product receipts and reflects the quantities from them.","pos":[6668,6760]},{"content":"The financial information for the invoice is based on the information that is entered when you post the invoice.","pos":[6761,6873]},{"pos":[6878,6908],"content":"Working with multiple invoices","linkify":"Working with multiple invoices","nodes":[{"content":"Working with multiple invoices","pos":[0,30]}]},{"content":"You can work with multiple invoices at the same time and post them all at the same time.","pos":[6910,6998]},{"content":"If you must create multiple invoices, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Pending vendor invoices<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[6999,7078],"source":" If you must create multiple invoices, use the **Pending vendor invoices** page."},{"content":"If you must post and print multiple vendor invoices, use the invoice approval journal page.","pos":[7079,7170]},{"content":"If you're using the invoice approval journal, at least one product receipt must be posted for the purchase order, and an invoice for the purchase order must be posted in an invoice register.","pos":[7171,7361]},{"content":"The financial information for the invoice comes from the invoice that was posted in the register.","pos":[7362,7459]}]}