{"content":"---\n# required metadata\n\ntitle: Manage a recruiting process\ndescription: This article describes a concept that recruiters can use to track the steps in a recruiting process, including efforts to advertise open positions and recruit applicants, tracking applicant and application information, interviewing applicants, and selecting one or more candidates to fill the open positions in your organization.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: HRMApplication, HRMRecruitingTable\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 7501\nms.assetid: 1ad725bf-20e2-42a1-8068-111f7ddddad9\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n\n---\n\n# Manage a recruiting process\n\n[!include[banner](../includes/banner.md)]\n\n\nThis topic describes a concept that recruiters can use to track the steps in a recruiting process, including efforts to advertise open positions and recruit applicants, tracking applicant and application information, interviewing applicants, and selecting one or more candidates to fill the open positions in your organization.\n\nOverview\n--------\n\nRecruitment projects can help you organize the steps you'll complete when filling open positions in a legal entity. An applicant is a person who applies for employment to your enterprise.  An application is an applicant's expression of interest in being employed by a company and may be tied to a recruitment project to express interest in a specific opening.  A single applicant may have multiple applications within the same legal entity or across multiple companies in your organization.\n\nRecruitment projects\n--------------------\n\nRecruitment projects allow recruiters to track progress against filling one or more open positions.  The recruitment project identifies the department and job for which one or more positions are open. Recruitment projects also track following information for open positions:\n-   The specific number of open positions\n-   The hiring manager and an alternative contact for the position\n-   The date that the requisition was approved\n-   The application deadline\n-   The estimated start date\n\nThe recruitment project contains the **Job ad** used on the **Employee self service** to advertise the opening. To display the opening to employees, the recruitment project must have a **Job ad**, the **Display on employee self service** field must be set to Yes, the **Application deadline** must be set to a future date, and the recruitment project must have a **Project status** of Started. The following table lists the possible recruitment project statuses and their description.\n\n| **Status**    | **Indicates that…**                                                                  |\n|-----------|------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Scheduled | Recruiting efforts are being prepared.  Recruiting has not yet started for this project. |\n| Started   | Applications are now being accepted for the openings in this project.                    |\n| Finished  | All openings for this project have been filled.                                          |\n| Canceled  | Recruiting has been canceled for this project.                                           |\n\nRecruiters can also record the **Media** used to advertise the opening through external outlets as well as track **Developments** against the project or applications.\n\nApplicants\n----------\n\nAn applicant is a person who applies for a job in your enterprise.  Applicants are shared among all legal entities in your organization giving you a large pool of talent to search from. You can maintain competencies, references, accommodation requests, and personal information for applicants. When you create an applicant record, a person record for that applicant is created in the global address book. You can use the **Applicant** page to update the following global address book information for people who are applicants:\n-   Address information\n-   Contact information\n-   Identification information\n-   Name details\n-   Personal information\n\n## Applications\nYou can record information from employment applications that you receive in the **Application** page. The application is the applicant's expression of interest in a job opening in your organization.  To create an application, the applicant must already exist as an applicant or person in your system.\nEmployment applications submitted by applicants on the web are either solicited applications that were entered in response to a job ad, or are unsolicited applications. Solicited applications are automatically associated with the recruitment project that the job ad was created from. Unsolicited applications are associated with the recruitment project that is specified in the **Recruitment** area of the **Human resources parameters** page.\n### Application status\n\nThe application status indicates where an application is in the recruitment process. The following table lists the possible application statuses and their description.\n\n| Status    | Indicates that…                                                                           |\n|-----------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|\n| Received  | The application was received.                                                             |\n| Confirmed | A notice can be sent to the applicant to confirm receipt of their application.            |\n| Interview | An interview invitation can be sent to the applicant.                                     |\n| Rejection | A rejection letter can be sent to the applicant.                                          |\n| Canceled  | A withdrawal confirmation can be sent to the applicant. This status is assigned manually. |\n| Employed  | An employment offer can be sent to the applicant.                                         |\n\n### Correspondence actions\n\nAn **Application’s** correspondence action determines the document or e-mail template that you use to communicate with the applicant who submitted the application. You can associate **Application bookmarks** with correspondence actions to allow you to use values from the Application, Applicant, Interview, and Recruitment project pages in your communications with applicants.  **Application e-mail templates** can be created for the correspondence actions to quickly send e-mails to applicants who have an application with a certain status and correspondence action combination. For example, you may send a Confirmation e-mail to all Applications with a **Status** of Received and a **Correspondence action** of Received.  After sending the e-mail, you have the option to automatically update the status of the applications.\n\n## Application routing\n\nIf an application must be reviewed by several workers, you can use the **Application routing** page to create a worker circulation list in order to manage the process.\n\n## Interviews\n\n**Applicant interviews** can be scheduled from the **Applications** page.  Use the **Send meeting information** button to send a calendar file with the interview schedule information to the applicant and interviewer.\n\n## Skill mapping\n\n**Skill mapping** and **Skill mapping profiles** can be used to identify candidates who may be a good fit for an opening.\n\n## Hiring applicants\n\nUse the **Applications** page to hire an applicant. When you hire an applicant, the application record will have a status of **Employed** and the applicant’s global address book person record is associated with the new worker record. Modifications to the global address book information for the new worker record are also displayed in the applicant record. This can help reduce data entry if the new worker ever applies for a different job within your enterprise.  To hire an existing worker into a new position, click **Change position** in the **Application status** drop down to initiate the transfer process.\n\n\n\n\n\n","nodes":[{"pos":[4,962],"embed":true,"restype":"x-metadata","content":"# required metadata\n\ntitle: Manage a recruiting process\ndescription: This article describes a concept that recruiters can use to track the steps in a recruiting process, including efforts to advertise open positions and recruit applicants, tracking applicant and application information, interviewing applicants, and selecting one or more candidates to fill the open positions in your organization.\nauthor: twheeloc\nmanager: AnnBe\nms.date: 06/20/2017\nms.topic: article\nms.prod: \nms.service: dynamics-ax-applications\nms.technology: \n\n# optional metadata\n\nms.search.form: HRMApplication, HRMRecruitingTable\n# ROBOTS: \naudience: Application User\n# ms.devlang: \nms.reviewer: twheeloc\nms.search.scope: Core, AX 7.0.0, Operations, UnifiedOperations\n# ms.tgt_pltfrm: \nms.custom: 7501\nms.assetid: 1ad725bf-20e2-42a1-8068-111f7ddddad9\nms.search.region: Global\n# ms.search.industry: \nms.author: twheeloc\nms.search.validFrom: 2016-02-28\nms.dyn365.ops.version: AX 7.0.0\n","nodes":[{"content":"Manage a recruiting process","nodes":[{"pos":[0,27],"content":"Manage a recruiting process","nodes":[{"content":"Manage a recruiting process","pos":[0,27]}]}],"path":["title"],"extradata":"MT"},{"content":"This article describes a concept that recruiters can use to track the steps in a recruiting process, including efforts to advertise open positions and recruit applicants, tracking applicant and application information, interviewing applicants, and selecting one or more candidates to fill the open positions in your organization.","nodes":[{"pos":[0,329],"content":"This article describes a concept that recruiters can use to track the steps in a recruiting process, including efforts to advertise open positions and recruit applicants, tracking applicant and application information, interviewing applicants, and selecting one or more candidates to fill the open positions in your organization.","nodes":[{"content":"This article describes a concept that recruiters can use to track the steps in a recruiting process, including efforts to advertise open positions and recruit applicants, tracking applicant and application information, interviewing applicants, and selecting one or more candidates to fill the open positions in your organization.","pos":[0,329]}]}],"path":["description"],"extradata":"MT"}],"header":"# required metadata\n","yml":true},{"pos":[970,997],"content":"Manage a recruiting process","linkify":"Manage a recruiting process","nodes":[{"content":"Manage a recruiting process","pos":[0,27]}]},{"content":"This topic describes a concept that recruiters can use to track the steps in a recruiting process, including efforts to advertise open positions and recruit applicants, tracking applicant and application information, interviewing applicants, and selecting one or more candidates to fill the open positions in your organization.","pos":[1043,1370]},{"pos":[1372,1380],"content":"Overview","linkify":"Overview","nodes":[{"content":"Overview","pos":[0,8]}]},{"content":"Recruitment projects can help you organize the steps you'll complete when filling open positions in a legal entity.","pos":[1391,1506]},{"content":"An applicant is a person who applies for employment to your enterprise.","pos":[1507,1578]},{"content":"An application is an applicant's expression of interest in being employed by a company and may be tied to a recruitment project to express interest in a specific opening.","pos":[1580,1750]},{"content":"A single applicant may have multiple applications within the same legal entity or across multiple companies in your organization.","pos":[1752,1881]},{"pos":[1883,1903],"content":"Recruitment projects","linkify":"Recruitment projects","nodes":[{"content":"Recruitment projects","pos":[0,20]}]},{"content":"Recruitment projects allow recruiters to track progress against filling one or more open positions.","pos":[1926,2025]},{"content":"The recruitment project identifies the department and job for which one or more positions are open.","pos":[2027,2126]},{"content":"Recruitment projects also track following information for open positions:","pos":[2127,2200]},{"content":"The specific number of open positions","pos":[2205,2242]},{"content":"The hiring manager and an alternative contact for the position","pos":[2247,2309]},{"content":"The date that the requisition was approved","pos":[2314,2356]},{"content":"The application deadline","pos":[2361,2385]},{"content":"The estimated start date","pos":[2390,2414]},{"content":"The recruitment project contains the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job ad<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> used on the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Employee self service<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> to advertise the opening.","pos":[2416,2527],"source":"The recruitment project contains the **Job ad** used on the **Employee self service** to advertise the opening."},{"content":"To display the opening to employees, the recruitment project must have a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Job ad<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>, the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Display on employee self service<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> field must be set to Yes, the <bpt id=\"p3\">**</bpt>Application deadline<ept id=\"p3\">**</ept> must be set to a future date, and the recruitment project must have a <bpt id=\"p4\">**</bpt>Project status<ept id=\"p4\">**</ept> of Started.","pos":[2528,2809],"source":" To display the opening to employees, the recruitment project must have a **Job ad**, the **Display on employee self service** field must be set to Yes, the **Application deadline** must be set to a future date, and the recruitment project must have a **Project status** of Started."},{"content":"The following table lists the possible recruitment project statuses and their description.","pos":[2810,2900]},{"pos":[2904,2914],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Status**"},{"pos":[2920,2939],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Indicates that…<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>","source":"**Indicates that…**"},{"content":"Scheduled","pos":[3114,3123]},{"content":"Recruiting efforts are being prepared.","pos":[3126,3164]},{"content":"Recruiting has not yet started for this project.","pos":[3166,3214]},{"content":"Started","pos":[3219,3226]},{"content":"Applications are now being accepted for the openings in this project.","pos":[3231,3300]},{"content":"Finished","pos":[3324,3332]},{"content":"All openings for this project have been filled.","pos":[3336,3383]},{"content":"Canceled","pos":[3429,3437]},{"content":"Recruiting has been canceled for this project.","pos":[3441,3487]},{"pos":[3533,3699],"content":"Recruiters can also record the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Media<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> used to advertise the opening through external outlets as well as track <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Developments<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> against the project or applications.","source":"Recruiters can also record the **Media** used to advertise the opening through external outlets as well as track **Developments** against the project or applications."},{"pos":[3701,3711],"content":"Applicants","linkify":"Applicants","nodes":[{"content":"Applicants","pos":[0,10]}]},{"content":"An applicant is a person who applies for a job in your enterprise.","pos":[3724,3790]},{"content":"Applicants are shared among all legal entities in your organization giving you a large pool of talent to search from.","pos":[3792,3909]},{"content":"You can maintain competencies, references, accommodation requests, and personal information for applicants.","pos":[3910,4017]},{"content":"When you create an applicant record, a person record for that applicant is created in the global address book.","pos":[4018,4128]},{"content":"You can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Applicant<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to update the following global address book information for people who are applicants:","pos":[4129,4250],"source":" You can use the **Applicant** page to update the following global address book information for people who are applicants:"},{"content":"Address information","pos":[4255,4274]},{"content":"Contact information","pos":[4279,4298]},{"content":"Identification information","pos":[4303,4329]},{"content":"Name details","pos":[4334,4346]},{"content":"Personal information","pos":[4351,4371]},{"pos":[4376,4388],"content":"Applications","linkify":"Applications","nodes":[{"content":"Applications","pos":[0,12]}]},{"content":"You can record information from employment applications that you receive in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page.","pos":[4389,4490],"source":"You can record information from employment applications that you receive in the **Application** page."},{"content":"The application is the applicant's expression of interest in a job opening in your organization.","pos":[4491,4587]},{"content":"To create an application, the applicant must already exist as an applicant or person in your system.","pos":[4589,4689]},{"content":"Employment applications submitted by applicants on the web are either solicited applications that were entered in response to a job ad, or are unsolicited applications.","pos":[4690,4858],"source":"\nEmployment applications submitted by applicants on the web are either solicited applications that were entered in response to a job ad, or are unsolicited applications."},{"content":"Solicited applications are automatically associated with the recruitment project that the job ad was created from.","pos":[4859,4973]},{"content":"Unsolicited applications are associated with the recruitment project that is specified in the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Recruitment<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> area of the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Human resources parameters<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[4974,5132],"source":" Unsolicited applications are associated with the recruitment project that is specified in the **Recruitment** area of the **Human resources parameters** page."},{"pos":[5137,5155],"content":"Application status","linkify":"Application status","nodes":[{"content":"Application status","pos":[0,18]}]},{"content":"The application status indicates where an application is in the recruitment process.","pos":[5157,5241]},{"content":"The following table lists the possible application statuses and their description.","pos":[5242,5324]},{"content":"Status","pos":[5328,5334]},{"content":"Indicates that…","pos":[5340,5355]},{"content":"Received","pos":[5540,5548]},{"content":"The application was received.","pos":[5552,5581]},{"content":"Confirmed","pos":[5646,5655]},{"content":"A notice can be sent to the applicant to confirm receipt of their application.","pos":[5658,5736]},{"content":"Interview","pos":[5752,5761]},{"content":"An interview invitation can be sent to the applicant.","pos":[5764,5817]},{"content":"Rejection","pos":[5858,5867]},{"content":"A rejection letter can be sent to the applicant.","pos":[5870,5918]},{"content":"Canceled","pos":[5964,5972]},{"content":"A withdrawal confirmation can be sent to the applicant.","pos":[5976,6031]},{"content":"This status is assigned manually.","pos":[6032,6065]},{"content":"Employed","pos":[6070,6078]},{"content":"An employment offer can be sent to the applicant.","pos":[6082,6131]},{"pos":[6179,6201],"content":"Correspondence actions","linkify":"Correspondence actions","nodes":[{"content":"Correspondence actions","pos":[0,22]}]},{"content":"An <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application’s<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> correspondence action determines the document or e-mail template that you use to communicate with the applicant who submitted the application.","pos":[6203,6366],"source":"An **Application’s** correspondence action determines the document or e-mail template that you use to communicate with the applicant who submitted the application."},{"content":"You can associate <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application bookmarks<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> with correspondence actions to allow you to use values from the Application, Applicant, Interview, and Recruitment project pages in your communications with applicants.","pos":[6367,6579],"source":" You can associate **Application bookmarks** with correspondence actions to allow you to use values from the Application, Applicant, Interview, and Recruitment project pages in your communications with applicants."},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application e-mail templates<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> can be created for the correspondence actions to quickly send e-mails to applicants who have an application with a certain status and correspondence action combination.","pos":[6581,6782],"source":"**Application e-mail templates** can be created for the correspondence actions to quickly send e-mails to applicants who have an application with a certain status and correspondence action combination."},{"content":"For example, you may send a Confirmation e-mail to all Applications with a <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Status<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> of Received and a <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Correspondence action<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> of Received.","pos":[6783,6925],"source":" For example, you may send a Confirmation e-mail to all Applications with a **Status** of Received and a **Correspondence action** of Received."},{"content":"After sending the e-mail, you have the option to automatically update the status of the applications.","pos":[6927,7028]},{"pos":[7033,7052],"content":"Application routing","linkify":"Application routing","nodes":[{"content":"Application routing","pos":[0,19]}]},{"pos":[7054,7221],"content":"If an application must be reviewed by several workers, you can use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Application routing<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to create a worker circulation list in order to manage the process.","source":"If an application must be reviewed by several workers, you can use the **Application routing** page to create a worker circulation list in order to manage the process."},{"pos":[7226,7236],"content":"Interviews","linkify":"Interviews","nodes":[{"content":"Interviews","pos":[0,10]}]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Applicant interviews<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> can be scheduled from the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Applications<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> page.","pos":[7238,7311],"source":"**Applicant interviews** can be scheduled from the **Applications** page."},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Send meeting information<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> button to send a calendar file with the interview schedule information to the applicant and interviewer.","pos":[7313,7454],"source":"  Use the **Send meeting information** button to send a calendar file with the interview schedule information to the applicant and interviewer."},{"pos":[7459,7472],"content":"Skill mapping","linkify":"Skill mapping","nodes":[{"content":"Skill mapping","pos":[0,13]}]},{"pos":[7474,7595],"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Skill mapping<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Skill mapping profiles<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> can be used to identify candidates who may be a good fit for an opening.","source":"**Skill mapping** and **Skill mapping profiles** can be used to identify candidates who may be a good fit for an opening."},{"pos":[7600,7617],"content":"Hiring applicants","linkify":"Hiring applicants","nodes":[{"content":"Hiring applicants","pos":[0,17]}]},{"content":"Use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Applications<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> page to hire an applicant.","pos":[7619,7670],"source":"Use the **Applications** page to hire an applicant."},{"content":"When you hire an applicant, the application record will have a status of <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Employed<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> and the applicant’s global address book person record is associated with the new worker record.","pos":[7671,7852],"source":" When you hire an applicant, the application record will have a status of **Employed** and the applicant’s global address book person record is associated with the new worker record."},{"content":"Modifications to the global address book information for the new worker record are also displayed in the applicant record.","pos":[7853,7975]},{"content":"This can help reduce data entry if the new worker ever applies for a different job within your enterprise.","pos":[7976,8082]},{"content":"To hire an existing worker into a new position, click <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Change position<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> in the <bpt id=\"p2\">**</bpt>Application status<ept id=\"p2\">**</ept> drop down to initiate the transfer process.","pos":[8084,8231],"source":"  To hire an existing worker into a new position, click **Change position** in the **Application status** drop down to initiate the transfer process."}]}